<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PolicyPage ID="x10535" Name="Approved Housing Requirements (Eligibility)" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" ID="1">Who can live in Approved Housing?</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" ID="2">This page outlines the eligibility requirements of who can live in Approved Housing.</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true" ID="3">20100831T06:00:00</Date><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" ID="4"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="5"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="6"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false" ID="7">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false" ID="8">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false" ID="9">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="10">0.5</Priority></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="11"><![CDATA[<h2>Single Students Must Live in Approved Housing</h2>
<p>All single students under the age of 30 must live in approved housing unless they live at home with their parents. Students who wish to live with a relative must submit a request for an exception and receive approval from the BYU-Idaho Housing &amp; Student Living Exceptions Committee (see "Exception to Policy" below). All off-track students who remain in Rexburg area must also live in approved housing.</p>
<p>Students in violation with the policies below may receive a restriction placed on their student account. For more information on resolving housing holds, click here.</p>
<h2>Qualifications for Living in Approved Housing</h2>
<p>All single students are required to live in BYU-Idaho approved housing. Those who qualify to live in approved housing are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Students who are currently attending BYU-Idaho as a student admitted to a track (the technical term is that a student must be a matriculated student).</li>
<li>Students who are off-track and continue to live in the immediate Rexburg area (includes summer session).</li>
</ol>
<h2>Not Eligible for Approved Housing</h2>
<p>Those who are not required or do not qualify to live in BYU-Idaho approved housing are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Individuals who have not been officially admitted to BYU-Idaho or who come to Rexburg prior to their assigned track.</li>
<li>Non-traditional or continuing education students.</li>
<li>Students who are married.</li>
<li>Single students who qualify as a family (have dependent children or are legal guardians of dependent children).</li>
<li>Widows or widowers, unless they receive an exception from the Housing &amp; Student Living Office.</li>
<li>Students who are divorced, unless they receive an exception from the Housing &amp; Student Living Office.</li>
<li>Students who are married but whose spouse is away for military duty, or who are otherwise not currently living with their spouse.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Loss of Eligibility</h2>
<p>As stated in approved housing standard contract, students who lose eligibility to live in BYU-Idaho approved housing must move out within 72 hours. This includes:</p>
<ol>
<li>Students who have been dismissed for a Student Honor violation or evicted for violations of BYU-Idaho Apartment Living Standards.</li>
<li>Students who are on academic suspension.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Exception to Policy</h2>
<p>Exceptions to the policy outlined above are handled on a case-by-case basis. Exceptions are reviewed weekly by the exceptions committee. To request an exception, complete an exception form and submit it to the Housing &amp; Student Living Office.</p>
<p>Students living at home with parents are granted an automatic exception. Students wishing to live with other family members or friends must get approval from the Housing &amp; Student Living Office by first submitting an exception form for review.</p>
<p>Note: exceptions will not be considered for students seeking to live with a married sibling when the non-relative spouse is the opposite gender. (For example, a young woman cannot live with her sister and brother-in-law or a young man cannot live with his brother and sister-in-law).</p>
<p>Students who are divorced or widowed and are interested in living in Approved Housing may file an exception. The Dean of Students may contact you after the form has been submitted. Students with children or legal guardianship(s) are not eligible to live in approved housing.</p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/housingexception">The exception form can be filled out online, here.</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="RelatedLinks" label="Related Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="RelatedLinksComponent" Expanded="false" ID="12"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9487" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false" ID="13"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" ID="14"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9287" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false" ID="15"/></PolicyPage>
