<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x10617" Name="Housing Exception Guidelines" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Who is eligible to fill out an exception?</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">All exceptions are handled on a case-by-case basis, but there are some generally accepted cases as well as situations that are not eligible for exception. For more details, click to learn more.</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110408T06:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>All exceptions are handled on a case-by-case basis, but there are some generally accepted for review as well as situations that will not be considered for exception.</p>
<h4>Examples of possible exceptions:</h4>
<ul>
<li>Students seeking  to live with extended family in the Rexburg area (aunts and uncles or grandparents)</li>
<li> Students seeking  to live with a married sibling where the non-relative spouse is the same gender</li>
<li>Divorced or widowed students (with no dependents) seeking to live in Approved Housing</li>
</ul>
<h4>Situations with no grounds for exception:</h4>
<ul>
<li>Married students seeking to live in Approved Housing</li>
<li>Students seeking  to live with a married sibling where the non-relative spouse is the opposite gender</li>
<li>Divorced or widowed students with dependents seeking to live in Approved Housing</li>
<li>Continuing Education students (i.e. students without a track assignment) seeking to live in Approved Housing</li>
<li>An engaged student seeking to live in community housing more than two or three weeks before their marriage date.</li>
<li>Non-students seeking to live in Approved Housing</li>
</ul>
<h4>Looking to come early?</h4>
<p>Many new students are interested in taking classes before they officially start school. These classes are offered through the continuing education program and are considered "Continuing Education students." Continuing Education students are not allowed to live in Approved Housing.</p>
<p>Students taking Continuing Education classes before they officially become admitted students and who wish to live in Approved Housing will need to submit a petition to the Admissions Office requesting to have the admitted, full student status granted to them early. That approval allows them to have all student services as well as sign-up for Approved Single Student Housing.</p>
<p>With the increasing growth of the University, this petition helps ensure current admitted student's needs are met.</p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/housingexception" target="_blank">The exception form can be filled out online, here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Housing/Documents Forms/PetitionToComeEarly.pdf">The petition to come early can be found, here.</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x10868" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9287" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
