<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x15480" Name="Produce Materials" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">How Do I Produce Communication Materials?</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">How Do I Produce Communication Materials?</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x15474" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style><!--
.article-bookmarks { border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: .5em; padding-top: 1.2em; padding-bottom: 0;  width: 180px; float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em; font-size: .8em;}
.article-bookmarks h3 { text-align: center; font-size: 1.6em;}
.article-bookmarks li { margin-left: 1em; font-family: "Helvetica", arial, sans-serif; }
.blue {color: #056CB6;}
a h2 {text-decoration: none !important;}
--></style>
<div class="article-bookmarks">
<h3>Marketing Options</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#bk-brochures">Brochure</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-email" style="font-family: Helvetica, arial, sans-serif;">Emails</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-fliers" style="font-family: Helvetica, arial, sans-serif;">Flyers&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li><a href="#bk-kiosks" style="font-family: Helvetica, arial, sans-serif;">Kiosks</a></li>
<li>Large Format Printed<a href="#bk-banners" style="font-family: Helvetica, arial, sans-serif;">&nbsp;Banners</a></li>
<li>Lawn SIgns</li>
<li><a href="#bk-overposters" style="font-family: Helvetica, arial, sans-serif;">Oversized Posters</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-posters">Poster</a></li>
<li>Table Tents</li>
<li>Web<a href="#bk-mywebbanner">&nbsp;Banners</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-other">Other Marketing Options</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><em>All</em>&nbsp;marketing materials on campus need to be approved by the University Relations Department before they are placed or distributed You can email your designs at <a href="mailto:branding@byui.edu">branding@byui.edu</a> or submit them by filling out the <a href="https://td.byui.edu/TDClient/Requests/TicketRequests/TicketForm.aspx?ServiceID=KYA5BFmKLwQ_">On-campus Marketing&nbsp;Approval Submission Form</a> for approval before anything is printed. This saves you time and money.</p>
<p>Below is a list of all the pre-approved marketing media that you can use on the BYU-Idaho campus. Each one includes a step-by-step guide to producing and receives approval for the respective option. If you have questions, you can always contact the Marketing Assistants at 208-496-3110 or <a href="mailto:branding@byui.edu">branding@byui.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong><em>Note:</em></strong> If you are an IBC company, please contact a Marketing Assistant for specific directions.</p>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-brochures"></a>Brochures&nbsp;</h2>
<p>Tri-fold or double-fold handout providing information about a department or society.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/brochures">Brochure template</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to <a href="mailto:branding@byui.edu">branding@byui.edu</a> for approval. One of the Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days.<strong> <strong>Please include the the following information in your email: (1) </strong></strong>PDF file of your brochure<strong> <strong>(2) </strong></strong>How many brochures you are planning to print<strong>&nbsp;<br /> </strong></li>
<li>Once your brochure(s) has been approved, you will have to bring them to Biddulph 362, where the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will stamp them. <strong>If you have recieved a digital stamp, you can skip this step.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;</li>
<li>Install them in the approved locations that will be listed in the approval email.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-overposters"></a>Email</h2>
<p>University Communications sends an email to students and another to faculty. There is three email types: Notices, Advisories, and The Feed. Students and employees are responsible for the information contained in both Notices and Advisories.&nbsp; The purpose of this email is to give organizations on campus the opportunity to send a message out via email (there is no other way for organizations to send an email out to everyone on campus besides this). Each office can send out one message per week (on either the Tuesday or the Thursday email).</p>
<ol>
<li>Write a headline that is up to 60 characters (including spaces) and two lines of text (up to 200 characters, including spaces). You may also include a URL that the message will link to from the email. This URL must be to a webpage on the BYU-Idaho website.</li>
<li>Send all of this information to newsdesk@byui.edu. All requests must be submitted to this email before 4:45pm on the day prior to being included in an email. Please visit&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/digital-ad-templates/campus-email">this page</a>&nbsp;for detailed information.<br /><br /></li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-kiosks"></a>Flyers/handbills</h2>
<p>Small, printed flyers and handbills may be used as promotional handouts that are handed out at booths in the MC, distributed via mail, or placed on a department countertop for people to take.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/fliers">flyer template</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days.</li>
<li>When you receive an email stating that your design is approved, you can print out the flyer. <strong>Fliers do not need a digital or physical stamp.</strong></li>
<li>This type of media is meant for distribution at events, booths, and as internal or external methods of communication for your office/department. <em>Note:</em> Please be sure that you're only distributing them in person, and only in the MC. Do not leave stacks of flyers around campus. If you are going to place flyers in any campus office, please obtain permission to do so from that office prior to placement.&nbsp;<strong><br /><br /> </strong></li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-banners"></a>&nbsp;Kiosks</h2>
<p>Kiosks are the 43.75x45 outdoor weather-protected posters in the three-sided covered stands in several different outdoor locations.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/kiosks">kiosk template.</a></li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business day. <strong>Please include the following information in your email: (1) </strong>PDF file of your Kiosks <strong>(2) </strong>How many Kiosks posters you are planning to print <strong>(3) </strong>Requested dates and locations. <strong><em>Note: </em></strong><strong>Remember, we hold a two-week policy for both Kiosk. </strong>Kiosks are posted for two weeks, and taken down for one week before going up again. If you wish to have your Kiosk poster up for an extended time, please contact our office.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters. You will then take them to the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants at 362 Biddulph Hall-they will put them up for you. Please bring your Kiosk posters a week in advance from the first display date. <strong><em>Note: </em></strong><strong>Any kiosk posters with expired dates are thrown away</strong> <strong>at the end of their display time</strong>. If you would like to keep the poster, be sure to contact the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants before the day that your kiosk is to be taken down.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-fliers"></a>Large Format Printed Banners</h2>
<p>Flexible, weatherproof signs for display that are 30x60 or 30x72 and are placed inside at a booth or outside on approved frames.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/banners">Large Format Banner template</a>.</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days. <strong>Please include the following information in your email: (1) </strong>PDF file of your banner <strong>(2) </strong>How many banners you will be printing <strong>(3) </strong>Where you will be placing the banner(s).&nbsp;</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print the posters and use the equipment needed. Please be sure to place them at the place of market or business. <strong>Large Format Banners do not need a digital stamp.</strong></li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-mywebbanner"></a>Lawn Signs/Walk-Along Signs/Ground Signs</h2>
<p>Weatherproof signs that are placed around campus on a temporary basis.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/posters">Posters template</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li>Download<strong>&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/logos">your organization's logo</a>&nbsp;</strong>and place it in the respective spot on the template<strong>.</strong></li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary<strong><br /></strong></li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days. <strong>Please include the the following information in your email: (1) </strong>PDF file of your lawn sign <strong>(2) </strong>Digital Stamp Request <strong>(3) </strong>How many lawn signs you are planning to print <strong>(4) </strong>Where you will be placing them: For Outside Use (Lawn Signs), please indicate where you will be placing the posters by the outside building location (EX: Outside the Hart, Outside the Taylor, Outside the Snow, etc.) <br /> <strong>NOTE: </strong><strong>The responsibility of placing and taking down the lawn signs is yours.</strong> Please make sure you pick up your lawn signs on the day you approval stamp expires.</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters or table tents. You will then bring them to 362 Biddulph Hall, where the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will stamp them. <strong>If you have requested the digital stamp, you can skip this step.</strong>&nbsp;</li>
<li>Install media in designated locations.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-email"></a>Oversized Posters/MC Posters</h2>
<p>Oversized posters are the 22x28 posters in the MC in the frames with rounded fronts.<br /><br /></p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/oversized-posters">oversized poster template</a>.</li>
<li>Download&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/logos">your organization's logo</a>&nbsp;and place it in the respective spot on the template</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business hours. <strong>Please include the following information in your email: (1) </strong>PDF file of your Oversize Poster <strong>(2) </strong>How many Oversize Posters you are planning to print <strong>(3) </strong>Requested dates and locations. <strong><em>Note: </em></strong><strong>Remember, we hold a two-week policy for Oversize Poster. </strong>Oversize Posters are posted for two weeks, and taken down for one week before going up again. If you wish to have you poster up for an extended time, please contact our office.&nbsp;</li>
<li>When you receive an email stating that your design is approved and your poster has been scheduled in an MC spot, you will print that email and bring it to the MC Info Desk with your printed media for installation. <strong>Oversized posters do not need a digital or physical stamp.</strong></li>
</ol>
<p><a name="Posters"></a><strong>Posters&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Posters are a common medium for campus promotion. Posters are 11x17 or 13x20 and are hung on the walls in buildings across campus in pre-approved locations.&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/posters">poster template</a></li>
<li>Download&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/logos">your organization's logo</a>&nbsp;and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days. <strong>Please include the the following information in your email: (1) </strong>PDF file of your poster <strong>(2) </strong>Digital Stamp Request <strong>(3) </strong>How many posters you are planning to print <strong>(4) </strong>Where you will be placing them (For Academic Buildings, please list the buildings that you plan to place you posters.)&nbsp;</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters or table tents. You will then bring them to 362 Biddulph Hall, where the Marketing Assistants will stamp them.</li>
<li>Put them up in the designated places. If you'd like to put table tents in the Crossroads, you'll need to first bring them to the MC Info Desk.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong><a name="Table Tents"></a>Table Tents</strong></p>
<p>Table tents are advertisements displayed three dimensionally on tables and counters.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/print-ad-templates/table-tents">table tents template</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li>Download&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/university-communications/templates-and-logos/logos">your organization's logo</a>&nbsp;and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Design your media with appropriate standards and submit to supervisor for approval if necessary</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to branding@byui.edu for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days. <strong>Please include the following information in your email: (1) </strong>PDF file of your table tent <strong>(2) </strong>Digital Stamp Request <strong>(3) </strong>How many table tents you are planning to print <strong>(4) </strong>Where you will be placing them. (For Academic Buildings, please list the buildings that you plan to place you posters.)</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters or table tents. You will then bring them to 362 Biddulph Hall, where the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will stamp them. <strong>If you have requested the digital stamp, you can skip this step.</strong></li>
<li>Install media in designated locations.&nbsp;<br /><strong><br /> </strong></li>
</ol>
<p><a name="Web Banners/My.byui Banners"></a><strong>Web Banners/My.byui Banners</strong></p>
<p>Campus message banners are the digitals ads that employees and students see on my.byui.edu, audience and department web pages open for events and other announcements.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/x16330.xml">my.byui banner template</a>&nbsp;and pay attention to the details outlined on that page about how to design a my.byui ad.</li>
<li>As you finish the design according to appropriate standards, please refer to the instructions on the template page. Do not edit the text in the template outside of changing the words.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Once the design is complete, send a PSD or JPG copy to <a href="mailto:ucidentity@byui.edu">branding@byui.edu</a> for approval. One of the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will email you back within 2 business days. <strong>Please include the following information in your email: (1) </strong>A PSD or JPG file of your web banner. <strong>(2)</strong>The URL link that audiences can be transferred to if they click on your banner for more information <strong><em>(Note:</em></strong><em> </em>This is essential to a web banner. We cannot post a web banner if there is not web page connected to it.) URL Links can be a social media page or school event/department page. <strong>(3) </strong>Target Audience (Students, Faculty, Online Students, Everyone, etc.) <strong>(4) </strong>Dates and Track that you would like to have the web banner on.</li>
<li>When you receive an email stating that your design is approved, the web banner will be posted.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;"><em>Note: </em></strong>we have a two-week policy for web banners. A banner can be up for two weeks with three consecutive days. After the two weeks the web banner must be down for one week. If you wish to have your web banner up for an extended time, please resend us the web banner with the url link and the new request days after the one week has passed. We have two tracks to choose from: Monday, Wednesday, Friday and Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday.&nbsp;
<ul style="display: inline !important;">
<li style="display: inline !important;">
<ul style="display: inline !important;">
<li style="display: inline !important;">If you do not include the above information, the Branding &amp; Marketing Assistants will make assumptions based on you web banner's information, which could potentially be incorrect.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="display: inline !important;"><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit; orphans: 3; widows: 3;"><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;"><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit; orphans: 3; widows: 3;"><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;"><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit; orphans: 3; widows: 3;"><strong style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #666666; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;"></strong></strong></strong></strong></strong></strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><br /> </strong></p>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-other"></a>Other Marketing Options&nbsp;</h2>
<ul>
<li>The school newspaper, the <em>Scroll</em>, sells advertising space in the paper. You can call 208-496-3730 or email scrollads@byui.edu for more information.</li>
<li>If you have an idea that is different from the above options, contact the Branding &amp; Marketing Office to propose it. If it is significantly different it may need to be approved by Communication Council, which could take several weeks.</li>
<li>Posters on easels can only be used at events to specify the location of the event (for example, right at the entrance to the room where the event is going on). They <em>cannot</em> be used for any other marketing across campus.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any questions about the above marketing options, please feel free to contact the Branding &amp; Marketing Office at 208-496-3110 or branding@byui.edu.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x10072" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
