<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x15585" Name="Policies and Procedures" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Policies and Procedures</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">policies and procedures for competitive sports</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&nbsp; <strong>8/27/2013</strong><br /><br /> <strong>Competitive Sports Policies and Procedures</strong> &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Competitive Sports at BYU-Idaho</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Competitive Sports is a student run sports program that provides opportunities for individuals to develop Personal Honor in a disciplined team environment. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>We feel the experiences individuals have in our programs allow them to see the power of acting for themselves which helps prepare them for lifelong learning, and their roles as citizens and parents.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>As a student run program everyone has the opportunity to learn through their interactions with their teams, their student coach(s), student leaders, and student officials.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&nbsp;There is no competition/practice outside the university or on campus against other schools. Each sport has an advisor employed by the university to mentor the students in leadership positions. Some of the characteristics seen in our competitive sports program include open tryouts for eligible participants, student coached teams, regular team practices (2-4 times per week), regular competitions (usually on Fridays or Saturdays), post season play, &nbsp;team uniforms, regular training meetings for coaches and other leaders.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Competitive Sports requires a greater commitment from the participants compared to the BYU-Idaho recreational sports program.&nbsp; Participants should plan to put in 5-10 hours per week.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;Stewardship Statement and Objectives 8/30/2013</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Competitive Sports provides opportunities for individuals to develop Personal Honor in a disciplined team environment.<strong></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quality Student Experience-Balance students expectations with outcomes</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Risk Management-Ensure a safe environment</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Communication-Successfully communicate with our audiences</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Organization and Management-Improve execution</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Personal/Leadership Development-Promote growth and fulfillment of the program's visi<strong>on</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Definitions</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">From simply playing your favorite sport to planning, organizing and running a sport league, participation in the Competitive Sports program is open to students in various forms.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Coach - This is a student volunteer position.&nbsp; Each team is led by a coach who is responsible to help plan and run tryouts, evaluate participants as they try out for a sport, draft their team, prepare and execute practice and game plans, attend and participate in weekly training meetings and ensure team members adhere to policies and rules.&nbsp; &nbsp;Most often coaches are motivated to take on the position simply because they desire to have the leadership experience coaching on campus can provide. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Assistant Coach - This is a student volunteer position.&nbsp; This position is selected by the head coach of a team and assists the head coach in all of their duties. It is preferred that all student assistant coaches attend the weekly training meetings. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Coordinator - This is a student volunteer position.&nbsp; The coordinator oversees all the logistics of running the competitive sports program including selection of coaches, schedules practices and games, uniforms, enforcing policies, weekly coaches meetings, tryouts, drafts,&nbsp; marketing sport, observations of coaches, one on ones with coaches, and student director, end of semester reflection banquets and reports. This can take 5-20 hours a week depending upon the things happening in the semester.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Director - This is a scholarship position.&nbsp; The director oversees multiple coordinators and assists them in training and duties to be performed (listed in coordinator responsibilities). The director will have weekly meetings with all the coordinators they oversee in training them about their responsibilities. They will meet with the area director, operations supervisor and advisors as needed to help in running the program. Observations of coordinators in their weekly meetings, individual team contests and practices are also part of their responsibility. They are in charge of retreats at beginning of semester and assisting area director in big events during the semester this may include, morning side, registration assistance meetings, and end of semester banquets. Average time spent will be approx. 10 hours per week.&nbsp; They may hold another campus employment position along with this position. In order to apply for this position, it is recommended that you first be a coordinator for a sport, to gain experience for the director position.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Area Director</strong> - <strong>This is a scholarship position. The area director meets with the advisor over competitive sports weekly and meets with directors in one on ones. They oversee all programs and events that take place over the course of the semester.&nbsp; &nbsp;They also are responsible for helping all student leaders to understand the stewardship statement and objectives in the programs. They follow up and review the measures of the objectives and help the rest of the student leaders to keep track and follow those objectives.&nbsp; They know all the current programs and look ahead to future offerings, timelines, and work closely with advisors in implementing policies and procedures with competitive sports.&nbsp; They may sit on governing boards for any participants that have had major infractions in a sporting event. &nbsp;Average time spent will be approx. 10 hours per week.&nbsp; They may hold another campus employment position along with this position. To apply for this position, it is recommended that you first be a director, in order to gain experience for the area director position.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Operations supervisor- Lead student paid over all the administrative activities involved with competitive sports.&nbsp; This includes: games management, compliance, IM leagues, web and social media, promotions, and broadcasting.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Other Paid positions competitive sports: &nbsp;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Games management: set-up, take down, sports first responders, sport misconduct, injury reports, game reports</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Compliance: eligibility, CPR, 1<sup>st</sup> response training, participation forms, registration, misconducts, governing board</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>o&nbsp;&nbsp; IM leagues: scheduling, team rosters, statistics</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Web and Social Media: print media, Facebook, twitter, Instagram, web pages, fliers and posters</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Broadcasting: webcasting, photography, videography, announcing</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Promotions (not paid), Half-time entertainment, game of the week and championship promotions (giveaways, entertainment, national anthem, sound opts program). </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Advisor - Full-time employee works with students in all levels of the program. &nbsp;This would include working with area director down to the participant. It is student run program; Advisors do their best to make sure that all objectives in the program are being met.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>4.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Participation Requirements</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Participation in Competitive Sports is restricted to</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Matriculating students from their first official day of classes until they stop matriculating which includes participation during their off track.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Spouses of matriculating students who have an activities I-card, and provide proof of insurance. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Personal Honor and how we conduct ourselves is very important in this experience. Winning in the sporting world outside of BYU-Idaho is considered one of the most important objectives.&nbsp; We understand the desire athletes have to win, but feel there are more significant ways to determine success such as commitment, determination and attitude.&nbsp; We want everyone who is participating to plan and prepare to do their best in every situation they are in and then to be able to reflect on their performance and make their own determination of success regardless of what a scoreboard says.&nbsp; Because this is a learning experience individuals may sometimes forget this and they may act inappropriately and receive sanctions for their actions.&nbsp; These sanctions are to help the individual identify an action or conduct in their lives they can work to improve on.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Participation Fee:&nbsp;&nbsp; All sport offerings require participants to pay a participation fee.&nbsp; This fee is charged when players are selected for a team.&nbsp; If you decide at any time before tryouts are completed that Competitive Sports is not for you there will be no charge.&nbsp; However, it is your responsibility to communicate this to the coordinator over that sport before the tryouts are completed.&nbsp; Some sports may have a spirit pack or some type of clothing that is additional to the participation fee in order to participate. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Eligibility for tryouts: To become eligible to try out for a sport you must create an IM leagues account, join the specific sport's registration team and complete the participation forms.&nbsp; IM Leagues is used to manage rosters and schedule all competitions if you are not registered or are ineligible on IM leagues you will not be allowed to participate. To create an IM leagues account there are step-by-step instructions that can be found on the Competitive Sports website. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">5.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Safety Participant safety is of utmost importance to the organization and administration of each activity. The program has established procedures to minimize the inherent risks to participants and spectators. Institutional resources such as the Safety Office are used to establish procedures to minimize the inherent risks to participants, and spectators.&nbsp; Each participant will read and accept assumption of risk form associated with playing via IM leagues. &nbsp; Each team will have at least one CPR certified person on each team before they can practice and play during the semester.&nbsp; This can be a player or a coach. &nbsp; Each coach will take and pass a quiz for sport emergency training certification each semester (online). &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">6.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Health, Injuries and Insurance There are inherent risks associated with participating in Competitive Sports. The Competitive Sports programs DOES NOT carry health or accident insurance for the participants. A medical insurance program is required by BYU-IDAHO for all students enrolled in school. This policy covers accidents that occur during Competitive Sports programs as well as many other cases. Each participant should check his or her personal coverage and be certain that his or her medical insurance is adequate and current before participating in any activity.&nbsp; &nbsp;It is the responsibility of every person participating in Competitive Sports to ascertain whether they have any health conditions that make it inadvisable to participate in that sport. We do not require physical examinations except for Competitive Football. The University and Competitive Sports Program DO NOT assume that responsibility. Persons who are uncertain should consult their physician. The participants should notify the certified athletic trainer at BYU-Idaho of ALL INJURIES sustained during Competitive Sports practices or competitions.&nbsp; EMS may be dispatched TO ASSESS INJURIES.&nbsp; THERE IS NO COST FOR INJURY ASSESSMENT BUT ANY COST FOR EMS TREATMENT/TRANSPORTATION IS THE PARTICIPANT'S RESPONSIBILITY. An accident/injury report will be completed for all injuries.&nbsp; BYU-IDAHO Student Health Center is open weekdays and is available to students for treatment of most injuries.&nbsp; Life threatening emergencies should be referred to the Emergency room at Madison Memorial Hospital.&nbsp; Any injury that needs treatment outside of the Student Health Center hours should also be referred to the Emergency room or Community Care.&nbsp; The Competitive Sports program will provide initial emergency care to any participant injured during a competitive practice or game.&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">7.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sports &amp; BYU-Idaho Rule modifications &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Baseball:&nbsp; Currently not available We follow NFHS rules with the following BYU-Idaho modifications:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Games are 6 innings</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Automatic slide rule for any play made at home plate</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speed up rule for pitchers and catchers</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We only allow the use of wood bats &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Softball women's fast pitch:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Automatic slide rule for any play made at home plate &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Soccer: &nbsp;BYU-Idaho Sports Slide Tackling Policy &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Slide tackling is prohibited, and any player in violation of this rule will be issued a sportsmanship infraction.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sliding is not a violation of the soccer rules, as long as it does not endanger any other player on the field.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Slide tackling shall be defined as player sliding in a way that endangers another player, i.e. sliding while trying to take the ball from another player's control or fighting for possession.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">* All calls are under the judgment of the official.&nbsp;</p>
<ul style="text-align: left;" type="disc">
<li>Use Fifa rules:</li>
<li>Equipment: Shin guards are required for practice and games.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: left;">Football:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: Kickoffs will occur and will follow rule 6-1 between the kicker's free kick line and up to ten yards beyond the receiver's scrimmage line. Any kick muffed or fumbled either in the air or on the ground by R within the zone REG is a live ball and may be advanced by R and recovered by K (but not advanced by K)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: Kickoffs kicked beyond the REG zone and into but not beyond the DOA zone may not be advanced by either team. If muffed in the air the ball remains live and may be recovered, but not advanced by either team. The ball will become dead upon recovery or as in a punt the ball will become dead if no player makes an attempt to secure the ball.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: Kickoffs kicked beyond the REG and DOA zones and into the ADV zone may not be advanced by either team. If muffed in the air the ball remains live and may be recovered, but not advanced by either team. The ball will become dead upon recovery or as in a punt the ball will become dead if no player makes an attempt to secure the ball. If a ball is caught by R in flight the ball will next be put in play 15 yards in advance of the spot of the catch. If the ball is recovered after first contacting the field or being muffed and recovered by R the ball will next be put in play 10 yards in advance of the spot of the recovery. If the ball becomes dead with no team in possession as in a punt the ball will next be put in play the spot the ball becomes dead.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: If K kicks the ball past the REG zone they may not gain possession of the ball except from a muff of an in-flight ball by R.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: Beyond the REG zone R will be required to fair catch a ball in flight with or without giving the fair catch symbol. No blocking may take place outside of the REG zone unless there is a muff of a kick in flight and the blocking is connected directly to the recovery of the ball.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: All K players except for the kicker must assume a starting position within 1 foot of the kicker's free kick line.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-1: All players in each zone must make a genuine attempt to play the ball instead of only contacting another player who is attempting to secure the ball. Penalty 15 Yards Personal Foul Illegal personal contact. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 6-2: Scrimmage kicks will be adapted for safety to require R to fair catch scrimmage kicks with or without giving the fair catch symbol and in the event of a muff neither team may advance the ball. All other scrimmage kick rules apply. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rule 7-5-2c-d: The illegal forward pass rule shall be adapted from the NCAA exception as follows. Exception: It is not a foul when the passer, who is or has been outside the frame of the body of the normal tackle position toward a sideline, throws the ball so that it crosses the neutral zone or neutral zone extended." Equipment: All equipment should be worn for practice when there is full contact. (mouth pieces, pads, shoulder pads, helmets etc.) Participants are first line of defense to make sure they're equipment is correct. Coaches are second line of defense to make sure they're equipment is correct. Officials for games are 3rd line of defense to make sure they're equipment is correct. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Lacrosse:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Rules modifications:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Lacrosse has modified the men's checking rules to be stick checks only and no body checks. Equipment: All equipment should be worn for practice when there is full contact. (Head gear, mouth guards, shoulder pads or chest protector and gloves) &nbsp;Participants are first line of defense to make sure they're equipment is correct. Coaches are second line of defense to make sure they're equipment is correct. Officials for games are 3rd line of defense to make sure they're equipment is correct. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Wrestling:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Rules modifications:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Rules are high school except for weight certification rules and we use college weights (plus any necessary adjustments) instead of high school weights.&nbsp; Additionally we often adjust the timing to 1-2-2 or 2-1-1 at the beginning of the season before the athletes are in shape.&nbsp; Equipment: Head gear is required for matches.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Basketball:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Use High school rules</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 30 second shot clock for all games</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Free throws lane players may enter on the release Rules Modifications: Fast Break Rule:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The defensive player must be even or ahead of offensive player to make a play on the ball.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If a play is made illegally the basket will be awarded along with the ball out of bounds for the offensive team.&nbsp; If the basket is made on the fast break rule and a foul occurs the basket will be awarded and one free throw with the ball afterwards being awarded to the offensive team. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Spirit team:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Safety protocol for spirit team:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hold cheer/stunt tryouts making sure the participants have a basic understanding and knowledge of cheer/stunting (spotting and safety issues)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Coaches must teach participants proper skills and how to spot and the importance of safety</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Extra Spotters (always)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Proper warm-ups/cool downs</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Building pyramids will be a (2-2-1) protocol only, no higher &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">8.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Resources As a participant in Competitive Sports you will have the following resources available to you: high quality facilities and equipment, uniforms,&nbsp; access to experienced sport advisors/mentors, sports specific training aids,&nbsp; and the sports first aid area. &nbsp; The sports first aid area is located in Hart 161 (north of the main gym). The sports first aid students are there to support competitive sports athletes with injury prevention and management.&nbsp; They provide the following services: athletic taping and wrapping for practices and games, care of acute injuries and game day coverage for the high impact sports.&nbsp; Treatment room hours: Monday-Friday 2:00 - 7:00.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp; 9.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sports Rotation The competitive sports program will try and offer each sport on their traditional sports season. We will try and offer them according to the demands of the students by measuring the amount of students in free play, interest in clinics/camps, interest in tournaments and interest of students in recreational sports. If a coordinator is not chosen by the 6<sup>th</sup> week of the semester before we will not run that sport.&nbsp; We are looking to select coordinators at the end of the traditional semester nearly a year in advance.&nbsp; This coordinator along with any assistants will help promote the sport during the off semester (s) via clinics, tournaments, or rec sports.&nbsp; They can use these events/leagues to help evaluate participants and aid in the selection process for coaching the next semester the sport is run. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Traditional competitive sports offerings</p>
<table align="center" border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Winter</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Winter 2014&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Spring 2014&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fall 2014 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Basketball &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Golf&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Football Wrestling&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Track and Field&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cross Country Water Polo&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Softball&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Soccer Spirit team&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ultimate&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Swimming &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lacrosse&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Volleyball &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tennis &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Spirit team &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">10. Deadlines All of our leadership positions have application deadlines.&nbsp; We encourage students to plan ahead and apply for leadership positions that will help them in their future careers, occupation and families.&nbsp; We can choose some coordinator positions as far as a year in advance.&nbsp; This way they can prepare ways for students to get in shape and to learn skills that will help them be better prepared for their regular sport season and to help them make a team. Director and Area director applications are typically due by the 4<sup style="font-family: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit;">th</sup> week of the semester for the next semester they intend to serve.&nbsp; Students on scholarship may serve two different semesters on scholarship in competitive sports, one as a director and one as an area director.&nbsp; Campus policy allows students to serve three different semesters on a leadership scholarship. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">11.&nbsp; Sanctions &nbsp; Good sportsmanship is absolutely essential in athletic competition. Good sportsmanship includes thoughtfulness and concern for others; sincere admiration for the skills of teammates, opponents, and officials; self-control, humility in victory; and calmness and composure in defeat. It is fair play, following both the spirit and the letter of the rules. It is the Golden Rule in action on the playing court, on the bench and in the stands. Promoting good sportsmanship in competitive activities is everyone's responsibility. &nbsp; Manipulation of the rules and intentional fouls are considered cheating and a gross offense against the spirit of competition. Abusive language and/or "trash talking" toward opponents, teammates or officials is not part of the game. Participants or teams who make a mockery of the game either through their actions or attire will not be allowed to participate in Sports Activities. &nbsp; <em>Sportsmanship is everyone's responsibility</em>. We hope that everyone will conduct themselves in a mature and friendly manner. Coaches are responsible for the conduct of their players AND their spectators. Spectators may be asked to leave if necessary. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;">Team:</strong> If a team accumulates 6 points during a semester, that team will be dropped from further play. However, during tournament play, a team will be dropped if they reach the cumulative total of 6 points or receive 4 points during tournament play, whichever comes first. &nbsp; <em>Team Conduct Resulting in a Forfeit</em> The following team behavior will result in a game being immediately stopped and forfeited. (Regardless of score and time) &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Three separate participants receiving any combination of sportsmanship cards</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two participants receiving red cards.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Failure of ejected participant(s) and/or spectator(s) to leave the vicinity immediately (2 minutes)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; An ejected individual returns to the vicinity or during or after the game. &nbsp; <strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;">&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;">Individual:</strong> <strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> Minor misconducts will be given for minor offenses and are worth one (1) personal sportsmanship point. The following are minor misconduct offenses:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Arguing</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rough play</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Taunting opponents</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jumping any fence around the facilities</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dishonesty</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Slide Tackling Major<strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;"> </strong>misconduct will be given for major offenses and are worth two (2) personal sportsmanship points.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The following are major misconduct offenses:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Illegal participation</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Flagrant contact</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Profanity</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Crude, Derogatory or offensive language</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fighting</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Threatening behavior Sports Activities upholds a no-swearing/verbal abuse policy.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Any participant found to be violating policy will be given an immediate major misconduct. If a player receives a major misconduct they will be suspended from all Sports Activities until they meet with the Sports Misconduct Council. Players are responsible for arranging their own misconduct meetings with Sports administration. After the player has met with the Sports Misconduct Council a decision regarding the length of suspension will be made. If a player receives three (3) individual points during a semester in one or more sports, his/her Sports Activities privileges will be suspended for the remainder of that semester. Individuals that receive six (6) points are sent a letter indicating that they will be suspended with the Sports Program for a period of one (1) year.&nbsp; Points begin to be dropped from an individual's record after two (2) years.&nbsp; An individual having 4 or 5 points to their record is considered on probation and may continue to participate. If they choose to continue to participate they are made aware that any more sanctions will result in an additional one-year suspension of Sports privileges.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Players meeting with Sports administration to resolve a major misconduct can expect the following as minimum consequences:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Profanity/Offensive/Derogatory language - one (1) week (or one game for tournaments) suspension from all Sports activities</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Use of extremely vulgar language including the F-word, taking the Lord's name in vain, etc. - two (2) week suspension from all Sports activities</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Verbal abuse - one (2) week suspension from all Sports activities Flagrant fouls, intentionally endangering an opponent, or threatening behavior - two (2) week suspension from all Sports Activities</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Impersonation of another player - Full semester suspension from all Sports activities and a referral to the Dean's Office.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Striking or fighting - Full-semester suspension from all Sports activities and a referral to the Dean's Office. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">12.&nbsp; &nbsp;Adding Players after tryouts &nbsp; Competitive Sports Policy for Adding Players&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">1-&nbsp;&nbsp; No participants are added after drafts and tryouts unless it is by consensus of the director, coordinator, and advisor (coordinator will gather information from coaches pertaining to the sport)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">2-&nbsp;&nbsp; Participants must participate in two regularly scheduled practices in order to play their first competition</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">3-&nbsp;&nbsp; Participants must participate in minimum of two weeks of competitions in order to play post season &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">13.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;Practice players&nbsp; PRACTICE PLAYER = Player who is not on active roster.&nbsp; Teams that have cuts may have practice players.&nbsp; Once a player participates in one competition they are then an active player for rest of semester.&nbsp; The coach will need to make it known to the league when the status of player has changed.&nbsp; ACTIVE PLAYER = Player selected to be on team roster --Only players to receive uniforms &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"></h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
