<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17694" Name="Eat Right 101" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Eat Right 101</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090301T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Julie Harker Buck</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Eat Right 101</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Julie Harker Buck</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, March 2009)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
&ldquo;Eat your vegetables&rdquo;, &ldquo;An apple a day keeps the doctor away&rdquo;, &ldquo;Drink your milk, it will help you grow healthy and strong.&rdquo; <br /> <br /> Growing up in a household of five sisters, we received a lot of  nutrition messages intended to help us make good food choices.&nbsp; We grew  up with loving parents that provided adequate food and family mealtimes.  Little did my family know that I would grow up to become a Registered  Dietitian. What were the food lessons you learned while young? What type  of food and nutrition information do you receive today?<br /> <br /> Let&rsquo;s consider what our children are viewing on television. It is  estimated that children view four hours of television everyday&sup1;. This  takes away from time spent in physical activity.&nbsp; The American Academy  of Pediatrics recommends no more than 2 hours per day&sup2;. What are  children watching? It is estimated that during one year of TV viewing,  children will see 2000 beer and wine ads.&nbsp; As parents, friends and  relatives, we must take an active role to influence healthy lifestyles  in those we know and love.<br /> <br /> As March is National Nutrition Month, let&rsquo;s focus on the importance of  making informed food choices and developing sound eating and physical  activity habits. When deciding to make the best food choices for our  health, we should gather as much credible information as we can. This  reminds me of the most often asked question each semester while teaching  nutrition at Brigham Young University Idaho, &ldquo;Which is better, butter  or margarine?&rdquo; To best answer this question, each person needs to  evaluate their individual health, eating patterns and if fat calories  are a concern in their diet.&nbsp; By reviewing each of our health indicators  such as meal intake, physical activity, laboratory blood work, weight  patterns and genetic influences, an informed food choice and sound  eating practice can be made for each of us. <br /> <br /> Living a physically active life is more than visiting a gym daily; it is  choosing to move more each day.&nbsp; Can we choose to take the stairs  instead of the elevator? Walk instead of drive? Push a lawn mower  instead of driving one? Stretch our muscles to improve range of motion?  Strengthen our muscles to ensure longer independence as we age?&nbsp; Would a  pedometer help motivate us to take more steps in a day or give us  credit for those we already take? Please consider ways you can daily  increase your movements to increase your health and well-being. Recently  a co-worker and I found time to walk while at work on a weekly basis.  Having someone to encourage me and be there helps me to show up. The  best method of becoming more physically active is the one that you will  regularly perform.<br /> <br /> Overwhelmed? Discouraged? Today, reach for the stars. Right now! Stop  reading and stretch your arms to the ceiling. Doesn&rsquo;t that feel good?  Just smile at those in the office/home wondering what you are doing.  Roll your head first to the right, then to the left. You are moving.  That is progress.<br /> <br /> Not sure what to have for dinner? Forgot lunch today? Grab a pen and  paper. Write down what is in your cupboard, refrigerator, freezer, and  pantry. When I try this experiment with students, the list often reveals  foods that could easily be made into a soup, stew or casserole.&nbsp; Many  keep food staples on hand for spaghetti, burritos or ready to eat items  such as chili or sandwiches. Recording what we eat will create a meal  record, which can become a monthly meal plan.&nbsp; Create your shopping list  according to your meal plan.&nbsp; Congratulations, you have just reduced  stress and saved money by planning your meals ahead of time.<br /> <br /> Need to find a nutrition expert in your area? Have a question about  something you have heard in the news, from a newspaper or friend?  Sorting out the nutrition fact from fallacy takes a lot of time and  effort. There is a resource that everyone can use to search for correct  facts, pertinent knowledge and helpful documents. Eatright.org is the  website from The American Dietetic Association&sup3;. They are the  international certifying organization for Registered Dietitians and  Certified Dietetic Technicians. Recently, they have revised their  website to provide a more user friendly source for credible nutrition  facts and resources. For those persons preferring a phone number, call  800-877-1600.&nbsp; By accessing the website or calling the toll free number,  you can find the answers you are looking for.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> References<br /> 1. www.med.umich.edu/1libr/yourchild/TV.htm University of Michigan Health System.<br /> 2. www.aap.org/ The American Academy of Pediatrics.<br /> 3. www.Eatright.org The American Dietetic Association. 1-800-877-1600.<br /> <br /> <br /> Article written by Julie Harker Buck, MHE, RD, CD, LCCE . Registered  Dietitian, Certified DONA doula, Lamaze Certified Childbirth Educator.  Mother of six. Adjunct Faculty member in the Department for Home and  Family Education at Brigham Young University- Idaho.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>