<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17702" Name="Daily Outside Play" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Daily Outside Play</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090508T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mike Godfrey</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Daily Outside Play</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Mike Godfrey</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, May 2009)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I  sure hope Mother&rsquo;s Day is beautiful this year! I hope the sun is  shining, the grass is green, and we have some warm weather. But even if  we don&rsquo;t, I&rsquo;ll bet it is still beautiful&mdash;a perfect day for going  outside. Mothers and girls&mdash;fathers and boys too&mdash;of all ages benefit from  daily outdoor play. It stimulates the senses and helps build  imaginations. The many sights, sounds, smells, and textures outdoors  combine to make a rich tapestry that can&rsquo;t be duplicated. Compared to  indoor play, preschoolers engage in more complex play outside and most  children extend the play for longer periods of time, explore deeper  themes, and develop a greater sense of wonder.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">So  in this age of declining recess and more exciting video games, how can  we encourage playing outdoors? Barbara Crossley, Beverlie Dietze, and  several others have a few ideas:</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">First,<strong>have a great attitude</strong>!  We must not let the outdoors keep us indoors. In Scandinavia they say  there is no such thing as bad weather, only bad clothes. In the winter I  heard adults say, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s too cold to go outdoors.&rdquo; Now that it is almost  summer I hear, &ldquo;But it will be too hot!&rdquo; If the weather keeps us  indoors too often, we and our children miss important opportunities. How  else can we learn about rain, or wind, or sun, or snow? Instead of  running to the window to see the rainbow, it&rsquo;s great to discover the  rainbow! Seeing the garter snake slither on TV is not nearly as  adventurous as watching it in real life.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><strong>Keep it healthy and safe</strong>.  Nationwide at least 44% ofthe injuries requiring hospitalization occur  on playgrounds because of inadequate supervision. Making sure the  equipment is safe is also a key, even on public playgrounds. Obviously,  we need to take the necessary precautions; supervision, safe equipment,  sunscreen and appropriate clothing come to mind, but part of being  outdoors is taking risks and exploring. The adult&rsquo;s role is not to lead  the play, but perhaps be part of the play. Let the youngster be in  charge in the absence of danger. If they are having trouble finding  something to do, create an activity with them.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Giveoutdoor play <strong>enough time</strong> so people can engage in complex, integrated, in-depth activities or  explorations. And it may be something that is worth revisiting the next  day. Personally, I was a play-in-the-dirt-with-trucks kid myself. My  mother would let us play for hours at a time, and when my brother and I  came back the next day, we would pick upright where we left off. Once,  my older brother told us there was gold hidden in a rock under the  garden. We were to &ldquo;mine&rdquo; it with our toys until we foundit. My brother  and I dug for days and finally had about a 2 foot hole in our garden.  After we found our &ldquo;gold,&rdquo; a common cobblestone rock, we were rich and  spent the next several weeks &ldquo;spending&rdquo; our riches. My older brother  later told us he did not know where the rock was but he knew we would  get to it sooner or later, we lived in Idaho.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Oneof the best parts of being outdoors is the ability to <strong>make </strong><strong>anything something else</strong>. Like Katherine Paterson&rsquo;s <em>Bridge to Terabithia</em>,  we can make the outdoors a terribly exciting place. All it takes is a  space, a fewprops, and time. The props may be something found&mdash;a stick,  some straw, perhaps even a ball. The best props are open-ended, that is  they do not have a defined purpose that limits their play. For example, a  stick is a staff, a goal post,the finish line, a shield, a wall, a  baby, the list is as limitless as the imagination!</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">If it is a good day weather-wise take a few, or more, <strong>indoor things outside</strong>. You can also take a few <strong>outdoor things inside</strong>.  Write a story about that spider and where it is going. Draw a picture  of grass growing. How would your child design that playhouse?&nbsp; Examine  that bulb closely under the lights.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">An  added benefit is the exercise. The outdoor space especially demands  activity from children. Since childhood obesity has reached epidemic  levels, spending some time outdoors may help curb the disturbing trend.  It has also been shown that boys especially need to spend time outdoors  to help them academically. It may seem counter-intuitive, but studying  all the time does not raise test scores&mdash;but a balance of studying and  physical exercise does, especially play outdoors.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Now  that I&rsquo;ve got all these things, I think I&rsquo;d better take my children  outside to play. What a better gift for mother&rsquo;s day than happy, healthy  children&mdash;whether the weather cooperates or not.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><br />Mike Godfrey is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>