<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17876" Name="The Benefits of Family Meetings " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Benefits of Family Meetings </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20081001T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Steve Dennis </Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The Benefits of Family Meetings</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Steve Dennis</p>
<h6>(LDS Life - October 2008)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A young boy watched as his father outlined his business contacts,  appointments, and prioritized his tasks for the busy day to come.  The  boy asked, "Dad, what's in your book?"  The father responded, "This is  my planner, where I keep a list of all the important people I know and  things I must do." After some reflection, the boy responded,  "Dad, is  my name in there?"</p>
<p>Often we think of family time as something that will just happen as an  automatic part of family life.  For many, the idea of bringing mission  statements, goals, meeting agendas and minutes home from the workplace  seems too formal for the family.  But would most businesses be  successful if they were managed like our families?  Steven R. Covey has  suggested that, "Many families are managed on the basis of crises,  moods, quick fixes, and instant gratification--not sound principles."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>He suggests that for families and business to be successful, they must  be proactive, not reactive. One of the best ways to be proactive or  intentional about our family is to hold a regular family meeting or  family council.  Elder M. Russell Ballard has said, "There has never  been a time when the world was in greater need of the strength and  security that are best sown and cultivated in the deep, fertile soil of  family love. The family is under heavy attack from antagonists bent on  extinguishing this powerful source of light in a darkening world.  Successful families have a wide assortment of tools, and one of the most  useful tools is the family council.("Family Councils: A Conversation  with Elder and Sister Ballard," Ensign, Jun 2003, 14)</p>
<p><br /> A family meeting can be an opportunity to clarify expectations,  celebrate accomplishments, strengthen communication, teach one another,  resolve problems, and build commitment to family time.  Without a  regular avenue to discuss family issues, miscommunication is common, and  problems are often discussed only when they have come to a boil.  Such a  time is hardly the best time to resolve problems in a loving and  cooperative way.</p>
<p><br /> Of course, family meetings can also be disastrous if they are held only  when cookies are missing from the cookie jar or the chore list needs to  be passed out.  Instead, they can be positive by planning for good  times, and celebrating family achievements.  Family meetings are most  successful when they are held regularly, follow a simple agenda, record  assignments and outcomes, and share the responsibility for running the  meeting.  They should also be short, fun, and end on a high note--like  chocolate!  Some families find having a gavel is fun.  Others share the  floor by passing a "talking stick".  Still other families have found  that ending with a family hug, or family song is useful.  Family  meetings can make a real difference in your life. Look in your planner.    Have you made time for your family?  Schedule a meeting--a family  meeting.<br /> <br /></p>
<p><br /> Steve Dennis is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>