<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17837" Name="A Family who Play’s Together, Stays Together" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A Family who Play’s Together, Stays Together</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090708T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Karla Kay Edwards</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>A Family who Play&rsquo;s Together, Stays Together</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Karla Kay Edwards</p>
<h6>(LDS Life - July 2009)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Outside the wind was howling, the snow was drifting, the temperatures  were dropping. Looking out the front window I realize how grateful I was  to have the warmth of home to keep the elements at bay. I was also  getting &ldquo;cabin fever&rdquo; as winter was still at its fury in February. How I  longed for those warm summer days on the beach. In my mind, I began  listening to the waves lap the shores while the sea gulls sang their  songs of sand and water. I yearned to sun myself on the banks of a lake.<br /> Inside the wood stove was fired up, electric lights replaced the sun,  and it looked like one more day of winter would keep us inside. It would  be another day of chores and routine for me and my four small children.  But those images of warm summer days continued to fill my mind. It was  at that moment I decided we all needed to spend the day at the beach.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Gathering my children, we began to formulate a plan. We would need  scenery, surf boards, beach balls, swimming and summer wear.&nbsp; A picnic  basket filled with all the aromas of summer would be required. Yards of  butcher paper were fastened to the walls of the family room. Those walls  soon began transforming into the waves of the ocean. Pictures portrayed  whales sputtering water above themselves.&nbsp; Multicolored marine life  swam in the waters or played on the sand. Several dazzling, smiling suns  dotted the bright blue sky. Cardboard surf boards were made and  strategically placed on the carpet. Beach toys and balls scattered the  floor to complete our make &ndash; believe sunny summer day.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>By the time my husband returned home from work, we were all in our  summer clothes, the wood stove had been cranked up, the picnic basket  was loaded, and the Beach Boys were blaring on the CD player. We headed  to the ocean front, or rather, to the transformed family room. There, a  red checkered table cloth was spread on the ground. We ate sandwiches,  carrots, grapes, and drank cool &ndash; aid. Then we put on sun screen (which  helped to invite the smells of summer) and danced to the music. It was a  delightful day of giggling, playing, laughing, and making a memory that  would remain in our hearts forever.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Play is a very important part of children&rsquo;s life.&nbsp; Play is the business  of children. It is essential because of the contribution it presents  toward the development of a child&rsquo;s cognitive, physical, social, and  emotional well&ndash;being. But more importantly, play offers an ideal  opportunity for parents to engage fully with their children.&nbsp; If parents  play with their children, a stronger relationship will bolster the  family unit.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Parents who truly enjoy the company of their young children will reap  the benefits.&nbsp; A stronger connection must become central as the children  move into the teenage years, onto adolescence, and finally adulthood.&nbsp;  The perfect time to cultivate this bond is during childhood. The best  way to connect is to laugh, play, and work together. If an offer of  social interaction within a family is suggested only after children are  teenagers, chances are, friends will become the social force of choice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As children progress towards their teenage years, parents often are  &ldquo;replaced&rsquo; as the entertainment committee, even worse, they are  substituted as confidante. These replacements come in the form of  friends and cohorts. A key in keeping the family unit connected is to  create activities more inviting. When I asked my son why he so eagerly  participated in family outings as a teenager, he replied, &ldquo;Because you  made it more fun than hanging out with my friends&rdquo;.&nbsp; That seems to be  the key ingredient. Make family together time more enjoyable than  &ldquo;hanging out with friends&rdquo;!<br /> Diane Loomans said it best, <br /> If I had my children to raise all over again,<br /> I&rsquo;d build self-esteem first, and the house later.<br /> I&rsquo;d finger-paint more, and point the finger less.<br /> I would do less correcting and more connecting.<br /> I&rsquo;d take my eyes off my watch, and watch with my eyes.<br /> I&rsquo;d take more hikes and fly more kites.<br /> I&rsquo;d stop playing serious, and seriously play.<br /> I would run through more fields and gaze at more stars.<br /> I&rsquo;d do more hugging and less tugging.<br /> <br /> Parent&rsquo;s who only enjoy their children&rsquo;s company once they reach  adulthood miss out on years of joy, happiness, and strong family ties.  Laughter and play can be a soothing balm to the challenges of guiding  children through their life. The best advice is to, &ldquo;Stop playing  serious, and seriously play.&rdquo;<br /> <br /> <br /></p>
<p><br /> Karla Edwards is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>