<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17897" Name="Best Christmas Trees Ever" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Best Christmas Trees Ever</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Parents can learn a lot from looking back at the things that really mattered to their children. Michael Williams shares an example of imperfect Christmas trees that taught valuable lessons.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20101201T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Your Name</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h2><strong>The Best Christmas Trees Ever</strong></h2>
<p>By Michael D. Williams</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, December 2010)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I had been encouraged to write about how we can avoid unnecessary stress and frustration during the holiday season. But I get tired of those kinds of talks and articles; they seem too negative at a time when I want the world and my home filled with joy.</p>
<p>So I decided to write about the most enjoyable Christmas seasons I've experienced. I was interested to note that there was something special about the trees that decorated our homes at those times. So I've decided to indulge myself...and write about those trees.</p>
<p>When I was about ten years old it looked like we might not have a tree at all. With only a couple of days until Christmas we didn't have one and we kids were pretty disappointed. So I was stunned when the door burst open as my father and uncle dragged in the biggest one I'd ever seen. It was huge-too tall to fit without trimming and beautiful branches that stretched into the middle of our modest living room. We six kids literally danced with excitement.</p>
<p>But I was confused by the less-than-thrilled looks my parents exchanged with each other. It made more sense months later, when I noticed the large tree in the back yard sporting a flat-top, and 12 feet shorter than it used to be. Years later my mother explained that they were simply too poor to afford a tree, and they had "made do" with what was available. Knowing how my mother also cared about the appearance of the yard I realize that this was a real sacrifice for her. I still smile when I think of that wonderful tree and the way my parents made it special for us.</p>
<p>My second favorite tree was not really a tree at all. I arrived in Denmark to begin missionary service on Thanksgiving day, and was assigned to a small branch where there had been no missionaries in two years. My companion and I quickly learned of the Danish tradition of celebrating "Yule" throughout the month of December and that it had little to do with the Savior.</p>
<p>This made door-to-door contacting especially unproductive. The irony was not lost on me, as people routinely shouted, "No, I don't want to hear anything about Jesus; it's Christmas!" (Any reference to deity before slamming the door was anything but reverent.)</p>
<p>So we set about making Christmas cards and improvised chocolate chip cookies, which we delivered to anyone who had spoken with us for even a few minutes. I was struck at their surprise that we should be thinking of them when they had nothing to offer us in return, and I am still touched as I think of how good it felt to do even small acts of service for anyone who would allow it.</p>
<p>On Christmas morning Elder Sederholm and I exchanged gifts in front of the small pine bough taped upright on the wall above our table, doing its best to imitate a Christmas tree. It was decorated with paper chains, a star, and the cards we had received from home. I loved that "tree"; it represented forgetting about myself and losing self in service of others.</p>
<p>But the tree of which I am most proud was the one I cut from a tree lot in Nipomo, California about 20 years ago. Money was tight for us that year-not an unusual situation, really. My wife, Ruth, had asked me to get any tree we could afford on the way home from work and was excited when I saw a sign pointing to a cut-it-yourself lot near the freeway.</p>
<p>As it was late in the season there were few trees left, but they were only eight dollars so I felt the pressure to make one of them work. I was thrilled when I spied a perfectly symmetrical spruce near the middle of the field. One problem: it has a gaping hole-10 inches high and 20 inches wide-right in what would otherwise have been the ideal front of the tree. But with an idea (and a little trepidation about what Ruth might say) I paid the eight dollars and began cutting.</p>
<p>When I got home Ruth sized up the tree, congratulated me on my thrift, and expressed disappointment that what would have been the prettiest side would have to face the corner. I asked her to trust me and dressed it with white lights, careful to make the wires inconspicuous. The kids and I then arranged her prettiest nativity scene carefully within that gap. It was not easy to get all the figurines to stand up, but I still believe it is the most beautiful and reverent of all the Christmas trees we've had over the years.</p>
<p>As I write this, it occurs to me that I actually have stumbled upon three keys to enjoying this season:<em> Make do and be grateful for what you have right in front of you.</em> Avoid the mistake of trying to impress someone with going beyond your means. It won't matter anyway.</p>
<p>&nbsp;<em>Lose yourself in service to others, perhaps even those who cannot fully appreciate what you are offering right now.</em> Joy almost always sneaks up on us while we are busy doing something good without any expectations.</p>
<p>&nbsp;<em>Place the Savior at the center of your celebration.</em></p>
<p>Merry Christmas...and may you keep "the reason for the season" in plain view.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>