<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17882" Name="Emotional Ties Between Parents and Children " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Emotional Ties Between Parents and Children </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20071001T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Steve Dennis </Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The Emotional Ties Between Parents and Children</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Steve Dennis</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, October 2007)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The feeling that binds us to the significant people in our lives is  often called "attachment."   In general use, the term "attach" might  mean to tie, to fasten, or to connect one thing to another.  If one car  was being towed by another, we might hope the connecting rope or the  "attachment" is strong enough to meet the challenge.  With a rope, each  new thread when woven with others adds to the overall strength of the  rope. Though individually insignificant, hundreds of threads woven  together can create a rope that is nearly unbreakable.  The attachment  relationship between parent and child is much like a rope.  Each  positive interaction between parent and child adds a new thread and  strengthens the overall emotional connection.<br /> <br /> Attachment is a mutual process.  Therefore, it is important to think of  parents being connected to children and as well as children being  connected to parents.<br /> <br /> When children are emotionally attached to a community of individuals who  care for them, they receive valuable support that helps them grow and  develop.  Children with healthy attachments are more likely to explore  and take appropriate risks.  Through their adventures and attachment  relationships they learn about right and wrong. They learn how to  interpret various experiences.  They learn social skills that help them  maintain existing relationships and develop new ones.  And they learn to  be both self-reliant and to work well with others.  In short, they  develop a variety of skills that are not easily learned through direct  instruction.  Social and emotional lessons are best learned through  relationships.<br /> <br /> Infancy is the ideal time develop a healthy attachment. Not only because  there is a lifetime ahead  in which to make a difference, but also  because of the overwhelming dependence of an infant on adults.  Because  infants depend on others to fulfill their needs, there are many  opportunities for adults to emotionally invest themselves in the  relationship as they care for them.  Changing diapers, feeding, bathing,  changing diapers, rocking, soothing, and changing diapers all help  infants to develop trust and a caring adult to develop commitment.  Even  the cute looks, subtle smiles, and baby fat seem almost designed to  keep adults close and involved.  One observer noted, "we serve those we  love and we love those we serve."  So it is in the very act of attentive  caring that attachment is born.<br /> <br /> Children can develop a healthy attachment with others without  interfering with the parent-child attachment. In fact, a healthy  attachment with a child care provider can enhance the attachment between  parent and child.  Just as the skills we learn at work may help us at  home, so to may the social-emotional competencies learned with caring  child care providers benefit the parent-child relationship at home.<br /> <br /> Although attachment begins in early childhood, the relationships with  those closest to us remain important throughout our life.  One of the  early researchers of attachment, John Bowlby, made the observation that,  "All of us, from cradle to the grave, are happiest when life is  organized as a series of excursions, long or short, from a secure base  provided by our attachment figure(s)."  <br /> <br /> Parents and caring adults can do many things to deepen an attachment. Here are a few:<br /> <br /></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Take care of yourself.</strong> It is difficult to reach  out and nurture the relationship with our child if we're overwhelmed  with personal problems.  At times our focus on personal problems may  cause us to turn inward.  Parents who are depressed, isolated, or having  marital problems are more likely to have problems forming a healthy  attachment. However, taking care of our self doesn't always mean  focusing on ourselves.  Sometimes the best therapy for ourselves is  being with and helping others-especially our children.</li>
<li><strong>Follow your child's lead. </strong> Every relationship is a  dance.  When one moves, the other moves in tandem. The best dancers  learn to identify and respond to the subtle cues.  The same applies in  relationships. When a child smiles with excitement, smile back with the  same enthusiasm. When your child expresses feelings of hurt, respond to  the emotional pain with sympathy and care. As you respond attentively to  your child's behaviors, your child will also learn to respond  appropriately to others.</li>
<li><strong>Be sensitive to your child's needs.</strong> Attachment  parenting is responsive to a child's needs. In infancy, children often  express their needs by crying.  They may cry when they are hungry,  tired, need a diaper change, or simply need to be comforted.  It is  difficult to be too attentive to children in infancy.  As children grow  older, identifying needs from wants may be more challenging.   Understanding child development in general, and your child's development  in particular, will help you be sensitive without spoiling (see unit on  spoiling in this series).</li>
<li><strong>Animate life.</strong> Young children often have a  difficult time distinguishing the subtle difference between various  emotional expressions.  Using exaggerated facial expressions or  nonverbal cues will help your child learn valuable lessons about sharing  and interpreting feelings.  Understanding and responding appropriately  to feelings is the basis for maintaining relationships.</li>
<li><strong>Spend time playing with your child.</strong> Nothing says  love like the time shared with your child. Make time to play together,  read together, work together, learn together, and snuggle together.   Simply spend lots of time together. Planned quality time is important,  but it is often during long car trips, or other unplanned moments that  children open up and reveal their innermost needs and concerns.   The  importance of quantity time should not be dismissed.  As one person put  it, "The key to being an effective parent is to be a good person and  then hang around your kids long enough that you rub off."</li>
</ol>
<p><br /> Steve Dennis is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>