<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17864" Name="Preserving the Past with Recipes " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Preserving the Past with Recipes </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20071201T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Carma Sutherland </Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Preserving the Past with Recipes</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Carma Sutherland</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, December 2007)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>While planning menus for holiday dinners, I reached for my red and white  vintage recipe box. It contains recipes that belonged to my mother and  step-mother on rows of yellowed index cards. The mostly handwritten  cards conger up memories of some family event or an evening meal eaten  around our kitchen table.</p>
<p><br /> Peppermint Ice Box Cake was the first card I pulled out of the dessert  section. The recipe sounded festive, but the handwriting was what held  my attention. I recognized it as the fine, angular hand of my mother  which I hadn't seen for awhile. A flood of memories and longing came  over me. I can recall a happy youth and wonderful family parties with  food at the center</p>
<p><br /> Mom was in a fatal car accident when I was 12 years old, but. Dad later  remarried, so my stepmother's recipes were filed in the same sections  and categories in-between those of my mother's. Similarly, my life's  memories are a blend of the lives of two wonderful mothers.</p>
<p><br /> I could always tell when my stepmother, Lorraine, had been baking bread.   The aroma wafted from the kitchen into the air and I recognized it as  soon as I came into the yard from school. It gave me a sense of security  and stability that was so needed during that time of my life. The  recipe was for Swiss Bread, brought with Grandma Hasler when she  emigrated from Switzerland. The loaves were braided European style, from  ropes of soft pliable dough. It wasn't just any bread--it was the best  bread I had ever tasted.</p>
<p><br /> I suppose that recall to my senses is why baking is my favorite part of  cooking. I would prefer making yeast bread, cookies, cakes or pies when  given a cooking assignment bread or dinner rolls were always taken to  Thanksgiving and Christmas get-togethers at Grandma's house with  cousins, aunts and uncles who all lived in Kamas, Utah. A wonderful  bread or dessert is sure to bring compliments or an atmosphere of  celebration.</p>
<p><br /> The baked food at holidays and family reunions was a smorgasbord made  from recipes that had been shared by friends, family members or Relief  Society sisters. Recipe swapping is part of our LDS culture. Some of the  best recipes in my collection are from wonderful Relief Society  sisters. There is something bonding about cooking from a recipe shared  by a trusted friend. A shared recipe is a gift that brings pleasant  thoughts of that person throughout the preparation and enjoyment of it.</p>
<p><br /> The red and white box doesn't just contain recipes. There are notes on  gardening and children's games. One card even contains marital advice.  That particular card from my stepmother's file had this note: Recorded  in the pages of an old cookbook published about 1871, among the formulas  for storing away fruits and vegetables, was a little piece entitled "<em>How to Preserve a Husband.</em>"       It read: "Be careful in your selection. Do not choose one too  young and take only such varieties as have been reared in a good  atmosphere. When once decided upon and selected, let that part remain  forever settled. Some insist on keeping them in pickle, while others are  constantly getting into hot water This makes them sour and bitter. Even  poor varieties may be made sweet, tender and good by garnishing with  patience, well-sweetened with smiles. Wrap in a mantle of charity, keep  warm with a steady fire of domestic devotion. When thus prepared,  husbands will keep for years and improve with age."</p>
<p><br /> The cards have been through more than four generations of meal  preparation. I view the collection as a treasure and though I have over  300 recipe books in my personal collection, these yellowed cards are  valued most. I shutter to think that I almost tossed them into the waste  basket one by one when I went through an organizing streak of putting  recipes on a computer program. They have become one of my most precious  possessions.</p>
<p><br /> I think everyone should have something written in the hand of their  loved ones. Unfortunately, like other folks in Rexburg, many treasured  handwritten family journals were lost in the Teton Dam flood. So these  recipes are a sort of family history for me. They have become a part of  me, who I am, my history and my legacy. Perhaps the red and white box  will sit in a granddaughter's kitchen cabinet and she'll prepare  something for her family from a yellowed recipe card.</p>
<p><br /> During the holiday season, as you focus on cooking and eating, it is my  wish that you will celebrate life itself and the significance of  bringing a family together to share your own favorite foods. Happy  Holidays.</p>
<p><br /> P.S. I'm always happy to share a recipe.<br /> <br /> <br /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Carma Sutherland is a retired member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>