<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17863" Name="Quality time IN GREAT QUANTITY " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Quality time IN GREAT QUANTITY </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20070601T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Scott Gardner</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Quality time IN GREAT QUANTITY</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Scott Gardner</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, June 2007)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The American family has time issue. There are so many myths regarding  time that we don't know which way is up anymore. We think our children  and marriages need "quality time." We consider it a success strategy to  skip our family vacations in favor of working more hours, and we enroll  our children in more and more extracurricular activities thinking more  is better. The result of each of these time myths is that our families  suffer.<br /> <br /></p>
<h4>Quality Time?</h4>
<p>I have to admit that one of my least favorite phrases is "You have to  spend quality time with your kids." Several years ago the TV station  Cartoon Network asked children to suggest possible prizes for a contest.  Kids could suggest whatever prize they thought would be the best to  win. "Ride in a limousine" was one of the top answers, but the next most  popular answer was shocking, "the chance to spend a whole day with my  mom or my dad."  Ouch! That's a sad and painful commentary on our  time-starved society. Time with Mom and Dad has become a coveted prize  that is so rare that it must be won in a contest. The reality is that  the "Quality Time" myth just isn't cutting it. Most research points to  the fact that the more time we spend with our children the better off  they will be. As one researcher put it, "Kids need quality time in great  quantity!"   As a marriage counselor, I also see some couples who have  swallowed this deceptive hook. Marriage really doesn't work very well  when there's little or no time together.  The research suggests that the  couples who spend plenty of time together doing all the little things  have the best marriages.</p>
<p><br /> Several years ago I worked with a young couple who couldn't figure out  why their marriage was falling apart. They were doing everything right,  except they had no time together. He worked days and she worked nights.  They basically waved at each other in passing during the 20 minutes that  their schedules overlapped each day. It didn't have to take a marriage  counselor to figure out what their problem was "quality time" just isn't  enough!<br /> <br /></p>
<h4>Time Famine in the U.S.</h4>
<p>"We're number one!"  Another time myth that clouds our vision in the  United States has to do with skipping vacations and working long hours.  We work longer hours than most industrialized countries and we have  fewer vacation days than any other developed country in the world. For  example, the average number of vacation days per year for Americans is  13; in Britain it's 28; in Canada, 26 days is average; France, 37;  Italy, 42 days. So we're the lowest in the civilized world, and  consequently we also work more hours than any developed country.<br /> <br /> Sure, our gross domestic product is the highest in the world, but we are  paying for it with our health, our families and our lives. We have the  shortest life expectancy in the developed world, we have the highest  child mortality rate, and the most chronic illness even though we spend  the most on health care! We have a lot more "stuff," but is our  lifestyle really better? Perhaps we could even say that we are trading  our vacation days for sick days. We've gotten into the "time-is-money"  mentality. That's true, but you know, if your family's falling apart or  you're dead, who cares about the money!<br /> <br /> Helping our Children be Workaholics? "or Dance and Soccer and Baseball, Oh my!"</p>
<p>Myth 3 has to do with overscheduling our children. Dr. Bill Doherty at  the University of Minnesota points out that children ages 3 to 12 have  lost 12 hours a week of free time. Now they play much less. Meanwhile,  they spend 50 percent more time studying than they did 20 years ago.  Their time in structured sports activities has doubled as well. So we  are teaching our children at young ages how to be workaholics.</p>
<p><br /> Last year the American Academy of Pediatrics recommended more play time  for young children and fewer structured activities. I get the feeling  that some families feel like "If my son misses one of his Little League  baseball games, he'll surely never make the Olympic team!" Or "if I  don't sign my two-year old up for kiddie gymnastics, she'll be way  behind the other kids!" In the meantime, our family's falling apart. We  never see each other. We're cranky and griping at each other as we drive  Billy here and drop Ashley off there.  That's just not worth it.</p>
<p><br /> Certainly we want to teach our children a good work ethic, but at what  point are we overscheduling our children and thus our families? We need  to ask ourselves who's in charge of our family. Is it the school? Is it  the sports team that our child is on? Is it our job, or are we in charge  of our own families? <br /> <br /></p>
<h4>Strengthening our Families</h4>
<p>We can strengthen our families by combating these myths. Here are a few simple ideas.</p>
<ul>
<li>Increase the amount of time you spend with your children in small ways such as having them work with you on household tasks.</li>
<li>Sing your children a bed time song or tell them a short story each night</li>
<li>Work alongside your spouse and spend time just talking as you work.</li>
<li>Carve out some untouchable time and then protect it - Families  should first ask what their priority is and then schedule some time  that's protected rather than just allowing all these other activities to  drive our family into workaholism. </li>
<li>Use those vacation days and make sure you take regular family  vacations. When the boss asks for somebody to work overtime on the  weekend, it doesn't have to be you. For those who are self-employed or  who don't punch a clock, it's helpful to track your own hours; and see  if you're cheating your family by working too much.</li>
<li>Give yourself permission to relax. It's okay to turn off the phone  and let the answering machine get the calls. Turn off the e-mail so it  doesn't beep at you as soon as a new message arrives. </li>
<li>It's okay for family activities to trump kids "sports activities" not the other way around.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information and ideas, see www.TimeDay.org or www.TakeBackYourFamilyTime.unm.edu<br /> <br /> Scott Gardner is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>