<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17875" Name="Peace at Home " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Peace at Home </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20080201T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Owen Anderson</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Peace at Home</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Owen Anderson</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, February 2008)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The late German philosopher Johann Wolfgang von Goethe declared, "He is  the happiest, be he king or peasant, who finds peace in his home."       The home should be a sanctuary for all who abide there. Thinking back to  my college experience, I remember reading a family studies textbook in  which the author paraphrased Dickens in <em>A Tale of Two Cities</em>,  in this way, "the family can be the best of human life and it can be the  worst of human life."      Indeed, it is in the family that we  experience some of the deepest joys and greatest fulfillment. The home  is a place that can refine, test and help us grow and mature in ways  that provide personal satisfaction, love, security and a sense of  belonging.</p>
<p><br /> Unfortunately, the home can also be the worst of time for some family  members. It is in the family that the ugliest side of humans also  thrives. Additionally, the family can be the source of some of the  deepest frustration, misery, forms of cruel abuse and exploitive  behavior.</p>
<p><br /> Parents have a powerful influence on the atmosphere of the home. Some  argue that the great goodness and beauty found in families is available  because such profound evil and ugliness is possible. This emotional  intensity can gravitate to either extreme, depending on our own sense of  self.</p>
<p><br /> "You learn the truth about yourself in the home, and you cannot hide  from the truths that you do not want to see and that you do not want to  be reminded of," stated a past BYU-Idaho president.</p>
<p><br /> When changes are needed the home is the ideal place to start, because  the way we treat other family members is the truest view of the person  we really are and the person we are becoming. It is in the home that our  social exchanges shape the sense of warmth, acceptance, affirmation and  belonging; or the sense of coldness, rejection, denial, insecurity that  children feel and carry with them into other social relationships.  Thus, a closer look at the communication used in the home would have  value.</p>
<p><br /> Our interactions can be divided into two broad domains, nonverbal and  verbal. Nonverbal communication is made up of actions rather than words.  In general, it includes facial expressions and body gestures. Feelings  of pleasure, happiness, anger, disgust and sadness can be expressed with  or without words, but the amount of meaning the message conveys  increases significantly when the nonverbal cues are added to the spoken  word. Verbal communication includes all of the positive and negative  oral exchanges that take place within a given setting.</p>
<p><br /> When interacting with children our actions and words combine to create  an environment in which a child(s self-evaluation is favorable or  unfavorable. In a family setting in which the interactions are negative  children feel unworthy, unloved, insignificant, or incompetent. Here are  a few examples of subtle messages that individually or collectively  could have harmful outcomes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li>Do you show little or no interest in your child because you are in a  hurry or busy with your own interest? When you do talk, do you respond  only grudgingly, or appear annoyed with irrelevant questions? Instead of  listening attentively when a child speaks, do you pay superficial  attention?</li>
<li>Are you discourteous when speaking with your child? Do you expect  children to respond to your requests immediately? Is your tone of voice  demanding, impatient or belligerent?  Do you combine a negative verbal  message and a scathing tone of voice with a pleasant facial expression  (sarcasm)?</li>
<li>Do you use judgmental words (i.e., selfish, spoiled, greedy, mean,  brat, baby, dumb, etc.,) when talking to your children or describing  them to others? Do you devalue their words by saying, "Hush," "Not now,"  "Later," with no intent of talking with your child later?</li>
<li>Does your talk generally involve one-way communication, such as  giving directions "Go to your room," "Do your homework" and stating  rules "Be nice to your sister," "Clean your room?" Do you ask questions  for which no real response is expected or desired "What were you  thinking," "Didn't I tell you?"</li>
<li>Do you use your child's name as synonymous with the word "No," "Stop," or "Don't?" </li>
</ol>
<p><br /> Next, let us consider some positive characteristics that tend to have helpful outcomes.</p>
<ol>
<li>Do you frequently give each child your full attention and become  engaged in their activities. Do you listen and concentrate when they  speak? Do you show enthusiasm with their ideas?</li>
<li>Do you use words that show you are interested in what they are  doing (i.e., "You seem to enjoy", "You've spent a long time"). Do you  speak courteously to your child, saying, "Please," Thank you," and  "Excuse me?" Do you have conversations with your child that are based on  their interests? Do you encourage them to express their ideas and  thoughts?</li>
<li>Do you refrain from judgmental comments and negative labels, and  instead use words and actions that treat children with dignity and  respect? Finally, do you use your child(s name in positive situations?</li>
</ol>
<p><br /> A prominent child psychologist (Urie Bronfenbrenner) is frequently  quoted for his idea that "every kid needs at least one adult who is  crazy about him." A child should feel this love through our daily words  and actions. A positive relational home setting is beneficial to both  the parent and the child.</p>
<p><br /> The positive principles outlined above provide ways for parents to  communicate warmth, respect, acceptance, and empathy to children. These  methods will increase the likelihood that children will view their  parents as a source of comfort and encouragement. Also, the positive  interaction patterns will help children to learn more about themselves  and to feel good about the self they are coming to know.</p>
<p><br /> Finally, as parents develop positive relational patterns with children,  home will be the place where their own sense of self will be one of  personal satisfaction, in which they broaden personal dignity, respect  and integrity. Thus, happiness with oneself will enhance peace at home. <br /> <br /></p>
<p><br /> Owen Anderson is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>