<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17881" Name="What Sarah Teaches Me " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">What Sarah Teaches Me </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20080801T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Lisa McLaughlin </Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>What Sarah Teaches Me</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Lisa McLaughlin</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, August 2008)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Sarah is my oldest child.&nbsp;&nbsp; Her birth and apparently normal early development were especially thrilling since my pregnancy with her had been preceded by several  miscarriages.&nbsp; My happiness, however, was short-lived. &nbsp;&nbsp;By the time  Sarah was about a year old, I had a sick feeling in what I came to think of as my &ldquo;mother gut&rdquo; that  something was seriously wrong .&nbsp; After a series of specialists and misdiagnoses, Sarah&rsquo;s symptoms progressed to the point  that her diagnosis was obvious. &nbsp;&nbsp;She stopped making eye contact or holding my hand and by age three she had fewer  than ten meaningful words or sounds.&nbsp; Sarah was autistic.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I spent the next seven years trying to &ldquo;fix&rdquo; Sarah.&nbsp; I chased after almost every treatment for autism I heard about.&nbsp;&nbsp; I wantedher to be totally cured and nothing else would do.&nbsp; &nbsp;I wanted my daughter back.&nbsp;&nbsp; I prayed hard and often for a miracle, but my prayers seemed almost futile.&nbsp; Although Sarah eventually progressed in speech and even learned to read, she made virtually no cognitive progress after about six years old and her behavior became significantly hyperactive and disruptive.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">By the time Sarah was ten years old I realized I was at a crossroads.&nbsp; My attempts to find a cure for Sarah&rsquo;s autism were costly in both time and money and they didn&rsquo;t seem to be helping her.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By then I had three other children and was expecting a fourth.&nbsp; In order to meet my entire family&rsquo;s needs, my priorities needed to be more in balance.&nbsp;&nbsp; I made a conscious decision to move on.&nbsp;&nbsp; Apparently, I was not going to get my miracle.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">To my surprise, acceptance of Sarah&rsquo;s handicap gradually opened my eyes to a different kind of miracle the Lord was &nbsp;giving me.&nbsp; In numerous ways, Sarah&rsquo;s autism was the answer to my prayers.&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">A wonderful essay by Emily Kingsley compares the experience of having a handicapped child to a dream vacation which apparently goes terribly awry.&nbsp; Imagine that expecting a baby is like planning a wonderful trip to Italy.&nbsp; You study the  language, plan your itinerary and talk with others who have been there.&nbsp; But the unthinkable happens.&nbsp; The plane you thought you were taking to Italy, has landed in Holland.&nbsp; You  are upset.&nbsp; You are angry.&nbsp; But there is no help for it; your vacation will have to be spent in Holland.<span>&nbsp; </span>You decide to accept your situation and that&rsquo;s when you begin to realize that Holland, although not as flashy as Italy, is also a wonderful place. Holland has tulips, Holland has windmills, Holland even has Rembrandts.&nbsp; Your vacation, while not what you had originally planned, is gloriousnonetheless.&nbsp; (Emily Perl Kingsley, &ldquo;Welcome to Holland.&rdquo; 1987)</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">During my eighteen year journey with Sarah I have seen more than my share of tulips and windmills and even Rembrandts. ,&nbsp; Being Sarah&rsquo;s Momchanges my focus and helps me see what matters more clearly. &nbsp;&nbsp;Success in life, she is teaching me, &nbsp;isultimately based on my willingness to do what I have come to think of as &ldquo;spiritual work.&rdquo;Unlike the work I was used to, measured by &ldquo;to do&rdquo; lists neatly checked off, spiritual work is much more difficult to quantify.&nbsp; Quality time with my children, really listening to others, patience with the daily dramas, living and loving in the moment, are more important than the appearance-centered activities I used to prioritize.&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Sarah has taught me to do &ldquo;spiritual work&rdquo; in ways too numerous to mention.&nbsp; For example, Sarah almost never looks as tidy as I would like.&nbsp; God has given her a wild, woolly head of hair; autism has given her a dread fear of scissors and an inability to be patient with grooming rituals.&nbsp; Consequently, Sarah often looks as though her hair hasn&rsquo;t been combed in a month and she won&rsquo;t let anyone cut it.&nbsp; Letting go of the myth that my children should always look perfect has helped me to see beyond appearances to the beauty of all children.&nbsp; When Moroni said, &ldquo;&hellip;all children are alike unto me,&rdquo; he wasn&rsquo;t just talking about pretty, well-behaved, talented children.&nbsp; (Moroni&nbsp; 8:17).<span>&nbsp;&nbsp; </span>Loving the difficult child is where the rubber meets the road.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Sarah teaches me to look beyond appearances to the heart of things in many other ways as well.&nbsp; Sarah is virtually incapable of either whispering or being quiet in social settings.&nbsp; Her husky, slurred speech has droned through more church meetings than I can count.Family prayer, family home evening, family mealsand &nbsp;outingsjust weren&rsquo;t what I &nbsp;envisioned before Sarah came along..&nbsp; Her constant talking and hyperactivty turned these everyday activities into depressing fiascos.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I had to learn to re-define success or throw in the towel, because Sarah&rsquo;s handicap ensured I would never have the picture perfect  life I thought I wanted. Eventually, &nbsp;I began to ask myself different kinds of questions.&nbsp; Was I patient with Sarah when she unwittingly sabotaged yet another family activity?&nbsp;&nbsp; Was I understanding of strangers who stared at ourpublic struggles?&nbsp; Was I calm with my other children during these stressful occasions?&nbsp; I  won&rsquo;t say I never feel a stab of envy when I see an apparently perfect family, but because of Sarah, I am more  likely to realize that my attitude is more important than my altitude.&nbsp; Perhaps 1  Samuel 16:7 says it best:&nbsp; &ldquo;&hellip;the Lord seeth not as man seeth; for man looketh on the outward appearace, but the Lord looketh on the heart.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">My husband and I eventually had eight more children after Sarah was born.&nbsp; People ask me why we would go on to have such a large family when we already had a handicapped child.&nbsp; I often answer that Sarah&rsquo;s handicap may be the very reason we did so. &nbsp;After Sarah, a non-handicapped child seems so, well, normal. &nbsp;&nbsp;I relish their early words much more than I couldhave &nbsp;had I not anguished for years over Sarah&rsquo;s impaired speech.&nbsp; I thrill over first steps, slobbery kisses and other developmental milestones with keen joy I doubt &nbsp;Iwouldhave experienced had I not grieved Sarah&rsquo;s stunted development.<span>&nbsp;&nbsp; </span>I even tend to view my other childrens&rsquo; tantrums, back-sassing, and numerous other bad behaviors with more patience than I might have had it not been for Sarah. &nbsp;&nbsp;Sarah teaches me that my children don&rsquo;t need to be perfect,;normal is OK, normal is good.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;Sarah never progressed mentally past the first grade, but as she grew the Lord gave  her the ability &ndash;unusual for a child with autism -to give and receive love,&nbsp; a  gift Sarah uses lavishly every day. &nbsp;Not only did her ability to hold my  hand and make eye contact return, but Sarah became incredibly loving and affectionate.&nbsp; She tells me , &ldquo;I love you, Mommy,&rdquo; every few minutes throughout the day. &nbsp;She has told  countless surprised strangers that she loves them, and neighbors and family acquaintances are often  the recipients of her sincere hugs. &nbsp;Again Sarah teaches me to do spiritual work as she reminds me of our common brotherhood with her unconditional love for all people.&nbsp; <span>&nbsp;</span>Sarah has learned the most important purpose of this life and I believe she sacrifices normal life on a daily basis to help me learn it too.&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Sometimes I catch Sarah staring at me in a wise way. In those moments the mask of &nbsp;autism seems to fall awayand I think I can &nbsp;hear her say, &ldquo;Do you understand now, Mommy?&nbsp; Do you see yet what&rsquo;s really important?&nbsp;&nbsp; I am here to help you &nbsp;learn about what really matters, what really brings happiness.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">It&rsquo;s Sarah&rsquo;s bedtime.&nbsp; Her soft, husky voice calls from her room, &ldquo;I love you Mommy.&rdquo;&nbsp; I love  you too, Sarah.&nbsp; And thank you, thank you for teaching me.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<br /> <br /> Article written by Lisa McLaughlin, Adjunct Faculty member in the  Department for Home and Family Education at Brigham Young University-  Idaho.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>