<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17878" Name="Wholesome Recreational Activities " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Wholesome Recreational Activities </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20070201T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Byron Webster</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Wholesome Recreational Activities</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Byron Webster</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, February 2007)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Family counselor and scholar William Doherty wrote a book entitled, <em>The Intentional Family: How to build family ties in our modern world.</em><sup>1</sup> The title of the book itself expresses a philosophy worth thinking  deeply about: building a successful, happy family does not just happen;  it takes deliberate, conscious effort.  The opposite of intentional or  deliberate is entropy.  Entropy is the tendency for a system to lose  energy over time.  That is what happens to families when we do not put  forth effort; families deteriorate, lose energy, and even drift apart.   An example of entropy in families is when we let external or selfish  activities determine what we do instead of applying healthy principles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Another book that focuses on healthy families is <em>Strengthening Our Families: An In-Depth Look at the Proclamation on the Family</em><sup>2</sup>.   Chapter Fourteen of that book focuses on the following phrase from the  Proclamation: Successful marriages and families are established and  maintained on principles of...wholesome recreational activities (The  Family: A Proclamation to the World, &para; 7).  Some people think that  recreational activities are those things we do to relax and not work  when, in fact, wholesome family recreation may take a great deal of  effort and planning to accomplish.  Doesn't recreation just happen in  families?  Not necessarily.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is true that spontaneous, fun activities do happen in our families.   We certainly should be open and flexible to the point that we can enjoy  those activities that "just happen."  However we can't count on those  activities happening very often.  We do need to intentionally plan and  schedule recreation with our family.  Many of our recreational  activities should actually have a purpose, a goal.<br /> We should consider our philosophy about recreation.  And we all have a  philosophy about recreation.  Some think that recreation is simply  idleness, not working.  Watching television or videos and playing  video/computer games would be examples of idleness.  Recreation and  idleness are not the same thing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Wholesome recreation serves the purpose of not only having fun but also  teaching and bonding in families.  We learn relax and balance work and  play.  We learn cooperation, fairness, teamwork, personal growth, taking  turns and more.<br /> We also learn that it doesn't take a lot of money to have fun.   Societies philosophy, as shown in many television commercials, tells us  that the only way to have fun is to buy expensive equipment and go on  lavish vacations at expensive places.  There is certainly nothing wrong  with any of that unless that is the only type of recreation that we  engage in.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Of course society promotes some recreational activities as legitimate  when there is something very wrong with them.  Gambling, now publicized  as "gaming," is an obvious example.  Some even promote gambling as a  sport.  We have been warned repeatedly of the harmful and even addictive  qualities of gambling.  And, of course, we should not participate in  most wholesome recreational activities on the Sabbath.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Some of the principles that can help guide us in our family recreation include<sup>3</sup>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Plan in advance</li>
<li>Plan age-appropriate activities</li>
<li>Plan activities that will foster development and bonding of each member of the family</li>
<li>Limit the consumption of media (TV, Internet, video games, Videos)</li>
<li>Intentionally establish rituals that connect family members</li>
<li>Create one-on-one time with each family member</li>
<li>Be of service as part of wholesome family recreation</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We do make a difference in our families.  How we plan and implement  activities, including wholesome recreation, reflects our commitment to  our families.  We can intentionally lead our families in healthy and  successful way.<br /> <br /> <sup>1</sup> W.J. Doherty (1997), The intentional family: How to build family ties in our modern world (New York: Addison-Wesley).<br /> <sup>2</sup> David C. Dollahite (2000), Strengthening Our Families: An  In-Depth Look at the Proclamation on the Family (Salt Lake City:  Bookcraft).<br /> <sup>3</sup> Dollahite (Ed) 2000, 199.<br /> <br /> Byron Webster is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>