<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x17867" Name="Family Mealtimes: Are they fun times? " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Family mealtimes: are they fun times? </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20080401T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Julie Harker Buck</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Family mealtimes: are they fun times?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Julie Harker Buck</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, April 2008)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Imagine the table that held your family meals as you were growing up.  Was it round or square? Did you eat at a counter or sofa instead?  Memories surrounding mealtimes stir up strong feelings, both positive  and negative. Let's explore some sound reasons to start having family  mealtimes, improve upon the mealtimes we are having and to encourage  healthy eating habits during mealtimes.<br /> Mealtimes can be hasty exercises in getting family fed or one of the  richest times of the family's day. Which describes the type of mealtimes  at your house? President Gordon B. Hinckley has said "mealtime provides  a wonderful time to review the activities of the day and to not only  feed the body, but to feed the spirit as well". How well are we  "feeding" the spirit of our family members during mealtimes? "Provide a  pleasant, positive eating environment, and allow enough time to eat " at  least 15-20 minutes of actual eating time after being served.  (Reference: "What time is lunch?" Journal of the American Dietetic  Association, 1996:96.)</p>
<p><br /> Parents are the first and most influential teacher of nutrition and  health to their children. When discussing nutrition concepts or showing  by example, children learn daily about our food preferences. By  utilizing a CARE mealtime policy, we can learn strategies to improve our  time together. C: Consider children's needs; A: Analyze your situation;  R: Respond with the best practice; E: Evaluate the outcome.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Consider children's needs</h4>
Children are responsible to  decide how much to eat and whether to eat. In most situations, children  can recognize and respond appropriately to their hunger cues. These  messages, from their brain and stomach, guide their eating so that they  are able to start when hungry and stop when full. As teenagers and  adults we may override our bodies' messages regarding fullness "satiety"  and hunger. By choosing a variety of foods that are appropriate for  each stage of a child's life, children can thrive in a healthy food  environment. "Healthy eating patterns include eating a variety of foods,  having regular meals and snacks, responding to body signals of hunger  and fullness, creating a positive environment for meals, and eating  family meals together when<br /> possible. Healthy eating also means taking time to relax, enjoy the  food, and feel satiety." (Reference: E. Satter, "How to get your kid to  eat but not too much," 1987, Palo Alto, CA: Bull Publishers).<br /> <br />
<h4>Analyze your situation</h4>
Consider your budget, time and  knowledge about food and nutrition. Have you planned meals to take  advantage of food in storage, in season and on sale? Is some free time  better used by preparing large quantities of food and freezing some  meals for later use? Is the cost of eating out worth the extra calories  and loss opportunity to eat around your own table? Would a class about  meal preparation or time spent with a knowledgeable friend/neighbor be  helpful and welcome by your family? Can someone else in your household  help with meal preparation? Prayerfully consider your options and  establish some new or improved plans for mealtimes.<br /> <br />
<h4>Respond with the best practice</h4>
Where, when and what should  you eat? As adults, we are responsible to decide what to purchase for  dinner, when to prepare the meal and where to eat it. Consider a  suitable table that can seat everyone comfortably. Allow for dishes and  utensils to properly fit the hands of those eating the meal, ie.  Child-sized utensils and dishes when needed. How is the lighting? Is the  area free from distractions such as television, radio or toys so that  discussion can occur? Have you let go of practices that have no  nutrition basis such as "clean the plate club", using food as a reward  or punishment and forcing children to eat? By respecting each other's  innate ability to know how much to eat or whether, we can encourage a  healthy eating environment. "When we learn to listen to these signals,  we can take better care of ourselves. There are many signals, such as  hunger and fullness, being cold or tired, feeling the need to move our  body, etc." (Reference: "The ABC's of Health-Focused Well-Being,"  www.uwyo.edu/winwyoming/projects.html).<br /> <br />
<h4>Evaluate the outcome</h4>
Occasionally review how changes are  being received, standard practices are working and new ideas are  becoming accepted. As parents or care providers discuss strategies to  include older children and teens in meal planning, preparation and clean  up. Yes, dishes! By encouraging meal planning, cooking and clean up, we  better prepare future missionaries, mothers, fathers, roommates, and  family to share in the rewarding mealtime atmosphere. <br /> <br /> For additional reading: "Secrets for feeding a healthy family," by Ellyn Satter, www.EllynSatter.com.<br /> For additional resources: "Winning conversation cards at WIN the Family," Wellness IN the Rockies, www.uwyo.edu/wintherockies<br /> <br /> Article written by Julie Harker Buck, MHE, RD, CD, LCCE . Registered  Dietitian, Certified DONA doula, Lamaze Certified Childbirth Educator.  Mother of six. Adjunct Faculty member in the Department for Home and  Family Education at Brigham Young University- Idaho.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>