<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x19081" Name="Health Professions Resources" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Health Professions Resources</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The webpage provides a summary of the resources available at BYU-Idaho for health professions students.  Resources include: tutoring, letter of evaluation service, mock interviews, personal statement reviews, and student societies.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4><strong>Health Profession Resources</strong></h4>
<p><a href="#Ag and Life Science Advising">Ag and Life Science Academic Discovery Center</a><br /><a href="#Student Societies">Student Societies</a><br /><a href="#Academic Support Centers">Academic Support Centers</a><br /><a href="#Library and Continuing Education">Library and Continuing Education</a><br /><a href="#Faculty Resources">Faculty Resources</a><strong><br /> </strong></p>
<hr />
<h4><strong><a name="Ag and Life Science Advising"></a>Ag and Life Science Academic Discovery Center</strong><em></em></h4>
<p><strong>Planning Documents</strong><br />Prerequisite Documents - lists the prerequisites you need for your health profession<br />Prerequisite Sequencing Documents - outlines when to take prerequisite classes.<br />Application Timeline Documents - provides general admission statistics and an application timeline</p>
<p><strong>Health Professions Workshops</strong><br />Want to know what admissions committees are looking for?  Attend the Health Professions Workshops. <a href="x21282.xml">Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>Online Grad Plan Tool</strong><br />The grad plan tool will enable you to organize major, minor/cluster, and prerequisite courses into a graduation plan. Using this tool early in your scholastic career will help prevent scheduling challenges later in regards to applying, graduating, and matriculating. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/gradplan">Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>BYU-Idaho LOE Service</strong><br />BYU-Idaho will collect letters of evaluation for you and send them to the schools you apply to.  Check the website for more information about how the service works.  <a href="x19589.xml">Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>Mock Interviews/Personal Statement Review</strong><br />Internship and Career Services offers mock interviews for pre-professional students.  It is based on the "Fifteen Common Questions" document found on the website. Career mentors have also been trained to review personal statements for content. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/careerservices/Student_Resources.htm">Click here...</a></p>
<h4><strong><a name="Student Societies"></a>Student Societies</strong></h4>
<p>Student societies are a great way to network and learn more about your future profession.  Societies usually meet once a week for one hour.  Societies bring in guest speakers including health professionals, current health professional students, and professional school admissions committee members.  BYU-Idaho currently has or has had societies in the following areas:  Pre-Med, Pre-Dental, Pre-Optometry, Pre-Pharmacy, Pre-Chiropractic, Pre-Vet, Pre-Physician Assistant, Pre-Physical Therapy, and Pre-Podiatry. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/societies/join"> Click here...</a></p>
<h4><strong><a name="Academic Support Centers"></a>Academic Support Centers</strong><em></em></h4>
<p><strong>Reading Center</strong><br />The Reading Center welcomes all students who seek to increase their textbook and college reading skills.  Many students come to the Reading Center to work with trained tutors on improving vocabulary, phonetic skills, reading fluency, textbook comprehension, reading efficiency, and advanced comprehension. Tutors also help international students read and understand their textbooks and have been trained to assist students with disabilities.  <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academicsupport/">Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>Study Skills Center</strong><br />The mission of the Study Skills Center is to provide assistance to students in learning or improving their study techniques and in developing better study habits that will not only help lead them to successful academic careers, but will also help them in life-long activities. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academicsupport/">Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>Tutoring Center</strong><br />The Tutoring Center is for students who desire help beyond their regular classroom instruction.  Individual, group, or walk-in sessions are available.  Tutors are chosen from students who have succeeded academically in the class, completed a tutor training program, and been approved by their department. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academicsupport/"> Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>The Writing Center</strong><br />The Writing Center is a free service for all BYU-Idaho students and faculty. The Writing Center will help you proofread and edit your personal statement.  <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academicsupport/">Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>The Math Center</strong><br />In the Math Study Center, you may work on regular math homework. The trained staff of tutors is available to answer math questions. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academicsupport/">Click here...</a></p>
<h4><strong><a name="Library and Continuing Education"></a>Library &amp; Continuing Education</strong> <em></em></h4>
<p><strong>Entrance Exam Study Guides</strong><br />The library offers a set of Kaplan study guides for the MCAT and DAT.  It is held on reserve on the main floor of the library.  Ask for the "Kaplan Binder" to review all the testing information available.  Tests can be checked out from the library for two hours.  If you are studying for the OAT, use both the MCAT and DAT materials to take practice tests.</p>
<p><strong>Online Resources</strong><em><br /></em>Additionally, the library has online resources for the GRE, DAT, and MCAT. <a href="http://abish.byui.edu/library/Nr_testPrep.cfm"> Click here...</a></p>
<p><strong>The GRE Prep Course</strong><br />The GRE Test Prep Course is a course to assist students planning to take the Graduate Record Examination (GRE)® for graduate program admission. Course cost is $399. This includes all classroom materials, skill-building and practice test CD-ROM, pre and post-practice tests, and evaluations.  <a href="http://www.byui.edu/cc/gre/default.htm">Click here...</a></p>
<h4><strong><a name="Faculty Resources"></a>Faculty Resources</strong><em></em></h4>
<p><strong>Career Information</strong><br />Each student at BYU-Idaho is assigned a faculty mentor.  Faculty mentors help with upper-division class planning as it relates to career strategy and graduate school.  Faculty at BYU-Idaho advise students interested in health professions every semester and can offer great insight into the admissions process.</p>
<p><strong>Research Opportunities</strong><br />Many science faculty members are currently working on scientific research projects.  Ask your science professors if they are currently working on research projects or if they know faculty who are.  Also, many science faculty members are aware of research internships available with private companies or higher education institutions. The Idaho-INBRE program is one example.  Contact a science professor for more information about this program.</p>
<p><strong>Letters of Evaluation</strong><br />All health profession schools require applicants to submit at least one letter of evaluation from a faculty member.  It is important for potential applicants to develop a professional relationship with faculty members throughout their undergraduate academic career.  The best letters of evaluation come from faculty members who can speak for your academic ability and for your personal qualities and characteristics.  Faculty members want to help students succeed in their career aspirations, but students need to take the initiative in developing and fostering the relationship.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19078" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x20965" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
