<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<CustomPageWithReturn ID="x20439" Name="Dance Alliance" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dance Alliance</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dance Alliance</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="LeftNavGroup" label="Left Nav Return" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><ParentName type="string" label="Parent Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Get Involved</ParentName><xPower Type="Link" Link="x9014" Name="Link" label="Link" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" LinkText="" Target="" Expanded="false" URL=""/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<h1>Dance Alliance</h1>
<hr />
<h4><img alt="Extravadance Finale" height="298" src="Images/dance/RainbowShirts.jpg" width="948" /></h4>
<h4></h4>
<h4>Artistic Director: Shawn Fisher</h4>
<h5><a href="mailto:larseng@byui.edu">fishers@byui.edu</a></h5>
<p>Dance Alliance is a distinctive dance company representing BYU-Idaho. This company is made up of 36 dancers dedicated to sharing their technical strengths and taking the opportunity to experience and/or learn other genres of dance. Dancers who are invited to participate in Dance Alliance and who come with strong backgrounds in various areas of dance will have every opportunity to work with several different choreographers from various professional backgrounds. Students take on greater responsibility as they assist in the teaching, choreography, and the development of testimonies.</p>
<p>As we create dances for performances we are bound by the 13th Article of Faith in our choice of music, costumes, and choreography which will be "virtuous, lovely or of good report or praiseworthy."</p>
<p>M. Russell Ballard has challenged artists to create works of art that "not only need to be uplifting, they must be excellent, to set it apart from the mediocre of the worldly." He goes on to say, "People deserve quality alternatives, the kind that invite the Holy Spirit. Few things bring joy more fully to the world than the arts." Our purpose as dancers and artists should be to lift and inspire, changing the hearts of those who experience the performance. It is this alternative in dance that Dance Alliance will seek out.</p>
<p>Boyd K. Packer challenged, "Go to, then, you who are gifted; cultivate your gift. Develop in any of the arts and in every worthy example of them." It is our desire as a department within higher education to take this challenge, along with the blessings that have been promised to us, "that revelation and inspiration may pour into our minds" if we strive to create a performance that will testify of Christ, and the joy of living the restored gospel can bring.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="font-size: large;">2015 Dance Alliance Auditions:</span></span></h3>
tentatively scheduled for Friday, January 9, 2015</div>
<div>more information will be posted in December 2014. Stay tuned!<br />
<h3></h3>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline; font-size: small;">Requirements to participate on Dance Alliance</span></p>
<p>Must be available for tour the 2 weeks following Spring Semester.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline; font-size: small;">Audition Requirements</span></p>
<p>Audition will consist of learning 2-3 short combinations of varying dance styles.&nbsp; Please come with 30 seconds of movement in your area of choosing to perform for the audition panel.</p>
<p>Dance styles used in the show will demonstrate a wide variety of genres, including ballet, modern, jazz, rhythmic/footworks, ballroom, and world/folk dance.&nbsp; Each style will be used in direct service to the show's theme.</p>
<p>We look forward to auditions and invite those who are looking for a positive artistic experience and also willing to bring their best selves to the magic of the creative process.</p>
<p>* Information subject to change</p>
<h4>Requirements to participate in Dance Alliance</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="x20463.xml">Click here</a></p>
<h4>Application</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To apply, please fill out and submit the <a href="Documents/theatre-dance/Dance/Dance Alliance Audition Sheetdocx.pdf">Dance Alliance Application</a>.</p>
<h5><a href="x20440.xml">Frequently Asked Questions</a></h5>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x8168" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></CustomPageWithReturn>
