<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21185" Name="Real Issues:  Sorting out what Teach One Another is and isn't" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Real Issues:  Sorting out what Teach One Another is and isn't</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Teach One Another definitely means a more selfless, engaged, collaborative and active role for students in their learning. And it definitely means a long-term, incremental, steady, upward effort by all of us as we try to be the kind of place, and help the students build the people around them into a community, where we all can truly love, serve and teach one another.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20091130T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fenton Broadhead and Devan Barker</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img height="172" src="Images/instructional-development/News/stories/11-2009/fenton.png" width="122" /><img height="172" src="Images/instructional-development/News/stories/11-2009/devan.png" width="122" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="display: inline;">The last several years have brought a whirlwind of changes, initiatives and experiments at BYU-Idaho. In the midst of that whirlwind, much conceptual dust has been kicked up causing confusion regarding what is meant, and what isn't meant, by&nbsp;Teach One Another. This article is an attempt to settle some of that dust.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Teach One Another is distinct and different from other peer-based initiatives</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Before the Learning Model was completely articulated in its current form, several initiatives emphasizing the role of peers in learning were promoted on campus. The most prominent of these were Peer-to-Peer Learning, and Eric Mazur's Peer Instruction.<em>&nbsp;</em>These are distinct from Teach One Another in the context of the Learning Model.<em>&nbsp;</em>Peer-to-Peer<a href="http://www.byui.edu/studentpeerinstruction/"> </a>was and is a way to explore reaching more students than would be possible if all instructional interaction came from professors. Experimentation with structures where a student assumes some of the traditional role of the instructor have found moderate success in settings like the Iron Rod program, the Heber J. Grant program and the Activities program. Indeed, something similar has been functioning for many years in the BYU-Idaho athletic program, where student coaches organize and lead competitive athletics.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>During this period, there was much discussion about how similar peer-to-peer structures might influence traditional academic courses. However, peer-to-peer models, based on students taking on the principle instructional role have not been successfully implemented in academically rigorous, content-rich environments. Instructors who rely heavily on student presentations to introduce new material to the class often labor under the mistaken impression that such peer-to-peer instruction is what is meant or required by the Learning Model. It is not.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Mazur's Peer Instruction, on the other hand, is a very specific and very effective teaching technique using concept tests and 'clickers' to engage students in thinking conceptually about what they're learning. The technique is effective and deserves consideration in many settings, but it is only one small example of what is meant by Teach One Another in the Learning Model.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Teach One Another is only one part of the Learning Model</em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Because of the early emphasis on peer-to-peer learning and peer instruction, the related but distinct concept of Teach One Another got disproportionate emphasis and attention when the Learning Model was formally introduced. The Learning Model, however, is much more than students teaching or working collaboratively in whatever format. The model is a shared campus language for thinking and talking about learning and teaching. It articulates principles and processes of a BYU-Idaho education. While highlighting and encouraging best practices around the principles and processes, the Learning Model itself does not mandate any specific instructional practice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The principles of the Learning Model help the campus community define what we mean when we talk about learning at BYU-Idaho. Learning, for this community, is an extension of faith. It's a spiritual quest as much as a secular one, sought in partnership with the Holy Ghost, and guided by the words of prophets. It is an expression of agency and willingly sought rather than passively received. And it is sought with the intent and for the purpose of blessing others; our learning is pursued in order to "love, serve, and teach" others.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The process steps<a href="http://www.byui.edu/learningmodel/src/default.htm"> </a>of the Learning Model describe for students their responsibility in pursuing and achieving this type of learning. They are to prepare in order to glean the most from their classroom experiences. They are to internalize their learning through reflection and pondering. They are to externalize the learning by proving in various ways what they've mastered. And the middle step, and the one too often misunderstood, is that they are to do this thing called Teach One Another.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Teach One Another Correctly Understood</em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If we are to understand Teach One Another, we must understand it as distinct from other peer-related initiatives, and as more than the techniques of collaborative learning. We must also understand that the process of students teaching one another is a reflection and extension of the Learning Model principle to "love, serve, and teach" one another.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This means that learning at BYU-Idaho should not be the pursuit of lone individuals, but of communities of learners. Success in a classroom should be defined as the result of a group effort, not just the achievement of individual learners. Turning to explain something to my peer only makes sense if I care whether or not my peer understands. Articulating my ideas to a small group only makes sense if I know that the group is truly listening and considering what I say. And trying to learn from peers who are as inexpert as I only makes sense if I believe that they have something to contribute to my learning beyond content expertise. <strong>It is from this sense of mutual service and joint effort within a community that the concept of Teach One Another must derive its meaning and power.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Teach One Another means that students should 'rejoice in the success of [their] brethren.' (Alma 29:14-16). It means that they, with our help, work together to crack difficult concepts or memorize material. It means that we promote study groups when feasible, and meaningful collaborative work when appropriate. It means that we make time in class for them to process, review and refine their understanding with each other, not just take notes. It means that we help each other and rely on each other as we pursue the spiritual quest of becoming educated. And in the end, it means that we do all of this to promote the Kingdom and to establish Zion.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Teach One Another in Practice</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Big words -- but what does this mean in practical terms for the classroom? It doesn't usually mean that we need to completely re-invent our courses or teaching styles, but it might. It means that we implement projects, case studies, scenarios, Socratic discussions or similar best practices into our course design. And it often means building curriculum around problems or inquiries that students pursue together. It means using class time for regular group processing<a href="http://web.byui.edu/LearningAndTeaching/Tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=34"> </a>of newly acquired understanding. It definitely means close consideration of tried and proven collaborative learning techniques in the classroom, but not to the exclusion of instructor contribution.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Teach One Another might, on occasion, mean that a student's initial introduction to new material -- when not obtained through pre-class preparation -- is presented by someone other than the instructor, but it doesn't mean this exclusively or extensively. It does preclude whole hours of talking-head lecture, but it doesn't preclude appropriate, limited, direct instruction or instructor-led discussion, especially if that discussion incites more than the occasional comment from the regular handful of students.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Teach One Another definitely means a more selfless, engaged, collaborative and active role for students in their learning. And it definitely means a long-term, incremental, steady, upward effort by all of us as we try to be the kind of place, and help the students build the people around them into a community, where we all can truly love, serve and teach one another.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/LearningAndTeaching/Tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=4">Teach One Another Overview Tool&nbsp;</a></p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/LearningAndTeaching/Tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=35">Instructor Role in Teach One Another</a></p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/LearningAndTeaching/post/2009/10/Principles2c-Processes-and-Practices-of-the-BYU-Idaho-Learning-Model.aspx#comment">Principles, Processes and Practices of the BYU-Idaho Learning Model&nbsp;</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>