<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21188" Name="Book Review: Thinking about Teaching and Learning" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Book Review: Thinking about Teaching and Learning</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The dearth of really good thought and writing about education makes it all the more exciting when one stumbles across a truly exceptional book, one well worth the time to read and think about.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20091105T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Devan Barker</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><!--[if gte vml 1]> <![endif]--><img align="left" height="294" hspace="15" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/11-2009/bookcover.png" style="padding-right: 8px;" width="199" />It's the unfortunate truth that much of what has been written about education could disappear from the library shelves and databases with no appreciable impact on our understanding of learning and teaching.&nbsp; Hugh Nibley spoke disparagingly of the flood of empty rhetoric in which much educational literature is awash.&nbsp; He said:</p>
<blockquote></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp; <br /> <em>It is not only easy and pleasant to discourse on the education of the race; it is actually a temptation which few can resist. The urge to improve other people's minds is, as Brigham Young observed, not a rare virtue but the commonest of vices. It should be avoided rather than rewarded. Talking about education is like beer-drinking (and the two often go together); it is pleasantly intoxicating, enormously time-consuming, idiotically exalting, and subtly enervating; while imparting a befuddled sense of power and glory, it effectively paralyzes activity of the mind and body.[i]</em><em><a href="#_edn1" name="_ednref1" title="_ednref1"></a></em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The dearth of really good thought and writing about education makes it all the more exciting when one stumbles across a truly exceptional book, one well worth the time to read and think about.&nbsp; Robert Leamnson's book&nbsp;Thinking About Teaching and Learning is one such exceptional book and deserves inclusion on the short list for those of us at BYU-Idaho interested in &lsquo;inspired learning and teaching.'&nbsp; This thin 152 page book manages to avoid the most common weaknesses of the genre, wholly skips the strained vocabulary so prevalent in its flavor-of-the-month counterparts, and offers refreshing and clear discussion about important ideas relevant to learning and teaching in higher education.</p>
<blockquote></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Robert Leamnson is a professor of biology at the University of Massachusetts at Dartmouth.&nbsp; His discussion about learning is rooted in the biology of the student brain and his thoughts on instruction reflect a deep psychological understanding of how to best impact and mold the desired changes within the student brain.&nbsp; He is especially insightful in developing the psychology of the first-year college student and presenting ideas for effectively teaching these young freshmen.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;Readers from the life sciences and hard sciences will breathe a collective sigh of relief to find a thoughtful discussion about learning and teaching that clearly defines each.&nbsp; He speaks of learning as, "stabilizing, through repeated use, certain appropriate and desirable synapses in the brain"(p. 5) This definition underscores the difficulties encountered, effort involved&nbsp; and the discomfort experienced by students as they try out these new neural pathways and work to stabilize the synapses.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Readers from the humanities and social sciences will appreciate the discussion of language and language usage as a student's principle means of demonstrating learning and therefore a significant target of our instructional endeavors.&nbsp; He discusses at some length the role of writing assignments in various disciplines as a principle means to initiate and &lsquo;stabilize' student learning.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Readers from every discipline will find Leamnson's utter rejection of &lsquo;magic bullets' a refreshing and honest break from literature describing the &lsquo;latest breakthrough.'&nbsp; His section on group work, for example, begins with the following comment:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote>Group study has so much potential for good that it has, in some instances, turned into something of a fetish.&nbsp; I have great faith in group study, but only so long as it remains a means to an end and does not become an end in itself...Techniques, methods and materials are effective only to the extent that they induce, or inspire, students to switch on the thinking parts of their brains and process the language of the discipline. (78-79)</blockquote>
<blockquote></blockquote>
<blockquote></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Indeed, the preface to the book includes the explanation that "the purpose of this book is not to eliminate the present difficulties, or to explain them away, but to turn the bright light of critical inquiry on them and exhort teachers of beginning college students to see the difficulties for what they are, and then to do what needs to be done."(x)&nbsp; The book, "aspires to present, to an audience not normally inclined to read books on pedagogy, some connections between sound traditional learning processes and ways of teaching both old and new."(xi)&nbsp; In this attempt, Leamnson has been uniquely successful.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The eight chapters of the book carry the following titles:</p>
<p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thinking about Thinking and Teaching</p>
<p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Biological Basis of Learning</p>
<p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Language</p>
<p>4.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today's First-Year Students</p>
<p>5.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Teach and Pedagogy</p>
<p>6.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Classroom</p>
<p>7.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Writing and other Technologies</p>
<p>8.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Final Thoughts</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The book ends with a short annotated bibliography of 10&nbsp; other works which each, in their own way, escape the mediocrity of much educational literature to join this book as worthy of a permanent spot on the desk of anyone interested in improving learning and teaching in higher education.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For those interested, used copies of this book start at $5.50 on Amazon.&nbsp; The Department of Instructional Development also has a copy available for lending at MCK 350.&nbsp; Call x2594 to enquire.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Thinking-About-Teaching-Learning-Developing/dp/1579220134/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1257367194&amp;sr=8-1">Thinking About Teaching and Learning</a> on Amazon</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="#_ednref1" name="_edn1" title="_edn1">[i]</a> Excerpts from an address to the History Honors Banquet, Wilkenson Center, Brigham Young University, May 12, 1965 by Hugh Nibley.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>