<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21265" Name="The Spori Summit Tradition Continues:" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Spori Summit Tradition Continues:</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Spori Summit let me re-examine what I do in the classroom.  Through conversation and brainstorming I was able to gather ideas and approaches from instructors with different backgrounds than my own.  The ideas they shared with me have already changed what I do in class.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090602T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Your Name</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s something about plentiful food and mountain air, interesting  company and no cell-phone signal that make for a great retreat.&nbsp; Throw in practical and meaningful discussions  about learning and teaching at BYU-Idaho and the retreat becomes the Spori Summit.&nbsp; The Spori Summit, named after Jacob Spori and  patterned on the Great Teacher&rsquo;s Seminar model, has been a fixture of  professional development at Ricks/BYU-Idaho for many years.</p>
<br />
<p><img alt="Jacob Spori" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/06-2009/jacobspori.jpg" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" />Last  weekend, a dozen or so faculty from departments across campus spent a day and a  half at Quick Water Ranch in Victor for this semester&rsquo;s iteration of this  biennial faculty development retreat.&nbsp;  While the Spori Summit is supported financially by the university administration,  it has since its inception, been a faculty organized and faculty driven forum  for collaborating with colleagues around improving instructional skills.&nbsp;&nbsp;This  time, Van Christman, chair of the Department of Teacher Education facilitated  the discussions with help from several faculty members who had attended the  summit before. Participants included instructors from engineering, home and  family, computer information systems, sociology, religious education, math,  history, education and Foundations.&nbsp;</p>
<br />
<p>During the course of the summit, faculty members got the chance to  share ideas and techniques that have worked for them in their own  classrooms.&nbsp; They shared books that have  had a significant impact on their development as professional educators.&nbsp; The core of the summit, however, was given  over to discussing difficulties faced by instructors and brainstorming ways to  meet those difficulties.</p>
<br />
<p><img alt="Quick Water Ranch" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/06-2009/quickwaterranch.jpg" style="float: right; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-left: 15px;" />Participants explored ways to help students,  especially younger students, manage the workload required by higher education.&nbsp; They addressed ways to improve student  participation in large classes and to help students prepare for classroom  experiences.&nbsp; Other discussion groups  focused on how to avoid social loafing during group work, how to deal with students  that register for a class without the pre-requisite knowledge or understanding  and how to deal with student complaints that become toxic to the classroom  environment.&nbsp; Discussion during Friday  afternoon turned to finding time for grading student work, managing student  excuses, working with dysfunctional group dynamics and helping students to  reach higher levels of comfort with the rigor and ambiguity that characterize  learning at the tertiary level.</p>
<br />
<p>Forums like the Spori Summit rarely provide absolute answers to the manifold  challenges we face as educators, put they do provide a much-needed venue for  gaining insight, exploring options, and seeing what has worked for others.&nbsp; Here are some comments by four of this year&rsquo;s  participants:</p>
<br /> 
<ul>
<li><em>The Spori Summit  has been a great blessing to me personally and the campus as a whole. &nbsp;It  is very refreshing to meet with faculty from a wide variety of  disciplines.&nbsp; I have learned that our subject matter may differ, but our  challenges and triumphs are very similar.&nbsp; Upon reflection, I think that  the Spori Summit has had a greater positive impact on my teaching than any  other single experience.&nbsp; It can be difficult to break away from classes,  but the rewards are great.&nbsp; I strongly recommend that each faculty member  take advantage of this professional development opportunity.</em></li>
<br />
<li><em>The Spori Summit let me  re-examine what I do in the classroom.&nbsp;  Through conversation and brainstorming I was able to gather ideas and  approaches from instructors with different backgrounds than my own.&nbsp; The ideas they shared with me have already  changed what I do in class.</em></li>
<br />
<li><em>Spori  Summit was a rejuvenating feast. &nbsp;It gave me a chance to get to know colleagues  from across campus. As we shared successes and challenges, I was impressed with  the openness, and it motivated me to reach out to others both to gain insights  and share my own experience, so we can all grow and serve our students more  effectively. &nbsp;Spori Summit served to polish the lens a little, so I can see more  clearly how I can work smarter to impact my students.</em></li>
<br />
<li><em>Spori  Summit is an amazing experience.&nbsp; The relaxed, safe atmosphere encourages  communication and discussion where ideas and teaching challenges can be shared  freely. &nbsp;The outcome of the discussions provides an opportunity for  the Spirit to teach you those things which you can do in the classroom to  improve teaching.&nbsp; Those discussion ideas have also helped me make ongoing  commitments which have enhanced my learning and teaching.&nbsp; I have raised  my level of expectations and most students are striving to comply by coming to  class prepared and teaching others the concepts and principles they have  learned.&nbsp; </em></li>
</ul>
<p>(Summaries and comments  about past summits may be found <a href="http://www.byui.edu/FacAssn/facultyrespond.htm" target="_blank">here</a>.)</p>
<br />
<p>The next Spori Summit is scheduled for October 8th and 9th,  2009.&nbsp; If you block out the dates now, it  should be easy enough to plan your Fall syllabi to permit attendance.&nbsp; Imagine &ndash; crisp autumn air, a warm cabin, an  unending supply of snacks (both the healthy and not-so-healthy variety), and a  day and a half of practical discussion with thoughtful and experienced  colleagues . . .</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>