<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21200" Name="Working through my feelings about student evaluations" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Working through my feelings about student evaluations</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Upon reflection, my gut-level, knee-jerk reaction to evaluations is anything but rational. But if I push past the fears, misunderstandings, fuzzy math, and ego, I find that the student evaluations tell me something very valuable.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090923T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Devan Barker</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div align="center"></div>
<p><img align="left" alt=" " height="170" hspace="15" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/09-2009/dbarker.jpg" style="padding-right: 5px;" title=" " width="120" /></p>
<p>For me, student evaluations are a lot like the evening news. They usually leave me perplexed and depressed, but I find myself going back time after time to hear what they have to say. That's not to say that my evaluations are all that bad - especially when compared to the evening news. Usually, they're pretty positive with mixed results on some of the questions and the occasional disgruntled student who has an ax to grind or is just plain nasty. Yet strangely, it's not the comments from the students who learned "a great deal more" than in other classes or the ones who thought that the course was "AWESOME!" that stick in my mind. Rather, it's the student who feels that she never got any useful feedback, or the one that feels the course objectives were cryptic that draw my attention and leave me feeling a failure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I understand that the brain tends to focus on the negative more than the positive. This doesn't change my disappointment, however, when a student I've really tried to reach and spent so much time and energy on, leaves with a negative parting shot - seemingly out of the clear blue sky. My initial defensive response is to discount and ignore the evaluations altogether. When the evening news makes me depressed, it seems logical to stop watching. Somehow, however, this reaction has never satisfied me. So if I can't simply ignore student evaluations, I need to better understand how to interpret them and how to glean the wisdom that they can offer me as an instructor. I need to rationalize my response to them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Part of my problem is ego. I got into teaching because I thought I had some natural ability in that direction. I like teaching - a lot; and in a completely illogical fashion, it seems that how much I enjoy it should somehow indicate how good I am at it. So when student comments shake the assumed relationship between my enjoyment of teaching and my skill as an instructor, it is profoundly disturbing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Part of the problem is math-deficiency. I've been told many times over the years that I'm a good teacher, so to score below 90% in any category feels troubling and to score at the average, like failure. It's easy to forget that I work in an institution full of people whose talent, training, commitment and experience meet and exceed my own. Like the children in Lake Woebegone, I think we should all be above the average.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In a similarly math-deficient way, I tend to interpret all data as statistically valid. If I remember my graduate course in statistics, a data set needs 30-33 data points to produce a reliable distribution. Fewer than that and the outliers skew the data disproportionately. Yet when I get results of a class with 25 students, or 15 students, my first response isn't to aggregate the data across multiple sections or semesters to get good data, but to simply look at how my skewed averages measure up.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Part of my difficulty is that the evaluations feel like a customer satisfaction survey instead of an assessment of how well I did my job. I agree 100% with the need to move from a&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">teaching&nbsp;</em></span>to a&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">learning&nbsp;</em></span>paradigm in higher education. Universities like BYU-Idaho should be learning-centered. Unfortunately, it's altogether too easy for students (and sometimes faculty and administration) to confuse&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">learning-centered&nbsp;</em></span>education, with&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">student-centered&nbsp;</em></span>education and then to cast students in the role of the&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">customer</em></span>, who as we know, is always right. (I've actually had a student tell me "I pay part of your salary...")</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;I try to clarify this misunderstanding to my students in the following way: There is a difference between being a&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">customer&nbsp;</em></span>and being a&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">client</em></span>. Customers buy commodities and products; clients pay for access to expertise and for expert help. While customers might always be right, that is not the case with clients. A doctor doesn't base his or her decisions primarily on what the patient wants, but on what is medically prudent. Likewise a lawyer doesn't prepare a case principally in order to please the plaintiff, but in order to win according to the statutes of law. As an educator I see my job as facilitating real learning, not selling consumers a package of &lsquo;education' to fit their tastes. I look to student evaluations to tell me how much students really learned and to what they attribute their level of learning. If a student is taking the tone of a customer rather than a client in their evaluation, I feel justified in discounting some of what they say as based upon false expectations on their part.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If I'm honest with myself, I have to admit that part of my initial reaction to evaluations is based in fear. In my work, I'm assessed against something over which I do not have complete control (student learning). It would be much less scary if I could be assessed based on my knowledge of my field. I mean, after all, that is what I was initially trained in, not in instruction. Or maybe I'd like to be assessed on my skill in carrying out instructional tasks without reference to the actual learning results. I don't like the feeling that my best efforts, my most sincere attempts at teaching, might not be sufficient. I, like my students, have the weakness of wanting to be graded on effort and intent, not results.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I also fear that in the absence of other data points, the student evaluations will take on a disproportionate weight and importance in making institutional decisions. I'd much rather see evaluations used as one of several measures to give me feedback on how I'm doing. But although I've invited colleagues into my classroom to observe, I've never extended the invitation to my chair to watch me at work and gain a wider perspective on my abilities. I haven't provided him with any other kind of measures or data points.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Instead of seeing how I'm doing compared to others who teach a similar subject or other sections of my courses, I find it slightly unnerving that I can only see how I perform against the university as a whole. Am I really judged based on how my courses measure up against the archery courses, the physics courses, the religion courses and the construction courses? Then, on the other hand, I've never asked my chair how my work compares within the department. He has that data and could easily show me my strengths and weaknesses compared to other instructors who teach the same course, but I've never sought out that information.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Upon reflection, my gut-level, knee-jerk reaction to evaluations is anything but rational. But if I push past the fears, misunderstandings, fuzzy math, and ego, I find that the student evaluations tell me something very valuable. They tell me that while I'm a competent teacher, there are things I can learn and areas where I can improve. They hint that as much as I enjoy teaching now, there is even more to be enjoyed as I become more and more skilled in different aspects of the craft. They show me that I'm surrounded by exceptionally gifted and experienced educators who have much to share and who can benefit from my abilities as well. They teach me that I have a responsibility to provide other performance measures and to help insure that the information the evaluations provide isn't misused. Finally, they remind me that this whole endeavor really isn't about me anyway, but about the learning of the students that come under my tutelage. In the end, I guess that's not as bad as the evening news.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Is your experience similar or dissimilar?&nbsp; Please explain how you respond to your student evaluations in the comments area below.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>