<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21262" Name="Watch One, Do One, Teach One" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Watch One, Do One, Teach One</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Watch one, Do one, Teach one, is an example of one of many ways that faculty apply Learning Model-type principles and practices in their disciplines.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090618T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brian Schmidt</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><img alt="Garth Waddoups" height="170" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/authorpics/WADDOUPSG.JPG" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="120" /> In  veterinarian school Garth Waddoups came to appreciate a simple teaching method  called <em>Watch one, Do one, Teach one.&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">It gave him the opportunity to observe,  practice, and explain a medical procedure.&nbsp;  These three different ways of learning were helpful as he sought to  understand and remember the procedures he was expected to learn in the program.&nbsp; Now as an instructor at BYU-Idaho, Garth uses  the same process to teach his students.</span></em> <br /> <em>Watch one, Do one,  Teach one<span style="display: inline;">, is an example of one of many ways that faculty apply Learning  Model-type principles and practices in their disciplines.&nbsp; In this case, experiential and then collaborative  learning components are added to traditional observation.&nbsp; After observing a procedure, students &ldquo;act.&rdquo; &nbsp;They literally &ldquo;<a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=5">prove</a>&rdquo;  what they are learning by repeating the procedure themselves.&nbsp; They then &ldquo;<a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=4">teach  one another</a>,&rdquo; meaning that they explain to another student what they just  did and why.</span></em> <br /> <img src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/06-2009/veterinarian1.jpg" style="float: right; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-left: 15px;" />Before  using the technique in his courses, Garth takes time to explain this teaching approach.&nbsp; He turns to the scriptures and recounts the  experience of Nephi hearing of his father&rsquo;s dream.&nbsp; While pondering upon the words he heard from  his father, the Spirit revealed to Nephi all the things that his father  saw.&nbsp; After experiencing his own vision,  Nephi able to explain the interpretation of the tree of life to his  brothers.&nbsp; Garth explains to his students  that in a way, Nephi went through the process of &ldquo;Watch one, Do one, Teach one&rdquo;  when he listened to his father, experienced the dream for himself, and taught  his brothers.&nbsp; Together these three steps  formed a powerful learning experience that deepened Nephi&rsquo;s understanding and  faith.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> In a similar fashion, Garth uses these three steps to teach  a number of procedures in his courses.&nbsp;  For example, in the Animal Health Lab students learn how to administer a  nerve block (before taking off the horns of a bull) by watching another student  inject the anesthetic with a syringe.&nbsp; In  turn, each student has the opportunity to administer the shot.&nbsp; Afterwards, each student gets to explain the  procedure to another student who is just learning.&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /> <br /> <img src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/06-2009/veterinarian2.jpg" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The  teaching approach changes the dynamics in the classroom.&nbsp; When students know they will have to apply  what they are learning, they are very attentive.&nbsp; After applying the technique, they enjoy  sharing their insights by teaching other students.&nbsp; Garth explains that rather than being up  front talking, he is able to roam the room and monitor what is happening.&nbsp; &ldquo;I am able to get a better assessment of my  students&rsquo; abilities.&rdquo; &nbsp;If needed, he may  occasionally step in to help a student group overcome a problem or  misconception.&nbsp; This allows him to  monitor and assure the quality of the instruction when students are teaching  each other.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> He explains that while it may be initially difficulty for  some to participate, students soon see they are on equal footing as all of them  get chances to watch, act, and teach.&nbsp; After  a few rounds of the process Garth finds that students enjoy the interaction and  appreciate the various ways of learning. <br /> <br /> The <em>Watch one, Do one,  Teach one</em> approach is one of many structured processes at our disposal to  help students teach and learn from one another.&nbsp; <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=31">Jigsaws</a>, <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=34">Mutual  Peer Tutoring</a>, and <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=33">Paired  Learning</a> are additional approaches discussed on this website.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>