<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21267" Name="Real Issues: The Art of Teaching" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Real Issues: The Art of Teaching</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">It's easy for me to seek out these types of teaching methodologies because they are tried and true, and like the flashing lights near the crosswalk, they serve a purpose.  I wondered, though, if the need to see these bright signals in my classroom might actually limit my ability to personalize my teaching and to see students who, like the morning jogger, need me to see beyond the "lights" and recognize their purpose.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090521T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Eric D'Evegnee</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img alt="Eric D'Evegnee" height="170" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/authorpics/DEVEGNEEE.JPG" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="120" /><strong><span style="font-weight: normal;"><strong><br /></strong></span></strong> <br />
<p>I take the same route to campus every day, and my thoughts are usually filled with a jumble of lesson plans, passages from novels, and a myriad of mundane concerns as I coast down the hill by the Rexburg Temple.&nbsp; Early one morning, I hurriedly made my way down the hill, glancing over at the panoramic vista in front of me.&nbsp; The wide valley stretched out, the soft light of sunrise beginning to spill over onto the Lost River Range.&nbsp; The temple protectively stood watch over the windless morning.&nbsp; Out of the corner of my eye, I barely noticed a shadowy figure moving off of the sidewalk and into the crosswalk.&nbsp; Luckily, I had just caught the runner&rsquo;s movements in the darkness, and slowed to a stop.&nbsp; As I watched her jog past, I was struck by how I had become conditioned to rely on the brightly flashing lights that normally signal drivers to stop.&nbsp; Had I only been looking for the lights I would have easily missed seeing the runner.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> <img alt="Pedestrian sign with flashing lights" height="366" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/pedestrian_sign.jpg" style="float: right; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-left: 15px;" width="224" />By all accounts, it was an unspectacular event.&nbsp; But as I parked the car and made my way to my office I couldn't stop thinking of my surprising dependence on the flashing lights.&nbsp; As a teacher, I have come to appreciate the value of certain "flashing lights" that externally signal to me that a certain lesson plan or activity will be effective.&nbsp; It's easy for me to seek out these types of teaching methodologies because they are tried and true, and like the flashing lights near the crosswalk, they serve a purpose.&nbsp; I wondered, though, if the need to see these bright signals in my classroom might actually limit my ability to personalize my teaching and to see students who, like the morning jogger, need me to see beyond the "lights" and recognize their purpose.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> While we as teachers constantly strive to perfect our teaching, we must ensure that we don't lose sight of the higher principles of what we teach. Without an enduring principle that transcends mere informational gathering, learning becomes a series of pavlovian exercises. In effect, we become more concerned with the lights flashing than with the person in the crosswalk. <br /> <br /> In the book of Jarom, we see teachers who are able to successfully combine the instruction of a measured law while keeping the art of its principles in sight. Verse two underscores the importance of skill, while maintaining respect for why we are teaching.&nbsp; It says that they "[taught] the law of Moses, and the <em>intent&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">for which it was given (italics added).&nbsp; These prophets and teachers still measured outcomes but the key is that they never lost sight of their motive&mdash;to prepare their students for a life beyond their classrooms. Like these teachers, I hope never to teach just for the sake of teaching or just to be able to take pride in measured outcomes.&nbsp; Like my friend's father, who has been a teacher in Connecticut&rsquo;s public school trenches for over forty years, says when people ask him what he teaches, "I teach students!&nbsp; I don't teach History, I teach students!" &nbsp;</span></em> <br /> Once in an American Literature class, I carefully set up a <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=31">jigsaw</a> with a few directed questions about the novel,&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Passing<span style="display: inline;">. As the students were in their first groups, the room was buzzing and it would have been easy for me to watch the clock rather than my students. However, as I walked around to each group, listening in on their conversation, every now and then a question that was outside of the "lesson plan" popped up from one of the groups. Excitedly, the students were taking the question about the novel and then applying their answer to a current social issue and wanted to get my opinion. Another group was involved in a debate about their interpretation of the final chapter. It would have been easy to quiet my students and get them back on "task," but I resisted the need to complete the activity as planned because I sensed my students desire to create their own questions and find their own answers.&nbsp;&nbsp; As I answered questions, ten hands were waving in the air, and there was an almost electric energy in the classroom.&nbsp; I still maintained my role as the teacher, as I directed their queries and added bits of my expertise to the discussion, and we all left the room with an expanded understanding of not only the text, but of how it applied to our lives. Here was a moment where I almost lost sight of what was happening in front of me because I was worried about accomplishing the task.&nbsp; Luckily, as I had on my morning drive to work, I had slowed enough to see the need in front of me. &nbsp;</span></em></span><br /> <br /> This type of revelatory classroom energy is only available to teachers who see teaching as a form of art that requires both careful training and an appreciation of the beauty of the spontaneous flow of new ideas.&nbsp; Without that beauty and energy, our classrooms would be the equivalent of a paint-by-numbers kit rather than an exquisitely rendered composition, carefully shaded with various textures and hues.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> To keep ourselves focused on both the signals of effective teaching the intent for which we teach, we can ask ourselves several questions:</p>
<br /> 
<ul>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Am I measuring both the skill level and the original thinking of my students?</li>
<li>Do I discuss the underlying purpose for various activities with my students?&nbsp; Do they understand the epistemological benefit of not only the thoughts but the way of thinking?</li>
<li>Do my students view the learning in my classroom as something that transcends disciplinary boundaries?&nbsp; Do they appreciate the learning process and not just measured success that will lead them towards a future job in the discipline?</li>
<li>Do I allow my students to feel ownership of their education by allowing my lesson plans to be flexible enough to allow for unplanned, energetic moments of learning?&nbsp; Do I likewise allow for the intimations of the Spirit to direct a discussion? Do I carefully use my own training to guide them to synthesize my expertise and their own thinking?</li>
</ol> 
<ul>
</ul>
<br />
<p>After the famous French writer, Albert Camus, won the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1957, he composed an emotional letter to his former teacher, Louis Germain.&nbsp; As satisfying as the award must have been, Camus looked beyond the external measure of his world-wide success and said, "[The Nobel Prize] gives me an opportunity to tell you what you have been and still are for me, and to assure you that your efforts, your work, and the generous heart you put into it still live in one of your little schoolboys who, despite the years, has never stopped being your grateful pupil."&nbsp; Notice that it was the combined force of his teacher's diligence and his intent that created the unforgettable classroom for Camus.&nbsp; External outcomes, like the flashing lights, are only an accompaniment to the type of teaching that allows the inspiration felt in the confines of a classroom to seep into students lives permanently, so that "despite the years," they will still practice both the habits and the aesthetics we, as their teachers, enjoyed with them.&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>