<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21268" Name="Real Issues:  Introduction to a New Series" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Real Issues:  Introduction to a New Series</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">“I see ahead a great season of creativity and innovation, a season of powerful new ideas and new curricula all across this campus. . . . because it is done by faculty whose hearts are right, whose eyes are single to the glory of God, and who desire nothing in their work but to bless the lives of their students” [italics added]. - President Clark</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090507T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Scott Ferguson and Clark Gilbert</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Scott Ferguson" height="170" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/FergusonS.jpg" style="margin: 15px;" width="120" /> <img align="left" alt="Clark Gilbert" height="170" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/GilbertC.jpg" style="margin: 15px;" width="120" />
<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<br />
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>The writer and educator Mauritz Johnson once observed: “It is easier to move a cemetery than to change a curriculum.” And yet at BYU-Idaho, we see a remarkable group of faculty members who repeatedly set aside personal and departmental identities to work across boundaries as we implement new ideas. It was President Clark who said in his <span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;"><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Presentations/Transcripts/MiscellaneousAddresses/2005_10_11_Clark.htm">Inaugural Response</a></em></span>: “I see ahead a great season of creativity and innovation, a season of powerful new ideas and new curricula all across this campus. . . . because it is done by faculty whose hearts are right, whose eyes are single to the glory of God, and who desire nothing in their work but to bless the lives of their students” [italics added]. And President Eyring in his talk, <span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;"><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Presentations/Transcripts/Devotionals/2001_09_18_Eyring.htmhttp:/www.byui.edu/Presentations/Transcripts/Devotionals/2001_09_18_Eyring.htm">A Steady Upward Course</a></em></span>, stated that it would be: “the faith of the faculty and those who lead here, that will lead us to be legendary in terms of our capacity to teach and to learn and in our capacity to innovate without needing the resources that others have to have in order to be the remarkable contributors you’re going to be.”</p>
<br />
<p>And yet, given all of the change happening at BYU-Idaho, we can’t take for granted this great willingness on the part of the faculty to innovate and to change. Foundations is a complete rethinking of our introductory curriculum, and the Learning Model is introducing a shared language which requires us to review our approach to teaching. These and other rapid changes bring with them concerns and issues which need to be addressed. But as discussions move away from the copy machines and drinking fountains into closed offices, there is a risk of creating an “us and them” mentality. If we don’t leave the door and the conversation open, a rift can develop between colleagues with differing points of view and between the faculty and administration. We all know the outcome of this approach—it is destructive to the institution and leads to being at “variance one with another” (D&amp;C 101:50). Ultimately, this results in a situation where we only interact with those of the same “mindset” or we shut down dialogue altogether.</p>
<br />
<p><strong>Learning from Personal Experience</strong></p>
<br />
<p>Recently we (Clark Gilbert and Scott Ferguson) entered an extended conversation over some of these issues. Initially, we think it is fair to say, our exchange was with passion but perhaps not quite enough saintliness on either of our parts. Through some soul searching, apologies, and willingness to listen and not steamroll past each other’s concerns, an exciting partnership and friendship has emerged. Clark initially felt that Scott was being overly critical; instead he found someone who cares a great deal about the institution and was willing to voice his concerns. Similarly, Scott initially felt that Clark was overly enthusiastic and uninformed about faculty feelings on the issues. What Scott found was that Clark (and the administration) were aware of many of the concerns facing the faculty and were just as interested as he in working toward improvement. We, like many of you, both feel the community should talk about concerns openly. And yes, it may take an extra dose of humility and forgiveness to get to where we need to go. This jointly written article is our attempt to add to and improve that dialogue.</p>
<br />
<p>Sometimes our passion for the issues can drive us to extreme views rather than measured consideration. Some of us—faculty and administrators—occasionally fall into a mode where we find ourselves “cheerleading” an idea without addressing the challenges it presents. In response to this, others might sit back and simply criticize without working toward solutions. Or we may get caught up in unhealthy discussions which solve nothing but leave us disenchanted with the issues and each other. We all have likely experienced this to some extent. We, the authors, hope to find a middle ground where we all recognize the potential power of focused dialogue. We assert this is possible, even on a very personal level. We believe it is time for all of us to settle these issues in our hearts. This takes humility and patience with one another: “Clothe yourselves with the bond of charity, as with a mantle, which is the bond of perfectness and peace” (D&amp;C 88:125). This article, and the series in which it appears, is an attempt to open the dialogue. We share it in the spirit of humility and unanimity in hopes that we may be of “one heart and mind.” This article is the first in what will be a sequence of articles examining some of the challenges facing the university while seeking solutions and ideas for improvement.</p>
<br />
<p><strong>Counseling with One Another</strong></p>
<br />
<p>The first topic of our extended discussion was, “Why the lack of counseling with councils.” Too many feel left out of the dialogue or that change is happening so fast they hardly get a chance to reflect, let alone discuss. As we talked with one another, Scott was surprised to learn the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Over the past year, the academic administration has been engaged in literally hundreds of conversations with individual faculty across campus. <span style="display: inline;">Our Academic Vice President, Fenton Broadhead, has scheduled meetings with departments, created an informal advisory council, and meets regularly with Academic and Dean’s Council. </span><span style="display: inline;">Bruce Kusch meets bi-monthly with the Curriculum Counsel and Phil Packer works with the Faculty Development Committee, made up of faculty from across campus. </span><span style="display: inline;">Task force committees have been created on a myriad of topics and a member of the Faculty Association participates in Academic Council. </span><span style="display: inline;">Brian Schmidt and Devan Barker have met with many of our faculty to discuss the Learning Model and classroom teaching. This effort started with 10 group lunches last summer and continues with over 30 separate departmental meetings since. </span><span style="display: inline;">The administration has captured anonymous survey data from over half the faculty on both the Learning Model and classroom instruction.</span></li>
</ul>
<br />
<p>And while no one perspective is ever complete, all of these efforts help to shape a sense of what is working well and what remains a challenge. As Scott observed, “Just because we were not included in a council does not mean counsel wasn’t obtained.” Obviously, with all that has been done, there is still more to do. It appears the water is not always getting to the end of the row.</p>
<br /> <img alt="Council" height="212" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/05-2009/intro/council.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 15px;" width="370" />
<p><strong>Some Suggestions</strong></p>
<br />
<p>There are many areas that need to be addressed as we consider our progress on the steady upward course that has been laid out for this university. As we prepared this article, we articulated four ideas to guide us toward an increasingly productive conversation:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Counseling with Councils.</span> <ol>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Principle:</span> There are individuals across the university whose stewardships require final decision making. For example, Brian Schmidt has responsibility for advancing the Learning Model, but he does not decide what specific techniques an instructor will use in their courses. That decision is left to individual faculty. Usually those who have leadership positions, or the final say, counsel with others before making these decisions—still, not every employee on campus is consulted. This is logistically and organizationally impossible.</li>
</ol> 
<ul>
<li><span style="display: inline;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Practice:</span></span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="display: inline;"> Those with the responsibility to counsel can often seek and invite counsel more than they do. Other times those implementing the counsel need to be satisfied that counsel has occurred and that it is time to go to work. We can error in either direction—we need, however, to be mindful of the tension.</span><br /><ol> </ol></li>
</ol><span style="font-size: 14px; display: inline;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Seek Solutions.</span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="display: inline;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Principle:</span></span></span><span style="display: inline;"> 
<ul>
<li><span style="display: inline;">We have found that more often than not, so many of us share the same concerns. Sometimes we have a tendency to focus on a point of criticism, rather than considering ways to address the shared issue.</span></li>
<li><span style="display: inline;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Practice:</span></span></li>
</ul>
</span></span><ol> </ol><ol>
<li> <ol>
<li><span style="display: inline;"> What we need is the ability to point out a concern without being labeled, but also the willingness to push toward a solution.</span></li>
<li>Ask constructive questions.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol> <ol> </ol><span style="font-size: 14px; display: inline;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="display: inline;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></span></span><ol>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Principle:</span> We noticed in our conversations with each other that it is too easy to make declarative statements like: “This won’t work for shy students” OR “This is too mechanical.” When we should have asked an inspired question that invites further discussion:</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Practice:</span> “How can we make sure this works for the shy students?” OR “How can we preserve individuality and diversity in what we are doing?” We believe the latter approach will lead to a more productive dialogue.</li>
</ol></span><ol>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Extend the conversation.</span> <ol>
<li>This series is a start, but we hope a similar dialogue can extend to other settings, including department meetings and conversations with our colleagues. We also hope you will discuss other ideas with Bruce Kusch (Foundations), Phil Packer (C.F.S), Brian Schmidt (Learning Model), Clark Gilbert (Online Instruction), and other members of the Academic office. Fenton Broadhead refers to this as counsel with a little “c.”</li>
</ol> </li>
</ol> <br />
<p>These are the principles we hope to follow in subsequent articles of this series.</p>
<br />
<p><strong>Upcoming Series</strong></p>
<br />
<p>There are a number of issues around teaching and learning that we would like to explore in this series. The first issue addresses effectively structuring Teach One Another activities: (See <a href="../../LearningAndTeaching/post/2009/05/Real-Issues-Concerns-Surfaced-in-Recent-Student-Survey.aspx">Don’t Hand Over Your Classroom</a> .) We hope that others will jump into the discussion and contribute to future articles. In each of these articles, it will not be enough to simply surface an issue; rather each contributor will be invited to provide suggestions to resolve the concerns. Future topics may include, but are not limited to:</p>
<br /> 
<ul>
<li><strong>Teaching is an Art</strong> — Even as we work on different pedagogical approaches, observe each other, and revise our courses, mechanics will never replace the magic and art of inspired teaching. How do we remember and honor this as a community even as we work on elements of our teaching?</li>
<li><strong>Purpose in Design</strong> — We find ourselves anxious to incorporate elements of the Learning Model into our teaching. How do we avoid doing something new just to be doing it?</li>
<li><strong>Don’t Toss the Baby out with the Bathwater</strong> — It is possible that in an effort to try new things we move away from proven strategies. What are some ways to experiment without overwhelming ourselves, and our students?</li>
<li><strong>The Learning Model is Not New</strong> — The Learning Model is grounded broadly in a rich body of theoretical and empirical educational research. More importantly, its roots are spiritually grounded in the teaching of the restored Gospel and of the Savior Himself. How can we accentuate these other resources around learning and teaching?</li>
<li><strong>Principles vs. Pedagogies</strong> — There is a risk that as we focus on methodology, we will move away from the Principles of the Learning Model and focus on a specific practice. What are ways that we can keep focused on the principles while still sharing ideas for practice?</li>
<li><strong>An Example is Not a Universal Suggestion</strong> — There are still too many people who think that one pedagogical approach should be applied universally (case method or group learning for example). Worse, there are some who think this is what the Academic Office believes. How can we remedy this?</li>
<li><strong>Time-constraints</strong> — How does the three-semester calendar impact they way we do professional development? How does it impact the revision cycle on courses and teaching plans?</li>
<li><strong>Foundations Teaching Groups</strong> — How can we leverage the collaborative benefits of Foundations Teaching groups without losing personal identity and unique teaching styles?</li>
<li><strong>Relationships between Campus and Online</strong> — How can we build out a focused, institutional online capacity without losing the power of connecting campus faculty to the remote adjunct faculty?</li>
</ul>
<br />
<p>Each of these topics will be addressed by different individuals with an explicit orientation toward solutions and suggestions. If you have other suggestions, post them on the comments section of this article or send us an e-mail.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>