<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21263" Name="Grade Center Gotchas – tips to avoid a catastrophe" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Grade Center Gotchas – tips to avoid a catastrophe</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">"In this installment of the Simplifying I-Learn series I’ll provide 10 recommendations on how to avoid these Grade Center catastrophes.  These are small and common user errors that can cause big problems."</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090618T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Orren Squires</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img alt="Orren Squires" height="170" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/authorpics/SQUIRESO.JPG" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="120" /><strong><br /></strong><br /> <br /> It&rsquo;s a fact - ask 10 faculty and you&rsquo;ll get 15 Grade Center catastrophe  stories.&nbsp; We&rsquo;ve all heard them or even  worse, experienced them.&nbsp; These range  from &ldquo;All my grades were wrong and I had to fill out grade change cards&rdquo; to  &ldquo;What happened to my exam scores?&rdquo;&nbsp; <br /> <br /> Academic Technology, with the help of our brethren in  Information Technology, take these catastrophic stories very seriously and  spend a lot of time investigating the root cause.&nbsp; The bad news: &nbsp;most were caused by user error. &nbsp;The good news:&nbsp;  it means we can at least partially fix the problem by sharing the Gotchas.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> In this installment of the Simplifying I-Learn series I&rsquo;ll  provide 10 recommendations on how to avoid these Grade Center catastrophes.&nbsp; These are small and common user errors that  can cause big problems.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #1 - Selecting  &ldquo;Remove Column&rdquo; from the column drop down menu:</strong>&nbsp; A warning is given but many people click OK  without reading the warning.&nbsp; This Gotcha  is easy to do but results in a lost assignment or exam for all students.&nbsp; The only recovery possible is if the item was  already scored the day before this mistake.&nbsp;  Most instructors make this mistake when trying to remove duplicate  columns caused by a course copy &ndash; they simply remove the wrong one.<br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #2 &ndash; &ldquo;Clear  attempts for all users&rdquo;:</strong>&nbsp; Like Gotcha  #1, the column drop down menu item &ldquo;Clear attempts for all users&rdquo; does exactly  what it says.&nbsp; What makes this one  particularly catastrophic is that there is no warning &ndash; you click it and you  got it.&nbsp; (I almost find this humorous  given the number of times I have to click OK everywhere else.)&nbsp; When an exam has only one attempt, clearing  the last attempt means clearing the exam immediately.&nbsp; Like #1 the only recovery possible is if the  item was already scored the day before the mistake.<br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #3 &ndash; &ldquo;Hide  results for this test completely from instructor and Grade Center&rdquo;:</strong>&nbsp; This one has tagged several instructors  recently.&nbsp; This ugly little checkmark  option is found when creating an exam or modifying the test options.&nbsp; Unfortunately, many instructors miss the warning  found right underneath the option.&nbsp; The  key phrase in the warning is &ldquo;this choice can not be reversed later without  losing all attempts.&rdquo;&nbsp; No successful work-around  has been found and checking this option really does make it so the test is  completely hidden from the instructor and Grade Center. <br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #4 &ndash; More than  25 items in a category:</strong>&nbsp; The actual  number varies a little but a maximum of 25 items in a category is the safe  number.&nbsp; This means item 26 may or may  not be included in the total or weighted calculations.&nbsp; There are absolutely no warnings that this is  the case, so keep categories below 25 items to be safe.&nbsp; The 25-item limit also applies to  uncategorized items.&nbsp; Don&rsquo;t have more  than 25 uncategorized items in Grade Center or it will start ignoring the  extras.&nbsp; This tricky little Gotcha will  cause inaccurate grade totals if ignored.<br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #5 &ndash; Running  totals:</strong>&nbsp; By default this option is  &ldquo;Yes&rdquo; when creating a calculated column and for most of the semester this is  fine.&nbsp; Here is the Gotcha&hellip;if you don&rsquo;t  enter a zero for a missed item then Grade Center ignores that item when  calculating grades.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> Here&rsquo;s why &ndash; running totals only calculate the grade based  on what the student has attempted to submit.&nbsp;  When a student misses an assignment, Grade Center assumes the student  has not attempted to submit anything and therefore ignores that item in the  calculation.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> If you use total points for your grades this won&rsquo;t affect  you since your grade is based on total points earned.&nbsp; However, if you use weighted grades,  percentages, or letter grades in the totals column this Gotcha can bite  hard.&nbsp; It is quite common for a good  student to get the same grade as a student who barely turns anything in, due to  this hitch.<br /> <br /> The workaround is to either enter zeros for missed  assignments OR change the running totals option to &ldquo;No&rdquo; before submitting final  grades.&nbsp; Also, be sure this option is set  the same for all total columns you may have that calculate into the final  total. <br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #6 &ndash;  Categories and missing items:</strong> &nbsp;This  is probably the hardest to find and the easiest Gotcha trap to fall into.&nbsp; When creating a category in Grade Center, be  sure every item you want in the category is actually included.&nbsp; It is easy to forget to assign an item to a  category and have it really mess up the final totals.<br /> <br /> A typical example:&nbsp;  You create a quiz category and weight it so that quizzes are 40% of the  final grade.&nbsp; You give a total of 15  quizzes in the semester but forget to add quizzes 6 and 12 to the quiz  category.&nbsp; Since the category is weighted,  these two uncategorized quizzes are ignored. &nbsp;One way to find the error is to look at the  &ldquo;Column Information&rdquo; for each column item and be sure it is categorized the way  you intended.<br /> <br /> A variant of this Gotcha happens when an instructor has two  categories with the same name and places some items in each one.&nbsp; In the totals column only one category is  selected which means the items in the other category are ignored. <br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #7 - Equally Vs.  Proportionally weighted grades:</strong>&nbsp; A  good understanding of these two choices is critical for the instructor who  decides to weight grades.&nbsp; The default is  equally graded but many don&rsquo;t pay attention to what that really means.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> Equally weighted grades means that each item in the category  is worth the same regardless of the number of points assigned. &nbsp;&nbsp;This means if a student gets 100% on a  5-point attendance quiz and 80% on a 30-point chapter quiz, the final grade is  90%.<br /> <br /> Proportionally weighted grades means each item is weighted  according to its point value.&nbsp; Now that  30-point chapter quiz is worth 6 times as much as that 5-point attendance  quiz.&nbsp; The same student now gets a final  grade of 82.9%.<br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #8 &ndash; Adding an  average column:</strong>&nbsp; It&rsquo;s not hard to  accidently select the &ldquo;Average&rdquo; menu item when adding a calculated column.&nbsp; Unfortunately, the screen you get looks just  like the &ldquo;Totals&rdquo; menu item and unless you read carefully it is easy proceed  without realizing your mistake.&nbsp;  Unfortunately, this catches a few instructors unaware and throws the  resulting grades way off.&nbsp; The only way  to catch this Gotcha is to select &ldquo;Modify Column&rdquo; from the column dropdown menu  and look at the page title &ndash; everything else on the page looks exactly like a  totals or weighted column page.<br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #9 &ndash; Student  View vs. Instructor View:</strong>&nbsp; What you  see is not what the student sees.&nbsp;  Selecting the &ldquo;Hide&rdquo; option in the column dropdown menu does not hide it  from the students.&nbsp; Similarly, the &ldquo;Show&rdquo;  option under &ldquo;Organize Grade Center&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t show the scores to the  students.&nbsp; Many instructors hide columns  they are not using but don&rsquo;t realize the students can still see them.&nbsp; The only way to change what a student sees or  doesn&rsquo;t see is to select &ldquo;Modify Column&rdquo; in each of the column dropdown menus, and  then select the appropriate radio button.<br /> <br /> <strong>Gotcha #10 &ndash; &ldquo;Include  this column in Grade Center calculations:&rdquo;</strong>&nbsp;  It may sound pretty straight forward but when we copy courses from one  semester to the next it is a simple thing to miss.&nbsp; There have been several instructors who  decided to not give a particular assignment one semester and then used it the  next.&nbsp; Unfortunately they kept the item  in Grade Center and just turned this option off.&nbsp; The course is copied for the next semester  and its still off.&nbsp; Basically the student  did the work but didn&rsquo;t get the credit.&nbsp;  It&rsquo;s even better for the student who decided to not do the work but  wasn&rsquo;t penalized.<br /> <br /> I hope these top 10 Gotchas will help you avoid most of the  catastrophes you hear about.&nbsp; The  interface for Grade Center may not be great but for the short term education is  our only option.&nbsp; If you have questions  or don&rsquo;t understand anything in this article please feel free to call the  helpdesk at (208)496-9000.&nbsp;]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>