<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21259" Name="What is an Integrated Curriculum? Lessons from the Online Task Force" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">What is an Integrated Curriculum? Lessons from the Online Task Force</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">As we discussed this question, there was broad consensus that online faculty personalize and make these courses “come alive” in ways that accentuate their unique and individual talents.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090701T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ron Bennett and Clark Gilbert</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img alt="Ron Bennett" height="170" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/authorpics/BENNETTR.JPG" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="120" /> <img alt="Clark Gilbert" height="170" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/authorpics/GILBERTC.JPG" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="120" /> <strong><br /></strong><br /> <br /> Should online courses replicate  corresponding campus courses down to the most miniscule detail? &nbsp;Or should they have an identity of their own,  determined entirely by the instructors&rsquo; personal preferences, vision and  teaching styles? &nbsp;Or would the ideal mix  be something in between those two extremes?<br /> <br /> That is one of the questions  discussed recently by a special committee on online learning at BYU-Idaho. Over the past three months, we have been participants  in an Online Task Force comprised of Deans, Associate Deans, Department Chairs,  and other faculty from across campus to counsel on issues related to the <a href="../../LearningAndTeaching/post/2009/02/Seven-Misconceptions-Regarding-Online-Learning-At-Byu-Idaho.aspx">online  learning initiative</a>.&nbsp; Topics have  ranged from how to involve departments in the hiring of remote adjunct faculty,  to the training of those instructors, to the measurement of learning.&nbsp; Members of the task force have included:&nbsp; Robyn Bergstrom (Business and  Communications), Larry Thurgood (Education and Human Development), John Ivers  (Language and Letters), Alan Dutson (Mechanical Engineering), Jon Linford  (Music), Mark Bennion (English), Sid Palmer (Biology), Scott Galer (Foreign  Language), Craig Bell (Business), Ron Bennett  (Communication), Phil Allred (Religion), Peter Williams (Online), Matt  Sanders (Online), Alan Young (Curriculum Development), and Clark Gilbert  (Academic Office).<br /> <br /> As a result of the discussions  mentioned above, a key element of the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/onlineinitiative">BYU-Idaho Online Strategy</a> has become the creation of an Integrated Curriculum.&nbsp; The intent of this effort is that the online  courses should be tied directly to the campus courses.&nbsp; In other words, if a student takes a course  online, the curriculum should be integrated to the corresponding on-campus  course.&nbsp; But what does this mean?&nbsp; Or stated more formally:&nbsp; <strong>&ldquo;What is an  integrated curriculum?&rdquo;</strong>&nbsp; <br /> <br /> As we discussed this question,  there was broad consensus that online faculty personalize and make these  courses &ldquo;come alive&rdquo; in ways that accentuate their unique and individual talents.&nbsp; But there was also a strong feeling that if we are going to offer these courses online there should  also be real parameters around the curriculum itself.&nbsp; This integration  was to ensure quality and to tie online classes to campus offerings.&nbsp; And while this integration was seen as important  for the online courses, many of the task force members saw a similar need regarding Foundations courses on campus.&nbsp; As one faculty member asked:&nbsp; &ldquo;How can you have <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=22">teaching  groups</a>&nbsp; &nbsp;if your curriculum is entirely different  across sections?&rdquo;<br /> <br /> So, in a spirit of communication and shared learning, we  would like to share five key dimensions that the task force felt were critical  in creating an online curriculum that is integrated with campus:<br /> 
<ul>
<li><strong>Outcomes<span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">:&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></strong><strong><span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">Learning outcomes are common among every section online and the main campus  course.&nbsp; Part of the online course development process includes not only  the creation of the learning outcomes to match campus, but also the  approval from campus Department Chairs or Associate Deans (in the case of  Foundations).&nbsp; The outcomes can be  revised and a process is being developed to capture  feedback from the online teaching group leaders, but changes to the  online learning outcomes can only occur through the Team Leader and Course  Development Team or Department.</span></strong></li>
<img alt="Learning Outcomes" height="400" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/07-2009/integratedcurriculum-1.jpg" style="margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="533" />
<li><strong>Learning Model Architecture<span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">:&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></strong><strong><span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">Each online course is built around an explicit Learning Model  architecture with a corresponding learning cycle or rhythm.&nbsp; The</span></strong><em>campus</em> Course Development Team determines this architecture, which is built into the  course design in I-Learn and remains a fixture of the course.&nbsp; However, each of these  course designs varies across courses.&nbsp;  For example, the online American Foundations course uses 13 weekly  cycles with a set of Prepare, Teach One Another, and Ponder/Prove activities  for each week.&nbsp; The Family Foundations  course uses six two-week cycles where different activities occur across each  lesson.&nbsp; The intent for online is that  while specific learning activities and instructor styles may vary, the core  architecture will remain common across each online section within a given  course.</li>
<li><strong>Content:&nbsp; </strong>The ideas from this  discussion pointed to a blend of fixed and elective content, determined again  by the campus Team Lead and Course Development Team.&nbsp; In other words,  whether content is fixed, elective, or some blend of  the two should be determined in the course design.&nbsp; Of course if other  suggestions come from the teaching of the course, those should be captured and  suggested just as they are on campus.&nbsp; But the general consensus  from the task force was the creation of a &ldquo;bounded choice&rdquo; model, whose  stewardship would continue to reside with the team leader on campus.&nbsp;  Scott Galer mentioned examples for this even on-campus where the Foreign  Language Department requires campus adjunct to use certain texts in language  instruction.&nbsp; Sid Palmer gave similar examples from Biology materials and  the need at a program level to be consistent, given content and course design  across different programs.&nbsp; Three general patterns were suggested, to be  determined by the campus curriculum development team in the design of the  course:&nbsp;  	
<ul>
<li><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Fixed Settings</span></em> It was  suggested that in some courses the content would be  largely fixed, particularly in technical areas where the content is either  linked directly to the outcomes or where it is cumulative across courses within  a program.&nbsp; Examples that were listed included Biology, Nursing, Engineering,  Foreign Language and other courses where even some of the field tests  are tied to specific content.&nbsp; We also discussed the benefit of faculty  (and students) accessing and discussing common content.&nbsp; Examples  discussed in the task force included Family Foundations where every student  discusses the &ldquo;Tyson Cases&rdquo; (focused on different family dilemmas) or in  Organizational Behavior where every student discusses the Robert Parsons Case  (how to manage a high achiever who does not fit with the organization&rsquo;s culture).</li>
<li><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Bounded Choice</span></em> The group also  felt it would to important to provide an &ldquo;options&rdquo; list where the content could  be flexible.&nbsp; For example, instructors could choose from a list of content  options, such as:&nbsp; &ldquo;Have students read and  discuss an example of Social Satire literature.&nbsp; We recommend Aldous  Huxley&rsquo;s <em>Brave New World</em> or George Orwell&rsquo;s <em>1984<span style="display: inline;">. Discussion questions and learning activities for both are listed  below.&rdquo;&nbsp; In this example, the curriculum provides bounded choice with  supporting learning activities in the course design itself.&nbsp;</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Open  Options</span></em>In other cases open options could be  offered, either because the course content needs to be constantly evolving  (current affairs, specific technologies, etc.) or because variance on the  content can happen within the stated learning outcomes for the course.&nbsp; It  was suggested that the course template always include a suggested piece of  content or an option set (there is always a recommended option), but  that one of the options to the instructors could include:&nbsp; &ldquo;Choose Content  A OR look for additional outside reading on this subject and build a learning  activity around it that follows the similar pattern above.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Teaching Plans:&nbsp; </strong>The ideas regarding  teaching plans were similar in principle to &ldquo;Content&rdquo;  but even more dynamic.&nbsp; The way an online  instructor engages the content becomes an area with the highest level of  personal and professional adaptation.&nbsp; There was a suggestion that each  course be built with a &ldquo;master&rdquo; teaching plan, but that faculty members should be able to adapt their own teaching plan in  ways that work for them and learn organically from what others are doing.&nbsp;  We discussed two dimensions of this concept:&nbsp;  	
<ul>
<li><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Learning  Activities<span style="display: inline;">:</span></span><span style="display: inline;">Are the  learning activities fixed? &nbsp;For example, can the online instructor choose  to do a blog instead of a discussion board?&nbsp; Can he or she choose  to do a problem-based activity vs. a group project?&nbsp;  The feeling of the group was that Learning Strategies should look similar to  content, but have even more choice and flexibility.&nbsp; It was assumed that  there would be some activities that were&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">fixed&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">into the course design, but both&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">bounded&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">and&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">open&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">options  would provide many more choices.</span></em></li>
<img alt="Learning Activities" height="400" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/07-2009/integratedcurriculum-2.jpg" style="margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="533" />
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Specific  Engagement Strategies<span style="display: inline;">:</span></span><span style="display: inline;">This might include the questions an online instructor  uses to open a discussion or different strategies to engage a specific learning  activity.&nbsp; For example, can the online instructor change the opening  question in a discussion board in American Foundations from:&nbsp; &ldquo;What drove  the split between Hamilton and Madison after they wrote&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">The Federalist  Papers<span style="display: inline;">?&rdquo; to &ldquo;How did being from Virginia vs. New York impact the  philosophical tension between Madison and Hamilton?&rdquo;&nbsp; On this topic, the  task force was comfortable with a broader degree of flexibility as long as the  strategy supported the lesson&rsquo;s learning outcomes.</span></em></span></span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Assessments<span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">:&nbsp;</span></strong><strong><span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">The task force felt  these should be fixed for each course and determined again by the campus Team  Leader and the Course Development Team.&nbsp; Some design flexibility should be  built in to accommodate content choices employed by  the online instructor.&nbsp; However, that decision still rests with the campus  development team as to where and how that happens.</span></strong></li>
</ul>
We will continue to  learn as we progress.&nbsp; What became clear  from the discussions was that a lot depended on where you stood.&nbsp; When campus faculty considered their own  teaching, they felt strongly that curriculum  should be quite open.&nbsp; When they  considered online courses, they were much more  concerned about consistency and integration with campus.&nbsp; We believe we are moving toward something  that balances both concerns and will help us provide a high quality online  learning experience that is tied to campus.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>