<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x21450" Name="Prerequisite Planning" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Prerequisite Planning</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Describes how best to plan for health professions schools prerequisites</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4><strong>Academic Requirements</strong></h4>
<p><strong>BYU-Idaho Degree Requirements </strong><br />The majority of health professions students enter health professions school with a bachelor's degree. For information about BYU-Idaho degree requirements please visit the Academic Discovery Center website.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing a Major</strong><br />Students are admitted each year from a wide variety of majors and minors. The majority of students applying to health professions schools each year choose to major in one of the sciences (biology, exercise physiology, chemistry, health science, etc.). However, students have been accepted into health professions school with degrees such as English, music, psychology, sociology, and business. When choosing a major, please keep in mind BYU-Idaho's 120 credit policy. Choose a major that allows you to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Prepare for a career in your chosen health profession</li>
<li>Enjoy an alternative career if you decide not to pursue a health related career</li>
<li>Complete the majority of your prerequisite classes as an undergraduate student</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Choosing a Minor/Clusters</strong><br />The following are recommended for students interested in applying to health professions schools:</p>
<ul>
<li>Chemistry Minor - allows you to fulfill all the chemistry prerequisites for health professions schools</li>
<li>Two Health Professions Clusters - allows students to fulfill the majority of prerequisite courses</li>
<li>Other Minors/Clusters - allows you to diversify your degree and pursue additional interests</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Prerequisite Course Requirements</strong><br />Health profession schools do not require a specific major, but they do require specific prerequisite classes. Prerequisite courses range from 40-50 credits. Prerequisite courses may be part of your major and minor degree requirements. For example, schools require students to take two classes of biology. If you choose biology as your major, those two classes of biology will fulfill both the requirements for your degree and prerequisite classes.</p>
<p><strong>Graduation Plan</strong><br />Use the "Grad Plan Tool" online to create a graduation plan. Remember to include both degree requirements and prerequisite requirements. Prerequisite requirements that will not fit within the 120 credit requirement may need to be taken after graduation. Use the "Prerequisite Sequencing" sheet to guide you in planning your prerequisite classes. Use the catalog and "Major Course Sequencing Sheets" found on the Academic Discovery Center     website to plan major requirements.</p>
<p><strong>Post-Baccalaureate Program</strong><br />The Post-Baccalaureate Program (Post Bac) is designed for students who need to finish prerequisite classes for graduate or health professions school. The application is located in the Ag and Life Science Academic Discovery Center. The post-baccalaureate guiding principles include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Students should complete coursework in 1-2 semesters</li>
<li>Students are required to enroll the immediate semester after graduation</li>
<li>Courses taken must be a required prerequisite course for graduate school</li>
<li>Students may take up to 21 credits per semester</li>
<li>Students may not retake undergraduate courses or Post Bac courses</li>
<li>Financial aid may be limited</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Non-Academic Requirements<br /></strong></h4>
<p>In addition to academic requirements, health professions schools also require or strongly advise students to have experience in non-academic areas. These non-academic admission factors allow applicants to demonstrate leadership, integrity, compassion, and other essential traits for a career in health professions. Admissions committees look at these non-academic factors when reviewing applications:</p>
<ul>
<li>Letters of evaluation</li>
<li>Personal statement</li>
<li>Shadowing</li>
<li>Community service and extracurricular activities </li>
<li>Leadership opportunities</li>
<li>Research</li>
<li>Patient exposure</li>
</ul>
<p>Don't wait until it is time to apply to start these requirements. Get involved now in organizations and activities that fulfill these requirements. If you start getting involved in extracurricular activities right before you apply, the admissions committee will look at you as a "minimum doer."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x20965" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
