<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x21599" Name="Re-Applicants" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Re-Applicants</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Unfortunately for a number of students each year, their hopes of getting into health professions school are not realized.  A variety of resources exist for</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong>"Each year more qualified individuals apply to our school than we can accommodate.  This results in a large number of applicants who will reapply to medical school.  We recommend that applicants planning to reapply meet with their premedical advisor for recommendations on how to make their medical school application stronger.  We recommend that applicants review the admissions requirements and make significant changes in more than one area.  The application must be updated, including the personal statement, prior to reapplying." <br />- University of Utah Medical School</p>
<h4><strong>Should I Reapply?</strong></h4>
<p><strong></strong>If you are not accepted into a professional school, ask yourself the following questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do I really want to become a doctor, dentist, optometrist, etc.?</li>
<li>Are my grades and entrance exam score competitive for acceptance?</li>
<li>What do I need to do to improve my application?</li>
</ul>
<p>Take the time to reevaluate your career goals.  It is important to call the admission offices of the schools you applied to and ask them why you were not accepted.  They will be honest and forthright in giving you feedback on what you can do to make your application stronger.</p>
<h4><strong>Academic Deficiencies</strong></h4>
<p><strong></strong>For re-applicants with academic deficiencies, options are available.  Post-Baccalaureate (different from BYU-Idaho's "Post Bac Program") programs are designed as one year programs that offer pre-health profession science classes.  Many admissions committees look favorably on students who pursue this route to improve GPA.  A search of the AMCAS website will provide a list of the Post-Bac programs available.</p>
<p>Applicants who scored low on the entrance exam should reevaluate and decide if they can do better.  Assess how much time and effort was spent studying.  If you feel you can do better, make a study plan and stick to it.  Take more practice tests if needed.</p>
<h4><strong>Non-Academic Deficiencies</strong></h4>
<p><strong></strong>Ask admission committees if there were any non-academic areas of your application which prevented you from being admitted.  Many students are not accepted each year because of a deficiency in a non-academic area.  If your personal statement was weak, set up an appointment with a BYU-Idaho career mentor for a personal statement review.  If your interview did not go well, sign up with a BYU-Idaho career mentor for a mock interview.</p>
<p>You should use the year between application cycles to make your application stronger.  Many applicants spend the year finishing up their bachelor's degrees, shadowing, volunteering in health clinics, working, pursuing a one year master's degree, or doing research with a professor or private company.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19078" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x20965" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
