<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21657" Name="Simplifying I-Learn: What is Grade Center good for?" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Simplifying I-Learn: What is Grade Center good for?</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">If you decide you want to be adventurous and use more of the features of Grade Center be on the lookout for the article “Grade Center Gotchas: tips to avoid catastrophes,” the next in the Simplifying I-Learn series.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090311T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Orren Squires</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Orren Squires" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/SquiresO.JPG" style="margin: 25px;" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is unfortunate that we have to ask that question because  the I-Learn Grade Center  really is packed with great features.&nbsp;  But as 53% of you told us in the recent survey, it is very frustrating  to use those features.</p>
<p>While I only teach about 100 students and don&rsquo;t approach the  number of students a typical faculty member has each semester, I can honestly  say that I&rsquo;m one of those 53%.&nbsp; So what  is Grade Center really good for?&nbsp; Here are 3 things to simplify Grade Center  and make it work for you:</p>
<ol style="margin-left: 15px;">
<li>Grade reporting instead of grade calculating:&nbsp;Research shows that the feature students like best in I-Learn is the  ability to log in at any time and see their current standing.&nbsp; However, many teachers are nervous about how Grade Center  is actually calculating their grades.&nbsp; If  you are one of those, use an Excel spreadsheet to do the calculations and  simply use the I-Learn   Grade Center  to report grades to students.&nbsp; It  requires that extra step but you&rsquo;ll likely sleep better at night.</li>
<li>Simplify your grading structure:&nbsp;On a weekly basis I get teachers who call asking how to get Grade Center to match their  grading structures.&nbsp;&nbsp; I think my favorite  so far is, &ldquo;How do I triple weight my grades?&rdquo;&nbsp;  While possible, it is quite complex and there are so many places to make  a mistake that I convinced the teacher it would be better to simplify how he  graded this particular set of assignments.&nbsp;  Students really do appreciate a simple grading structure that is easy to  calculate.&nbsp; If you find it a struggle to  get Grade Center to calculate grades the way you  want, chances are your students are having a hard time understanding the  explanation in your syllabus.&nbsp; Ask your  students to explain your grading structure to you and you may get a surprise!</li>
<li>Use it to organize assignment submissions: &nbsp;One really nice feature of Grade Center is the  fact that when a student submits an assignment, it is organized and available  for grading.&nbsp; No more papers to file in a  folder in the desk.&nbsp; Using Grade Center  to organize assignments and keep your desk clutter free can be a wonderful  thing.&nbsp; </li>
<li>Use Grade Center to do automatic grading: &nbsp;We all like to find things that  save us time and this can be a big one.&nbsp;  If you are giving simple tests and quizzes that require multiple choice,  true/false, or other simple questions, you can use grade center to  automatically grade those tests and quizzes.&nbsp;  Keep in mind though that essay, short answer, and other types of  questions that require the student to type an answer will require a teacher to  grade.</li>
<img alt="Automatic grading" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/03-2009/test.jpg" />
<li>Student management: Another nice feature of Grade Center  is the fact that it automatically enrolls and removes students who add and drop  classes without any teacher intervention.&nbsp; </li>
</ol>
<p>If you decide you want to be  adventurous and use more of the features of Grade Center be on the lookout for  the article &ldquo;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Grade Center Gotchas:&nbsp; tips to avoid catastrophes,<span style="display: inline;">&rdquo; the next in  the Simplifying I-Learn series.</span></em></span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>