<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21764" Name="Simplifying I-Learn: I-Learn Gotchas" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Simplifying I-Learn: I-Learn Gotchas</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">This article builds on our previous article entitled “What is I-learn good for?”  If you haven’t already read that one, please do.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090212T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mike Whitesides and Arlen Wilcock</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Arlen Wilcock" height="170" hspace="8" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/wilcocka.jpg" width="120" /> <img align="left" alt="Mike Whitesides" height="170" hspace="8" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/whitesidesM.jpg" width="120" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>How To Avoid Common Mistakes While Using I-Learn.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This article builds on our previous article entitled &ldquo;What is I-learn good for?&rdquo;&nbsp; If you haven&rsquo;t already read that one, please do.&nbsp; The Top Five list is a good place to start and includes features that should save you time and make your life easier.&nbsp; When you feel comfortable with those, then you can move ahead to more advanced features.&nbsp; Any Learning Management System has its challenges, so here are some suggestions that can help faculty achieve their learning objectives and avoid some headaches.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I-Learn Gotchas fall into three main categories:&nbsp; 1) Grade Center Gotchas, 2) Assessment Gotchas, and 3) General Gotchas.&nbsp; Since the next two articles in this series deal with Grade Center, this article focuses on General Gotchas and Assessment Gotchas.</p>
<p><br /> <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">General Gotchas</span></strong></p>
<p><br /> <strong>Gotcha #1 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t wait until the first week of the semester to copy your courses:</strong>&nbsp; Perhaps you&rsquo;ve noticed that I-Learn is sluggish during the few days before and after the first day of a new semester.&nbsp; That&rsquo;s because one of the most intensive operations for I-Learn to perform is copying course content. So a good approach is to request new courses well ahead of the next semester.&nbsp; Then wait until just after the semester ends to copy from an old course into a new.&nbsp; This lets I-Learn do its copying during a time when fewer users are trying to access it.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #2 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t bite off more than you can chew:</strong>&nbsp; Or as King Benjamin advises, don&rsquo;t run faster than you have strength. Start with the basic features and then move on to the advanced features if they support your learning outcomes. &nbsp;With these more advanced features, comes a recommendation for training. &nbsp;There are five great sources of help:</p>
<ul>
<li>Help Desk (3550) </li>
<li>The Faculty Technology Center (MCK 355)</li>
<li>Satellite I-Learn help centers (Smith 208, Spori 226, and Hinckley 309) </li>
<li>Scheduled training <a href="http://www.byui.edu/at/ilearn_schedule.htm">workshops</a></li>
<li>I-Learn <a href="http://www.byui.edu/onlinelearning/tutorials/ilearn/facultytuts.htm">online tutorials</a></li>
</ul>
<img alt="Help for faculty" height="226" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/02-2009/Gretchen_and_Chris.jpg" vspace="8" width="273" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #3 &ndash; </strong><strong>Give your courses descriptive names:</strong>&nbsp; When you request a new course, you are asked to give it a Course Name.&nbsp; Rather than using something general &ndash; like&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">REL 324</em></span>, or&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Doctrine &amp; Covenants&nbsp;</em></span>&ndash; use something more descriptive like&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">W09 D&amp;C REL 324 Sec3 KIV</em></span>. &nbsp;This enables you and others to quickly locate the right course.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #4&ndash; Don&rsquo;t use Adaptive Release for tests and assignments:&nbsp; </strong>There are too many ways to mess this up.&nbsp; There are other ways to allow a student to take a test early or late.&nbsp; If you need to use this feature, ask for training first.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #5 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t use I-Learn just because . . . :</strong> &nbsp;The use of any educational tool should make sense instructionally; otherwise, it&rsquo;s just using technology for technology&rsquo;s sake.&nbsp; Hopefully, using I-Learn will benefit you in at least the following ways: help you reach your instructional outcomes, save you time and effort, and help your students learn and teach more efficiently.&nbsp; If it isn&rsquo;t doing that, then it may not be worth using.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Assessment Gotchas</span></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #6 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t select &ldquo;Open test in new window&rdquo;:&nbsp; </strong>Most students have pop-up blockers and won&rsquo;t be able to see the exam.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #7 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t select &ldquo;Hide results for this test completely from instructor and Grade Center&rdquo;:</strong> <img alt="Gotcha #7" border="2" height="184" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/02-2009/Gotcha_7.jpg" vspace="8" width="500" /></p>
<p>This regrettable little checkmark option is found when creating an exam or modifying the test options.&nbsp; Unfortunately, many instructors miss the warning found right underneath the option.&nbsp; The key phrase in the warning is &ldquo;this choice can not be reversed later without losing all attempts.&rdquo;&nbsp; No successful workaround has been found and checking this option really does make it so the test responses are completely hidden from the instructor and Grade Center.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #8 &ndash; Create test questions using the Pool Manager instead of the Test Manager:&nbsp; </strong>If you suspect that you may use all or even part of a test again, create your questions in the Pool Manager.&nbsp; Then use Test Manager to create your test from the Pool Manager.&nbsp; This will allow you to re-use questions on a future test.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #9 &ndash; Double-check your options before submitting a test:&nbsp; </strong>Make sure the test is available to students and that the availability dates are correct.&nbsp; Generally, don&rsquo;t use forced completion.&nbsp; Don&rsquo;t uncheck &ldquo;Include this test in Grade Center score calculations&rdquo; &ndash; the message under the checkbox is self-explanatory.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Gotcha #10 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t modify a test after it has started:</strong>&nbsp; This isn&rsquo;t fair to students, who get different versions of the test.&nbsp; If you open a test and then notice that something in it needs to be changed, like a typo, you can change it.&nbsp; But you would want to be sure that your change wouldn&rsquo;t give subsequent test-takers an advantage over those who took it early.&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">Here are two more important Gotchas that aren&rsquo;t specific to I-learn, but are directly related:</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Bonus Gotcha #1 &ndash; Don&rsquo;t give your login info to a TA or secretary:&nbsp; </strong>Some faculty have given their NetIDs and passwords to student TAs or secretaries so they could enter grades or do I-Learn modifications for them.&nbsp; There&rsquo;s an easier and more secure way to give them access without compromising your credentials.&nbsp; To learn how, call the Help Desk or watch the short online tutorial.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Bonus Gotcha #2 &ndash; Instruct students to call the Help Desk while the problem is occurring:&nbsp; </strong>If students aren&rsquo;t able to do something in I-Learn (like access a course or submit an assignment), they should call the Help Desk (3550) <em>while the problem is actually happening&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">instead of just emailing the instructor and explaining what happened.&nbsp; To diagnose the problem, it&rsquo;s very helpful if the Help Desk agent can ask questions (Are you on campus or off?&nbsp; Are you on a Mac or Windows computer? Are you using Internet Explorer of Firefox?).&nbsp;</span></em> Thanks for reading this article.&nbsp; We hope you&rsquo;ll read the upcoming ones on <em>Simplifying Grade Center&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">and&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Grade Center Gotchas<span style="display: inline;">.&nbsp; If you need additional help, don&rsquo;t hesitate to call the Help Desk at 3550.</span></em></span></span></em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>