<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21765" Name="Faculty Voices: Jolene Smith" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty Voices: Jolene Smith</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Brother of Jared’s world changed as light led to vision.  He comprehended more than he ever knew was possible.  It was a new world; one which the Brother of Jared had never seen before or even knew existed.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090212T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Jolene Smith, Department of Home and Family</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Jolene Smith" height="170" hspace="8" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/Smithjg.jpg" width="120" /><strong><br /></strong>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Last year while reading in the Book of Mormon, I came to understand that the Lord used Learning Model principles to teach the Brother of Jared.&nbsp;&nbsp; The more I readand study, the more I become convinced that the Lord teaches all His children using the principles promoted in the Learning Model.&nbsp; We can learn much from the dialogue the Brother of Jared had with the Lord about how we ought to teach the students placed in our care.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Different Questions Call for Different Answers</strong></p>
<p>The Brother of Jared was given an assignment from his &ldquo;Teacher&rdquo; to build some barges.&nbsp;&nbsp; Along with this assignment the Lord gave the directions needed to build the barges and reasons for building them.&nbsp; Put simply, the Lord told the Brother of Jared to &ldquo;Go to work and build&rdquo; (Ether 2:16).&nbsp;&nbsp; During the process of constructing the barges, three serious questions arose.&nbsp; How will we breathe? &nbsp;How will we steer? &nbsp;Must we journey in darkness?&nbsp; Seeking solutions, the Brother of Jared inquired of the Lord, and the Lord answered.&nbsp; But He responded differently to each question.&nbsp; Likewise, we must respond differently to different types of questions asked by our students.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br /> <br /> <strong>Responding to Air Questions</strong></p>
<p>The Brother of Jared&rsquo;s first question was a simple question about air.&nbsp; Consistent with the level of the question, the Lord responded with a simple solution&mdash;cut holes in the top and the bottom.&nbsp; But why did the Lord respond with such a direct answer?&nbsp; I believe that it was because He knew that the Brother of Jared would not be able to find an appropriate solution alone.&nbsp; Air is a necessity, a matter of survival.&nbsp; Without air we perish.&nbsp; &nbsp;Just like the solution to the air problem, solutions to many student questions can be provided through direct and simple answers.&nbsp; Such answers are appropriate when a student asks a vital question that he/she doesn&rsquo;t have the knowledge or experience to answer alone.&nbsp; To survive, that student needs a direct, simple answer.&nbsp; We can&rsquo;t let him/her perish for lack of air!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Responding to Steering Questions</strong></p>
<p>Next, the Brother of Jared inquired as to how to steer the barges.&nbsp; Steering questions are about direction.&nbsp; How will we navigate our barges without crashing or getting lost?&nbsp; Winds, like new information, principles, or instructions, seem to blow from all directions at once. &nbsp;Students need to feel safe.&nbsp; The Brother of Jared needed to believe that the winds, the rains and the floods had been &ldquo;sent forth&rdquo; by the Lord (see Ether 2:24-25) before he could summon the courage to sail into unknown waters.&nbsp; Likewise, we need to provide students with safe environments where they can contribute, participate in discussions, and try out new ideas.&nbsp; Without proper steering, our students will be &ldquo;swallowed up in the depths of the sea&rdquo; (Ether 2:25).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Responding to Light Questions</strong></p>
<p>The last question that the Brother of Jared asked concerned light.&nbsp; He asked the Lord, must we cross the great waters in darkness?&nbsp; It seems like a reasonable question, but this time the Lord didn&rsquo;t provide an answer.&nbsp; Instead, he answered the question with a question.&nbsp; &ldquo;What will ye that I should prepare for you that ye may have light when ye are swallowed up in the depths of the sea?&rdquo;&nbsp; (Ether 2:25) &nbsp;This response wasn&rsquo;t like the plain and direct answers that followed the steering and air inquiries.&nbsp; The Lord essentially said to the Brother of Jared, &ldquo;You have a problem.&nbsp; What are you going to do about it?&rdquo; (see Ether 2:25).&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In response to this challenge, the Brother of Jared acted for himself.&nbsp; He came up with a plan, climbed a mountain, and then melted, shaped, and polished sixteen small stones.&nbsp; After doing all he could do to solve the problem, the Brother of Jared went to the Lord and said something like this: &ldquo;Now don&rsquo;t be angry with me, but I know you have the ability to touch these stones and make them glow.&nbsp; Please touch them.&rdquo;&nbsp; By presenting those little stones to the Lord, the Brother of Jared exercised his faith to bring to pass &ldquo;much righteousness&rdquo; (D&amp;C 58:27).&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We as teachers must learn to recognize Light questions.&nbsp; Light questions are opportunities for students to take responsibility for their learning.&nbsp; Light comes after a student makes the effort to apply what he has learned.&nbsp; Students are blessed to receive revelation in response to their Light questions but they need to propose their own solutions first.&nbsp; I sometimes tell my students, &ldquo;That is a Light question. &nbsp;What are you going to do about it?&rdquo;&nbsp; As they struggle to find meaningful solutions to their questions, their vision becomes clearer.&nbsp; They have to stretch to apply new knowledge and in the process they learn how to govern themselves.&nbsp; It is in this struggle that they find answers to Light questions.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>A New World</strong></p>
<p>The Brother of Jared&rsquo;s world changed as light led to vision.&nbsp; He comprehended more than he ever knew was possible.&nbsp; It was a new world; one which the Brother of Jared had never seen before or even knew existed.&nbsp;&nbsp; We all walk in darkness until we develop enough faith to walk in the light.&nbsp; Our students must learn that lesson.&nbsp; It is in the struggle to polish the stones that we develop the faith that allows the Lord to touch our small offering.&nbsp; We must remember that there is a great difference between air, steering and light questions.&nbsp; There should be great differences in our answers.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Related Tools</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=26">Teaching Your Class about the Learning Model</a></p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=37">Developing Inspired Questions</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>