<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x21778" Name="Learning From Peers" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Learning From Peers</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">We all have a sacred responsibility to learn some basic principles of teaching.  There are many principles of teaching and learning, and it is not enough for us just to read about them.  First, we need to understand these basic principles, and second, we need to be shown how they are used by successful teachers.  This can be done by carefully watching able teachers …</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20081204T19:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Devan Barker</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><strong><span style="font-weight: normal;"><strong><br /></strong></span></strong> <br /> </span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">One of the most striking characteristics of the professions is that they are, to a large degree, self-monitoring and self-regulating.&nbsp;Doctors regularly draw on each other&rsquo;s expertise as they call in consultations or give referrals.&nbsp;Their professional development opportunities are organized and defined by their colleagues in the field, not by hospital administrators.&nbsp;Lawyers also look to their colleagues for ongoing professional growth opportunities.&nbsp;Most of us as professionals look to others in our discipline through conferences or peer-reviewed literature to help us stay current in the field. </span></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">When we ask, then, where we as professional educators should look for insight and growth opportunities in our instructional skills, the answer seems obvious.&nbsp;We look to one another.&nbsp;Over the past year, more and more faculty members at BYU-Idaho have discovered the power of observing other professional educators in action as a means of informing and refining their own instruction.<span> </span></span></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">Last January, members of the faculty association visited each other&rsquo;s classrooms.&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 14px; display: inline;"><span style="font-size: small;">An article written by David Peck&nbsp;</span></span><span style="display: inline;">on the Learning and Teaching website described the experiences of some of these colleagues.&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;">Jolene Smith, from the Department of Home and Family also participated in this exchange.&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;">About her experience, she commented:</span></span></span></p>
<blockquote dir="ltr" style="margin-right: 0px;">
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">The past couple of years have brought a whole new vision for me personally and in the classroom in regards to teaching.&nbsp;If you want to improve, watch someone else and have them watch you.&nbsp;Talk, share and think about the direction of the learning and how it can be better.&nbsp;Ponder, reflect, make suggestions, try new ideas that another teacher has mastered.</span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;"><em>Each of us has been given gifts and talents to use with our own personalities.&nbsp;Let me experience yours!&nbsp;Then come and share with me, mine.&nbsp;D&amp;C 46:12 &ldquo;to some is given one, and to some is given another, that all may be profited thereby.&rdquo;</em> </span></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">Soon thereafter, the math department began inviting instructors to visit each other&rsquo;s classrooms within the department.&nbsp;What started as occasional visits by a few interested instructors has now become a regular occurrence throughout the entire department.&nbsp;Other departments, such as foreign language have begun experimenting with dropping in to observe and learn from each other. Lei Shen, an instructor in Mandarin Chinese said the following about her experience observing her colleagues&rsquo; classes: </span></span></p>
<blockquote dir="ltr" style="margin-right: 0px;">
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">First of all, I believe classroom observation is an effective and "quick" way to improve myself and be a good teacher. The "Open Door Program" has broadened my view in terms of pedagogical approaches and classroom management. I have become more sensitive to things that might seem trivial, but which can distract students or even ruin their interest.</span></em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">All of the teams of instructors teaching Foundations courses have begun meeting together regularly to coordinate their efforts, and some of these teams have included classroom visits as part of that coordination.&nbsp;Several of the faculty discussion groups called &lsquo;learning communities&rsquo; have also chosen to visit each other&rsquo;s classes as part of their discussion and research around specific Learning Model topics and issues.&nbsp;One of these groups, led by Lynda Hawkes, was asked to share their experiences in writing: good, bad or otherwise.&nbsp;Below are the comments that they sent:</span></span></p>
<blockquote dir="ltr" style="margin-right: 0px;">
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">I've very much enjoyed learning from my peers through my classroom observations.&nbsp;It has struck me powerfully what a wonderful resource we as faculty have in each other!&nbsp;I've seen firsthand that the gifts and talents each of us is blessed with truly are diverse and are meant to be shared for the benefit of all. (This applies to students as well.)</span></em></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<div style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">From observing my friends in biology, Jason Hunt and Jason Shaw, I've learned not only interesting lessons about blood, the heart and the circulatory system (things I'd forgotten if I ever knew them), but also how to ask better questions to steer the discussion.</span></em></span></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">From observing my friend Henry J. Eyring, a master discussion leader, I was reminded of the usefulness of analogy and the importance of being able to articulate the fitness of a given analogy.</span></em></span></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"></span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">From serving on the CFS committee of my friend and departmental colleague James Helfrich, I've seen the difference it makes in observational acuity when the objective is to provide feedback on behaviors, good and bad.</span></em></span></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"></span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">I love the low-key, no-pressure approach our group has taken, to observe minus the onus of giving feedback, to just share the good things we've learned.</span></em></span></div>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><em><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">-- Rick Nef--</span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">Computer Science and Engineering</span></span></em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote dir="ltr" style="margin-right: 0px;">
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"></span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">Taking the opportunity to observe and be observed by my peers has been a great professional blessing.&nbsp;At times I wonder if I am the only one dealing with some of the issues I find difficult in the classroom.&nbsp;It is such a blessing to me to see others deal with the same issues and learn from them how to properly handle such things, in the spirit of love and service.&nbsp;I realize that I do not always hold all of my students accountable during small group discussions.&nbsp;I felt that I let some students "off the hook", and I didn't like seeing that happen in my classroom.&nbsp;While watching one of my peers teach, I observed how she held all of her students accountable while they worked in small groups.&nbsp;All were assigned a specific job to complete during the time assigned.&nbsp;As I watched the students working, I wondered how she would hold them accountable for their jobs.&nbsp;I watched as each student in the class taught another student what they had learned during their small group discussion.&nbsp;Students were paired up with students that did not have the same assigned job, so that each came to the paired discussion with different information.&nbsp;It was a chance for these students to report their learning, and gave the other student the opportunity to ask questions.&nbsp;I tried this very strategy the next week in one of my classes, and found great success.&nbsp;I was glad I was able to "see" it first instead of just hearing or reading about it.&nbsp;I observe others so that I can become better.&nbsp;Teaching by example is the best teacher.</span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><em><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">--Lynda Hawkes--</span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">Teacher Education</span></span></em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote dir="ltr" style="margin-right: 0px;">
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">Without question, making the effort to visit other people&rsquo;s classes has improved my own classes.&nbsp;I never visited a classroom with the intent to critique the teacher; I went with the selfish motive of seeing what I could learn.&nbsp;As I sat in different classrooms, I picked up on some ingenious methods of holding students accountable for their pre-class preparations and I discovered some new approaches to peer-to-peer learning that I could implement in my own classroom.</span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">Perhaps the greatest blessing of this experience, however, was being able to sit with the students and attempt to understand the subjects that were being presented.<span> </span>I enjoyed the variety of learning activities I observed in the classrooms that took me from my first exposure to a new idea to the point of comprehending and applying it.&nbsp;From this, I realized that I don&rsquo;t fully appreciate the process my students must go through in order to learn what I want them to learn&mdash;and that I could be a much more effective teacher with a little practice.</span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">I feel blessed to teach on this campus and, until recently, didn&rsquo;t realize how many great teachers surround me.<span> </span>It would be a shame if I never got to see what was happening in other classrooms just around the corner or even across campus; there is so much to learn!<span> </span></span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span></span><em><span style="font-size: small;">--Justin Mille--</span></em></span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><em><span style="font-size: small;">Automotive Technology</span></em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"></span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">William D. Oswald, in the last general conference, made the following observations:</span></span></p>
<blockquote dir="ltr" style="margin-right: 0px;">
<p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">&hellip; We all have a sacred responsibility to learn some basic principles of teaching.&nbsp; There are many principles of teaching and learning, and it is not enough for us just to read about them.&nbsp; First, we need to understand these basic principles, and second, we need to be shown how they are used by successful teachers.&nbsp; This can be done by carefully watching able teachers &hellip;</span></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 10pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"></span><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">From the looks of things, many instructors at BYU-Idaho are taking this counsel to heart.</span></span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>