<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 6.0.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<BlankDetailPage ID="x23187" Name="ROTC" Layout="default.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ROTC</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ROTC</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x14" Name="RelatedLinks" label="Related Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="RelatedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><a href="#1">What is ROTC?</a></p>
<p><a href="#2">Why should I consider majoring in ROTC?</a></p>
<p><a href="#3">What will I learn from studying ROTC?</a></p>
<p><a href="#4">What are interests and values are related to ROTC?</a></p>
<p><a href="#5">What career fields are related to ROTC?</a></p>
<p><a href="#6">How can I learn more about ROTC?</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="1"></a>What is ROTC?</h2>
<p>Army ROTC is an elective curriculum you take along with your required college classes. It gives you the tools, training and experiences that will help you succeed in any competitive environment. Along with great leadership training, Army ROTC can pay for your college tuition. Because Army ROTC is an elective, you can participate your freshman and sophomore years without any obligation to join the Army. You will have a normal college student experience like everyone else on campus, but when you graduate, you will be commissioned as an Officer in the Army. At that point, you will have a wide range of interest areas you can specialize in called branches.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="2"></a>Why should I consider majoring in ROTC?</h2>
<p>Army ROTC is one of the only college programs that teaches leadership. This training is invaluable for any career that involves leading, managing and motivating people or fostering teamwork. Young Army Officers are typically responsible for hundreds of Soldiers and millions of dollars in equipment; this kind of management experience can be very attractive for post-Army employers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="3"></a>What will I learn from studying ROTC?</h2>
<p>Army ROTC classes normally involve one elective class and one lab per semester. Although the classes involve hands-on fieldwork as well as classroom work, they are standard college classes that fit into a normal academic schedule. These courses can help students with personal and academic decision-making while giving them the tools to exercise leadership in college life, even before graduating and becoming Officers. For more details, see: Curriculum. Army ROTC will give you valuable real-world tools and leadership skills that will benefit not only your professional career but your personal life as well.</p>
<p>Army ROTC is an elective curriculum you take along with your required college classes. It prepares you with the tools, training and experiences that will help you succeed in any competitive environment. Along with great leadership training, Army ROTC can pay for your college tuition, too. You will have a normal college student experience like everyone else on campus, but when you graduate, you will be an Officer in the Army.</p>
<p>Being an Officer in the U.S. Army means you're a leader, a counselor, a strategist and a motivator. It's similar to being a vital manager in a corporation. As an Officer, you will lead other Soldiers in all situations and adjust in environments that are always changing. You'll be driven to achieve success with your team on every mission.</p>
<p>Army ROTC is a one-of-a-kind experience. The challenges you face and the obstacles you'll overcome will prepare you for future success.</p>
<p>Army ROTC is one of the nation's top leadership programs, with many benefits to joining.</p>
<p>Through Army ROTC you can:</p>
<p>Get help with your college tuition with an Army ROTC scholarship</p>
<p>Gain experience you can't find anywhere else</p>
<p>Gain the respect of your peers and future employers</p>
<p>Train to become a leader and manager</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="4"></a>What interests and values are related to ROTC?</h2>
<p>Those who succeed in the Army ROTC program are students who excel and want something more out of the college experience. Generally, these students are scholars who keep their grades up, athletes who are physically strong and leaders who have a great desire to learn.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="5"></a>What career fields are related to ROTC?</h2>
<p>Army ROTC is one of the only college programs that teaches leadership. This training is invaluable for any career that involves leading, managing and motivating people or fostering teamwork. Young Army Officers are typically responsible for hundreds of Soldiers and millions of dollars in equipment; this kind of management experience can be very attractive for post-Army employers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="6"></a>How can I learn more about ROTC?</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.goarmy.com/rotc/college_students.jsp" target="_blank">Army ROTC</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bls.gov/OCO/">Occupational Outlook Handbook</a></p>
<p><a href="x23114.xml">DISCOVER Career Guidance and Information System</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Contact Source:</h4>
<p>College of Business &amp; Communication</p>
<p>Location: Smith 296</p>
<p>Phone: 208-496-9825</p>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:businessadv@byui.edu">businessadv@byui.edu</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ImageComponent" Name="LeftColumnImageComponentList" label="Left Column Image Component List" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1798" Name="ImageComponent" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x946" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></BlankDetailPage>
