<?xml version="1.0"?>
<DetailPage ID="x23122" Name="Social Studies Education Composite" Layout="default.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" ID="1">Social Studies Education Composite</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" ID="2">Social Studies Education Composite</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" ID="3"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="4">Social Studies Education Composite</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="5">Social Studies Education Composite at BYU-Idaho</MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false" ID="6">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false" ID="7">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false" ID="8">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="9">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x14" Name="RelatedLinks" label="Related Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="RelatedLinksComponent" Expanded="false" ID="10"/><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="11"><![CDATA[<p><a href="#1">What is Social Studies Education?</a></p>
<p><a href="#2">Why should I consider majoring in Social Studies Education?</a></p>
<p><a href="#3">What will I learn from studying Social Studies Education?</a></p>
<p><a href="#4">What are interests and values are related to Social Studies Education?</a></p>
<p><a href="#5">What career fields are related to Social Studies Education?</a></p>
<p><a href="#6">How can I learn more about Social Studies Education?</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="1"></a>What is Social Studies Education?</h2>
<p>The teacher of social studies has a great responsibility. Your purpose is to educate and enlighten students and to offer instruction in the core disciplines of history, geography, economics, political science, and behavioral studies. This includes grade levels from K-12.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="2"></a>Why should I consider majoring in Social Studies Education?</h2>
<p>If you would like to teach history in a high school or junior high/middle school, you should pursue a major in social studies education. Social studies classes should be the locus of middle and high school student learning about American society and the world, past and present. It is in social studies that students are supposed to prepare for their role as citizens by studying history, economics, geography, and government. The opportunities for exciting learning in social studies seem unlimited, since students can grapple with the great issues of our world: war and peace; democracy versus autocracy; poverty; racial, class, and sexual inequality; prejudice; technological change; and corporate economic dominance. Our Program in Teaching Social Studies, Grades 7-12, is dedicated to producing a new generation of middle and high school teachers who are equipped to take students beyond the world of bland textbooks and multiple choice tests and to generate real student interest in history, the social sciences, and the challenges of active citizenship.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="3"></a>What will I learn from studying Social Studies Education?</h2>
<p>In this program, you will learn how to teach specific social science subjects and programs at various educational levels, including history, geography, and psychology. The program begins with courses specific to the subject matter. In upper level courses, the focus shifts to lesson planning, instructional techniques for communicating the subject matter, assessment and evaluation techniques, and supervision and discipline strategies. The final phase of the program is an on-site student teaching practicum. You will first observe an experienced teacher work with students at your selected educational level. You will work with the supervising teacher to plan your lessons, and then you will teach those lessons to the students. The supervising teacher provides ongoing advice, support, and evaluation of your performance at this time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="4"></a>What interests and values are related to Social Studies Education?</h2>
Have good health and physical stamina <br />Be able to work well with others <br />Have good organizational skills <br />Be motivated to help others succeed <br />Have excellent communication skills <br />Be a leader
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="5"></a>What career fields are related to Social Studies Education?</h2>
<p>Teacher at elementary, secondary, and higher education.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="6"></a>How can I learn more about Social Studies Education?</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bls.gov/OCO/">OCCUPATIONAL OUTLOOK HANDBOOK</a><br /><a href="x23114.xml">DISCOVER Career Guidance and Information System</a><br /><a href="http://www.socialstudies.org/">http://www.socialstudies.org/</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Contact Source:</h4>
<p>College of Education &amp; Human Development<br />Location: Hinkley 309<br />Phone: 208-496-9830</p>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:edadvising@byui.edu">edadvising@byui.edu</a></p>
<h4></h4>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ImageComponent" Name="LeftColumnImageComponentList" label="Left Column Image Component List" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="true" ID="12"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false" ID="13"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" ID="14"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x946" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false" ID="15"/></DetailPage>
