<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x24051" Name="Terms of Use" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Copyright and Use Information</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Terms of Use</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110802T06:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Copyright and Permissions</strong></p>
<p>All materials, including computer code, contained on this website are protected by United States and International copyright and other applicable laws. You may print material, other than computer code, from this website for personal or non-profit educational purposes only. All copies must include any copyright notice originally included with the material. All other uses, including the use of any computer code requires the prior written permission of BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p>For further information regarding the use of materials contained on this site, please contact the Intellectual Property Rights Specialist, by telephone (208) 496-7218 or e-mail wisen@byui.edu.</p>
<p><strong>About This Site</strong></p>
<p>Through this website, Brigham Young University Idaho (BYUI) offer broad public access to a wide range of information and resources.</p>
<p><strong>Conditions of Use</strong></p>
<p>We reserve the right to change these conditions at any time, without advance notice. Your use of the site indicates acceptance of any changes.</p>
<p><strong>About Trademarks</strong></p>
<p>Many of the trademarks, service marks, and logos (collectively, the "Marks") displayed on this website, including "BYU-IDAHO" are registered and/or unregistered Marks of BYU-Idaho. The Marks of third parties may also be displayed on this website. Nothing contained in this website should be construed as granting, by implication, estoppel, or otherwise, any license or right to use any Marks displayed on this website without the express written permission of BYU-Idaho or any third party that may own the Marks displayed on this website. Any unauthorized use of the Marks or any other material, except as authorized herein, is strictly prohibited.</p>
<p><strong>Internet Links</strong></p>
<p>The BYU-Idaho website contains links to other Internet sites and resources. BYU-Idaho is not responsible for the availability of these outside resources or their contents, nor does it endorse, or take responsibility for any of the contents, advertising, products, or other materials on such sites. Any concerns regarding any external link should be directed to its respective site administrator or webmaster.</p>
<p>The inclusion of materials, by reference, link, or otherwise does not necessarily imply endorsement by or affiliation with BYU-Idaho or The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
<p><strong>Security</strong></p>
<p>For site security and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, deny service, cause damage, or access non-public information. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information are strictly prohibited.</p>
<p><strong>Privacy </strong></p>
<p>For site management, this computer system may use software programs to create summary statistics that are used for such purposes as assessing what information is of interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance areas. BYU-Idaho may collect and store the following, and other information:</p>
<p>The name of the domain from which you access the Internet <br /> The date and time you access our site <br /> The pages you peruse and files you access <br /> The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site</p>
<p>If you choose to provide us with personal information, as in an e-mail message or completing online forms and applications, BYU-Idaho may use this information to respond to your request. There are times when your e-mail or other information may be forwarded to others, including other appropriate institutions, which are better able to assist you. BYU-Idaho will take reasonable precautions to not share personal information with outside organizations without first obtaining your permission.</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer and Limitation of Liability</strong></p>
<p>BYU-IDAHO MAKES NO WARRANTY, EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OF ANY MATERIAL DISPLAYED OR DISTRIBUTED THROUGH THIS WEBSITE, NOR REPRESENTS THAT ITS USE WOULD NOT INFRINGE PRIVATELY OWNED RIGHTS. WE DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THE INFORMATION PROVIDED. IN NO EVENT WILL WE BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OR LOSSES WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM OR CAUSED BY THE USE OR MISUSE OF THIS WEBSITE, OR ANY GOODS, SERVICES, OR CONTENTS AVAILABLE THEREIN.</p>
<p>BYU-IDAHO USES REASONABLE EFFORTS TO INCLUDE ACCURATE, COMPLETE AND CURRENT INFORMATION. WE DO NOT, HOWEVER, WARRANT THAT THE CONTENT HEREIN IS ACCURATE, COMPLETE, CURRENT, OR FREE OF TECHNICAL OR TYPOGRAPHICAL ERRORS. IT IS THE USER'S RESPONSIBILITY TO VERIFY ANY INFORMATION BEFORE RELYING ON IT. WE RESERVE THE RIGHT TO MAKE CHANGES AND UPDATES TO ANY INFORMATION CONTAINED WITHIN THIS SITE WITHOUT PRIOR NOTICE.</p>
<p>ACCESS TO, AND USE OF, THIS WEBSITE AND THE CONTENT THEREOF IS AT THE RISK OF THE USER. IN CERTAIN INSTANCES WE HAVE PROVIDED LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES SOLELY FOR YOUR CONVENIENCE. THESE SITES ARE NOT MAINTAINED OR CONTROLLED BY BYU-IDAHO, AND WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THEIR CONTENT. IT IS UP TO YOU TO TAKE PRECAUTIONS TO ENSURE THAT WHATEVER YOU SELECT FOR YOUR USE IS FREE OF SUCH ITEMS AS VIRUSES, BUGS, WORMS, CANCELBOTS, TROJAN HORSES AND OTHER ITEMS OF A HARMFUL OR DESTRUCTIVE NATURE.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19227" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
