<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_FullWidth ID="x24166" Name="Time Clock Help Page" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Time Clock Help Page</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Time Clock Help Page</Abstract><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Clock into the time clock system at http://www.byui.edu/timeclock .</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">I-Number needs to be entered.  (If a student is unable to login they should contact payroll at ext. 1060.)</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Clock in -  On the right side of the title bar is the clock in option.  Simply click on it and you will be clocked in.  Be sure to exit after clocking in. A second method of clocking in is just press the enter key after login and a message will appear asking "Are you sure you want to clock in?"  Press enter again and you will be clocked in. A message will then appear "Click OK to exit".  You can press enter to exit or you may cancel if you need to do something else on the screen.  If you forget to clock in and remember later, clock in but wait to adjust clock in time until you have clocked out.  If you forgot and it is time to clock out, click the add time on the left of the title bar.  Adding time is explained below.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Clock out - After clocking in, the clock in option turns to clock out.  Click on this option when it is time to clock out.  A second method of clocking out  is just  press the enter key after login and a message will appear asking "Are you sure you want to clock out?"  Press enter again and you will be clocked out.  A message will then appear "Click OK to exit".  You can press enter to exit or you may cancel if you need to do something else on the screen.   Be sure to exit after review of time.  (Special Note: If you forget to clock out the next time you try to clock in you will be prompted to modify time.  If you work over 8 hours straight and try to clock out you will also be prompted to modify time.  You must modify the time appropriately.)</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Exit - When finished clocking in or out be sure to remember to exit the program by clicking the exit option on the left of the title bar.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Print - If a record of the time is wanted, click this option to print recorded time.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Send Message - This option is not in current operation.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Add Time - This is used when a student forgets to clock in and out.  If time in and out need to be added, click this option.  An adjustment screen appears.  Choose the date, in time, and out time and make comments as to why this adjustment.  You are required to make comments to explain the entry.  Choose add entry to add time or cancel to cancel entry. (Supervisor will be alerted to any addition of time)</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Add other time - This allows hourly employees who earn leave like vacation, sick, etc. to enter that time.  Choose this option,  Select the date of leave and leave type.  Enter a comment if desired. Choose add entry to add time or cancel to cancel entry.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Modify Time - Click this button <img alt="Picture of the 'Modify Time' button" height="12" src="Images/financial-services/ModifyTimeIcon_f2.gif" style="display: inline;" title="Modify Time Button" width="13" /> in front of the day that needs to be modified.  The day's recorded time will show on an adjustment screen.  Modify the appropriate option; date, in time, or out time, and make appropriate comments.  Choose modify entry to make changes, cancel or delete time if needed. (Supervisor will be alerted to any modification of time)</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Change Department Number - If under approved conditions, a second department is worked by the student, another department can be chosen.  It is important the correct department is chosen so it will be charged for the labor.  This is a drop down menu that will only allow the student to choose from those shown.  If the second department is not shown, or an incorrect department is shown they should contact student employment.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Computed daily totals are shown in the Day Total column.  At the bottom are the total hours for the pay period.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">End of Pay Period - Students should check time to be sure all has been entered correctly the last day of the pay period.  If adjustments need to be made they should do it then.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Supervisor Review of Time - If the supervisor reviews the time and makes an adjustment, the student will be alerted and informed the next time they logon of the change.  If there is a disagreement they must go to their supervisor, and if changes need to made and adjustment to current time should be done and comments added.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_FullWidth>
