<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x24895" Name="12-28-10 Winter Performing Arts" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Center Stage announces winter performing arts lineup</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at BYU-Idaho has announced its winter lineup, including Forever Plaid, Vocal Point, and Savior of the World.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20101228T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Writer: Don Sparhawk</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho has announced its winter lineup, including Forever Plaid, Vocal Point, and Savior of the World.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Jan. 13-15:	Forever Plaid <br />West Yellowstone's Playmill Theatre will present the musical Forever Plaid for three nights in mid January. This critically acclaimed show is an affectionate revue of the close-harmony "guy groups" (e.g., The Four Aces, The Letterman) that reached the height of their popularity during the 1950s. The Plaids, a quartet of high-school chums, dreamed of recording an album, but their dreams ended in death (literally and figuratively) in a collision with a bus filled with Catholic schoolgirls on their way to see the Beatles' American debut on "The Ed Sullivan Show." The play begins with the Plaids returning from the afterlife for one final chance at musical glory.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Jan. 21-22:	Barbershop Music Festival (featuring The Perfect Gentlemen)<br />The Perfect Gentlemen will headline this year's Barbershop Music Festival with harmony and humor. The quartet was named the "Best <br />A Cappella Vocal Group" in the United States in 2002, winning the National Harmony Sweepstakes. You'll also hear student quartets, the BYU-Idaho Men's Choir and Women's Choir, and the Carousel Chorus.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Jan. 29:	BYU Vocal Point (featuring Noteworthy)<br />Vocal Point, Brigham Young University's nine-man contemporary a cappella group, thrills audiences with a creative show that combines harmony, humor and remarkable vocal percussion into an exciting and unique musical style-Maximum A Cappella. After a stunning performance at Lincoln Center in New York City in April 2006, Vocal Point became the winner of the International Championship of Collegiate A Cappella. Opening for Vocal Point will be Noteworthy, an award-winning all-women's a cappella group from Provo, Utah.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Feb. 4-5:	Jazz Festival (featuring Eric Marienthal) &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;Sax player Eric Marienthal from Los Angeles will headline this winter's BYU-Idaho Jazz Festival. Six of Marienthal's songs have made it to the top 10 on the National Contemporary Jazz Radio Charts, and two have made it to No. 1. Besides performing with the BYU-Idaho Sound Alliance jazz ensemble, he will teach clinics and rehearse with students.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Feb. 12:	4Troops Patriotic Concert<br />4Troops is made up for four U.S. combat veterans-three young men and one woman who served on the front lines in Iraq and Afghanistan. Their purpose is to sing on behalf of all troops, to honor their sacrifices, and to create awareness for their needs. The group performs many well-known positive pop and country songs. All of the songs take on a special meaning in the context that they are performed by these four combat heroes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Feb. 19:	RawMoves<br />The contemporary dance company RawMoves from Salt Lake City presents the Story of Eight. Eight props and eight dancers come together in an evening of dance filled with vibrant and poetic images. Using a chair, ladder, bouquet of roses, man's sport coat, pillow, mattress, rope and basin, each section features one or more of these objects in the story. RawMoves presents the choreographic works of Nicholas Cendese and Natosha Washington, co-artistic directors of the company. Their artistic ideas and explorations present the "raw" elements of our lives today.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	March 5:	Brothers Sing On! (featuring BYU Men's Chorus and BYU-Idaho Men's Choir)<br />Everyone loves a men's choir. BYU-Idaho welcomes the famed BYU Men's Chorus in a performance celebrating the unique sound of men's voices. The BYU Men's Chorus is purportedly the largest collegiate male choral organization in the United States and is known not only for its polished musical performances but also for its engaging and entertaining performance style. The concert will include a performance by the always-popular BYU-Idaho Men's Choir in solo as well as some combined numbers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	March 16, 18:	Alfie Boe (featuring BYU-Idaho Sinfonietta)<br />British singing sensation Alfie Boe will perform for two nights at BYU-Idaho, accompanied by the university's Sinfonietta chamber orchestra. The Tony Award-winning tenor was discovered while working in a car factory in Blackpool, England. He enjoyed entertaining his coworkers by singing opera while he polished the cars. One day he was overheard by a client with connections to the music industry who suggested he audition for the D'Oyly Carte Opera Company in London. From there, he went on to a successful music career. In October 2010, he took the role of Jean Valjean in a concert performance of the musical Les Miserables at the O2 Arena in London to celebrate the 25th anniversary of the show.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	March 25:	Savior of the World<br />The first production in the new 15,000-seat BYU-Idaho Center auditorium will feature a concert version of Savior of the World: His Birth and Resurrection. The story of Jesus Christ begins before the His birth and concludes with His resurrection. We invite you to celebrate the timeless message of the Savior's earthly ministry and his poignant, selfless sacrifice while you view this dramatic program presented by the BYU-Idaho College of Performing and Visual Arts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><br />A free brochure listing all performing arts events is available at the BYU-Idaho Ticket Office, the BYU-Idaho Alumni Center on Main Street in Rexburg, the Rexburg Chamber of Commerce, or by calling 496-1150. Detailed information, such as ticket prices and sale dates, may also be found at www.byui.edu/centerstage. Season tickets may be ordered at www.byui.edu/tickets or at the BYU-Idaho Ticket Office. For high resolution images, please contact us.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>