<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x25463" Name="07-08-10 Interior Design" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Department of Interior Design afforded top honor</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho’s interior design program was recently awarded the National Kitchen and Bath Association (NKBA) 2010 Excellence in Education Award. </Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20100708T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Writer: Ryan Kunz</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Brigham Young University-Idaho's interior design program was recently awarded the National Kitchen and Bath Association (NKBA) 2010 Excellence in Education Award. Out of more than 60 eligible institutions, BYU-Idaho and seven other NKBA-accredited colleges received the award by demonstrating high standards of kitchen and bath design instruction.</p>
<p><br />"We are proud to award the Excellence in Education Award to BYU-Idaho," said Sherylin Doyle, NKBA academic relations manager. "The award would not be possible without the dedication and commitment from BYU-Idaho's NKBA coordinator, Wendy Harris. The association commends her and her students on all of their hard work."</p>
<p><br />The accredited program coordinator from each college submitted two student design projects. Kitchen and bath industry professionals judged the designs based on the association's planning guidelines and graphic and presentation standards, using the designs to evaluate the quality of the interior design program itself. To qualify for the award, the school's designs had to reach an average score of at least 93 out of 100. The BYU-Idaho students' designs scored an average of 96. This year is the third year in a row that the school's interior design program has received the award.</p>
<p><br />Caley Park, a senior studying interior design, also won the NKBA Outstanding Student Award for BYU-Idaho. She received a $100 scholarship and her name and photo on a perpetual plaque located in the Department of Interior Design.</p>
<p><br />For a student to win the award, he or she must demonstrate excellence in kitchen and bath design, as well as participate in volunteer or work experience related to the kitchen and bath industry. Park was BYU-Idaho's NKBA student chapter president for 2009-2010.</p>
<p><br />In addition, four of the seven BYU-Idaho Interior Design graduates from 2009 who passed the Associate Kitchen &amp; Bath Designer (AKBD) Exam have now successfully completed the certification process to earn the AKBD designation: Lacey Janelle Allen, Lauryn Donat, Chad Farley, and, Emily Larsen.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>