<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x25702" Name="Zaharis Elementary School" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Zaharis Elementary School</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Zaharis Elementary School</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><img alt="Picture of Zaharis Elementary" border="0" height="196" src="http://www.mpsaz.org/zaharis/images/dsc_0122_2.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Zaharis Elementary School, Mesa, Arizona" width="550" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong></strong><strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit; color: #000000;">Principal: Mike Oliver</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">9410 East McKellips Rd, Mesa, AZ 85207<br /><a href="http://www.mpsaz.org/zaharis/">School Website</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"></p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">About</h6>
<p style="text-align: left;">We strive to honor what John Dewey said about a hundred years ago:&nbsp;&nbsp;<em>Education isn't preparation for future living.&nbsp; Education is life</em>.&nbsp; At Zaharis, our students see themselves as democratic participants in the world whose voices and opinions count. In an authentic learning environment, they&nbsp;<em>are</em>&nbsp;mathematicians, historians, readers, writers, scientists, and social scientists.&nbsp;Critical thinking is nurtured through a workshop pedagogy where we place a premium on inquiry-based, hands-on learning.&nbsp; Children develop independence as learners and the ability to work together to raise questions, investigate issues, and solve problems. Our classroom communities are alive with a passion and fire for learning.&nbsp; Children apprentice themselves to their teachers and they work side-by-side to make sense out of the world.&nbsp;Zaharis places a very heavy emphasis on literacy development. We help children grow as readers by using&nbsp;<em>real books.</em>&nbsp;Literary discussions illuminate our classrooms, as we challenge ourselves to look at the world through new perspectives. At Zaharis, children develop a love for reading, and it becomes a central part of their lives.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.edtv99.org/shows/test/video/15767">Click here to hear about <strong>Zaharis from former student teachers</strong></a></p>
<h5></h5>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-avI_5cQNuY?rel=0" width="480"></iframe><br /><br /><iframe frameborder="0" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CfV0dMR4kuo?rel=0" width="480"></iframe></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"></p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">Would you like to be part of the Zaharis team for a semester?</h6>
<p style="text-align: center;">To be considered for a placement at this school, we recommend you read the following books before you apply.&nbsp; We recommend that you purchase them and mark them up, but if your budget is restricted, you can check them out at your local library.&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Grand Conversations - Literature Groups in Action</em> by Ralph Peterson &amp; Maryann Eeds.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">This book introduces the reader to the notion: real books and the conversations they inspire should be at the&nbsp; heart of classroom literacy practices.&nbsp; The latest edition is&nbsp;enriched by updated booklists and by reflections of teachers deeply influenced by the original book.</p>
<p><em>Creating Curriculum - Teachers and Students as a Community of Learners</em> by Kathy G. Short &amp; Carolyn Burke.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Curriculum is not just a set of activities, it is putting into action a system of beliefs that highlights both action adn reflection in learning and teaching.&nbsp; And because curriculum so obviously involves both students and teachers, it should be built collaboratively between them.&nbsp; This redefinition gives back decision-making to teachers and students instead of taking it out of their&nbsp; hands through mandates and prescribed programs.</p>
<p><em>On Solid Ground - Strategies for Teaching Reading K-3</em> by Sharon Taberski.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Enter Sharon Taberski's classroom and enter a world where children take pride, take risks, and most&nbsp; of all, take reading seriously.&nbsp; In her book, Sharon shares what she's gained in her twenty years fo working with children adn teachers.&nbsp; It's organized around a series of interconnected interactions with the learner: Assessment, Demonstration, Practice, Response.&nbsp; It is loaded with advice, booklists, ready-to-use reproducibles, etc.</p>
<p><em>From the Ground Up </em>by Heidi Mills &amp; Amy Donnelly</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">This is the story of a small group of teachers, university partners, and a school district when they joined together to create the Center for Inquiry to explore what was possible rather than typical for teachers and children in elementary education.</p>
<p><em>Teaching with Intention</em> by Debbie Miller.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Effective, intentional teaching begins with a strong set of beliefs, but even the best teachers struggle to make sure that their classroom practice consistently reflects their core convictions.&nbsp; This book shares the process of definingh beliefs, aligning practice, and taking action to ensure that children are the true beneficiaries of the teaching.</p>
<p><em>Ish</em> by Peter H. Reynolds</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Drawing is what Ramon does.&nbsp; It's what makes him happy.&nbsp; In one split second, however, all that is changed.&nbsp; Combining the spareness of fable with the potency of parable, Reynolds shines a bright beam of light on the need to kindle and tend our creative flames with care.</p>
<p><em>The Table Where Rich People Sit</em> by Byrd Baylor, illus. by Peter Parnall</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Mountain Girl knows her family doesn't have enough money.&nbsp; But as the family sits around their scratched-up kitchen table, they begin to count up the value of the things they have.&nbsp; How much is it worth to be able to see the sky all day and feel the wind and smell the coming rain? Could her family really be rich after all?</p>
<h5></h5>
<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/SClK0MQMOvo?feature=player_detailpage" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="350" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XOum6z2DmZU?rel=0" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="425"></iframe></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
