<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x25775" Name="South Jordan Middle School" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">South Jordan Middle School</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">South Jordan Middle School</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><img alt="South Jordan" height="200" src="Images/education-human-dev/Field Services_New/sjmspic.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="250" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Principal: Shawn McLeod</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">Jordan School District<br /><strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit; orphans: 3; widows: 3;"><a href="http://www.sjms.jordan.k12.ut.us/">School Website</a></strong></p>
<hr />
<h5 style="text-align: center;"></h5>
<h5 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Our Story</strong></h5>
<p>While all good stories have a beginning, middle and end, the story of Jordan School District is still being written. As our next chapter unfolds, our founding principles of providing a quality education and promoting lifelong learning will guide our future.</p>
<p>Jordan School District will continue to lead the way in research-based curriculum and strategies. We believe education must be relevant and responsive to the ever-changing world.</p>
<p>How we educate our students is perhaps our greatest accomplishment. Quality teaching promotes quality learning. That is evident in our students who continually outperform their counterparts across the nation on standardized tests.</p>
<p>We inspire future generations one student at a time. Our strength lies in the hearts and talents of our employees. The teachers, support staff and administrators have developed a synergy that has fueled Jordan's legacy of serving and educating students for more than a century. As students leave our system we hope they are inspired to continue learning for a lifetime.</p>
<p>Established in 1905, Jordan School District opened its doors with 3,000 students, 70 teachers and 20 community schools. We provide public education for more than 49,000 students living in Bluffdale, Copperton, Herriman, Riverton, South Jordan and West Jordan who attend our 52 schools.</p>
<p>Jordan School District is under the leadership of a seven-member Board of Education and District Administration.</p>
<hr />
<h5></h5>
<h5 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Mission Statement<br /></strong></h5>
<p>The South Jordan Middle School community is committed to improving student learning by creating a safe and respectful environment, providing a challenging curriculum, addressing the diversity of middle school learners, and fostering individual responsibility.</p>
<hr />
<p></p>
<h5 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Belief Statements</strong></h5>
<ul>
<li>All students can learn.</li>
<li>Everyone within the school community should be valued, respected, and challenged to meet their personal best in a safe and positive environment.</li>
<li>The diversity of middle school students requires a wide range of teaching and assessment methods.</li>
<li>Responsibility for student achievement is shared by students, parents, staff, and the community.</li>
<li>The curriculum should meet the needs of students, adhere to district and state standards, and prepare students for the future.</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h5></h5>
<h5 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Desired Results for student learning</strong></h5>
<ul>
<li>Students will demonstrate core knowledge and develop skills that support life long learning.</li>
<li>Students will communicate effectively using reading, writing, speaking, and listening skills.</li>
<li>Students will develop critical thinking and problem solving skills.</li>
<li>Students will develop interpersonal skills.</li>
<li>Students will demonstrate positive character development.</li>
<li>Students will demonstrate responsible citizenship</li>
</ul>
<p>South Jordan Middle School (SJMS) is located in the western part of the city of South Jordan. This area changed rapidly from an agrarian community to a suburban society. The patrons of this middle to upper income community are highly supportive of the school and are dedicated to educational excellence which includes curriculum, instruction, and activities which enrich the educational opportunities for each child.</p>
<p>Historically, the plan for SJMS developed as Bingham Middle School (BMS) needed replacement. Rather than expend the substantial funds necessary to renovate BMS, it was determined that a wiser course would be to build a new school. Although BMS would remain open for a couple more years, most of the student population began attending SJMS as it opened in 1989.</p>
<p>From its beginnings, students at South Jordan Middle School have excelled. State and national test scores indicate that SJMS students collectively perform at or near the top in all subjects. Students are also found developing their other talents in and out of school. Service is also a priority to many of the SJMS students. To further strengthen the dedication and commitment necessary to excel, students are taught and encouraged to be "Snow Leopards on the P.R.O.W.L." The students come Prepared, are Respectful, are On time, have a Winning attitude, and Listen and learn.</p>
<p>As dedicated professionals, the South Jordan Middle School staff is committed to pursuing the tenets of middle school philosophy by emphasizing academic excellence and by working to help students develop individual strengths, talents and problem solving skills. The school provides an environment where individual differences are valued and the rights of others are respected.</p>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle School serves approximately 1,400 students in grades seven through nine. The school has an ethnic minority population of approximately 3 percent.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle School operates on a traditional nine month, 180 day school calendar. School instructional hours are from 7:55 a.m. to 2:50 p.m. A printed calendar of assemblies, drama, chorus, band, orchestra, and other activities is made available each year.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle School has an experienced faculty trained at universities throughout the nation. All of the professional staff members have bachelor's degrees, and a number have advanced degrees as well.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Faculty and staff undergo formal evaluations on a regular basis to help assure quality teaching and appropriate use of school resources.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The curriculum follows the State Core Curriculum and exceeds state requirements. In addition to giving students a good foundation in basic skills, the faculty provides excellent opportunities for students to learn music, drama, foreign language, etc.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Special education classes in English, math and reading, and counselor-directed study skills classes help students who have special learning needs. Resource teachers, guidance specialist, speech language pathologist, and psychologist are on staff to assist students with special needs.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Honors classes are offered to qualifying students.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Vocational classes provide introductory and intermediate training in woods, home ecology, business, and computer science. All seventh grade students participate in the Technology/Life/Careers (TLC) program.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Students are expected to attend school every day and to help maintain a good learning environment. School dress standards are posted and students are expected to dress in clean, modest clothing which is appropriate for school.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>A hot lunch is served daily in the school cafeteria. An a la carte menu is also available. Service is quick and efficient during three lunch periods.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Bus service is provided for all students who live two miles or more from school.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>An active School Community Council, comprised of elected representatives, meets regularly to deal with important school issues such as student safety.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Visitors are welcome and asked to go to the office for directions and other help before visiting classes.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle provides released time for special studies in athletics, academics and religion.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle students have won numerous awards for math, music, foreign language, vocational keyboarding, essay writing, science projects, magazine writing, and news reporting.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle School recognizes student achievement and their positive contributions through several student recognition and incentive programs.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>South Jordan Middle School encourages student involvement and provides many opportunities for students to showcase their talents and develop leadership skills. Among the possibilities are history, science and foreign language fairs, band, orchestra and vocal festivals, and many other activities which promote student growth.</li>
</ul>
<ul></ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
