<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x26372" Name="Making Deposits or Posing Problems" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Making Deposits or Posing Problems</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Making Deposits or Posing Problems</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20080829T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">David Magleby</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<img align="left" hspace="8" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/MAGLEBYD.JPG" />
<p>I asked.  I waited. There was only stillness.</p>
<p>Perhaps you have experienced something similar. You are desirous of an interesting classroom conversation, yet potential participants remain still, eyes averted. Movements are stifled as they fear a gesture or sweep of the hand may be interpreted as a wish to join the discussion. The reading for that day was Chapter 2 of Paulo Freire&rsquo;s <em>Pedagogy of the Oppressed, </em>wherein a distinction is drawn between the banking method of education and that of problem posing. As I waited for a response, any response, I began to wonder about the oppressed and oppressors and how close the danger might be.</p>
<p>Freire&rsquo;s view is drawn from his experience with literacy initiatives in Brazil. The approach that has become known as liberation education intended to bring light and hope to people perpetually anchored in a peasant class. These &ldquo;little people&rdquo; were primarily descendents of freed slaves who scratched out a living on the outskirts of larger cities. Upon emancipation, this new social class found their place on leftover land between the cities and hills and mountains. Freire intended the process of education to end their exclusion from eating, bathing in clean water, and attending school. Freire found that for education to truly empower, to become transformational, the vehicle itself would need to be transformed.</p>
<p>On the day I invited students to read and capture Freire before coming to class, I assumed there would be energy and excitement; I perceived only blankness.</p>
<p>I probed. They waited.</p>
<p><img align="left" alt="Freire" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/06-2008/freire2.jpg" /> Freire described our traditional approach to schooling as the banking method. In this framework, the teacher controls the bank and makes factual deposits with the students. The student role is to accept deposits. The role of the teacher is to make deposits through an orderly, measured approach, thus maintaining control and power over the dissemination of information and growth of the student. Freire&rsquo;s accusation is that students become objects to be acted upon, rather than subjects, able and prepared to act. For me, the moment was powerful. I, standing in front of my objects, realized that the &ldquo;culture of silence&rdquo; was not limited to Brazilian peasants or other disadvantaged populations. Middle class white students were either content in complacency, unaware, unprepared, or uninterested in becoming subjects who act upon and transform their world. They were in class, willingly. I don&rsquo;t believe they viewed themselves as they oppressed.</p>
<p>They were simply awaiting a deposit.</p>
<p>Consider a class for which you have prepared several slides. In the course of the hour, students become animated in their questioning and shared conversation. Time is running short and you have slides yet unseen. In similar situations, I have at times called a halt to the dialogue so that my final slide deposits could be made. Freire challenges that decision.</p>
<p>Problem posing is Freire&rsquo;s answer to the question of how to transform the culture of school. Problem posing attacks classroom settings in which &ldquo;teachers act, and students have the illusion of acting through the action of the teacher.&rdquo; Problem posing forces us to view education as a process of inquiry rather than as the bestowal of the gift of knowledge from the knowledgeable to those who know nothing. Students become subjects as they ask and pose questions relevant to their own experience and needs. The learning process becomes the attempt to answer real questions that students are actually asking. People become critically literate, able to perceive themselves and the environment in which they exist. This true perception then frees them to accept or transform their society as needed.</p>
<p>Through the method of problem posing, learning becomes a dialogue. No longer dependent upon a banker making deposits, such methods are replaced with the posing of problems with immediate relevance. Education becomes a conscious effort of being and becoming. No longer is knowledge the prize to be won, rather the prize is the cooperative process of growth and development. In short, Freire argues for the development of a humane approach to teaching and learning in which the power to act is afforded to all.</p>
<p>Consider another class on another day.  A student accepts the invitation to ask a question. She has found herself described in the course reading and views herself as unable to act&mdash;as a mere object.  One by one, classmates comment and make connections to their experiences and, from my perspective, truly love, serve, and teach one another. The banker simply weeps and awaits his turn to speak another day. No deposits. Only a process of inquiry prompted by a problem posed.</p>
<p>Sometimes it takes an extreme case to awaken us to possibilities. Freire provides a perspective that, given our work at this institution, is worth our while to consider. I enjoy the process of envisioning that the work promotes. I was fortunate to be in the devotional assembly when Elder Eyring pronounced Brigham Young University- Idaho a &ldquo;place of innovation &ndash; permanently.&rdquo; Since that address, I have seen the words used in various written documents and presentations. I have walked by classrooms and overheard the words being played back to our students. I believe we have a conviction of transformational practices. Reading Freire&rsquo;s Pedagogy of the Oppressed in light of President Eyring&rsquo;s pronouncement, I assume redecorating the bank will not be enough.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>