<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x26520" Name="Rule 3: Game Play" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 3: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Basketball Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x26524" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>Start of Game</em></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball is put in play to begin the game with a jump ball at center court. The alternating-possession arrow will be utilized.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Timing</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Two (2) twenty minute running halves and a five minute half time will constitute a game.</li>
<li>The clock will stop in the last two minutes of the second half for all dead balls.</li>
<li>Each team will be granted five (5) thirty-second timeouts per game.</li>
<li>A two minute overtime period will be played in the case of a tie during playoffs ONLY. If the overtime period ends in a tie score, then another two minuteextra period is played until a winner is decided. Each team shall be allowed one timeout during the ENTIRE overtime period.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Scoring</em></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal is scored when a live ball enters the basket from above and remains in or passes through. A goal is scored from behind the team's own 19-foot, 9-inch arc counts as three (3) points, a free throw is worth one (1) point, and all other goals will count as two (2) points.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Mercy Rule</em></p>
<ul>
<li>The game shall be ended if a team us up by twenty (20) or more points with two minutes or less remaining in the game.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Live Ball and Dead Ball</em></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball becomes live when:</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">It leaves the referee's hand for the jump ball </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">It is at the disposal of the thrower for a throw-in </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">It touches the rim of the basket following a free-throw</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball becomes dead or remains dead when: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal is scored</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A held ball occurs or a ball becomes lodged between the backboard and ring or comes toa rest on the flange</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A player or team control foul occurs</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">In the cases of time expiring, an official blowing their whistle or a non-player or nonteamcontrol foul occurs. The only exceptions occur when:</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A try for a field goal or free throw is in flight</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A free-throw violation by the throwing team occurs</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A violation occurs</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Out of Bounds</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A player is out of bounds when they contact the floor or any other object other than aplayer/person on or outside a boundary line.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball is out of bounds when it is contacted by a player, person, the floor, or anyobject that is outside a boundary.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball is out of bounds when it contacts the supports or back of the backboard, theceiling, or the flange.Violations &amp; PenaltiesFor the following violations a throw-in will be awarded to the offended team out of bounds atthe location of the violation:</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Throw-in violations include leaving the designated throw-in spot, handing the ballinbounds, carrying the ball onto the court, throwing the ball directly into the goalwithout being touched by another player inbounds, the opponent reaching through theout of bounds boundary, and taking more than five seconds to release the ball.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Travel: A player holding the ball may not move a foot or feet in excess of the limitsprescribed.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Kick: A player may not kick or strike the ball with any part of their leg or foot. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Illegal Dribble: A player may not dribble a second time after their first dribble hasended unless the player has lost control due to a try for goal, touch by an opponent, orpass or fumble that has been touched by another player.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A player may not palm or carry the ball during a dribble.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Three Seconds: When the ball is in the front court an offensive player may only be in thekey for three seconds.o An exception may be made for a player who has been in the key for less thanthree seconds and dribbles or moves immediately to try for a goal.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Ten Seconds: The offensive team has 10 seconds to move the ball from the backcourt tothe frontcourt when possession is gained or regained in the backcourt. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Backcourt: If the ball travels from the frontcourt to the backcourt the team in control ofthe ball shall not be the first team to touch the ball in the backcourt. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Closely Guarded: When a player is legally guarded by a defensive player within six feet,that player shall not hold the ball for more than five seconds or dribble for more thanfive seconds.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Excessive Swinging of Elbows: A player may not excessively swing their elbows.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Free-throw violations have different penalties dependent upon which team committed theviolation:</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the shooting team enters or leaves a marked lane space or the shooter enters the keyprior to the ball contacting the rim the ball becomes dead and the next free-throw isattempted or the ball is awarded to the opposing team out of bounds if there are noremaining free-throw attempts.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the non-shooting team enters or leaves a marked lane space prior to the ballcontacting the rim the free-throw shall be re-attempted if the shot is unsuccessful.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Fouls &amp; PenaltiesIncidental contact (contact that does not hinder an offensive or defensive player from normalmovement) is allowed, however contact in the following forms by a players arm(s) or leg(s) isrestricted:</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Holding</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Pushing</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Charging</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Hitting</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Blocking</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Tripping</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">*The penalty for such fouls is the ball awarded for a throw-in at the spot nearest the foul. If theplayer was in the act of shooting, the player is awarded free-throws instead of the ball for athrow-in. If it is a team's seventh, eighth, or ninth foul and the player was not shooting, theoffended player will be awarded one free-throw, this situation is called 'bonus'. If successful, asecond free-throw will be awarded. If a team has fouled 10 or more times the offended playerwill be awarded two free-throws, this situation is called 'double bonus'. No bonus free-throwswill be awarded for team control fouls.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">**Any of the above fouls are considered Intentional if the player does not make an attempt toplay the ball, if excessive contact occurs, if it is premeditated, or if it is designed to keep theclock from starting. The penalty is two free-throws awarded to the offended player and the ballis awarded to the offended team at the spot of the foul.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">***If any of the above fouls are considered outside the scope of basketball the player will beejected from the game. The penalty is two (2) free-throws awarded to the offended player andthe ball is awarded to the offended team at the spot of the foul.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
