<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x27018" Name="Volleyball Coed Rules" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Volleyball Coed Rules</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Volleyball Coed Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27090" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left">&nbsp;<em>Any rule not specifically covered will be governed in accordance with the USA Volleyball Rules. Modifications have been made to suit Brigham Young University-Idaho Recreational Sports programs. </em></p>
<p><strong>Rule 1: Players</strong></p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>A team shall consist of six (6) players on the court. A minimum of four (4) players are required to start a game.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p><strong><em>Substitutions:</em></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Substitution of players may be made when the ball is dead, upon making the request to either referee.</li>
<li>A team is allowed an unlimited number of substitutions. On a player-for-player basis, a player starting a game may be replaced by a substitute and may re-enter the game, but in the original position in the serving order in relation to other teammates. The starter and the substitute may replace each other an unlimited number of times throughout the game.</li>
<li>A team may also choose to substitute by rotation. Players enter the game from the center back position and exit following their service.</li>
<li>Choice of procedure must be declared prior to the start of each game. Choice of substitution method may change from game to game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Rule 2: Play</strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Start of Game</em></strong></p>
<p>A coin toss will determine who serves the first game of the match. The captains still call the toss of a coin. The winner of the toss chooses service, receive, or choice of side of court for the first game. The loser of the toss may choose one of the two remaining options.</p>
<p>A new coin toss is performed before the third game, if necessary.</p>
<p><strong>Timing</strong></p>
<p>Regular season matches will be played the best two (2) out of three (3) games.</p>
<p>The first two (2) games are played to 25 points. Teams must win by two with a cap of 30. The third game is played to 15 points with a cap of 20.</p>
<p>Each match has a 45 minute time limit. The team who is ahead during the current game will win that game. If this causes each team to have one win each, then a third game to seven will be played. The winning team is NOT required to win by two.</p>
<p>After each game of the match, the teams will switch sides of the court.</p>
<p>Requests for a time-out may be made by the captain when the ball is dead.</p>
<p>Teams are allowed two (2) 30-second time-outs per game.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong>Scoring</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>All games are rally scoring.</li>
<li>When a fault is committed by the receiving team, a point is awarded to the serving team.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mercy Rule</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Grass Volleyball does not have a mercy rule.</li>
</ul>
<p>Recreational Sports Coed Grass Volleyball Rules</p>
<p><em><strong>Playing Area</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>&nbsp;Boundary lines that are moved during play shall not cause a rally to stop. If it cannot be determined whether a ball lands "in" or "out" the rally shall be cancelled and replayed.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p><em><strong>Service</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>The service zone is behind the end line and between the extensions of the sidelines. It extends in depth to the edge of the sand area. Players may serve the ball from any point in the service zone.</li>
<li>Each team is allowed a maximum of three successive contacts of the ball in order to return the ball to the opponent's area.</li>
<li>The ball may be hit with any part of the body.</li>
<li>Players may have successive contacts of the ball during blocking and during a single attempt to make the first team hit of a ball coming from the opponents, even if the ball is blocked, provided the ball is not held or thrown.</li>
<li>When the ball visibly comes to rest momentarily in the hands or arms of a player, it is considered as having been held. The ball must be hit in such a manner that it rebounds cleanly after contact with a player. Scooping, lifting, pushing, or allowing the ball to roll on the body shall be considered a form of holding.</li>
<li>A player is not allowed to attack the ball on the opponent's side of the net. If the ball is hit above the attacker's side of the net and then the follow through causes the attacker's hand and arm to cross the net without contacting an opponent or the net, such action does not constitute a fault.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p><em><strong>Net Play</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Play off the net is legal, including serves. The posts are out of play.</li>
<li>A player's lower body may break the centerline underneath the net as long as it does not interfere with play. No contact with the net is allowed.</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Blocking</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>May be legally accomplished only by players who are in the front row at the time of service.</li>
<li>Back row players may not block or participate in a block, but may play the ball in any other position near or away from the block.</li>
<li>Any player participating in a block shall have the right to make the next contact, such contact counts as the first of the team's three hits.</li>
<li>Blocking or attacking a served ball is a fault.</li>
<li>Blocking of the ball across the net above the opponent's playing area shall be legal provided that such block is:</li>
</ul>
<p>After a player has attacked the ball, or in the first referee's judgment, has intentionally directed the ball toward the opponent's playing area; or,</p>
<p>After the opponents have completed their three hits; or,</p>
<p>After the opponents have hit the ball in such a manner that the ball would, in the first referee's judgment, clearly cross the net if not touched by a player, provided no member of the attacking team is in a position to make a legal play on the ball; or, provided no member of the attacking team is in a position to make a legal play on the ball; or,</p>
<p>If the ball is falling near the net and no member of the attacking team could reasonably make a play on the ball.</p>
<p><em><strong>Faults</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>A double fault occurs when players of opposing teams simultaneously commit faults. In such cases, the first referee with direct a play over.</li>
<li>If faults by opponents occur at approximately the same time, the first referee shall determine which fault occurred first and shall penalize on that fault. If it cannot be determined which fault occurred first, a double fault shall be declared.</li>
<li>All faults shall result in the opposing team being awarded a point.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Rule 3: Mixed Modifications</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Each team shall consist of a maximum of four players on the court at a time.</li>
<li>At least two players are required to start the game, one of each gender.</li>
<li>One player of each gender is required to be on the court at all times, and with 4 players the required gender ratio is 2:2.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Rule 4: Playoffs</strong></p>
<p>Teams must maintain a "3.5" sportsmanship average during the regular season and have zero forfeits to be eligible for the playoffs.</p>
<p>Sportsmanship points for each regular season contest will be added together and divided by the total number of contests held to find each team's sportsmanship average.</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: small;" data-mce-mark="1">&nbsp; Related links:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;" data-mce-mark="1"><a href="x24388.xml">Return to Volleyball</a></span><span style="font-size: small;" data-mce-mark="1"><a href="x24452.xml"></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;" data-mce-mark="1"><a href="x90367.xml">Policies and Procedures</a> </span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
