<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x27094" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Wallyball Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27097" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>Start of Game </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A rally will determine which side servers first. The team  not serving first in the first game will serve first in the second game.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;If a third game is necessary, the team who scores the most  combined points in games one and two will have the choice of serve or  side to begin the third game.</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Timing </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All matches shall consist of the best two of three games.  The first and second games are played to 21 points, rally scoring (cap  at 23). The third game, if necessary, will go to 15 points, rally  scoring (cap at 17).</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each team shall be allowed two 30-second timeouts per game.</p>
<p><em>Scoring </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The team winning the volley will receive one (1) point. Also, the team winning the volley will serve next.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Out of Bounds </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball shall be called out of bounds whenever it hits the ceiling or back wall on the opponent's side.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>The Serve </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The player in the back position of the court shall put the  ball in play by hitting it with one hand only, or any part of his arm,  in an attempt to send the ball over the net and into the opponent's  court. A serve must be cleanly struck.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The serve is good if the ball passes over the net without touching a member of the serving team or the net.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A served ball that hits a wall on either the serving team's  side or the receiving side is good provided the ball contacted only one  wall before landing in the opponent's court.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the ball is contacted, no part of the server's body can be in contact with the service line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players must maintain the serving order that started the game. Serving order may be changed after each game only.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The person who is serving cannot spike or block.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is illegal for a player to receive a serve with an open hand pass or to set the serve.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Play at the Net </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The service area is designated by a blue line, three feet  from the end wall. The service area extends the entire length of the end  wall.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A ball that touches or rebounds off the net or net hardware  may be played unless the team has already contacted the ball three  times.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player or any part of his/her body or uniform that  touches the net while the ball is in play will be charged with a fault,  unless the ball is driven into the net with such force that it causes  the net to touch a player.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player may step on, but cannot cross the center line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A ball directly above the vertical play of the net may be played by either team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If a net does not extend to the wall, any ball passing  through the opening between the net and wall on the first or second hit  will be replayed. A ball passing through the opening on the third hit or  serve will result in a point be awarded to the receiving team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player may follow through over the net provided he/she  first makes contact with the ball on his/her side of the playing court.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players attempting to block may reach across the net but  shall not contact the ball until the opponent strikes the ball in an  attempt to send it to the blocker's side of the net.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player cannot block an opponent's set unless it crosses the vertical plane of the net.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Playing the Ball </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Up to three (3) contacts with the ball are allowed for each  team in order to play the ball over the net into the opponent's court.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; NOTE: A block does not count as one of the three contacts allowed by a team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player may make successive contacts with the ball on the  first contact, provided it was a hard driven spiked ball, and it is  counted as one contact.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player who participates in a block and makes only one  attempt to play the ball during the block may make successive contacts  with the ball during such play.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Contacting two or more walls with the ball is allowed only  by the team in possession of the ball on their own side of the court,  provided a player on that team touches the ball first.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the ball crosses the net after contacting two or more  walls without making contact with a player, a point will be awarded to  the opposing team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Holding, lifting, scooping, pushing, or carrying the ball  with one or two open hands, either underhand or overhand, is a fault and  a point will be awarded to the opposing team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If two (2) players on the same team hit the ball  simultaneously, one contact with the ball will be called and either  player may contact the ball on the next play.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If a player contacts the ball in such a manner that the  ball deflects off the back wall on his/her side of the court and goes  over the net, the ball shall be considered good.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player cannot dink the ball with an open hand. They must use a closed fist, knuckles, or Cobra shot.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Faults </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When two (2) opposing players commit faults simultaneously, a double fault shall be called and the point replayed.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When opposing players commit faults at approximately the  same time, the team that committed the fault first shall be penalized.  If it cannot be decided which team committed the fault first, a double  fault will be declared.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A fault called on the serving team will result in a point  being awarded to the opposing team and turned over to the opposing team  for serve.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any of the following faults committed during play by a  player or team shall result in a point and the ball awarded to the  opposing team for serve:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball is played more than three (3) times by a team.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball touches the ceiling on the opponent's side.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball hits two (2) or more walls consecutively on the receiving team's side.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball hits the back wall on the fly or volley on the receiving team's side.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball is hit twice by the same player consecutively.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The net is touched by a player while the ball is in play.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A player crosses the center line.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball hits the floor of the court.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A ball contacts a player below the waist.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A player holds, carries, scoops, or lifts the ball.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
