<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x27104" Name="Fair Use" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fair Use - Section 107</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Exemptions in Copyright Law- Sections 107 Fair Use</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fair Use</strong></p>
<p>The fair use exception exists to achieve a balance between copyright owners and the general public who may benefit from using copyrighted works without seeking permission.  A fair use is any copying of copyrighted material done for a limited and "transformative" purpose, such as to comment upon, criticize, or parody a copyrighted work. The Fair Use doctrine recognizes the need to permit reasonable public access to copyrighted works in order to support the advancement of knowledge. The uses should repurpose and recontextualize the original or be<em> </em>accompanied with commentary - scholarly, educational, historical, and/or critical.  Uses should be brief and noncommercial and proper credit and notice should always be given.</p>
<p><strong>The Law of Fair Use</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.copyright.gov/title17/92chap1.pdf">U.S. Copyright Act, 17 U.S.C. ¤ 107 Limitations on Exclusive Rights: Fair Use</a></strong></p>
<p>"Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 106 and 106A, the fair use of a copyrighted work, including such use by reproduction in copies or phonorecords or by any other means specified in that section, for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching (including multiple copies for classroom use), scholarship, or research, is not an infringement of copyright. In determining whether the use made of a work in any particular case is a fair use the factors to be considered shall include-</p>
<ol start="1" type="1">
<li>The      purpose and character of the use, including whether such use is of a      commercial nature or is for nonprofit educational purposes.</li>
<li>The      nature of the copyrighted work.</li>
<li>The      amount and substantiality of the portion used in relation to the      copyrighted work as a whole.</li>
<li>The      effect of the use upon the potential market for or value of the      copyrighted work.</li>
</ol>
<p>The fact that a work is unpublished shall not itself bar a finding of fair use if such finding is made upon consideration of all the above factors." <a href="http://www.copyright.gov/title17/92chap1.pdf">(17 U.S.C. ¤ 107)</a></p>
<p>Fair use is based on weighing these four factors:</p>
<p><strong>1)</strong> <strong>Purpose and Character of the Use</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Is the      use for a commercial or noncommercial purpose?</li>
<li>What      is the target audience?</li>
<li>If the      purpose is educational is the copied work to be accompanied by original      commentary?</li>
<li>Does      the use of the work "transform" the material taken from the      copyrighted work by using it for a different purpose than that of the      original?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2)</strong> <strong>Nature of the Copyrighted Work</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Is the      copyrighted work informational or creative?</li>
<li>Is the      copyrighted work educational or entertainment?</li>
<li>Is the      copyrighted work published or unpublished?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3)</strong> <strong>Amount and Substantiality of the Portion Used</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Did      you use only the amount you needed to accomplish your purpose?</li>
<li>Is the      copied amount the "heart of the work"?</li>
<li>Is the      copied amount a substantial percentage of the whole work?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>4) Effect Upon the Potential Market or Value of the Copyrighted Work</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Will      the copying interfere with marketability of the original work?</li>
<li>Are      permissions available to purchase at a reasonable price?</li>
<li>Is the      use a "substitute" for purchasing the work?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Weighing and Balancing the Factors</strong></p>
<p>A central principle of the fair use analysis is the flexible doctrine that Congress wanted us to test and adapt for changing needs and circumstances. The law provides <strong>no clear and direct answers</strong> about the scope of fair use or its meaning in specific situations. Instead, we are compelled to return to the four factors and to reach <strong>reasoned and responsible conclusions</strong> about the lawfulness of our activities. Reasonable people may differ widely on the applicability of fair use, but any reliable evaluation of fair use must depend upon a reasoned analysis of the four factors of fair use. If most factors lean in favor of fair use, the proposed use is probably allowed; if most lean the opposite direction, the purposed use will not fit the fair use exception and may require permission from the copyright owner.</p>
<p><strong>Tools for conducting a Fair Use Analysis</strong></p>
<p>Do an analysis each time you want to determine if your use of a work is a fair use. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/copyright/contact-information">Contact</a> the University Intellectual Property Rights Specialist if you have any questions regarding the overall analysis and use of the checklist. Complete a checklist, sign, date, and attach a copy of it to the material analyzed for fair use in order to document that you are acting in good faith.</p>
<p>To do your analysis, print and complete the Checklist for Fair Use (<a href="Documents/copyright/Fair Use Analysis.pdf" target="_blank">PDF</a> | <a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/copyright/fairusechecklist.doc">Word Document</a> - requires document download).</p>
<p>The following tools can also be helpful in determining whether the use of material protected by copyright is a fair use.</p>
<p><a href="http://files.lib.byu.edu/copyright/Checklist_for_Fair_Use.pdf">BYU Checklist for Fair Use (PDF)</a><br /> <a href="http://www.vraweb.org/resources/ipr/dirc/page_7.html">Digital Image Rights Computator</a> (DIRC), Visual Resources Association<br /> <a href="http://librarycopyright.net/fairuse/">Fair Use Evaluator</a>, Michael Brewer, ALA Office of IT Policy</p>
<p><strong>Fair Use and Best Practice Publications</strong></p>
<p>The Association of Research Libraries (ARL) recently released of the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/copyright/Library%20code-of-best-practices-fair-use.pdf" title="ARL Code of Best Practices" target="_blank"><em>Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for Academic and Research Libraries</em></a>, a clear and easy-to-use statement of fair and reasonable approaches to fair use developed by and for librarians who <a href="http://www.arl.org/pp/ppcopyright/codefairuse/faq-profs.shtml" title="FAQ for Profs" target="_blank">support</a> academic inquiry and higher education. It offers 8 principles that provide an outline to some common situations where many in the library community agree fair use can apply. These codes of Best Practice in fair use function as <strong>guides to reasoning</strong>, <strong>not guidelines that dictate</strong>, and like the guidelines, do not have the force of law. They merely mark a well-trodden path through the fair use landscape.</p>
<p><strong>From American University Center for Social Media</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://centerforsocialmedia.org/rock/backgrounddocs/bestpractices.pdf">Documentary Filmmakers Best Practices in Fair Use</a><br /> <a href="http://centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/related-materials/teaching-materials/examples-successful-fair-use-documentary-film">Examples of Successful Fair Use in Documentary Film</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/resources/publications/code_for_media_literacy_education/">Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for Media Literacy Education</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/best-practices/media-literacy/fair-use-media-literacy-education-faq" title="Fair Use in Media Literacy Education FAQ">Fair Use in Media Literacy Education FAQ</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/resources/publications/fair_use_in_online_video/">Code of Best Practice in Fair Use for Online Video</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/sites/default/files/documents/pages/fairusepoetrybooklet_singlepg_3.pdf">Code of Best Practices In Fair Use for Poetry</a><br /> <a href="http://blip.tv/file/2081224">Remix Culture: Fair Us is Your Friend</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/related-materials/codes/code-best-practices-fair-use-scholarly-research-communication" title="Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for Scholarly Research in Communication">Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for Scholarly Research in Communication</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/related-materials/codes/best-practices-fair-use-dance-related-materials" title="Best Practices in Fair Use of Dance-related Materials">Best Practices in Fair Use of Dance-related Materials</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/related-materials/teaching-materials/fair-use-scenarios" title="Fair Use Scenarios">Fair Use Scenarios</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/resources/publications/fair_use_in_online_video/" target="_blank">Fair Use and Free Speech<br /> Code of Best Practice in Fair Use for Online Video</a><br /> <a href="http://centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/related-materials/teaching-materials/fair-use-language-course-syllabi">Fair Use Language for Course Syllabi</a><br /> <a href="http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/ocw" title="Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for OpenCourseWare">Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for OpenCourseWare</a></p>
<p><strong>Other Fair Use Resources</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/copyright/FairUse_hurley.pdf" target="_blank">Fair Use</a> Sister Casey Hurley, BYU-Idaho Perspectives article <br /> <a href="http://www.vraweb.org/organization/pdf/VRAFairUseGuidelinesFinal.pdf">Statement on the Fair Use of Images for Teaching, Research and Study,</a> Visual Resources Association<br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/">Fair Use in Education and Research</a>, Copyright Advisory Office, Columbia University<br /> <a href="http://copyright.lib.utexas.edu/copypol2.html#Intro">Copyright Crash Course, Fair use of copyrighted materials</a>, Georgia Harper, University of Texas<br /> <a href="http://www.arl.org/bm%7Edoc/educationalfairusetoday.pdf" target="_blank">Educational Fair Use Today</a>, by Jonathan Band, Association of Research Libraries<br /> <a href="http://fairuse.stanford.edu/Copyright_and_Fair_Use_Overview/chapter9/index.html" target="_blank">Copyright and Fair Use</a>, Stanford University Libraries<br /> <a href="http://copylaw.com/new_articles/fairuse.html" target="_blank">Fair Use in a Nutshell</a>, CopyLaw.com by Attorney Lloyd J. Jassin<br /> <a href="http://www.copyright.com/copyrightbasicsvideo" target="_blank">Copyright Basics: Fair Use</a>, Copyright Clearance Center</p>
<p><strong>Fair Use Case Summaries</strong></p>
<p>Court decisions regarding the question of fair use can provide insight in applying Fair Use to specific situations. Although there are not many cases directly related to the university community, the following summaries will offer some helpful understanding.  These case summaries are authored by Dr. Kenneth H. Crews, Copyright Advisory Office,  at Columbia University.</p>
<p><a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries1">Teaching: Copies for Classroom Instruction</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries2">Research: Copies for Study</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries3">Research: Quotations or Excerpts in Scholarly Presentation</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries4">Publications: Quotations or Excerpts of Text</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries5">Publications: Reprinting of Visual Images</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries6">Web Sites: Posting for Public Access</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries7">Video Production: Excerpts of Sound Recording</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.columbia.edu/copyright/fair-use/case-summaries/#summaries8">Multimedia Development: Manipulation of Photographic Images</a></p>
<p><strong>Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>During and after enactment of the 1976 U.S. Copyright Act several fair use guidelines emerged. These guidelines were created as "safe harbor" standards by interested stakeholders representing a variety of interests. Related to the Copyright Act of 1976, Congress included in H.R. 94-1476, an initial set of <a href="http://louisville.edu/copyright/resources/classroom-guidelines-1976.html">Guidelines for Classroom Copying in Not-for-Profit Educational Institutions with Respect to Books and Periodicals</a>. During later years the Conference on Fair Use (CONFU) was established to help resolve copyright issues within emerging technology. CONFU released draft guidelines on distance education, multimedia, images, electronic reserve services in libraries, and interlibrary loan. No consensus agreement has been achieved surrounding CONFU guidelines and they remain in draft.</p>
<p>In referring to the guidelines, it is important to note they are <strong>not</strong> <strong>the law</strong> and often express <strong>minimum standards</strong> for fair use.</p>
<p>While many institutions strictly adhere to the CONFU guidelines, Brigham Young University- Idaho has chosen not to adopt them as official standards for the campus community. They are provided here for reference and information only.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/dcom/olia/confu/confurep.pdf">Complete Conference on Fair Use (CONFU) report</a>, United States Patent and Trademark Office<br /> <a href="http://louisville.edu/copyright/resources/classroom-guidelines-1976.html">Classroom Guidelines (1976), Agreement on Guidelines for Classroom Copying in Not-For-Profit Educational Institutions with Respect to Books and Periodicals, Published in House Report 94-1476</a><br /> <a href="http://copyright.musiclibraryassoc.org/Resources/CopyrightAndFairUse">Statement on the Copyright Law and Fair Use in Music</a>, Music Library Association<br /> <a href="http://copyright.musiclibraryassoc.org/Resources/DigitalReserves">Statement on the Digital Transmission of Audio Reserves</a>, Music Library Association<br /> <a href="http://www.lib.berkeley.edu/MRC/Kastenmeier.html">Guidelines for Off-Air Taping for Educational Purposes</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19227" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
