<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x27487" Name="09-02-09 Crossroads" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho set to feed thousands in new food court </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho is opening the Crossroads, a new 18,000 square-foot food court, on Sept. 10.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090902T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Writer: Colby Flint</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Brigham Young University-Idaho is opening a new 18,000 square-foot food court on Sept. 10. The new facility, known as The Crossroads, seats about 1,200 people and is three times the size of the current dining area. It features seven unique eating venues, a salad and dessert bar, a stage for student performances, wireless Internet and a string of electrical outlets for convenient laptop use.</p>
<p><br /> "The Crossroads isn't going to be just for food, it's a gathering place where students will mingle, study and be entertained," said Greg Carson, BYU-Idaho's Food Services manager. "We call it The Crossroads because it will be the center of activity on campus."</p>
<p><br />Although the area is not just for food, it will bring a lot of customers to Food Services. Thus, the department is receiving a major facelift before moving to its new home. Food Services is expanding its menu and implementing new pieces of equipment. Employees will cook in the open air, sending aromas of breads, pastries and other foods into the crowd and up to the 28-foot ceiling. Dining options will include Asian and Mexican cuisine, pizza and pasta, a full grill line, home-style cooking, deli and wraps, soups, salads, retail bakery items and desserts, ice cream and more.</p>
<p><br />"We're going to keep the quality of our food at a very high level but provide more of it, all in an interactive and fun atmosphere," Carson said.</p>
<p><br />The Crossroads' interactive atmosphere will continue to grow as construction moves forward on campus. The next stage of construction on the Hyrum Manwaring Student Center will include an enclosed bridge that connects the dining area with the David O. McKay Library, making the food court an even bigger junction point on campus.</p>
<p><br />Students, employees and community members can currently access the new facility through entrances on the east side of the Manwaring Center. The Crossroads will open at 7 a.m., Monday through Friday, and at 9 a.m. on Saturdays. Closing times have not yet be determined, but will later established based on optimum hours in support of the university.</p>
<p><br />A press conference is scheduled for Sept. 16 at 11 a.m. Please contact Andy Cargal at cargala@byui.edu if you plan to attend.<br /><br /></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>