<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x27431" Name="Standards for Social Work Students" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Standards for Social Work Students</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Standards for Social Work Students</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">In order to qualify to participate in the program and pursue a degree in Social Work, students must have the requisite abilities necessary to perform the essential functions required by the program and be able to meet the appropriate programmatic standards. These standards should be met in the classroom, in field placements, and elsewhere in the program. In addition, as students at Brigham Young University-Idaho, students are expected to adhere to the moral and personal standards set by the Honor Code.</span></p>
</div>
<p>Accordingly, by applying to and accepting admission into the School of Social Work, students commit that they have the following abilities and attributes and will conduct themselves according to the following guidelines:</p>
<p>Motor Abilities: Students need to have the ability to fully participate in classes and field agency placement, and to acquire and integrate data through use of their senses. Reasonable accommodation for a qualifying disability may be allowed, but it is the student's responsibility to obtain and relay the necessary information from the University Services for Students with a Disability office to each instructor and field supervisor. <br /> <br />Communication Skills: Students must have sufficient skills in written and spoken English. Students must also have the ability to process information expeditiously and communicate effectively with instructors, other students, faculty members, staff, clients, and other professionals.</p>
<p>Ethical standards: Students are ethically and professionally bound to adhere to the National Association of Social Workers (NASW) Code of Ethics and conduct themselves pursuant to pertinent Idaho statutes and applicable administrative codes. In addition, it is essential that students demonstrate appreciation for empathy, diversity in society, and non-judgmental attitude in their interaction with others. The value of confidentiality is foundational to the profession of social work, and sound interpersonal skills must be observed. <br /> <br />Knowledge base: Students need to learn and practice within the scope of social work profession's knowledge base, by recognizing the distinctive components of the biopsychosocial perspective of social work practice and social work methodologies. These must guide their work with clients and become the basis for their contribution to other related work.</p>
<p>Professionalism: Students are expected to demonstrate a commitment to professional conduct, including practicing within the scope of social work, adhering to the limit of their knowledge and skills in the delivery of services to clients, respecting others, being punctual and dependable, completing assignments and reports on time, and prioritizing responsibilities. Appearance and personal demeanor should reflect an appropriate understanding of the professional context. Conflict resolution should reflect respect for proper channels of authority, and feedback dealt with in a professional manner. Respect should be shown to fellow students, faculty, staff, clients, and colleagues in the classroom and in the field. Disrespect for others or any form of sexual harassment will not be tolerated.</p>
<p>Self-care: Students need to recognize the signs of stress and emotional problems, develop appropriate means of self-care, and seek supportive services when necessary to minimize any adverse impact on scholastic and professional performance. Students must be willing to seek the advice of their faculty advisor and follow recommendations made by their advisor and/or faculty decisions regarding the appropriate maintenance of their academic, physical, or psychological health, which may include assessment and/or therapeutic services at the student's expense.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"></h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x41749" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
