<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x27439" Name="12-08-09 Allred" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty member shares insights about the body’s spiritual properties</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Philip Allred, faculty member in the Department of Religious Education at BYU-Idaho, encouraged students to keep their bodies pure at today’s devotional.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" /></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20091208T19:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Writer: Colby Flint</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Philip Allred, faculty member in the Department of Religious Education at Brigham Young University-Idaho, encouraged students to keep their bodies pure at today's devotional. Allred quoted past and present leaders of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints to explain how people's moral cleanliness shows in their countenance.</p>
<p><br /> He focused on four statements that reveal the importance of a human body's spiritual properties. "Our bodies are figuratively and literally our "Book of Life" because they are constantly recording and registering our desires, thoughts, words and actions," Allred said, as the first statement. He followed directly with the second: "The resurrection will reunite each spirit with its body in an ultimate fulfillment of the law of harvest, revealing our obedience or disobedience to God's laws at our final judgment."</p>
<p><br /> Allred then quoted Elder Dallin H. Oaks of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, saying that everone will stand before God and be judged, not according to their sum total of good and evil acts but according to what they have become. In his third statement, Allred said the Atonement can cleanse and transform bodies in the resurrection, helping each individual prepare for this judgment by becoming pure. Christ's cleansing power, however, will only be applied as each individual repents and is obedient.</p>
<p><br /> The fourth statement described how gospel principles will gradually guide those who follow them: "The gospel enables us to fully bridle these &lsquo;instruments of our minds' so that we can record holiness in us-line upon line-with the Lord's personal commandments as our guide."</p>
<p><br /> In conjunction with these four statements, Allred described God's personal love for each of His children. He promised that Jesus Christ's grace is sufficient for all who follow His teachings.</p>
<p><br /> "I have found that the Lord is willing to lead me along, line upon line, grace for grace," Allred said. "How exciting the gospel of Jesus Christ is. There is a perfect brightness of hope for me and for you because of these redeeming and refining gospel principles and ordinances, directed so lovingly and individually by our Lord who holds the divine authoring and finishing powers."</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>