<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x27732" Name="Budget Preparation Process" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Budget Preparation Process</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Explanation of how department budgets are prepared</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110904T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Policy</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">The budget process starts around the first part of March with the Division Deans, Department Chairmen, and Administrative Directors receiving a letter of instructions from the Budget Office. The letter includes information regarding the budget preparation time line, continuing budget guideline increases, and other helpful information for completing their continuing budget request worksheets. The letter will also provide information on how to request funds for new and expanded programs as well as capital, computer, and operating equipment, which are budgeted separate from continuing budgets.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Procedures</h4>
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Basic Steps in Budget Preparation</h5>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>Each Department Chairman submits to the Division Dean a list of their capital, computer and operating equipment needs for prioritization by the Division Dean.</li>
<li>Each Department Chairman submits to the Division Dean a list of current and long term budget concerns and any new and expanded programs requests (these are requests for funds over and above the approved guideline increase).</li>
<li>Department Chairmen, Division Deans and Administrative Directors are to complete their continuing budget request worksheets and return them to the Budget Office.</li>
<li>The Division Deans meet with the Academic Vice President and his assistant to explain the issues and begin to prioritize the requests.</li>
<li>Academic Council will finalize the prioritization of special issues, new and expanded programs, and capital equipment requests and have them ready to present in the budget hearing process.</li>
<li>Members of the Budget Committee will prioritize the Academic Vice President requests along with the lists of prioritized requests submitted by the other Vice Presidents and approve as many items as dollars available permit.</li>
<li>The Budget Officer will compile the budget from the continuing budget request worksheets and other special requests approved by the Budget Committee.</li>
<li>The Commissioner and members of his staff will come to BYU-Idaho to review the budget with the Budget Committee.</li>
<li>The Commissioner's Office reviews the budget and gives approval for it to be presented to the Board of Trustees.</li>
<li>The budget is presented to the Board by the Commissioner's Office. </li>
<li>The final approval of the budget is made by the Board and the Council on Disposition of Tithes.</li>
</ol>
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Budgeting Guidelines</h5>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">The budgeting process is inteded to:</p>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>Respond effectively to CES needs and guidelines</li>
<li>Facilitate effective decision making</li>
<li>Promote communication and unity at all administrative levels</li>
<li>Tie dollars directly to programs</li>
<li>Encourage thriftiness and efficiency</li>
<li>Be flexible and adaptive to changing needs</li>
<li>Provide for clear, continuous fiscal accountability</li>
<li>Facilitate implementation of new ideas</li>
<li>Contribute to, rather than detract from, the educational process and faculty morale</li>
</ol>
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Approximate Budget Time Line/Dates</h5>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">(A letter from the Budget Officer will be sent out around the 1<sup>st</sup> of March giving the exact budget time line/dates.)</p>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By February 26</strong> - Academic departments and divisions are to have all special issues, operating equipment, and capital equipment lists submitted for initial review by Academic Council.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By April 9</strong> - Department chairmen and Administrative Directors are to have completed work on the continuing budget worksheets (including obtaining applicable division and/or Vice President approvals), and return them to the Budget Office.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By April 19</strong> - All non-academic areas are to have completed special issues, operating equipment, and capital equipment lists, and to have submitted them to the appropriate Vice President.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By May 31</strong> - President's Council is to have completed the budget hearings with the academic divisions and the departments under the other Vice Presidents.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By August 15</strong> - President's Council is to have completed the process of reviewing and approving the requests submitted during the budget hearing process.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By September 1</strong> - President's Council is to have the budget ready for the CES Budget Office to review.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">By September 21</strong> - The Commissioner's Office comes to BYU-Idaho for an on-site budget review.</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">At the end of the budget year</strong> - Excess funds are returned to general fund.  However, of their unspent budget, departments are allowed to carry over up to 1% of the total budget.</li>
</ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18419" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
