<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x27730" Name="Accounts Receivable &amp; Charges on Campus" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Accounts Receivable &amp; Charges on Campus</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Explanation of accounts and charges made by students, employees, government units, Church units, campus clubs, and off-campus individuals and businesses</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110908T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Policy</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Students, employees, government units, Church units, campus clubs, and off-campus individuals and businesses can obtain approval to charge for goods and services provided on campus.  An account must exist before any charge can be made.  All charges are due by the end of the month following the month in which the charge was made.  Some restrictions do exist in various departments on campus concerning credit sales.  The University can cancel the account of any student, employee, or customer at any time.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Procedures</h4>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>NO NUMBER, NO CHARGE. There should never be any charge made on campus without a valid account number. Campus departments should not assume that all Church units, governmental agencies, or businesses have accounts with the University.</li>
<li>Student and employee ID cards serve to identify them as having a valid account on campus. The student or employee ID number serves as the individual's account number. Employee dependents are allowed to charge on the employee's account provided they have a valid BYU-Idaho dependent ID card or their parent's card at time of purchase. Cards are not issued to other customers.</li>
<li>Usually accounts will be set up for government, church, business, individuals, and other off campus units only after a credit application has been (1) completed and signed by the prospective charge customer and (2) processed and approved by the Accounting Department. However, in a situation where a department feels the need for instant credit for a customer, (1) obtain a completed and signed application form, and (2) call the Accounting Office to obtain approval and the new account number. On the application form, record who gave approval, the date, and the account number to be charged. Then send the application form to the Accounting Office.</li>
<li>A credit check or verification will be made by the Accounting Office before giving credit approval to non-students, non-employees, and businesses. Automatic approval will be given to Church units and governmental agencies. An application will be required so that the proper information will be available for setting up the account.</li>
<li>Generally, charges to student and employee accounts will be done automatically through electronic transfer; for example, (1) tuition and fees, (2) campus housing, (3) meal contracts, (4) parking citations, (5) library fines, (6) health center charges, and (7) bookstore charges.</li>
<li>If a charge cannot be processed electronically, an invoice should be prepared by the selling department for each charge and sent to the Accounting Office. If the customer is present when the sale is made, have him sign the invoice. The selling department will be credited for the sale when the customer's account is charged. In some instances, a list of individuals with related charges will be used instead of an invoice for every person. Contact the Accounting Office for details.</li>
<li>The three copies of the invoice should be distributed as follows: 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: lower-alpha; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Original or first copy (white) should be sent to the Accounting Office. Only the original copy of invoices will be processed and filed in the Accounting Office.</li>
<li>The second copy should be given or mailed to the customer by the selling department. HOWEVER, if the customer is a Church unit, a government agency, or a school, send this copy with the original (white) copy to the Accounting Office. These entities require their copy to be attached to the monthly statement.</li>
<li>The selling department should keep the third copy to be checked against the monthly reports received from the Accounting Office to make sure that proper credit is received. Those offices with regular credit sales should have their invoices placed in batches before sending to the Accounting Office. Then the total amount of the batch will appear on the monthly statements rather than each invoice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Invoices received in the Accounting Office will be returned to the selling department if (1) required information is missing, or (2) the account has not been approved. If the account does not exist, it will be the departments responsibility to contact that customer and obtain payment or make arrangements for a credit application and account approval before resubmitting the invoice to the Accounting Office.</li>
<li>If problems occur in obtaining payment from the customer, the Accounting Office will cancel the credit privileges of the customer. All departments making regular sales will be notified. If at any time a department has a question about a customer's credit standing, they should call the Accounts Receivable section of the Accounting Office BEFORE completing any credit sales.</li>
<li>All payments are due to the University by the end of the month following the month in which the charge was made. Monthly accounts receivable statements will be mailed to each customer showing the balance due. If payment is not received by this date, interest will be charged monthly on the unpaid balance at the rate of 12% per annum (minimum charge of $.50).</li>
<li>If the Accounting Office is not able to obtain payment from a customer, the balance of the debt will be charged back to the selling department . The customers account will either be turned over to a collection agency or written off.</li>
</ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18419" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
