<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x27914" Name="Discovery Fair - Employers" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Discovery Fair - Employers</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">This Winter 2011 BYU-Idaho is hosting an Internship, Career, Graduate School and Student Teaching Fair title Discovery Fair to help students prepare for the future.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>During our fall and winter semesters each year, BYU-Idaho holds a Career Fair.  Our fair is designed to connect BYU-Idaho students with employers interested in recruiting for internships and entry-level positions.  We appreciate employer participation in past years and look forward to continued support in the future.<br /><br /> <strong>The next Career Fair will be held <br /> Thursday, February 23rd, 2012<br />9a.m. - 2 p.m. in the BYU-Idaho center</strong> <br /><br /></p>
<h3>Combined Fair</h3>
<p>We are excited to announce that the BYU-Idaho Internship &amp; Career Services office and the Career and Academic Advising office have recently formed a new partnership, and as a result, will be combining our efforts for our  fairs. <br /><br /> This fair promises to be bigger and better than ever before – by providing students with opportunities to seek jobs, internships, careers and graduate school information all in one place! With over 12,000 students on campus in the fall, we anticipate many will be in attendance making plans for their futures.                                     <br /><br /></p>
<h3>Location</h3>
<p>We are equally excited to announce that construction is now complete on the BYU-Idaho Center, and we will be hosting our fair in this brand-new facility! <br /><br /> At the heart of campus, the BYU-Idaho Center is Brigham Young University-Idaho’s newest and largest building. The 435,000-square-foot building, containing a 15,000-seat auditorium and a multi-purpose area large enough for 10 full basketball courts, opened following a dedication on Dec 17.<br /><br /> Tours of this new facility will be available during Career Week. For more information, including pictures, visit the BYU-Idaho Center website at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/byuidahocenter/default.htm" target="_blank">http://www.byui.edu/byuidahocenter/default.htm</a>.                                     <br /><br /></p>
<h3>Registration</h3>
<p>Registration <span lang="en-US">is now open. Please <a href="https://web3.byui.edu/GraduateFair/#fair" title="Discovery Fair Registration">click here</a> to register. (Only works in Internet Explorer or Firefox)<br /></span></p>
<p>The cost to attend is $125, which covers one booth and two recruiters, as well as continental breakfast items, and lunch at our dining facility, The Crossroads. Additional recruiters are welcome to join us for $25 each.  If you need more booth space, additional booths are available on a limited basis for $25 each<br /><br /></p>
<h3>Career Week Activities</h3>
<p>Many activities are planned for students the week of February 21–24 in conjunction with the fair. These events will help students understand the importance of preparation, networking, and other activities related to successful futures.<br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li>Pair your Fair attendance with information sessions, group presentations, and/or individual interviews and appointments. We can provide you with rooms of many sizes and amenities that meet your needs. </li>
<li>You may post positions, interviews, and events on Career Navigator, our on-campus database, and prepare for the fair by reviewing résumés, scheduling interviews, taking RSVP’s for events, and more.</li>
</ul>
<p>We would love to have you on campus – please let us know if you’d like to host additional events, and we’ll get to work! Be sure to indicate your needs during registration, and we’ll contact you to discuss details.</p>
<br />
<h3>More Information</h3>
<p>Once you have registered, more details will be sent to you regarding the fair, activities, parking, and more. Please visit our website at <a href="default.htm">www.byui.edu/careerservices</a> for additional information – which will be updated regularly as the fair approaches.                                     <br /><br /></p>
<h3>Not Able to Attend?</h3>
<p>BYU-Idaho has an open-door recruiting policy, you are welcome to come to campus any time that is convenient for you. Just contact our office to schedule your visit, and we’ll do our best to accommodate your needs.<br /><br /> We also invite employers to utilize Career Navigator to post openings, review student résumés, schedule events and interviews, and more. <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/employers/index.php" target="_blank">Click here</a> to get started.                                     <br /><br /></p>
<h3>Thank you!</h3>
<p>We appreciate your support and participation of our BYU-Idaho students and programs.  Our goal is to provide valuable, top-level internship and career opportunities through organizations such as yours – as well as provide opportunities for you to meet and recruit our students for your own programs.  By hosting you at this event we hope to be able to meet your needs and those of our students.                                      <br /><br /></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
