<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x28167" Name="Who's Coming" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Who's Coming</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A list of employers and graduate schools that are coming to the BYU-Idaho Internship, Career and Graduate School fair on Wednesday October 5th.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><a href="#companies">Companies that are coming</a></p>
<p><a href="#gradschools">Graduate Schools that are coming</a></p>
<p><a href="#schooldistricts">School Districts that are coming</a></p>
<h2><a name="companies"></a>Companies</h2>
<h3>AMX International</h3>
<p><a href="www.amxinc.com" title="AMX International">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Communication, Computer Information Technology<br />AMX International, Inc. is a leading software consulting firm headquartered in Rexburg, Idaho.  AMX has the privilege to work with Oracle, one of the world’s largest software companies, as a partner to provide businesses with Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) and Customer Relationship Management (CRM) software solutions.  AMX provides clients with the resources and services needed to increase efficiency and lower costs.  For over 22 years, AMX has worked with clients around the world like the Government of Bermuda, Coca Cola, Master Image 3D, Zion’s Bank, Clif Bar, Spyder Active Sports, and the American Heart Association.<br />AMX has a long-standing relationship with Brigham Young University-Idaho, providing professional experiences and careers for students interested in the software industry.  Current opportunities include: Software Development, Business Development/Marketing, Sales, and Human Resources.</p>
<h3>AVA</h3>
<p><a href="http://americanvirtualacademy.com/" title="AVA">Website</a><br />Majors: Creative Writing, Computer Information Technology, Marketing, Professional Writing, Video<br />American Virtual Academy is one of the nation's premier online educational providers. We empower education through innovative technology and a commitment to keep students motivated to learn.</p>
<h3>Barton Consulting, LLC</h3>
<p><a href="bartonseo.com" title="Barton Consulting , LLC">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Communciations, Computer Science, English<br />Barton Consulting is a local Rexburg company that provides quality search engine optimization, web design, and web programming services.  Barton prides itself on their top notch skills and customer support. Barton is actively hiring talented computer programers, and internet marketers.</p>
<h3>Blackfoot Charter Community Learning Center</h3>
<p><a href="bbblc.com" title="Blackfoot Charter Community Learning Center">Website</a><br />Majors: Elementary Education<br />Will be looking to hire elementary teachers. (1st and 3rd Grade Teachers)</p>
<h3>Buckle, Inc.</h3>
<p><a href="www.buckle.com" title="Buckle, Inc.">Website</a><br />Majors:</p>
<h3>CBIZ MHM LLC</h3>
<p><a href="CBIZ.com" title="CBIZ MHM LLC">Website</a><br />Majors: Accounting<br />CBIZ MHM LLC, the 7th largest CPA firm in the nation is seeking interns for its Southern California Offices for the fall semester, 2012.</p>
<h3>CH Robinson</h3>
<p><a href="www.chrobinson.com/careers" title="CH Robinson">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Communications, Marketing, Transportation, Logistics<br />At C.H. Robinson Worldwide, Inc. our roots run deep. In 1905, Charles Henry Robinson started a small produce brokerage that developed the traditions and standards of service that shaped the Fortune 500 Company we are today. As a global provider of multimodal transportation and produce services, we are headquartered in Eden Prairie, MN and operate through a network of more than 7,000 employees in more than 235 offices in the United States, Canada, Mexico, Europe, Asia, South America, Australia, and the Middle East. We are the largest third party logistics (3PL) company in North America, and our services extend to more than 35,000 customers globally, ranging from other Fortune 500 companies to small businesses in a variety of industries. <br />Our people are our greatest asset and create a unique corporate culture that has built strong relationships with customers around the world. They execute our tradition of service on a daily basis and take pride in sustaining our dynamic leadership in the transportation logistics industry. You’ll feel the energy the moment you step into one of our branches. That energy is what inspires us to find motivated individuals to join us in our quest to find solutions, develop innovative technology, and provide exceptional service to our customers.</p>
<h3>China Horizons</h3>
<p><a href="www.chinahorizons.org" title="China Horizons">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors, Education<br />China Horizons offers short-term ESL cultural exchange programs with numerous schools throughout the People's Republic of China (PRC). We provide an authentic Chinese experience for honest, dedicated and creative English-speaking teachers. This unique experience promotes cultural awareness and deep immersion into the Chinese culture and way of life. An affordable semester long volunteer program (4-5 months) is available to those participants without a degree while paid positions are open to applicants with a BA/BS degree or higher and a minimum of 2 yrs. post graduate work experience. Chinese language knowledge is not required to apply. Applicants are placed with at least one other China Horizons participant during their stay at the host school.</p>
<h3>Circle Four Farms</h3>
<p><a href="www.murphybrownllc.com" title="Circle Four Farms">Website</a><br />Majors: Agriculture – Agbusiness, Animal Science etc.<br />Around here, people matter. We employ more than 6,000 across the country and offer a wide variety of career opportunities. Since we’ve grown Murphy-Brown into a vertically integrated company, you can find positions in every aspect of pork production. Our workforce is made up of people with a strong work ethic who thrive in a challenging yet stable environment.</p>
<ul>
What We Are Looking For:
<li>People with a strong desire to care for animals</li>
<li>Solid experience in swine production is preferred, but not required</li>
<li>Individuals with business and leadership skills</li>
<li>The ability to operate in a fast-paced, dynamic environment</li>
<li>A willingness to relocate</li>
<li>Strong communication skills (English/Spanish bilingual skills helpful)</li>
<li>A solid production-based background</li>
</ul>
<h3>Citizens for Decency</h3>
<p><a href="cleanminds.org" title="Citizens for Decency">Website</a><br />Majors: Communication, Political Science<br />Seeking to interview potential interns who are interested in making a difference via legislation, grassroots, and political activities to: empower persons to take a stand against pornography. Already Citizens for Decency has been instrumental in introducing and passing Idaho legislation which protects children in all Idaho schools and in all Idaho public libraries (beginning October 2012). Additionally, we have hosted many conferences in Southeastern Idaho which have provided specific benefits to ecclesiatical leaders, citizens, and families. Applicants must have a proven track record of increased responsibility and willingness to work hard for a worthy cause.</p>
<h3>Clearwater Analytics</h3>
<p><a href="http://clearwater-analytics.com/" title="Clearwater Analytics">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Computer Engineering<br />Clearwater is an innovative leader providing investment portfolio reporting and analytics for institutional investors in over 4,500 organizations. We leverage web-based software (SaaS) and world-class client service to maximize the visibility, transparency, accountability and efficiency of investment portfolios. With clients that span the insurance, technology and consumer sectors, to name a few, our solutions provide reporting and analytics on over $650 billion in assets. Corporate standouts like Group Health, 21st Century Insurance, WellCare, Cisco, Seagate, Oracle, Yahoo!, Costco, Netflix, Facebook, Best Buy and others trust Clearwater to navigate and streamline the complexities of aggregating, reconciling, validating and reporting on financial portfolios. We also partner with more than 50 custodians, asset managers, dealer/brokers and electronic trading portals to deepen the perspective and our reach into the financial world.<br /> Clearwater transforms the current, limiting status quo of portfolio reporting and reconciliation. Replacing laborious, manual aggregation and accounting, our solution matches the speed of the marketplace. Headquartered in dynamic and scenic Boise, Idaho, with an office in the financial district of New York City, Clearwater’s technology sets a standard for responsive and responsible investment portfolio reporting– making significant ripple effects throughout the industry.</p>
<h3>Clyde Companies, Inc.</h3>
<p><a href="www.clydeinc.com" title="Clyde Companies, Inc.">Website</a><br />Majors:<br />Clyde Companies, Inc., was formed in 1997 to consolidate the business entities owned and operated by the Clyde family and to provide support services for its five subsidiaries: W.W. Clyde and Company, Geneva Rock, Sunroc, Gorge Rock, and Beehive Insurance.<br /> These influential companies have been involved in almost every aspect of building and construction in the Intermountain West.</p>
<h3>Del Sol</h3>
<p><a href="www.delsol.com" title="Del Sol">Website</a><br />Majors:</p>
<h3>EMC</h3>
<p><a href="www.emc.com/college" title="EMC">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Engineering, Computer Science, Electical Engineering, Information Technology<br />EMC Corporation is a global leader in enabling businesses and service providers to transform their operations and deliver IT as a service. Fundamental to this transformation is cloud computing.  Through innovative products and services, EMC accelerates the journey to cloud computing, helping IT departments to store, manage, protect and analyze their most valuable asset, information in a more agile, trusted and cost-efficient way.</p>
<h3>Entheos Academy</h3>
<p><a href="entheosacademy.org" title="Entheos Academy">Website</a><br />Majors: Elememtary Education K-9, Middle School Art, Middle School Career and Technical Education, Middle School Language Arts, Middle School Math, Middle School P.E., Middle School Science, School Counselor, Special Education - Elementary,<br />Entheos Academy, an Expeditionary Learning Charter School serving grades K-9, is located in Kearns, Utah with a 2nd campus opening in the fall of 2012 in the Magna, Utah area. Each school serves approximately 500 students. Entheos has partnered with Expeditionary Learning Schools (ELS), one of the nations top ten school reform models, to implement its educational vision of a comprehensive education program emphasizing high academic achievement through active learning, character growth, service, and teamwork. Entheos Kearns was the first EL school in Utah.</p>
<h3>Fastenal</h3>
<p><a href="www.fastenal.com" title="Fastenal">Website</a><br />Majors: Business Management, Marketing<br />Seeking full and part-time sales employees for the sales and distribution of industrial and construction supplies.</p>
<h3>Grand Teton Council</h3>
<p><a href="www.grandtetoncouncil.org" title="Grand Teton Council">Website</a><br />Majors:</p>
<h3>Great Salt Lake Council: The Boy Scouts of America</h3>
<p><a href="saltlakescouts.org" title="Great Salt Lake Council: The Boy Scouts of America">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors <br />We are recruiting for summer employment at Boy Scout Camps.  There are supervisory positions available.  We are looking for LPN, RN or EMT personnel to act as first responders.  We are also looking for people in aquatic sports, shooting sports, outdoor skills, climbing sports, cooks and kitchen personnel etc.</p>
<h3>Heise Hot Springs</h3>
<p><a href="www.heisehotsprings.net" title="Heise Hot Springs">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Recreation<br />We are recruiting seasonal help for the summer of 2012. We also are offering internships.</p>
<h3>HELP International</h3>
<p><a href="help-international.org" title="HELP International">Website</a><br />Majors: Advertising &amp; Marketing, Art &amp; Music, Business, Biology, Construction Management, Education &amp; Elementary Ed, Engineering/Pre-engineering, English, Exercise Science, Finance &amp; Accounting, Health Science, History, Home and Family Living, Political Science, Public Health, Pre-Dental &amp; Pre-Med, Recreation Management, Social Work, Sociology<br />HELP is a registered 501(c)3 nonprofit organization specializing in three core competencies: (1) public health, (2) education and (3) entrepreneurship/business projects. Though HELP has engaged in primary aid relief in the form of earthquake and tsunami aftermath relief efforts, its primary drive is to work more in the context of secondary development relief with training initiatives, and program partnering. HELP currently runs programs in El Salvador, India, Uganda, Peru, Tanzania, Thailand, Belize and Fiji. HELP has grown and changed through the years and continues to focus on facilitating poverty alleviation worldwide by adhering to its mission to fight poverty and empower people</p>
<h3>Idaho Department of Health and Welfare</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.healthandwelfare.idaho.gov/" title="Idaho Department of Health and Welfare">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors, Business, Counseling, Education, Nursing, Occupational Therapy, Physical Therapy, Physician Assistant Studies, Public Health, Science, Social Work, Speech-Language Pathology<br />The Idaho Department of Health and Welfare offer programs that deal with complex social, economic and individual issues, often helping people in crisis situations. Our programs are designed to strengthen families and promote self-reliance. Last year, we served almost 340,000 people, one out of every four Idahoans. From birth throughout life, we strive to enrich and protect the lives of our state's citizens. As Idaho's largest state agency, we have close to 3,000 employees. Our positions range from Social Work to IT to Public and Environmental Health. We continously have needs for professionals with a variety of backgrounds, education and experience.</p>
<h3>Idaho Falls Crops</h3>
<p>Majors: <br />We are interested in an intern with a farming background to help with planting, record keeping, GPS, and harvest. They would also help with field work as well as driving truck.</p>
<h3>International Language Programs</h3>
<p><a href="www.ilp.org/taiwan" title="International Language Programs">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors<br />International Language Programs is a non-profit Organization based in Orem, UT. ILP sends volunteers to Russia, China, Ukraine, Mexico, and Thailand. ILP also has a paid teaching opportunity in Taiwan.</p>
<h3>Jacob Lake Inn</h3>
<p><a href="jacoblake.com" title="Jacob Lake Inn">Website</a><br />Majors: All majors<br />Jacob Lake Inn was established in 1923 and has provided an oasis for travelers visiting the North Rim of the Grand Canyon ever since. We have a hotel restaurant, gift shop, country store and service station and are looking for young people to staff positions in those areas. We guarantee at least $1,100.00 per month and we pay for housing and food. We provide a wonderful work environment and insist on LDS standards.</p>
<h3>Land O'Lakes, Inc.</h3>
<p><a href="www.mycoopcareers.com" title="Land O'Lakes, Inc.">Website</a><br />Majors: Agronomy, Agribusiness<br />Agronomy Scouting Internship<br /> (Freshman, Sophomore, Junior Level)<br /> Taking place at a local retailer, Agronomy Crop Scouting interns have a hands-on opportunity to connect classroom knowledge to the field first-hand.  The summer will consist of weed and insect identification, nutrient testing, soil sampling, making recommendations, miscellaneous operations work and providing customer service to growers.  This internship comes with strong technical training prior to the internship start date.  Although agronomy knowledge is helpful, no previous work experience is required.</p>
<p>Agronomy Sales and Marketing Internship<br /> (Junior, Senior Level)<br /> This experienced agronomy internship is the best way to expand on previous agronomy scouting internships.  The Sales and Marketing internship takes agronomy one step further with solid sales and product training. Intern responsibilities include; marketing Answer Plot sessions, conducting micronutrient testing, weed and insect identifications.</p>
<h3>LDS Church</h3>
<p><a href="ldschurch.jobs" title="LDS Church">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Management Information Systems<br />The Information and Communication Services Department of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints provides IT support for all departments of the Church.  We develop, support and maintain all Church software, web sites and technology for areas of the Church such as Seminaries and Institutes, Missionaries, Temples, Church History, LDS.org, operations, Members and Leaders, Facilities and eCommerce.  We are located in Riverton, Utah.</p>
<h3>LDS Church - Genealogy</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.familysearch.org/careers" title="LDS Church - Genealogy ">Website</a><br />Majors: Information Technology<br />Employees and Interns will gain experience supporting and delivering systems and services to users at Church Headquarters and millions of users throughout the world.<br /> These positions offer a unique and exciting opportunity to work for one of the largest Information Technology centers in the Wasatch Front.</p>
<h3>LegacyLifequote.com</h3>
<p><a href="legacylifequote.com" title="LegacyLifequote.com">Website</a><br />Majors: English and Marketing<br />LegacyLifequote is a National Insurance Company providing products and service for MetLIfe, American General, Prudential, Lincoln Financial, and ING, as well as other major providers through out the United Sates.</p>
<h3>Little America Hotels</h3>
<p><a href="littleamerica.com" title="Little America Hotels">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors<br />Little America has many great summer/fall work positions available. We also offer very inexpensive on-site housing, which provides you with a great opportunity to save money for school.</p>
<h3>Lov, Inc<a title="Lov, Inc."></a></h3>
<p><a href="www.jacksontradingco.com" title="Lov, Inc.">Website</a><br />Majors: All majors<br />We provide great off-track and summer jobs in the beautiful town of Jackson, Wyoming. We are a gift shop providing customer-service opportunities. Housing included - great job for first or second year students.</p>
<h3>Managed Wealth Financial</h3>
<p><a href="www.managedwealthfinancial.com" title="Managed Wealth Financial">Website</a><br />Majors: Accounting, Business, Finance, Marketing<br />We're looking to develop the Champion in you. Would you like to be a part of Financial Revolution? We are making a difference, and want those who are for the noble cause of serving families with great services, concepts, and opportunity.</p>
<h3>Maurices</h3>
<p><a href="maurices.com" title="Maurices">Website</a><br />Majors: Business Management, Clothing Contruction, Fashion Merchandising, Marketing<br />Our ideal candidate has a history of accomplishment in school, work and outside interests as well as the drive, desire and determination to succeed.  We have high expectations for our associates and our management team. Candidates should have some sort of retail or service background (not necessarily clothing retail).  We currently are seeking part time sales associates, part time/full time assistant managers, Store Manager candidates and summer internship candidates.</p>
<h3>Melaleuca, Inc.</h3>
<p><a href="www.melaleuca.jobs" title="Melaleuca, Inc.">Website</a><br />Majors: Accounting, Business Management<br />Melaleuca is among the fastest growing health and wellness companies in the world. We are searching for bright, motivated individuals to work in our global headquarters in Idaho Falls. You can enjoy a lifelong career with a multi-national company without ever leaving Southeast Idaho, where good schools and safe, values-oriented communities abound. We invite you to learn more at our campus presentation and booth at the career fair.</p>
<h3>North Fork Native Plants</h3>
<p><a href="northforknativeplants.com" title="North Fork Native Plants">Website</a><br />Majors: Horticulture<br />North Fork Native Plants is a native plant nursery located west of Rexburg.  We are looking for general laborers and an intern for the summer.</p>
<h3>Northwest Farm Credit Services</h3>
<p><a href="www.magnificentcareers.net" title="Northwest Farm Credit Services">Website</a><br />Majors:<br />We are the Northwest's leading agricultural lender and crop insurance provider. As a customer-owned, financial services cooperative, we provide more than $9 billion in credit and related services to those who make their home and livelihood in rural America. Northwest FCS is a cooperatively owned lending association specializing in financing farmers, ranchers, agribusinesses, commercial fishermen, timber producers, and country home owners in ID, MT, OR, WA, and AK. We also provide leasing services, appraisal services, and life, mortgage, disability, and crop insurance programs. We serve our customers through 44 branch offices located throughout the Northwest and our corporate headquarters office in Spokane, Washington.   Northwest FCS is part of the 90-year-old Farm Credit System, the largest single provider of credit to American agriculture.</p>
<h3>Northwestern Mutual Financial Network</h3>
<p><a href="www.nmfn.com/internship" title="Northwestern Mutual Financial Network">Website</a><br />Majors:Business and financial economics/ economics<br />The Northwestern Mutual Financial Network (NML) offers career opportunities to establish personal relationships and help clients plan for their financial needs in the areas of risk management, wealth accumulation, and wealth distribution. We focus on individuals with backgrounds in sales, marketing, finance, accounting, and management. There are no set salaries, as compensation is commission based and depends on personal production. Relocation options are available as NML has offices throughout the country.</p>
<h3>Novell, Inc.</h3>
<p><a href="novell.com" title="Novell, Inc.">Website</a><br />Majors:<br />Novell, Inc., is a global enterprise software provider delivering solutions that make work environments more productive, secure and manageable. Novell supports thousands of organizations around the world with collaboration, endpoint management, and file and networking technologies, all of which drive end-user productivity directly or on the backend.<br />Novell reaches businesses of all types and sizes in 43 countries around the world. But we're still personable enough to know your name. You'll find career development programs, benefits and lifestyle perks, and the chance to be part of the IT industry's top solutions.</p>
<h3>Prosper</h3>
<p><a href="www.prospercareers.com" title="Prosper">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors<br />If you're looking for a work environment that challenges your mind, rewards your accomplishments and recognizes the value you can add to the team, then Prosper may be the company for you. <br />We are always searching for top talent, and we offer healthy salaries and benefits, including Personal Time Off, 401(k), medical, dental and vision insurance, and flex medical spending accounts. Our sales commissions are also highly competitive. <br />When you join the Prosper team, you also become part of our unique corporate culture that provides opportunity for your personal growth and advancement. We are a professional organization built on relationships, doing the right thing, focusing on solutions, and keeping promises. <br />Prosper is an equal opportunity employer. If you have the talent, we have the position for you.</p>
<h3>The McPartland Group of Guardian Life Insurance</h3>
<p><a href="www.mcpartlandgroup.com" title="The McPartland Group of Guardian Life Insurance">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors<br />The McPartland Group of Guardian Life was founded with the goal of assisting our clients in every aspect of their financial lives.  We've provided the most personal service available, thus earning us a reputation for excellence in our industry.  For each of our clients we strive to help create financial stability and security to provide financial independence.</p>
<h3>The Sherwin Williams Company</h3>
<p><a href="www.sherwin-williams.com" title="The Sherwin Williams Company">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors, College Intern, Management/Sales Training Program<br />Since its founding by Henry Sherwin and Edward Williams in 1866,  The Sherwin-Williams Company has not only grown to be the largest producer of paints and coatings in the United States, but is among the largest producers in the world.</p>
<h3>Trapper Trails Council</h3>
<p><a href="www.trappertrails.org/camps" title="Trapper Trails Council">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors <br />Need a summer job?  Work at our Summer Camps!  Rock climbing, scuba, swimming, boating, horses, hiking, and camp administration.  Stop by our booth and learn more!</p>
<h3>Troops to Teachers</h3>
<p><a href="montana.edu/ttt" title="Troops to Teachers">Website</a><br />Majors:</p>
<h3>United States Army</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.goarmy.com" title="United States Army">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors</p>
<h3>United States Marine Corps</h3>
<p><a href="marineofficer.com" title="United States Marine Corps">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors</p>
<h3>USAA</h3>
<p><a href="www.usaa.com/careers" title="USAA">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Information Technology<br />As a Fortune 200 financial services company with more than $147 billion in owned and managed assets, USAA is on a mission to facilitate the financial security of our members, the men and women of the U.S. military and their families worldwide. Headquartered on a showcase campus in San Antonio, Texas, USAA attributes its long-standing success to its most valuable resource, our 24,000 employees. They are the heart and soul of our member-service culture.</p>
<h3>Walt Disney World</h3>
<p><a href="www.disneyinterns.com" title="Walt Disney World">Website</a><br />Majors: Agricultural Education, Agricultural Engineering, Agriculture, Agronomy, Aquaculture, Biology, Biotechnology, Entomology, Horticulture, Landscape Engineering, Marine Biology, Soil Science<br />The Agricultural Sciences Professional Internship Program is designed to provide qualified college students with the opportunity for hands-on work experience in the unique growing areas that are part of Living with The Land, an agricultural attraction at Epcot.</p>
<h3>Yellowstone Bear World</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.yellowstonebearworld.com" title="Yellowstone Bear World">Website</a><br />Majors:</p>
<h3>Zion Ponderosa Resort</h3>
<p><a href="zionponderosa.com" title="Zion Ponderosa Resort">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors, Park Recreation Tourism<br />Zion Ponderosa is located on the east side of Zion National Park.</p>
<h2><a name="gradschools"></a>Graduate Schools</h2>
<h3>Brigham Young University</h3>
<p><a href="http://marriottschool.byu.edu/mpa/" title="BYU" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Programs: MPA<br />The Romney Institute MPA emphasizes practical management training by supplementing faculty lectures with team projects, field research, case analysis, and internships. The program's integrated curriculum prepares students to meet the demands of public service with a strong understanding of sound management principles. Core courses are taught in analysis, public-sector accounting, communications, statistics, economics, financial management, human resources, ethics, organization and management, and the environment of public administration. Equipped with valuable technical skills and general management knowledge, Romney Institute MPA graduates are well prepared to become leaders in the public arena.</p>
<h3>Cleveland Chiropractic College</h3>
<p><a href="www.cleveland.edu" title="Cleveland Chiropractic College" target="_blank">Website</a><br />For more than eight decades, Cleveland Chiropractic College has been the place to learn this science, philosophy and art. More than one in every 10 chiropractors practicing in North America is a Cleveland graduate. A career in chiropractic gives you the freedom to determine how, where and in what specialty areas you will practice.  At Cleveland Chiropractic College, you will put health and healing into your own two hands.</p>
<h3>Concordia University School of Law</h3>
<p><a href="www.concordialaw.com" title="Concordia University School of Law" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Concordia University School of Law is a new law school located in Boise, Idaho.  Our inaugural class will begin Fall 2012.  We are currently accepting applications for our full-time and part-time scheduling options.</p>
<h3>Idaho State University</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.isu.edu/cob/" title="Idaho State University" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
<h3>University of Idaho</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.uidaho.edu/cogs" title="University of Idaho" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Programs: Accountancy, Agricultural Sciences<br />As the graduate degree-granting college for the University of Idaho, the College of Graduate Studies combines nationally competitive academic and research opportunities,  the kind you'd expect at a large metro institution with the small town, hands-on approach that will jumpstart your research and your career.</p>
<h3>University of Wyoming College of Law</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.uidaho.edu/cogs" title="University of Wyoming College of Law" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Programs: Law<br />The University of Wyoming College of Law may be the smallest public law school in the country, but the quality of education and diversity of experiential learning opportunities rival our national competitors. Small class sizes promote student-faculty interactions that are often unavailable at larger institutions; our classrooms and moot courtrooms offer state-of-the-art technology and design; four clinical programs, an international human rights practicum, a rural law center, and growing externship and internship programs give our graduates the experience they need to hit the ground running when they enter the legal profession; and, our faculty bring expertise and experience to the classroom while maintaining active contributions to legal research and inquiry. The college is proud of what it has to offer prospective students.</p>
<h3>Utah College Of Dental Hygiene</h3>
<p><a href="www.ucdh.edu" title="Utah College Of Dental Hygiene" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Earn your pre-requisites at BYU-I and transfer to our 20-month bachelors degree in Dental Hygiene. Located in Provo.</p>
<h3>Utah State University - Graduate School</h3>
<p><a href="www.usu.edu/graduateschool/" title="Utah State University" target="_blank">Website</a><br />As a Carnegie Doctoral/Research Extensive University, USU ranks among America's leading research institutions. USU's distinguished faculty work closely with graduate students to create a rigorous, yet relaxed, learning environment that promotes strong collegial ties between faculty and students. Graduate degrees are offered by 40 departments, and include 96 master's programs, 38 doctoral programs, as well as six educational specialist and one civil engineer degree. Nationally and internationally known research units support many graduate degree programs, and graduate students typically are actively involved as research assistants and teaching assistants in their discipline. In addition, a wide variety of financial assistance is available to USU graduate students.</p>
<h3>Utah State University - Jon M. Huntsman School of Business</h3>
<p><a href="http://huntsman.usu.edu/mba/" title="Utah State University" target="_blank">Website</a><br />The Huntsman School of Business at Utah State University offers a one-year, on-campus MBA, streamlined to provide the knowledge and tools necessary to compete in today's global business environment with an innovative and cost-effective program.  The mission of the Huntsman MBA program is to provide students with a relevant and rigorous background in business subject matter, to increase student problem-solving and critical analysis skills, and to develop the next generation of managers and leaders.</p>
<h3>Weber State University</h3>
<p><a href="http://weber.edu" title="Weber State University" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
<h3>Willamette University MBA</h3>
<p><a href="www.willamette.edu/mba" title="Willamette University MBA" target="_blank">Website</a><br />The Willamette Early Career and Career Change MBA is an excellent choice for recent college graduates and applicants with limited work experience who are seeking their first professional position or career change. Previous work experience is not required.<br /> The program features an excellent faculty, an integrated curriculum that provides the knowledge and perspective required for management decision-making, a full program of career services and student organizations, and resume building professional experience through internships, class consulting projects with real clients and a realm of innovative courses that emphasize learning by doing."</p>
<h2><a name="schooldistricts"></a>School Districts</h2>
<h3>Aberdeen School District</h3>
<p><a href="www.aberdeen58.org" title="Aberdeen School District" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
<h3>Cache County School District</h3>
<p><a href="www.ccsdut.org" title="Cache County School District" target="_blank">Website</a><br />The Cache County School District is located in the beautiful Cache Valley 80 miles north of Salt Lake City.  This pristine mountain valley offers a multitude of outdoor recreation activities, world-class cultural venues, a dynamic and growing economy and a quality of life that is truly unmatched.<br />For more information regarding the picturesque Cache Valley, please visit <a href="www.tourcachevalley.com" title="Cache Valley">www.tourcachevalley.com</a><br />Cache County School District serves the entire Utah portion of Cache Valley except for Logan City and is the valley’s third largest employer.  The Cache County School District focuses on academic rigor, professional development and student achievement at all levels.  Cache County students test well above their state and national counterparts on a consistent basis.  Cache County School District is a fantastic district in which to build or continue your educational career.  Cache County School District is truly a great place to teach!</p>
<h3>Cassia Jt. School District No. 151</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.sd151.k12.id.us/" title="Cassia Jt. School District No. 151" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Various positions, Burley Jr. High School, Math, Physical Education, Raft River High School</p>
<h3>Clark County School District #161</h3>
<p><a href="www.clarkcountyschools161.org" title="Clark County School District #161" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
<h3>Grace Joint School District #148</h3>
<p><a href="www.sd148.org" title="Grace Joint School District #148" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Clark County School District is a small, rural district that shares a northern border with Montana. We currently have possible openings in Music and 1 Elementary position.</p>
<h3>Idaho Falls School District 91</h3>
<p><a href="www.d91.k12.id.us" title="Idaho Falls School District 91" target="_blank">Website</a><br />The children of Idaho Falls School District 91 are served by child-centered, dedicated educators who strive to meet the individual needs of their students.  Idaho Falls is an innovative and progressive district whose primary mission is serving all children.  Idaho Falls offers an outstanding three-year mentoring program, providing support and mentoring opportunities to teachers new to our district.  Our district also has an exceptional, ongoing professional development program, offering courses both online and in traditional classroom settings.  If you are passionate about children and teaching, Idaho Falls is where you will thrive as a teacher!</p>
<h3>Jefferson School District #251</h3>
<p><a href="sd251.org" title="Jefferson School District #251" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Jefferson School District #251 has 5 elementary schools, 1 middle school, 1 junior high, and 2 high schools. There are approximatley 4,900 students and over 400 employees. The district is located between Idaho Falls and Rexburg, Idaho.</p>
<h3>The Lake and Peninsula School District</h3>
<p><a href="www.lpsd.com" title="The Lake and Peninsula School District" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Lincoln County School District #2 in Afton, Wyoming is one of the premier districts in terms of student achievement, curriculum, facilities, technology, salary and benefits.</p>
<h3>Lincoln County School District #2</h3>
<p><a href="www.lcsd2.org" title="Lincoln County School District #2" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Lincoln County School District #2 in Afton, Wyoming is one of the premier districts in terms of student achievement, curriculum, facilities, technology, salary and benefits.</p>
<h3>Morgan School District</h3>
<p><a href="www.morgan.k12.ut.us" title="Morgan School District" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
<h3>Teton School District 401</h3>
<p><a href="http://tsd401.org" title="Teton School District 401" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Teton School District 401 located in Teton Valley, Idaho, looks to hire teachers that are focused on excellence in themselves, their students, their school and their community.</p>
<h3>Uinta County School District #1</h3>
<p><a href="www.uinta1.com" title="Uinta County School District #1" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Evanston is nestled in the foothills of the beautiful Uinta Mountains at an elevation of 6,794 feet above sea level. It is located on the banks of the winding Bear River in the far southwest ocrner of Wyoming. The community is only three miles east of the Utah/Wyoming border and only an hour and a half way from Salt Lake City, UT. Our mission is to provide powerful instruction that is relevant and challenging. We commit to provide daily experiences that prepare students for the 21st century, build positive relationships and encourage maximum student effort.</p>
<h3>Weber School District</h3>
<p><a href="www.wsd.net" title="Weber School District" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Weber School District: Lifelong learning at its best</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
