<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x28992" Name="New York City Service Missionary" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">New York City Service Missionaries</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A short biography and contact information for the New York City Service Missionary</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div style="float: left; width: 200px;"><img alt="New York Service Missionary" height="250" src="Images/advising/missionaries/Ibanez.jpg" title="New York Service Missionary" width="200" />
<p style="margin: 0;"><strong>Sister Nelly Ibanez</strong></p>
<em>43-16 53rd Street Apt 1E<br /> New York, NY 11377</em>
<p style="margin: 10px 0 0 0;">Home: (718) 476-1581<br />Cell: (917) 658-9095</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 25px;"><a href="mailto:nbibanez@aol.com" onclick="
	var s = s_gi(s_account);
	s.linkTrackVars='events';
	s.linkTrackEvents='event4';
	s.events='event4';
	s.tl(this,'o','Service Missionary Email');
	" title="Email the New York City Service Missionary">nbibanez@aol.com</a></p>
<p><a href="x28991.xml">Learn more about New York City &raquo;</a></p>
</div>
<div style="width: 475px; float: right;">
<p>I was born in Colombia, South America and I am the oldest child of six. I have four sisters and a brother who died in his childhood. When I was 8 years old my parents came to the United States and left me and my two younger sisters in the care of my paternal Grandmother and Aunt. My Grandmother was a positive influence in my spiritual development. She enrolled me in Catholic school, made sure I went to mass on Sundays, and also taught me to say my prayers every night before going to bed.</p>
<p>At the age of ten (10) I was reunited with my parents and a new baby sister and one on the way and two years later they had a boy. My parents were non-practicing Catholics. We only went to Church on Easter Sunday, baptisms and weddings. Even though we did not attend any Church I knew in my heart that my Heavenly Father loved me and that he answered my prayers. Most of my life I have lived in New York City where I attended grade school all the way to 2 years of College, but I didn&rsquo;t graduate. In 1980 I got married, didn&rsquo;t have any children and my ex-husband was also a non-practicing Catholic.</p>
<p>I started working for the New York City Department of Sanitation in 1981. I started as a clerk and moved up the ranks to Administrative Assistant to the Executive Assistant to the Commissioner of Sanitation.</p>
<p>In 1990 I realized that I needed to get closer to my Heavenly Father and needed him in my life. I decided to go back to Church and naturally I went to my neighborhood Catholic Church since I considered myself a Catholic. Once there I felt so alone instead of feeling comforted. At first, I thought that it was because this particular Church building was dark and kind of gloomy, and also because I had been away so long that I felt like a stranger in a strange place. I then decided to give it another try and went to another Catholic Church with my neighbors. The Church building was much brighter and cheery than the one I had attended the previous Sunday. Even thought, I was with friends and in a different atmosphere I still felt there was something missing, but I didn&rsquo;t know what it was at the time. I then decided that going to Church was not for me.</p>
<p>After a couple weeks of making that decision, I happened to see a commercial on TV about the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints. As I listened to the message, I felt the spirit so strongly that I knew that this feeling was what I was missing before. I immediately called the number and asked for a book of Mormon to be sent to me. A week later I received a phone call and was asked if I wanted the Missionaries to visit my home. As soon as I heard the first discussion I knew in my heart that I had found what I was looking for. I had no bought whatsoever that I wanted to be baptized when the Missionaries asked me. I was baptized on July 30, 1990 which was also a special day, my mother&rsquo;s birthday.</p>
<p>My then husband did not accept the gospel but I was grateful that he supported me in my decision and was always nice to the many missionaries who came to visit and all the Church members.</p>
<p>In 1994 we bought a house and moved to New Jersey where I continued to grow spiritually and served in many callings. Unfortunately, as I grew stronger in the gospel my ex-husband became involved with people that were not doing the right things and he changed for the worse instead of becoming a better person. I had to make the hard decision that for my spiritual well being I had to get a divorce.</p>
<p>I moved back to New York City to be with my family in 2001. My mom passed away and I moved in with my Dad after her death. After 31 years with the NYC Dept. of Sanitation I retired at the age of 57 and now I am looking forward to enjoying my retirement with my family which has grown quite a bit. I have 8 nieces, 5 nephews and two grand-nieces and one on the way. I also want to serve as much as I can and I&rsquo;m looking forward to this new calling as a BYU-Idaho Career Internship Missionary.</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x87843" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
