<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x28936" Name="Job Search Tips" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Job Search Tips</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A list of several suggestions for those who are searching for a job.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<ul>
<li>A positive first impression is very important. Dress appropriately for the occasion and make sure that your materials look professional.</li>
<li>Always be professional. Even with casual encounters with other employees, conduct yourself as if you were already in the interview.</li>
<li>Networking is one of the most effective ways to get a job. Don't hesitate to contact those you know who are in the industry you want to join.</li>
<li>Ask people before you list them as a reference on your application or r&eacute;sum&eacute;.</li>
<li>Proof-read everything that you send to an employer.</li>
<li>Prepare for the interview. Do your homework about the company and the position. It is obvious to the employer when you don't. Also be prepared for common questions.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Be courageous and confident. Look people in the eyes. Know your own skills and qualities.</li>
<li>If you are willing to relocate, you will often have a better chance of finding employment. Some cities are faster growing, more economically healthy, and have lower unemployment rates.</li>
<li>Every job has its positives and negatives. Find a job where you will be comfortable and able to learn and contribute.</li>
<li>Don't get discouraged; searching for a job can be a challenge, no matter how qualified you are.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p></p>
<hr />
<p></p>
<h1><strong>Safe Job Searching</strong></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">While we try to screen employers and the positions they post to Career Navigator, it is very important that you as a job seeker exercise common sense and caution. You should read position descriptions carefully.</span></p>
<h3>Here are some red flags:</h3>
<ul>
<li>You are asked to give credit card, bank or any financial account numbers</li>
<li>You are asked to send a payment by wire service, courier or money orders</li>
<li>You are asked to perform any monetary transactions</li>
<li>You receive any check that is not your paycheck</li>
<li>Offers you a job without ever interacting with you</li>
<li>You are asked for personal information through email or phone</li>
<li>You are requested to send a photo copy of your ID, i.e., driver's license to "verify identity"</li>
<li>Offers to pay for almost no work</li>
<li>Posting does not indicate the company name, or&nbsp;says it is from a reputable company, but comes from a non-corporate email address&nbsp;</li>
<li>Job posting doesn't mention the responsibilities of the job; rather it focuses on the amount of money&nbsp; you will make.</li>
<li>Craigslist is not a good resource for finding a job</li>
<li>Posting/Email tells you they "don't have time" to do the work themselves, it's easier/quicker to find someone else to do it for them</li>
<li>Offers to pay you before you do any work</li>
</ul>
<p>Also, please be aware that there are fake job postings being sent via email. Some may even tell you that they got your email address or resume from your school's career center; this is untrue.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">For emails: Do not click on links or provide any personal information.</span></p>
<ul></ul>
<h3>If you encounter suspicious postings in Career Navigator or receive a questionable email:</h3>
<ol>
<li>End all communication with the employer, and if personal information was disclosed, contact your bank and monitor your accounts closely.</li>
<li>Please report your experience to the Academic Discovery Center at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:careernavigator@byui.edu" title="Email" target="_blank">careernavigator@byui.edu</a> or 208-496-9800 (so we can remove the postings) and to&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ic3.gov/">The Internet Crime Complaint Center</a></li>
<li>If the scam is local please contact the local police and report the fraud or scam.</li>
<li>If you have sent money to a fraudulent employer, contact your bank or credit card company immediately to close your account and dispute the charges.</li>
<li>If the incident occurred entirely over the internet, file an incident report with the FCC at 1-877-FTC-HELP (1-877-382-4357) or at http://www.cybercrime.gov.</li>
</ol>
<h3>More Resources for Safe Online Job Searching:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://ftc.gov/jobscams">Job-Hunting/Job Scams</a> from the Federal Trade Commission</li>
<li><a href="http://www.worldprivacyforum.org/resumedatabaseprivacytips.html">World Privacy Forum: Job Seekers' Guide to Resumes: Twelve Resume Posting Truths</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.privacyrights.org/fs/fs25a-JobSeekerPriv2.htm">Privacy Rights Clearinghouse: Avoiding Online Job Scams</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bankrate.com/brm/news/pf/20060321c2.asp">6 Safety Tips for Online Job Seekers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://career-advice.monster.com/job-search/Getting-Started/A-Safe-Job-Search/article.aspx">Monster.com: A Safe Job Search</a></li>
</ul>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x87843" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
