<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x28920" Name="On Campus Recruiting" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">On Campus Recruiting</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Information for recruiters who wish to visit BYU-Idaho campus, including available amenities, recruitment opportunities, and recruiting policies.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2>Visit our Campus!</h2>
<ul>
<li>Schedule information sessions, group presentations, and/or individual interviews and appointments. We can provide you with rooms of many sizes and amenities that meet your needs.</li>
<li>Post positions, interviews, and events on Career Navigator, our on-campus database, and prepare for your recruiting session by reviewing résumés, scheduling interviews, taking RSVP's for events, and more.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="x24268.xml" title="Contact Us">Contact us</a> to schedule your visit.</p>
<ul>
</ul>
<p>Employers are welcome to visit our campus any time during the year. Visiting our campus in this informal atmosphere gives you a chance to meet our students, one-on-one, and recruit full- or part-time employees for your business or organization. You also have the opportunity to speak with students about possible internship positions within your organization. Additionally, the Academic Discovery Center can provide a quiet, distraction-free environment for your convenience in conducting on-campus interviews.</p>
<p>Pair your on-campus interview schedule with an information session as an additional recruiting tool for students and alumni. At an information session, you will be able to directly network and interact with potential candidates.</p>
<p>Once you secure a date(s) for on-campus recruiting, qualified students will be notified of your upcoming visit via our campus newspaper, The Scroll, and by email. Other advertising venues may include bulletin boards and posters, a booth in the Manwaring Center (our "student union" building), class visits and other marketing tools.</p>
<p><a class="intLink" href="x24268.xml" title="Contact Us">Contact Us</a> to schedule your visit.</p>
<h2>On-campus Recruiting Policies</h2>
<p>All employers recruiting on campus must meet the following guidelines:</p>
<ul>
<li>All visitors must be sponsored by the ADC (or an academic department or college)</li>
<li>All printed materials, brochures, etc. must be university approved before being distributed.</li>
<li>Printed materials, marketing tools, etc may not be distributed on campus except from approved locations. Materials may not be handed out on sidewalks, in lobbies, outside classrooms, etc.</li>
<li>All booths, information sessions, etc must be scheduled in University approved venues. Organizations may not set up booths without obtaining permission.</li>
<li>The University does not allow travelling display vehicles, trailers or vans to be parked on campus for recruiting purposes including, but not limited to, food service/distribution, vendor trucks, display trailers, etc.</li>
<li>All backdrops/displays must meet university guidelines, and should follow the BYU-Idaho Honor Code in regard to decency in images, language, etc. Tablecloths and backdrops that meet standards are allowed in booths and sessions.</li>
<li>Catering should be approved in advance. No outside food may be brought into the Manwaring Center, regardless of venue or recruiting session. <a class="extLink" href="http://www.byui.edu/foodservices" title="Food Services" target="_blank">University Catering</a> is available for all events in the Manwaring Center.</li>
<li>The ADC reserves the right to allow organizations to recruit on campus.        
<ul>
<li><strong>Full-time Jobs </strong>- Those organizations that hire for career opportunities with salaried positions, benefits, training, and a reputable history will be promoted by the ADC. Organizations that do not match these criteria will be reviewed by the ADC.</li>
<li><strong>Part-time Jobs </strong>- Those organizations that hire for part-time opportunities with hourly wage positions, training and a reputable history will be promoted by the Career Placement office. Organizations that do not match these criteria will be reviewed by the Career Placement and Internship Committee.</li>
<li><strong>Seasonal Jobs: </strong>Those organizations that hire for temporary/seasonal positions with salaried positions, training and a reputable history will be promoted by the Career Placement office. Organizations that do not match these criteria will be reviewed by the Career Placement and Internship Committee.</li>
<li><strong>Commission Sales Jobs</strong>- Those organizations that hire for commission sales opportunities are not permitted to recruit on campus. Commissions-based companies with a reputable history are allowed to post jobs on BYU-Idaho's website with the condition that no start up or training fees may be required of the student or the graduate. Organizations that do not match these criteria will be reviewed by the Career Placement and Internship Committee.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<div>
<p><strong>University policy does not allow us to post positions of the following types in our database or on our campus bulletin boards, nor are these businesses approved to recruit on campus:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Third-party recruiting services</li>
<li>Personal Services-including, but not limited to nanny's, babysitters, yard keepers, housekeepers, etc.*</li>
<li>Direct Sales-including, but not limited to pest control sales, alarm sales, satellite sales, and door-to-door sales       
<ul>
<li>PLEASE NOTE:  In addition to not posting direct sales positions, university policy does not allow us to post ANY positions for direct sales companies</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other positions that do not appear to fit the University's guidelines for employment postings.</li>
</ul>
<p>* Personal services may be posted on our <a class="intLink" href="x32480.xml" title="Help Wanted Postings">student Help Wanted page</a>.</p>
<p><strong>If you need alternative methods to advertise your position to students, there are several resources available to you for job postings. </strong></p>
<table border="1" width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p>LDS Employment</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>208-523-4880 or 208-359-1446</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Idaho Department of Labor (Job Service)</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>208-557-2501 or <a href="http://labor.idaho.gov/" title="Idaho Department of Labor" target="_blank">labor.idaho.gov</a></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Express Personnel</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>208-529-2661 or <a href="http://expresspersonnel.com/" title="Express Personnel Staffing Services" target="_blank">expresspersonnel.com</a></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Gem State Staffing</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>208-528-8900</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>BYU-I Scroll</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>208-496-2900</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
