<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 6.0.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<BlankDetailPage ID="x29073" Name="Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries" Layout="default.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries at BYU-Idaho</MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x14" Name="RelatedLinks" label="Related Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="RelatedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><a href="#1">What is ecology, range, wild life and fisheries?</a></p>
<p><a href="#2">Why should I consider majoring in ecology, range, wild life and fisheries?</a></p>
<p><a href="#1">Emphasis in ecology</a></p>
<p><a href="#2">Emphasis in wild life and fisheries<br /></a></p>
<p><a href="#3">Emphasis in range</a></p>
<p><a href="#4">What interests and values are related to ecology, range, wild life and fisheries?</a></p>
<p><a href="#5">What career fields related to ecology, range, wild life and fisheries?</a></p>
<p><a href="#6">How can I learn more about ecology, range, wild life and fisheries?</a></p>
<p> </p>
<h2><a name="1"></a>What is ecology, range, wild life and fisheries?</h2>
<p>Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries all are the study of organisms and their relationship with the environment and how we can become better stewards of the outdoors. Each area focuses on specific organisms and their environment. The study of Range focuses on prevention and restoration of depleted vegetation or alterations of the terrain due to overgrazing or other environmental changes. Wild life and fisheries focuses on the conservation of wild animals and aquatic animals.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><a name="2"></a>Why should I consider majoring in Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries?</h2>
<p>A degree in Ecology, Range, Wild life and Fisheries provides a foundation for natural resource related fields with emphases in Ecology, Range or Wild Life and Fisheries. Natural resources and conservation is a broad, interdisciplinary field of study that addresses the management, protection, use, restoration, and enjoyment of the Earth’s resources.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr />
<h4><a name="3"></a>Emphasis in Ecology</h4>
<p>Ecology is a science that focuses on the relationship between organisms and their environment (ecology.com). Ecologists study the effects of population size, rainfall, temperature and altitude. They may also collect, study and report data of the quality of air, food, soil and water (bls.gov).</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr />
<h4><a name="4"></a>Emphasis in Wild Life and Fisheries</h4>
<p>Fisheries explore the biology and ecology of fishes and other aquatic species. Courses cover both basic science and applied aspects of commercial and recreational fishing activities. Fisheries management is a science-based field that requires you to understand and apply principles of biology, ecology, statistics and social sciences. Fisheries management assesses and stock fish populations; improve habitats for certain species to protect biodiversity and interact with the public. Wildlife deals with conservation of animal populations, ranging from those that are regularly hunted to those that are considered endangered and the habitats in which these animals are found.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What will I learn from studying Wild Life and Fisheries?</h2>
<p>Most of your courses are in biology, but you must also take chemistry, mathematics, and statistics; anatomy and vertebrate zoology courses such as ornithology and mammalogy. You will take lab courses which are strongly field oriented. During lab you will directly work with animal populations and their habitats. In labs you will acquire firsthand knowledge of how and where the animals that you study in the classroom live. You will also take field techniques, ichthyology (the study of fishes), and fish ecology; freshwater ecology, human dimensions of fisheries and wildlife management, aquaculture and a capstone course in fisheries.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What interests and values are related to Wild Life and Fisheries?</h2>
<p>If you like fishing, boating, or hiking; working with your hands as well as your mind; keeping an aquarium or raising live animals; learning about living creatures and natural ecosystems; Outdoor activities such as hiking, camping, fishing and hunting; science; Scouting; caring for animals; bird watching; natural history museums; zoos; travel; learning about the natural world.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr />
<h4><a name="5"></a>Emphasis in Range</h4>
<p>The Range emphasis is designed for students who are interested in the management of rangeland ecosystems and the livestock, wildlife and human interests that depend on them. Students in this major will learn principles and skills that prepare them to be rangeland managers and stewards.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What will I learn from studying Range?</h2>
<p>Course work focuses on the main points of Animal Science, Botany, Ecology, Natural Resource Policy and Soil Science. Range managers prevent overgrazing and deterioration of vegetation.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><a name="4"></a>What interests and values are related to Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries?</h2>
<p>If you like fishing, boating, or hiking; working with your hands as well as your mind; keeping an aquarium or raising live animals; learning about living creatures and natural ecosystems; Outdoor activities such as hiking, camping, fishing and hunting; science; Scouting; caring for animals; bird watching; natural history museums; zoos; travel; learning about the natural world.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><a name="5"></a>What career fields related to Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries?</h2>
<p>Ecology is designed to be somewhat broader and should be taken by students interested in careers in:</p>
<ul>
<li>Conservation</li>
<li>Biology</li>
<li>Botany</li>
<li>Natural history education</li>
<li>Park ranger</li>
<li>Natural resource policy and law</li>
<li>Post graduate work in other ecological fields</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2><a name="6"></a>How can I learn more about Ecology, Range, Wild Life and Fisheries?</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bls.gov/OCO/">Occupational Outlook Handbook</a></p>
<p><a href="x23114.xml">DISCOVER Career Guidance and Information System</a></p>
<p> </p>
<h4>Contact Source:</h4>
<p>College of Agriculture &amp; Life Sciences Academic Discovery Center</p>
<p>Location: Benson 240</p>
<p>Phone: 208-496-9830</p>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:CALSacademicdiscoverycenter@byui.edu" title="Email the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences' Academic Discovery Center">CALSacademicdiscoverycenter@byui.edu</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ImageComponent" Name="LeftColumnImageComponentList" label="Left Column Image Component List" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1777" Name="ImageComponent" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x946" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></BlankDetailPage>
