<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x29021" Name="Internship FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Internship FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently asked questions and important information about academic internships at BYU-Idaho.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Do I have to do an internship?</strong></p>
<p>Internship requirements vary by major. Check with your <a href="x24268.xml" id="link4" title="Contact US">Faculty Internship Coordinator</a> for complete information.</p>
<p><strong>What are my responsibilities?</strong></p>
<p>You are responsible for securing an internship and registering it with the Internships office in the Academic Discovery Center. You must be registered for the internship before you begin working. Once you have secured your internship, contact your <a href="x29025.xml" title="Faculty Internship Coordinators">faculty internship coordinator</a> who will lead you through the rest of the process.</p>
<p><strong>How do I find an internship? Who can help me?</strong></p>
<p>Start here: <a href="x29027.xml" title="How to find an internship">How to Find an Internship</a></p>
<p><strong>Are internships paid?</strong></p>
<p>Since you are responsible for finding your own internship, it's up to you to determine what type of position you select.&nbsp; Often well-known and respected companies have a larger hiring pool and will therefore offer unpaid internships. Although unpaid these experiences look great on a resume and could lead to higher paying jobs later. Some of the best internships are unpaid.</p>
<p><strong>How do I register for an internship?</strong></p>
<p>Start here: <a href="x90097.xml" title="Internship Approval">Internship Approval</a></p>
<p><strong>Do I need insurance during my internship?</strong></p>
<p>All students will need to carry health insurance during their internship, whether through the University or through a family/private insurance company. Depending on the company/organization you are working for and the state in which they are located, Workers Compensation may apply to any accidents. Your employer will take care of the necessary details for you.</p>
<p>During the registration process, your experience provider will sign a Master Agreement, this will ensure that each intern is covered by the University's liability policy during the semester of their experience. This will cover you in case of a major mishap while on the job.</p>
<p><strong>What do I do when I'm done?</strong></p>
<p>You will receive a reminder to complete an evaluation. In addition, you should check in with your faculty internship coordinator to see if there are any final evaluations, assignments or reports that you need to submit.</p>
<p><strong>Are internships pass/fail, or do I receive a grade?</strong></p>
<p>All internships are academic courses, and you will receive credit and a grade. Any questions about grades should be addressed to your internship faculty coordinator. Grades will not be posted until the end of the semester.<br /><br />If your experience ends after the end of the semester, your faculty may decide to hold your grade until you are done. In this case, a T grade will appear until you are done, at which time the faculty will submit a Change of Grade form. T grades for internships do not affect your ability to register for the following semester's courses or adversely affect your student standing. Your internship will not be considered complete until the grade is issued.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x87900" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
