<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x30075" Name="CE CR 2"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">[N-330/400] Advanced Med/Surg / Advanced Nursing Concepts</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong>Clinical Requirements</strong><br /> Clinical hours for NURS 330/400 are completed in the intensive care area  of local hospitals. All clinical experiences are to be approved by  faculty. Thirty-six (36) hours are deducted from the 96, giving credit  for 1) orientation time at the individual health care facilities; 2)  organization time fulfilling preceptor agreements; 3) previous learning.  At least 50% or 30 hours is required in an adult ICU.  The other 50%  may be in an ER, NICU, or ICU area.  If the student holds CCRN  certification up to 50% of the clinical may be waived.  The student will  work closely with the instructor to choose an area of clinical  experience to be arranged through a preceptor.<br /> <strong>Number of Hours</strong><br /> Credit hours: 5, Theory: 3 hours allotted for theory, Clinical: 2 hours allotted for clinical<br /> 2 credits x 3 (ratio number approved) = 6 hours of clinical per week x  16 weeks in the semester = <strong>96 hours/semester required for clinical.</strong><br /> Total clinical/lab hours per semester are calculated on a 1 credit hour:  3 clinical hours ratio and are based on a 16-week semester. Faculty may  choose to plan individual experiences to equal the total number of  hours as needed related to optimal experiences, testing, holidays, etc.  Thirty-six (36) hours are deducted from the 96, giving credit for 1)  orientation time at the individual health care facilities; 2)  organization time fulfilling preceptor agreements; 3) previous learning.]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
