<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x30074" Name="CE CR 3"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">[N-449] Community Nursing</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Clinical Requirements</strong><br /> Clinical hours for NURS 449 includes the completion of the following projects:</p>
<ol>
<li>Family assessment - Student will visit a family of their choice  (not their immediate family) weekly for 5 weeks, assessing family and  doing health teaching.</li>
<li>Health teaching project - This can be a group  project completed by 4-5 students if fellow students live in your area.  A population within your community with a teaching need is selected.  Students prepare and present a 30-minute health teaching program. A PowerPoint of the project and a professional brochure are to be  submitted to the instructor.</li>
<li>Community assessment - This can also be  completed as a group if students live in the same area.</li>
<li>Each  student is required to visit and participate in three (3) community  health clinics. When attending a clinic, be on time, plan spending the  entire morning or afternoon. Students are to arrange all clinicals.</li>
</ol>
<p>Clinical Option: Students have the option of completing part of the  course and/or clinical at a trans-cultural site if one is available.  Further details will be provided to students choosing this option.</p>
<p><strong>NURS 449 does not require a clinical placement request nor a preceptorship agreement because clinical hours are information gathering only.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Number of Hours</strong><br /> Credit hours: 5<br /> Two (2) hours theory per week. Total theory hours are calculated on a 1  credit hour: 1 theory hour ratio and are based on a 16-week semester  compressed into 14 weeks.<br /> 3 x 3 = 9 hours/week x 16 = <strong>144 hours/semester required for clinical</strong> <br /> Total clinical/lab hours per semester are calculated on a 1 credit hour:  3 clinical hours ratio and are based on a 16-week semester compressed  into 14 weeks. Faculty may choose to plan individual experiences to  equal the total number of hours as needed related to optimal  experiences, testing, holidays, etc.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
