<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x30281" Name="Help Wanted Postings" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Help Wanted Postings</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">List of local job postings that are temporary - just a few hours, few days or few weeks.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a little extra cash or gas money? This page contains odd jobs and tasks listed by local community members - you'll find personal service needs like painting a house, helping someone move, raking leaves and yard work, etc.</p>
<p><strong> These are jobs for which someone would like to hire a student for only a few hours or a few days </strong> .</p>
<p>For career and "regular" employment postings, internships, etc - please be sure to visit <a class="extLink" href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" onclick="
  var s = s_gi(s_account);
  s.linkTrackVars='events';
  s.linkTrackEvents='event2';
  s.events='event2';
  s.tl(this,'e','Career Navigator');
  " title="Career Navigator" target="_blank"> Career Navigator </a> .</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho strives to ensure all postings are legitimate, and advises you to use caution and common sense in applying for any position.</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Pauline Marshall<br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;208-534-3165 <br /> Address, City, State:&nbsp;949 N. 12th W. Rexburg, Idaho<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:pmarshallrn@gmail.com">pmarshallrn@gmail.com</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;housekeeping help/ mothers helper<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;Help with house work, and care of small children.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;previous house cleaning, and child care experience<br /> Start Date:&nbsp;8-14-14<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;open ended<br /> Hours:&nbsp;flexible 2-10 hours/week<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;to be determined <br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Email <a href="mailto:pmarshallrn@gmail.com">pmarshallrn@gmail.com</a>&nbsp;or call&nbsp;208-534-3165 <br />Posted: 8/20/14</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Pauline Marshall<br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp; 208-534-3165<br /> Address, City, State:&nbsp;949 N. 12th W. Rexburg, Idaho<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:pmarshallrn@gmail.com">pmarshallrn@gmail.com</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;piano teacher<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;Looking for advanced piano student to tutor/teach piano to my children in my home.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Must be an advanced pianist. Teaching experience prefered.<br /> Start Date:&nbsp;Sept. 2014<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;open ended<br /> Hours:&nbsp;2-4 /day Mon.-Fri.<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;to be determined<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Send resume' to <a href="mailto:pmarshallrn@gmail.com">pmarshallrn@gmail.com</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;call&nbsp;208-534-3165 <br />Posted: 8/20/14</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name: Buddy Wright<br />Company Name: CTS Auto Wash. <br />Job Description: We provide fleet wash services for UPS. We do this in 3 different states and several different cities. Currently I am looking for a person to wash UPS trucks at the Rexburg Location.&nbsp;It should be &nbsp;understood that this position is manual labor and should be considered labor intensive. You can expect to get dirty and wet washing these trucks. Even though we wash trucks In doors, the seasons bring temperatures and conditions that a potential employee should consider. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <br />Hours: &nbsp;This work shift is Monday through Friday. The shift starts around 5:30 pm. And usually works 5 - 6 hours / day for around 25 - 30 hours / week. <br />Wage: I would start the right person out at $11.00 / hour. &nbsp;<br />Requirements/Qualifications: A drivers license and some driving skills are required for this position, as it is that after we wash these trucks we are required to park each vehicle in its assigned parking spot. Several of these trucks are standard transmission and therefore require this employee to be able to drive stick. <br />How to Apply: If you are interested in this position please &nbsp;call Buddy Wright at&nbsp;<a href="tel:%28801%29%20682-3388">(801) 682-3388</a>&nbsp;to schedule an interview. Or you can send a resume to&nbsp;<a href="mailto:ctsautowash@gmail.com">ctsautowash@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<hr /><hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Debra Mitchell<br /> Company:&nbsp;Duchesne County School District<br /> Contact Phone: 435-738-1202<br /> Address, City, State:&nbsp;Po Box 446 Duchesne, UT 80021<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:dmitchell@dcsd.org">dmitchell@dcsd.org</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;UHS Science Teacher, Elementary Ed Art Instructor, RJHS Sixth Grade Teacher<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;Teaching required curriculum to students.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Must have or be willing to obtain a valid Utah teaching license with appropriate endorsements.<br /> Start Date:&nbsp;ASAP<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;10/10/2014<br /> Hours:&nbsp;182 days August-May 1440 hour<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;As per district salary schedule<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Applications may be obtained at <a href="http://www.dcsd.org/">www.dcsd.org</a> or by calling Duchesne County School<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;District. You may also apply via Teacher-Teacher.com. Please submit application, current resume, letter of interest, and letters of recommendation to: <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Attn: Debra Mitchell<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Duchesne County School District<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;PO Box 446<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;50 E 100 S<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Duchesne, UT 84021<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;435-738-1202 fax 435-738-1254<br />Posted: 8/20/14</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Nathan Marshall<br /> Company:&nbsp;NorthPoint Apartments<br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;208-569-0108<br /> Address, City, State:&nbsp;141 S 1st W, Rexburg, ID<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:nathan@northpointrexburg.com">nathan@northpointrexburg.com</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;Maintenance/Custodian<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;General maintenance and custodial work including but not limited to vacuuming, mopping, carpet cleaning, dusting, landscape maintenance, window washing, exc. <br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Hard working with an eye for quality. Ability to complete tasks with little to no supervision. <br /> Start Date:&nbsp;ASAP<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;2-4 weeks, possibly more. <br /> Hours:&nbsp;Up to 8, depending on schedule<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;$8/hr<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Contact Nathan or stop by the office at the Northpoint complex.<br /> Posted: 8/19/14<br /><br /></p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Josh Garner<br /> Company:&nbsp;The Law Office Of Joshua Garner<br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;208-359-3181<br /> Address, City, State:&nbsp;117 E. Main<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:garnerassistantuser@gmail.com">garnerassistantuser@gmail.com</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;Legal Assistant/ Office secretary<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;We are a local law office, located on main street. Looking for a part time assistant. Hours are Monday-Friday 9-1. Duties include: Answering phones, Making appointments, Filing, Running errands, and billing.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;We are looking for someone who has plans to stay in Rexburg for at least two semesters with a flexible schedule. Previous Office experience is preferred. <br /> Start Date:&nbsp;September 8th 2014<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;September 8th 2015<br /> Hours:&nbsp;9:00 AM-1:00 PM <br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;Negotiable depending on expirence <br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;To apply please email your resume to the following emails: <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="mailto:garnerassistantuser@gmail.com">garnerassistantuser@gmail.com</a> <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="mailto:garnerlawoffice@gmail.com">garnerlawoffice@gmail.com</a><br />Posted: 8/15/14</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Larissa Jaster<br /> Company:&nbsp;Jaster Family<br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;425-770-2632<br />Location:&nbsp;Rexburg, Idaho<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:larissajaster@gmail.com">larissajaster@gmail.com</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;Babysitter/Nanny<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;My husband and I both work from home, so I am needing a babysitter to watch my 21 month old daughter from around 9:30am to 12:30pm M-F until she goes down for a nap. Our offices are downstairs so we will be home while you watch her. She just needs a play mate so we can work. :) We will be interviewing to find the right person. <br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Please give references. <br /> Start Date:&nbsp;~August 25th<br /> Hours:&nbsp;3 hours a day<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;$6 an hour<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Call or e-mail Larissa.<br /> Other / Comments:&nbsp;Please call or e-mail for more information or if you have questions.&nbsp;<br />Posted: 8/15/14</p>
<hr /><hr />
<p>Company: TEG Global<br />Location: Idaho Falls<br />Job Title:&nbsp;Contract: MS .NET Application Developers with Telerik and Cyber Security <br />Job Description: TEG Global is seeking two positions for Sr Programmer Analyst Technical Developers with Microsoft .Net coding skills<br />Below is a description of what we are looking for.&nbsp;<br />1 resource:&nbsp;needs 7 years experience and a Bachelors or an Advanced Degree and 5 years experience.&nbsp;<br />1 resource:&nbsp;needs 11 years experience and a Bachelors or an Advanced Degree and 9 years experience.&nbsp;<br />Job Description:&nbsp;Client is looking for a mid-level .NET Application Developer that can quickly step in and develop .NET code with little technical assistance from our client's existing development team.&nbsp;This individual will work under the direction of project managers and work leads and be expected to track all work in a task tracking system and follow our development processes.&nbsp;This will be a 6 month assignment with a government client requiring US citizenship.&nbsp;The work is being performed onsite in Idaho Falls, ID.<br />Required Skills:&nbsp;Individuals must have a working knowledge of and experience with the following software and tool development approaches and practices:<br />* Application development using Microsoft Visual Studio* Microsoft Visual C#.net* .NET 4.0 Framework Class Library* SQL Sever* Web Presentation Foundation (WPF)* Cyber Security background* Telerik tools* Object-oriented paradigm, design patterns and proper class design* Technical software quality assurance (SQA) documentation* Software configuration management within an agile development environment* Deployment and release of software from design through production<br />Client is an Affirmative Action/Equal Employment Opportunity employer (AA/EEO)/VEVRAA Federal Contractor.<br />For more job opportunities please see&nbsp;<a href="http://www.teg-global.com/">http://www.teg-global.com</a> <br />How to Apply: Potential applicants are welcome and encouraged to call or email me directly at:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:darwinmecham@teg-global.com">darwinmecham@teg-global.com</a>&nbsp;or call&nbsp;(208) 419-8555<br />Hours: Schedule is 8-5 daily - full time - no part time.<br />Length: Contract development for 6 Months Minimum.<br /> Must be US Citizen &amp; be able to qualify for a DOE clearance. <br /> Must have:<br /> * Application development using Microsoft Visual Studio<br /> * Microsoft Visual C#.net<br /> * .NET 4.0 Framework Class Library<br /> * SQL Sever<br /> * Web Presentation Foundation (WPF)<br /> * Cyber Security background<br /> * Telerik tools<br /> * Object-oriented paradigm, design patterns and proper class design<br /> * Technical software quality assurance (SQA) documentation<br /> * Software configuration management within an agile development environment<br /> * Deployment and release of software from design through production</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Breck <br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;(208) 680-3143<br /> Address, City, State:&nbsp;Rexburg, ID<br /> Job Title:&nbsp;Private Swimming Instruction<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;Private Swimming instructor for special needs adult. Pupil is 32 years old. Can float, partial back stroke but needs assistance to learn how to be safe in water. Desires lessons 2 to 3 times per week. Hours can be arranged convenient to instructor. Call Breck at (208) 680-3143.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Swimming Instructor<br /> Start Date:&nbsp;8/4/14<br /> Hours:&nbsp;To be arranged<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;DOE<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Call Breck<br />Posted: 8/12/14</p>
<hr />
<p>Job Description: Zylun Insights is a premier consumer insights corporation with the mission of bringing clarity to the most pressing business problems organizations face. Our fast-paced and engaging environment provides our employees with a competitive wage, meaningful work, skills development, and is a perfect complement for individuals looking to pair their educational pursuits with real-world business exposure. Our Rexburg office is expanding. Advancement opportunities exist for those with sound character and the ability to lead others by example and manage processes effectively. We maintain a respectful, clean and comfortable office environment, work hard and believe in having a great time. We provide flexible scheduling to help our employees balance their busy lives. Administer surveys by telephone to our clients' customers, business professionals and the general public across the nation. ABSOLUTELY NO SELLING, EVER.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications: Must be 17+, ability to read and speak English well, key 30 wpm, be curious and professionally represent the companies with whom we work. (Having a good sense of humor is a plus, but not an absolute requirement.) <br /> Hours: 12-30 hours/wk with flexible scheduling <br /> Pay / Wage: $8.50/hr base wage with achievable incentives up to $10.50/hr <br /> Please apply by sending a resume to &nbsp;<a href="mailto:jobs@zyluninsights.com">jobs@zyluninsights.com</a><br />Posted: From 8/12/14 to 9/30/14</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name: Robert Budenbender or Jon Decker<br /> Company: We Hang Christmas Lights <br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;480-389-6404 <br /> Address, City, State: 6497 S. Tucana Lane &nbsp;Gilbert AZ, 85298 <br /> Job Title: Christmas Light Installers <br /> Job Description: Help needed from off track students in the fall from the second week in&nbsp;October 13th. -&nbsp;Dec 20th&nbsp;&nbsp;and optional extension from&nbsp;January 2 - 31 2015.&nbsp;&nbsp;We are a growing &nbsp;small business in Gilbert Arizona and we install and take down Christmas lights and decorations.&nbsp; <br /> Requirements/Qualifications : Hardworking and trust worthy. Must be able to to go up and down ladders and get on roofs. &nbsp;Have a &nbsp;Driver's Licence. Work with 3-5 man crew all day (Room and Board NOT included) Please send resume and references to&nbsp;<a href="mailto:info@azchristmaslights.com">info@azchristmaslights.com</a>&nbsp; <br /> Pay/Wage: &nbsp;Starting at $12.00 (depending on experience) &nbsp;( a bonus is payable if you complete season through&nbsp;January 31st, 2015)&nbsp; &nbsp; Start Date:&nbsp;Oct. 13th&nbsp;(6 days a week) no Sundays&nbsp; &nbsp; End Date:&nbsp;Dec. 20&nbsp;or option to extend&nbsp;January 1 -&nbsp;31,&nbsp;&nbsp;2015 <br /> Hours: &nbsp;Full Time ( possible over time)&nbsp; <br /> How to Apply: Click on this link&nbsp;<a href="http://azchristmaslights.com/jobs">http://azchristmaslights.com/jobs</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;and fill out and submit form and we will contact you when we receive it.<br />Posted: 8/12/14&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x87843" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
