<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x30354" Name="FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently Asked Questions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Badger FAQ's provides answers to the commonly asked questions about badger creek.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3><strong>General FAQs:</strong></h3>
<ol>
<li><a href="#bc1" target="_parent">Where is the BYUI Outdoor Learning Center located?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc2" target="_parent">How much does programming cost?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc3">Is there a waiting list?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc4">Where do participants stay at the Learning Center?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc8" target="_parent">Can we provide our own food?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc9" target="_parent">Who coordinates the workshops, or do we provide our own staff?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc10" target="_parent">Can BYUI Outdoor Learning Center be used for family reunions?</a></li>
<li><a href="#bc11" target="_parent">How many participants can attend programming as a group?</a></li>
</ol>
<h3><strong>Youth Programs FAQs:</strong></h3>
<ol>
<li><a href="#q1y">What is the difference between AFY, OYA, and LFL?</a></li>
<li><a href="#q2y">What ages may attend AFY, OYA, and LFL?</a></li>
<li><a href="#q3y">How many roommates can I request?</a></li>
<li><a href="#q4y">I want to room with my friend/cousin/brother/sister who is older/younger. Is that possible?</a></li>
<li><a href="#q5y">What do I do if I can't complete the registration process?</a></li>
<li><a href="#q6y">How do I get on the waiting list for your Youth Programs?</a></li>
<li><a href="#q7y">What is your Refund Policy?</a></li>
</ol>
<p></p>
<h3>General Answers:</h3>
<h5><strong><a name="bc1" title="bc1" target="_parent"></a>1.&nbsp; Where is BYUI Outdoor Learning Center Located?</strong></h5>
<p>Badger Creek is located approximately three miles north of Tetonia, Idaho, and 45 miles northeast of Rexburg.&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong><a name="bc2" title="bc2" target="_parent"></a>2.&nbsp; How much does programming cost?</strong></h5>
<p>Prices for the BYUI Outdoor Learning Center 2013 programs depends upon the&nbsp;program chosen- see our Community, Campus, or Youth Program pages located on our homepage.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">Campus Groups can now come up for no cost, but if there is a meal provided we have to charge for the cost of the food.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">Groups have the choice of having a full course meal for $5.50 per person or doughnuts and hot chocolate for $2.00 per person.</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Note:</strong> Horses are also available during the summer months.<em>&nbsp; An additional $10 per person will be added to&nbsp;the regular&nbsp;amount when choosing to ride horses as a workshop option.<br /></em></p>
<p><em>Because the food is ordered and confirmed in advance for the amount of people in the group, these are set prices regardless of anyone in the group arriving late or leaving early.</em></p>
<h5><strong>&nbsp;<a name="bc3"></a>3.&nbsp; Is there a waiting list?</strong></h5>
<p>No.&nbsp;Groups are scheduled on a first come, first serve basis.</p>
<h5>&nbsp;<a name="bc4"></a><strong>4.&nbsp; Where do participants stay at the Outdoor Learning Center?</strong></h5>
<p>&nbsp;Participants stay in bunk cabins,&nbsp;tents, yurts, or tepees depending on the program your group is participating in.</p>
<h5><strong><a name="bc8" title="bc8" target="_parent"></a>5.&nbsp; Can we provide our own food?</strong></h5>
<p>Yes, we have pavilions available for food preperation and serving.</p>
<h5><strong><a name="bc9" title="bc9" target="_parent"></a>6.&nbsp; Who coordinates the workshops, or do we provide our own staff?</strong></h5>
<p>The workshops are coordinated by the Outdoor Learning Center Staff.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong><a name="bc10" title="bc10" target="_parent"></a>7.&nbsp; Can the Outdoor Learning Center be used for family reunions?</strong></h5>
<p>No. Scheduling is limited to campus groups,&nbsp;scout camps, and community/family group day use at this time.&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong><a name="bc11" title="bc11" target="_parent"></a>8.&nbsp; How many participants can attend BYUI Outdoor Learning Center programs as a group?</strong></h5>
<p>The total number&nbsp;of all participants at one time varies between 48-90 people depending on&nbsp;when your group&nbsp;plans to attend.&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<h1>Youth Programs Answers:</h1>
<p></p>
<h5><strong><a name="q1y"></a>1.What is the difference between AFY, AFY Outdoor Edition, and AFY Life After High School?</strong></h5>
<ul>
<li><a href="x28834.xml">Adventure For Youth</a>(AFY) participants go whitewater rafting on the Snake River, experience challenging activities on the BYU-Idaho campus, and&nbsp;do baptism at the Rexburg Temple. Devotionals, dances, and counselor-led gospel discussions help complete this adventure.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="x44459.xml">AFY Outdoor Edition </a>(formerly known as OYA) is held&nbsp;at Badger Creek Ranch located at the base of the Teton Mountains. Participants camp in tents&nbsp;or teepees.&nbsp;Activities&nbsp;include&nbsp;horseback ridding,&nbsp;whitewater rafting,&nbsp;with challenging outdoor workshops, high ropes courses, group activities, devotionals, and daily scripture study.</li>
<li><a href="x44442.xml">AFY Life After&nbsp;High School&nbsp;</a>(formerly known as L4L) is also hosted at the Outdoor Learning Center and particpants will engage in Stephen Covey's "7 Habits of Highly Effective College Students" and have a special workshop with college prep authority Henry J. Eyring.&nbsp; Also have a full day trip to Yellowstone National Park, white-water rafting, high ropes courses, leadership-building activities, and nightly fireside devotionals.</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<h5><strong><a name="q2y"></a>2.What ages may attend?</strong></h5>
<p>Participants for&nbsp;all programs&nbsp;should be youth between the ages of 14 and 18. All participants should be the minimum age by the first day of the session they attend and should not exceed the maximum age before the first day of the session they will attend.</p>
<p></p>
<h5><strong><a name="q3y"></a>3.How many roommates can I request?</strong></h5>
<p>AFY youth may request one roommate to a room with&nbsp;eight in a cabin or wall tent.&nbsp;AFY Outdoor Edition youth can request up to four roommates per tent.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br /><br /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Notice: </span>We try our best to accommodate roommate and group requests. However, BYUI Outdoor Learning Center reserves the right to make roommate or group assignments according to the needs of the program. All requests are due two weeks prior to the program start date.To make a roommate request or group request, email BYUI Outdoor Learning Center at: <a href="mailto:badgercreek@byui.edu">badgercreek@byui.edu</a>.</p>
<h5><strong><a name="q4y"></a>4. I want to room with my friend/cousin/brother/sister who is older/younger. Is that possible?</strong></h5>
<p>Roommates must be the same gender for all programs. We try to assign roommates or groups so that members are the same age or no more than one year apart.</p>
<h5><strong><a name="q5y"></a>5.What do I do if I can't complete the registration process?</strong></h5>
<p>Please contact our office at (208) 456-2531. We would be happy to help you complete the registration process, and we do apologize for any inconveniences.</p>
<p></p>
<h5><strong><a name="q6y"></a>6.How do I get on the waiting list for your Youth Programs?</strong></h5>
<p>If the program is full, contact one of our office assistants (badgercreek@byui.edu or (208)456-2531) and ask to be added to the waiting list. We will contact people as spots become available, based on a first-come-first-serve basis.</p>
<h5><strong><a name="q7y"></a>7.What is your Refund Policy?</strong></h5>
<p>There will be a $25 processing fee for each refund. If you drop within three weeks of the starting date, the processing fee will be $100. If you are within one week of the starting date of your session, no refund will be granted.</p>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x44785" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
