<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x30473" Name="Travel Card" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Travel Card</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Travel Card</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20080918T12:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Policy</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">The University Corporate Travel Card gives the cardholder a personal credit card that can be used for authorized University travel expenses.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">All full-time and part-time (non-student) employees who travel at least once a year are eligible to apply for a card.  If a card is issued, the cardholder is responsible for the following:</p>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>Security and proper use of the card</li>
<li>Reviewing the monthly statements for accuracy - including while away from the University for extended periods of time</li>
<li>Paying off the balance in full each month</li>
</ul>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">When a cardholder terminates employment, retires, or has a change in responsibilities his/her card will be cancelled.  The Human Resources Office is responsible for notifying Financial Services of all terminations, retirements and other position changes in a timely manner.</p>
<br />
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Procedures</h4>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>Application forms for a new University Travel Card are obtained from the Cashiers Office during normal business hours (ext. 1950).  Each form must be signed by the applicant and the Director of Financial Services.</li>
<li>Personal credit history will be checked in order to qualify for the card.  The decision to issue the card will be made by the issuing company rather than the University.</li>
<li>If approved, when the card is received by Financial Services from the issuer, the card applicant will be notified that it can be picked up at the Cashiers Office.</li>
<li>Once the employee has received his/her card, it should be used in place of other payment methods for authorized travel expenses.</li>
<li>The dollar limit will be based upon personal credit history with a maximum limit of $5,000.</li>
<li>The card should not be used to make personal purchases.</li>
<li>The employee is the only one authorized to use the card.  Purchases should not be made by anyone else.</li>
<li>The card cannot be used for any services performed by an individual, partnership, or sole proprietorship which may be reported to the IRS (e.g., entertainment, royalties, honorariums, stipends, consultations, applied music lessons, contract services, moving expenses, etc.).  Use a Check Request for these items.</li>
<li>Each cardholder should obtain a receipt or other documentation for each charge to be compared to the monthly statement when received.</li>
<li>Travel expenses for a trip should be included on the Travel Authorization (TA) which is submitted to the Accounting Office for reimbursement.  This reimbursement should be applied by the employee towards the balance on the card.</li>
<li>The balance due on the University Travel Card is paid each month by the employee rather than the University.</li>
<li>Any late fee payments are the responsibility of the individual cardholder.</li>
<li>If a charge on the monthly statement is disputed by the cardholder (either a wrong amount or unknown charge), the cardholder is responsible to resolve the dispute as he would with any dispute on his own personal account.  
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>If the amount is wrong, the cardholder should call the vendor and ask for clarification or a correction of the error.</li>
<li>If there is an unknown charge, the phone number on the statement or the back of the card should be called and any instructions received should be followed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>If the card is lost or stolen, the cardholder should immediately call 1-800-VISA-911 (inside the US/Canada) or 1-410-581-9994 (outside the US).  The Financial Services secretary (ext. 1901) should also be notified as soon as possible.</li>
</ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18419" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
