<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x32130" Name="BFA Info" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BFA Info</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BFA Info</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4></h4>
<h2><img alt="Painting Demo" src="Images/art/140617_PaintingDemo_14.jpg" /></h2>
<h5>Bachelor of Fine Arts</h5>
<h5>Fall 2014</h5>
<p>Applications due: Oct. 20, 2014 at 5:00 p.m. in Spori 316</p>
<p>Portfolios due:&nbsp; Oct. 27, 2014 at 5:00 p.m. in Spori 316</p>
<p>Application is available <a href="Documents/art/BFA Application12.pdf">here</a>, or in the Art office, Spori 316.</p>
<p class="underline"><strong>Bachelor of Fine Art Portfolio Review Guidelines</strong></p>
<p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>
<p>A special application process is required for the Bachelor of Fine Art degree. The BFA is a professional studio degree that prepares a student to enter an art profession and/or to pursue graduate studies. This degree requires a portfolio review at the completion of the sophomore level.</p>
<p>Be sure to complete TWO identical applications (one to be submitted with your portfolio and one for Department records) and use your I-Number (not a social security number) on the application. Please submit your portfolio and applications to the Department of Art office (Spori 316) by 5:00 p.m. on the dates listed above.</p>
<p><strong>Academic Requirements</strong></p>
<p>To be eligible for BFA consideration, a student should have a minimum of 30-33 credits of GE completed and a minimum of 55 total credits earned. Depending on the emphasis area, there may also be additional art courses beyond the Art Core that should be completed at the time of the BFA review. Students should consult their faculty advisor. Applicants must have a 2.7 GPA in all studio art courses in order to be considered for admission into the BFA program. No grade lower than a C in a studio art course will be accepted.</p>
<p>There are a limited number of spaces available for students in the BFA program at each review. Portfolios become the most important deciding factor for acceptance.&nbsp;All portfolios must be in the designated room by the deadline--late work will not be accepted. Applicants should fill out the BFA Review Form completely and tape it to the outside of the portfolio. A current Grad Report is also required with the application and portfolio (students may print out their own Grad Reports from the BYU-Idaho website). Students are encouraged to include a sketchbook of their preliminary work in the portfolio.</p>
<p>All applicants will be notified by mail within approximately two weeks of the review date.</p>
<p>A faculty committee will review all applications, Grad Reports, and portfolios. It is important to note that this committee considers stduents grades, in-class performance, preparation, and participation. Portfolio work must be presented in specific ways depending on the emphasis area. Students should see their faculty advisor for specific information.</p>
<p><strong>Options for Students Who Are Not Accepted Into the BFA Program</strong></p>
<p>All applicants will receive a summary form from the review that gives the observations of the faculty review committee. Students are limited to TWO application opportunities for the BFA program in this Department. If a student is not accepted at their first review, they may consider the following options:</p>
<p>1.&nbsp; Reapply for an additional review on the next regularly scheduled BFA Portfolio Review (see the published dates). In the meantime, a student should work to improve their portoflio based on the recommendations from the faculty committee. A student may also consider retaking a course to improve their work.</p>
<p>2.&nbsp; A very good consideration is for a student to pursue another Art degree. The Bachelor of Art degree with an emphasis in Integrated Studio Art will allow them to take additional upper-division studio art courses, where they will add additional work to their portfolio.&nbsp;More importantly, this degree gives a student the opportunity to combine their studio art experience with a minor&nbsp;such as business, education, marketing, and many others. These added skills can make a student a valuable professional with multiple skill sets. Additionally, the Art Education degree prepares students to teach in the K-12 grade levels.</p>
<p>3.&nbsp; Transfer to another major at BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p>4.&nbsp; Transfer to another college or university.</p>
<p><strong>Continuing Enrollment and Graduation from the BFA Program</strong></p>
<p>A student may be removed from the BFA program if their grades fall below the minimum 2.7 GPA average for BFA studio art courses. No grade lower than a C in a studio art course will be accepted for graduation. A two-year limit must apply for an extension at the conclusion of their second year (see Department office).</p>
<p>All BFA students must complete two semesters of Art 495-BFA Project during their senior year in preparation for the BFA Exhibition-see the faculty advisor at the beginning of the junior year for important details regarding this course and exhibition. Many BFA emphasis areas also require for graduation a sample portfolio, self-promotion booklet, or a set of slides for Departmental records-please see the faculty advisor for more information.</p>
<p>This Department reserves the right to retain student works of art from the BFA Exhibition for the BYU-Idaho Permanent Art Collection.</p>
<p><strong>Click the above image or click here to download the&nbsp;<a href="Documents/art/BFA Application12(1).doc">BFA Application</a> .&nbsp; Copies of the application are also available in the Department of Art office (Spori 316).</strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1853" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
