<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x32154" Name="Resources for Academic Success" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Resources for Academic Success</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A list of resources for academic success, including career assesments, introductory courses, and Academic Support Centers for tutoring.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><img alt="Resources for Academic Success" height="256" src="Images/advising/aa-and-cp/acadsuccessbanner.jpg" title="Resources for Academic Success" width="710" /></p>
<p>At BYU-Idaho, we offer many tools to help you succeed in college. These include introductory courses as well as Academic Support Centers where you can find tutors, Reading/Writing and Math labs and other aids.</p>
<h2>Resources</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="x31905.xml" title="Career Assessments">Career Assessment Tests</a>: Several tests are offered that show you how your interests, skills, and abilities can translate into various major and career options.</li>
<li><a href="x30742.xml" title="Recommended Course Sequences">Recommended Course Sequences</a>: These planning resources show you what classes to take your first semester and all the way through to your last.</li>
<li><a href="x24268.xml" title="Contact Us">Satellite Academic Discovery Centers</a>: Each major is assigned to a specific Academic Discovery Center on campus. These centers are always available to give you guidance, support, and advice.</li>
<li><a href="x28930.xml" title="Networking Resources">Networking Resources </a>and<a href="x69808.xml" title="Networking Resources"> Career Mentors</a>: There are many people available to guide you to a successful career. Learn from BYU-Idaho Alumni and others what you need to do now to be successful in the future.</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h2>Academic Support Centers</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Academic Support Centers are designed to supplement classroom instruction and help students practice, sharpen and master essential college skills. The Learning Centers include Content Tutoring, Reading, Writing, Math and Study Skills centers.</li>
<li>The Academic Support Centers are for&nbsp;<strong>everyone</strong>. Each year, over 8,000 students use 300+ tutors.</li>
<li><strong>Tutoring is free</strong>! Some institutions have services similar to ours, but there is often a cost attached. Here, you will only be charged if you schedule a session and then don't show up for it.</li>
<li>You will be wise to sign up early. Don't wait until you are behind in a class to seek help. The most repeated comment on student surveys is something like, "I wish I'd known about this sooner."</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information on Academic Support Centers, please click&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/academicsupport/" title="Acad" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<hr />
<h2>Introductory Courses</h2>
<p>If you have settled on a major, you will find your major's introductory courses in your first-semester success plan or eight-semester graduation plan. If you are exploring careers, or if you are looking for an introduction to college life, consider the following options:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>GS 100 - Career Exploration</strong>:&nbsp;Designed to aid in making a decision concerning a career or a major. In-depth career assessments are given to help students identify strengths concerning major and career options.</li>
<li><strong>GS 101 - Principles of Personal Achievement</strong>: The intent of this course is to focus on principles that produce success in college and beyond.</li>
<li><strong>GS 102 - Study Skills</strong>: This class is designed to help students improve their learning effectiveness, attitudes, and motivation. Time management, memorization methods, note-taking skills, textbook study methods, test-taking strategies, and critical thinking are all part of the curriculum. It also provides an orientation to services and resources available to students on campus.</li>
<li><strong>GS 103A-J - Individual Study Skills Modules</strong>: The Study Skills Center offers six online modules for students to choose from:
<ul>
<li>Concentration and Memorization</li>
<li>Note Taking</li>
<li>Thinking Skills</li>
<li>Textbook Study</li>
<li>Time Management</li>
<li>Test Taking</li>
<li>It is recommended that students take no more than one module at a time.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>GS 105 - College Success</strong>: This class is designed to be an experiential class where students will learn various study methods and be given the opportunity to apply them. They will learn about campus resources which can help them. They will also learn what their learning style is and study strategies which apply to their style. In this course students will review and enhance their attitudes toward learning.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul></ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
