<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x32125" Name="Dieting is Out" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">How Dieting can be a Precursor to Eating Disorders</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dieting and Eating Disorders from the BYU-Idaho Counseling Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<script type="text/Javascript">
   function expand(num) {
      var hidden = document.getElementById("hidden" + num);
      var expand = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (expand.innerHTML == "+") {
         expand.innerHTML = "-";
         hidden.style.display = "block";
      } else {
         expand.innerHTML = "+";
         hidden.style.display = "none";
      }
   }

   function hover(type, num) {
      var hover = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (type == 1) {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#999999";
      } else {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#007ebd";
      }
   }
</script>
<h4 align="center" style="text-align: left;">Dieting is Out; Listening to Our Bodies is In</h4>
<h5 align="center" style="text-align: left; margin-top: 10px;">Dieting as a Precursor to Eating Disorders</h5>
<h5 align="center" style="text-align: left; margin-top: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;">By Alice Covey, RD CD</h5>
<p align="left">Dieting may not be the cause of eating disorders, but it is often a  precursor.  The National Eating Disorders Association reports that 35%  of "normal dieters" progress to pathological dieting and that 20-25% of  those individuals develop eating disorders.  It is far too common that  eating disorders start off as dieting.  Dieting can be a way for  individuals to exercise control -counting calories and fat grams,  limiting types and amounts of food, and watching the numbers drop on the  scale.  Focusing on dieting and weight loss can be a "perfect" escape  from true emotions and issues.  Not only can the focus on dieting and  weight loss be distracting, but also dieters tend to have slower  reaction time and less ability to concentrate due to lack of adequate  nutrition.</p>
<h5 align="left">Dieting as a Cultural Norm</h5>
<p align="left">Dieting has become common and normalized in our society.  So much so,  that children ages nine to eleven are dieting at alarming rates.  A  study published in the Journal of American Dietetic Association in 1992  found that 46% of nine to eleven year olds are "sometimes" or "very  often" on diets and that 82% of their families are "sometimes" or "very  often" on diets.  It would not be surprising if the rates have increased  over the years, especially since that has been the trend of the dieting  industry.  In 1980 the dieting industry was a $10 billion dollar  industry.  In 1991 it was reported to be a $50 billion dollar industry,  and it just keeps growing.  Fifty billion dollars is more than the Gross  national Product (GNP) of over half of all the nations in the world.</p>
<p align="left">This trend for dieting and being "thin" is a relatively new phenomenon  in the course of history.  Less than one hundred years ago Americans  strived for "excess" body fat.  They viewed fatness as a sign of  success, health, and beauty.  There were even articles in magazines like  Harper's Bazaar with advice on how to put on extra pounds.  At this  time physicians were even encouraging Americans to gain weight, and they  believe that a "balanced personality" was obtained by having a large  number of fat cells.</p>
<h5 align="left">Diet Failure</h5>
<p align="left">Our culture has brainwashed us into thinking being ultra-thin is equated  with beauty.  To obtain this image, Americans put so much time, energy,  and money into diets, and in the end the diets don't  even work.  The  dieting failure rate helps to explain the industry's rapid growth.  When  a diet fails, the search is on for a new one that "really works."   Ninety-five percent of dieters regain their lost weight.  Plus, many of  those who have "failed" put on additional weight within one to five  years.  The 5% of "successful dieters" are usually successful because  they have actually adopted a new lifestyle, not because they have stuck  to their diets.</p>
<p align="left">Most people blame themselves and their lack of willpower for their diet  failures.  In reality, it has nothing to do with willpower.  Diet  failure can be attributed to the body responding to hunger and the  body's state of semi-starvation or starvation.  The body and mind react  to a diet in the same way they would to starvation.  In starvation, the  body's metabolism decreases, and cravings increase.  This is the set up  for diet failure.  Metabolism naturally slowing down during starvation  is the body's attempt to conserve energy.  A decrease in metabolism  means the body is burning calories at a slower rate.  Also while on a  diet, the mind becomes preoccupied with thoughts of food and cravings  intensify, especially for foods that will provide quick energy, like  sweets.  Eventually it is too difficult to fight nature.  People can't  remain on diets forever and when dieters terminate their diet efforts,  it is common for overeating  to ensue.  Overeating and even "normal  eating" with a suppressed metabolism will cause the weight that was lost  to come back.  The failure rate of dieting (95%) is so high, not  because people aren't good enough or strong enough but because our  bodies were designed to fight weight loss.</p>
<h5 align="left">The Cons of Meal Plans to Treat Eating Disorders</h5>
<p align="left">Many treatment facilities and dietitians use meal plans as a way to  treat eating disorders.  This approach has many cons, however.  Meal  plans are virtually the same as a diet.  People following meal plans are  allotted a certain amount of carbohydrate, protein, and fat servings,  or they are allowed to choose from pre-planned food items.  Just like a  diet, there are rules and boundaries that the meal plan provides are  just replacing the old set of rules the eating disorder provided.   Sometimes dietitians will even encourage their clients with eating  disorders to weigh and measure their food to get the "correct" amount.   The act of weighing and measuring food allows for no flexibility.  And  on top of that, it gives the message that food must be controlled,  regulated, and monitored, which is exactly how someone with an eating  disorder already feels about food.  In essence, meal plans feed into  eating disorder behaviors and thoughts.  If a mistake is made with a  meal plan, as is inevitable, strong feelings of guilt and failure will  most likely emerge.  Meal planning gives an individual with an eating  disorder the impression that they need these guidelines because they  have proven themselves untrustworthy with food.  They can become very  dependent on this external method of controlling food intake, instead of  looking inside themselves for the answers.</p>
<h5 align="left">Intuitive Eating</h5>
<p align="left">Intuitive eating teaches individuals how to look inside themselves and  listen to internal cues.  It also provides guidance on how to form a  healthy relationship with food.  It is an anti-diet approach to eating.   There are no rules to break and no temptations to resist.  Intuitive  eating, unlike dieting and meal planning, is not a set up for failure.</p>
<p align="left">To get back to a healthy and natural relationship with food, it is  important to remember that infants and toddlers innately possess this  ability.  Infants easily know when they are hungry and full.  Doctors  guide new mothers to respect their infant's inner wisdom.  They instruct  moms to never force-feed an infant.  It is amazing that infants  intuitively know that they need more food right before a growth spurt  and will naturally crave increased feedings.  Toddlers are the same.  A  study done by Leann Birch, Ph.D., showed that children ages two to five  were eating, on average, the same amount of calories daily for a week,  even though the calories from their individual meals varied greatly.   This study shows that toddlers don't need to count calories to get the  appropriate amount of energy; they naturally know what they need.</p>
<p align="left">The ability to use the internal cues (hunger and fullness sensations and  cravings) to regulate food intake is present in everyone.  This is true  no matter how long the individual has been ignoring them.  The  challenge in becoming an intuitive eater is to reconnect with the  already present internal cues and to learn to ignore the external ones.</p>
<p align="left">Dieting is a purely external way to regulate food intake.  Other things  that control food intake, which are external, are only choosing "good"  or "healthy" foods, automatically finishing everything on the plate, and  taking the portion that is listed on the food label.  Using external  factors to determine what, how much, and when to eat is a dangerous path  because it disconnects us from our bodies and our intuition.</p>
<h5 align="left">Fears Regarding Listening to Our Bodies</h5>
<p align="left">Most people initially believe that by using internal cues to guide food  amounts and food choices, they will inevitably be "unhealthy," make the  wrong choices, and eat too much.  This is a sign of a lack of  self-trust, which is natural when external factors have been used for so  long to make these choices for us.  Regaining trust is a process.  It  takes time and practice, but it is well worth it.  By using internal  cues it is possible to never diet again!</p>
<p align="left">When people start eliminating all the old external rules and controls,  it is normal to crave foods that were once restricted.  For example,  when individuals go on low-carbohydrate diets, usually that is the  nutrient they start to think about and crave.  After stopping the diet  it is quite common to "over-indulge" in foods high in carbohydrates.   This is because the body is craving them so intensely.  It is the same  with any food.  The more and longer a food is restricted, the more  intense the cravings will be.  This can be especially scary for  individuals with eating disorders.  At first, it may make them feel out  of control and like they cannot be trusted with food.  But eventually  the extreme cravings subside and return to "normal."  It is important  for them to keep this in mind as they are going through the process of  becoming an intuitive eater.</p>
<p align="left">Just as the body and mind intensely crave foods that have been  restricted, the reverse also holds true.  An example of this is going on  a road trip and only having limited options of fast food available.  At  first it may be fun, exciting and pleasurable to eat these foods,  especially if they aren't foods normally consumed.  However, after a  while, fat food will get old and boring, and cravings for other foods  will arise.  This is because your body and mind get tired of the same  thing over and over.  We crave variety, and we can think of the old  adage "variety is the spice of life."</p>
<h5 align="left">Listening to the Body and Weight</h5>
<p align="left">By listening to hunger and fullness cues and to what the body is  craving, our body will naturally find a weight where it feels  comfortable.  This is known as the body's set-point weight.  An easy way  to understand this concept is with an analogy.  A thermostat is set at  70 degrees.  When the room drops below that temperature, heat will blow  out of the vent and warm the room.  If the temperature in the room goes  above 70 degrees the air conditioner will blow cool air.  Metabolism and  hunger operate in a very similar way.</p>
<p align="left">Hunger and fullness cues and metabolism play a role in the regulation of  our body's weight, just as the heating and cooling of the room helps  control the temperature where the thermostat is set.  When weight drops  below our set-point, hunger will increase and metabolism will lower to  conserve energy.  When our weight goes above our set-point, hunger  decreases and metabolism increases to burn energy more easily.</p>
<p align="left">It is true that the regulatory mechanisms do work harder to keep the  body from going below the set-point than above it.  This is most likely  due to the fact that during the majority of human history food sources  have been scarce, and it has been vital for the body to preserve energy  as a means of survival.  However, the more we are able to tune into the  regulatory mechanisms, the more likely weight will remain stable.</p>
<p align="left">A study was done to exhibit the phenomenon of set-point weight.   Volunteers were made to either gain or lose weight.  After the  artificial control was removed from the experiment, their weight  automatically returned to normal.  Most likely, the individuals in this  experiment were able to reconnect to their bodies by listening to their  hunger and fullness cues, after the artificial, external controls were  removed.</p>
<h5 align="left">Being Mindful while Eating</h5>
<p align="left">In order to get back in touch with hunger/fullness cues and to figure  out what the body is craving, it is important to be mindful while  eating.  Using our senses while eating is a great way to get back in  touch with our bodies.   In our modern-day lives, many of us are rushing  around and eating food on the run.  Eating in this manner, most  individuals do not pay attention to hunger and fullness cues, let alone  the taste, texture, sight, and small of their food.  Staying fully aware  of these aspects of food will enhance the experience of eating, and  more enjoyment and satisfaction will be derived.</p>
<p align="left">Checking in during various times throughout the meal can also help us to be mindful while eating.  Ask questions like:</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">1. Where is my hunger/fullness level?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">2. Am I enjoying this food?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">3. What would make my eating experience more pleasurable in this moment?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">4. Would I rather be eating something else?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">5. I am staying present while I am eating, or is my mind wandering around?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">6. What external things influenced my food choices today?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">7. How can I reconnect to the internal signals my body is giving me?</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;">Asking questions and being curious and mindful during mealtimes will be  beneficial to someone trying to become a more intuitive eater.   Awareness is such an important component of change.  Without this subtle  awareness we may find it impossible to become an intuitive eater and  move out of the diet mentality.</p>
<h5 align="left" style="margin-bottom: 15px;">Tips for Families</h5>
<p>Click the (+) next to each topic to learn more.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td id="plus1" onclick="expand(1)" onmouseout="hover(2, 1)" onmouseover="hover(1, 1)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong> </strong><strong>Don't be the Food Police</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden1" style="display: none;">
<p>Trying to control the food intake of a loved one with an eating disorder   can only lead to trouble.  It not only reemphasizes the already  present  thoughts, "I can't be trusted with food," but it also teaches  your  loved one that they need to rely on yet another external voice to   determine what they "should" and "should not" eat.  Stay away from   phrases like, "maybe you want some more of this 'healthy' food," or "you   shouldn't have dessert before dinner."  If you are concerned about  your  loved one's eating habits the best time to confront them is when  food  is not present.  It may be helpful to enlist the help of a  dietitian.   This way a professional, whose sole job relates to food and  eating  behaviors, can deal with food issues.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus2" onclick="expand(2)" onmouseout="hover(2, 2)" onmouseover="hover(1, 2)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>Get rid of scales</strong> <strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden2" style="display: none;">
<p>This doesn't mean just hide them.  Actually, throw them away.  To   someone with an eating disorder the number of the scale can become a way   to determine how much to eat or how to feel ("good" or "bad" about   themselves).  Weighing can become an unhealthy obsession.  The number on   the scale is another way for individuals with eating disorders to look   outside themselves (externally) for answers.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus3" onclick="expand(3)" onmouseout="hover(2, 3)" onmouseover="hover(1, 3)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong><strong>Don't comment on appearances</strong> <strong> </strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden3" style="display: none;">
<p>This is true even if you think it's a compliment.  Something like, "you   look healthy," or even "you're so thin," can be twisted around and   distorted in the mind of someone with an eating disorder.  Try to avoid   these comments at all times.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus4" onclick="expand(4)" onmouseout="hover(2, 4)" onmouseover="hover(1, 4)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>Keep a wide variety of foods around the house</strong> <strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden4" style="display: none;">
<p>Being an intuitive eater means figuring out what is being craved during   times of hunger.  The more variety that is available, the better chance   the craving can be identified and satisfied.  Keep various grains like   breads, pastas, rice, and cereals on hand.  Also, try to keep fresh  and  frozen fruits and vegetables in the house.  Meats, like deli cuts  and  ground beef and other protein sources like peanut butter and cheese  are  important for specific cravings.  Snack foods are a necessity, as  well.   Try to keep chips, cookies, and nuts around.  These are just  some  suggestions.  It is important to consider taste preferences and  meal  options while shopping at the grocery store.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus5" onclick="expand(5)" onmouseout="hover(2, 5)" onmouseover="hover(1, 5)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>Don't buy "diet foods"</strong> <strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden5" style="display: none;">
<p>These are very triggering and tempting to individuals with eating   disorders.  They feed into eating disorder thoughts and behaviors.    Plus, they are generally unsatisfying.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus6" onclick="expand(6)" onmouseout="hover(2, 6)" onmouseover="hover(1, 6)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong><strong>Challenge traditional beliefs about food</strong> <strong> </strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden6" style="display: none;">
<p>Avoid labeling foods as "good" or "bad."  Food is food.  It has no moral   value.  All foods have nutritional value because every food is made up   of carbohydrates, protein, and/or fat.  These are the main nutrients   needed for bodies to function properly, a.k.a. macronutrients.  By   listening to and tuning into the body's needs, these macronutrients will   be consumed in an appropriate way.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="left"><strong><em> </em></strong><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<h5>REFERENCES AND SUGGESSTED READINGS</h5>
<p align="left">Facts and Figures on Body Image and Eating Disorders. Available at: <a href="http://www.cswd.org/facts.html" target="_parent">http://www.cswd.org/facts.html</a>.  Accessed October 10, 2005.</p>
<p align="left">Know Dieting: Risks and Reasons to Stop.  Available at: <a href="http://www.nationaleatingdisorders.org/" target="_parent">http://www.nationaleatingdisorders.org/</a>.  Accessed October 10, 2005.</p>
<p align="left">Reiff DW, Reiff KKL.  Eating Disorders: Nutrition therapy in the recovery process.  Set-Point.  1998.</p>
<p align="left">Robison, JI.  Weight, Health, and Culture: Shifting the paradigm for  alternative health care.  Alternative Healthy Practitioner.  Spring  1999; v 5 n 1.</p>
<p align="left">Taylor, Mary.  Tasting Mindfulness.  Yoga Journal.  Available at: <a href="http://www.yogajournal.com/health/10_1.cfm" target="_parent">http://www.yogajournal.com/health/10_1.cfm</a>.  Accessed August 10, 2005.</p>
<p align="left">Tribole E, Resch E.  Intuitive Eating: A Revolutionary Program That Works.  2<sup>nd</sup> ed.  New York, NY: St. Martin's Griffin; 2003.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Courtesy of Center For Change, Orem, Utah</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x24495" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
