<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x32213" Name="Antidotes for Low Self-Esteem" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Antidotes for Low Self-Esteem in Eating Disorder Recovery</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Antidotes for Low Self-Esteem from the BYU-Idaho Counseling Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<script type="text/Javascript">
   function expand(num) {
      var hidden = document.getElementById("hidden" + num);
      var expand = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (expand.innerHTML == "+") {
         expand.innerHTML = "-";
         hidden.style.display = "block";
      } else {
         expand.innerHTML = "+";
         hidden.style.display = "none";
      }
   }

   function hover(type, num) {
      var hover = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (type == 1) {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#999999";
      } else {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#007ebd";
      }
   }
</script>
<h4 align="center" style="text-align: left;">By Michael E. Berrett</h4>
<h4 style="margin-top: 20px;">Introduction</h4>
<p>I write this article as one having great interest in self-esteem and the  impact of avoidance on one's sense of self. This interest has come from  personal life experience growing up and professional experience as a  clinician working with many different kinds of clients who have  struggled with poor self-esteem. I write this article as one who has  worked with many eating disorder patients over the last twenty years,  most of whom suffered greatly from a poor sense of self and poor  feelings of self-worth. They have taught me as I have made great effort  to help them down that road to recovery. Those suffering from eating  disorders most often have two things which are the common denominators  of eating disorders. The first common denominator is poor self-esteem,  the belief that they are not good enough, that they do not have much to  offer the world, and the "felt need" to do something to "make up for  that," which is partially acted out in the eating disorder. Secondly,  the eating disorder truly is a disorder of avoidance. It becomes a way  for those so addicted and so trapped in its grip to avoid painful  emotions, painful beliefs about self, pain that comes from a lost sense  of one's identity, and further, a way to avoid rejection and other  painful experiences in life.</p>
<p>Why would I want to write about self-esteem? Firstly, understanding and  remediating poor self-esteem is critical. Poor self-esteem is the thread  of the deep woven fabric of an eating disorder. Regardless of failure  or success, relationships or lack thereof, mental disturbance or mental  health, poor self-esteem is a robber. It unconsciously puts a ceiling on  the breadth and the depth of the joy in our lives and it puts an  artificial and unnecessary limit on the depth or our experiences. Poor  self-esteem erodes one's confidence and it is often a quiet, insidious,  and invisible thief. We do not seem to understand enough about it and  all the while, millions and millions suffer from it. Secondly, it is  personal. It impacts my life. It impacts my children's lives. It impacts  the lives of patients, clients, and employees with whom I work.</p>
<p>It breaks my heart to see those with eating disorders suffering from  their poor self-esteem. This poor self-esteem is typified in the story  of a patient who my friend, Dr. Frost, and I once worked with. This  brief story typifies the poor self-esteem so often found in one  suffering from eating disorders. Brenda came into a therapy session and  described her previous night's dream.  She and her boyfriend were on an  ocean beach. As they looked out to the ocean, there was a sign which  read, "No swimming! Danger! Great White Sharks!" Despite the sign, her  boyfriend grabbed her by the hand and took her ankle deep into the  water. Brenda expressed her discomfort about being in the water and her  boyfriend replied, "It's okay, the water is too shallow for a shark to  come." Pretty soon the water felt so good and they were having such a  great time in the sand, in the water, in the sun, and with each other,  that they found themselves out to their knees. Again, she went away from  the fun for a moment and remembered the sign. She expressed her fear of  the sharks, to which her boyfriend said, "It's all right. Nothing is  going to happen." Pretty soon they were up to their waists in the  water.  Her expression of concern and his reply were repeated. Then  finally, up to their necks in the water, her boyfriend reassured her  that, all was okay, ignoring her fears and her pleas for them to go back  onto the dry land. Hard to see at first, but then clear and sure, there  came the fin of a Great White Shark. Within no time, the shark came up  underneath her and took half of her body in one bite. The Great White  snapped her off at the waist, and swam away with half of her riddled  body. In this unrealistic, yet terrifying dream, her boyfriend turned to  her and said, "Oh, I am so sorry about what happened," to which she  replied, "Oh, it's okay. It's no big deal."</p>
<p>As you can see this young woman's low self-esteem was played out in this  dream. It was her life to yield to the wants and desires of others and  to ignore her heart, her sensibilities, her intuition, her mind, her  best interest, and her feelings. To Brenda, her feelings did not count,  were not worth listening to, were not worth following, and the only  thoughts and feelings of worth were someone else's. The daily lives of  those so similarly suffering is dramatically typified in this symbolic  dream, which is about a chronic, poor, and destructive belief about  themselves.</p>
<h4>What Self-Esteem Is</h4>
<p>First of all, let us talk about what self-esteem is not. Self-esteem is  not about, and does not come from "externals." A model of self-esteem,  according to many who are trapped in an addictive eating disorder, was  conceptualized by a colleague of mine, Dr. Harold Frost. "Eating  disorder patients most often become trapped in a belief about self which  is: 'I am nothing more than my appearance, my achievements, and what  others think of me.'" It is these beliefs about themselves that keep the  eating disorder alive and well. Therefore, a step to recovery, and then  ultimately one of the blessings of recovery, is to once again learn  that esteem and worth are much more than appearance, so much more than  achievements, and everything more than what others might think and feel.</p>
<p>Self-esteem has more to do with what one believes in, what one thinks,  feels and desires, the intentions of one's heart, one's sensibility,  intuition, capabilities, and more. It has to do with passion and how one  lives their life. Self-esteem has more to do with the internal than the  external. For the religious, it has to do with deity and divinity, the  meaning of being a creation of God. For others, it may include ideas of  connection with others, self-respect, good intention, talents, whether  developed or not, a sense of being rather than doing. It is about who we  are and the intentions of the heart.</p>
<p>According to Bednar Wells and Peterson (1989), self-esteem is:  "An  enduring and affective sense of personal value based on accurate  self-perceptions."</p>
<p>It is my belief that children have at birth, as infants and toddlers, a  positive sense of self. It is not until circumstances, experiences, and  interactions which teach differently, that beliefs about self change and  poor self-esteem "raises its ugly head."Then, children begin to forget  and disbelieve how wonderful they are. Part of overcoming poor  self-esteem is to "come back to" that which you once knew about your  value and worth before life's negative experience began to teach  falsehoods about the value of yourself.</p>
<h4>Traditional Models of Self-Esteem</h4>
<p>A person's belief about where poor or positive self-esteem comes from  depends on their model of human growth and development, and their model  of personality and learning theory. It is the "filter," the "sunglasses"  we look through, which helps us find meaning in the world and also  dictates our model of self-esteem. I present only a few of many  traditional models of self-esteem, ways to help build self-esteem in  each model, and finally, I will discuss some unanswered questions and  concerns which remain after traditional models are rendered.</p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin-bottom: 0;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 180px; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; padding: 5px;">
<p align="center"><strong>Philosopher / Behavioral Scientist</strong></p>
</td>
<td style="width: 180px; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; padding: 5px;">
<p align="center"><strong>Interventions Based on Model</strong></p>
</td>
<td style="width: 180px; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; padding: 5px;">
<p align="center"><strong>Interventions Based on Model</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 157px; padding: 5px;">
<p>William James</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Setting goals and realizing them.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Baby steps structure for success, then generalize to other situations.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 157px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Sullivan</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Reflected appraisals of significant others.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Cognitive restructuring.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 157px; padding: 5px;">
<p>George Herbert</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Winning approbation from significant others.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Seek positive feedback from trusted loved ones.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 157px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Gordon Allport</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Coping with difficulties versus avoiding difficulties.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>DBT: Dealing with different emotional states, "Feel the fear and do it anyway."</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 157px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Rollo May</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Courage to allow all of oneself to exist.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Existential therapy and acceptance of being.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 157px; background-color: #efefec; padding: 5px;">
<p>Scott Peck</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Face adversity head on.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Grandma's rule, face things first, play or enjoy later.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 157px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Rosenberg</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 156px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Self-confidence, the expectation of success amid challenges.</p>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 144px; padding: 5px;">
<p>Plan to goal setting and success.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3" style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; background-color: #efefec; width: 457px; padding: 5px;">
<p><em>* Information adapted from Bednar Wells and Peterson's (1989).</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>In reviewing these traditional models and theories about self-esteem,  and the consequent interventions needed to overcome poor self-esteem, it  is seen that traditional models have many strengths, and luckily, many  of these models have been utilized in the current therapies, including  cognitive/behavioral therapy and the "positive mental attitude" programs  that people have used in self-growth, psychotherapy, and business  consulting. But despite the good that has come out of these and other  traditional models, many questions remain unanswered. That leaves room  for new theories, hopefully more useful and practical in helping people  overcome poor self-esteem and make gains in their journey of recovery  from emotional and mental illness and from addiction. One of these new  models will be presented later in this article.</p>
<h4>Questions Remain from Traditional Models</h4>
<p>Difficult and unanswered questions remain from traditional models such as these:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. What if young people growing up are treated well within family and  social circles, and they still have poor self-esteem? What does that  mean about the old theories?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. What about those with loving and attentive parents who would give  everything and anything for their children, and who have done their  best, have done well, and still their children suffer with poor  self-esteem?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. What about the resilient who suffer horrendous trauma, abuse,  neglect, and abandonment, but yet seem to feel good about themselves?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">4. If self esteem is based on the appraisals of significant others,  then why is it that all too often, our positive and expressed appraisals  do not seem to make much difference?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(Questions were adapted from Bednar, Wells, and Peterson 1989).</p>
<h4>The New Model of Self-Esteem</h4>
<p>A new and practical way of looking at self-esteem is that no matter the  source of low self-esteem, it is avoidance that maintains it. The ideas  presented here come from my twenty plus years of clinical experience,  personal life experience, and from the book <em>Self-Esteem: Paradoxes and Interventions in Clinical Theory and Practice</em>, APA, 1989, by Bednar, Wells, and Peterson.</p>
<p>The basic philosophy in this model is this: "One's overall evaluation of  self is the natural consequence of a person's tendency to consistently  cope with or avoid that which he or she fears. Low self-esteem is,  therefore, both a cause and a consequence of disordered behavior"(pg.  4).   Bednar et al., propose that "When there is a consistency in one's  tendency to cope or avoid conflict, there is a continuous basis for  internal feedback from the self about the adequacy of the self."</p>
<p>In other words, it is believed that there is interpersonal(external) and  inter psychic (internal) feedback which we all receive in life, which  is ongoing, and there are basic truths about that feedback:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. Everyone is going to receive, and might as well expect, plenty of negative feedback from the social environment.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. Many people receive a lot of favorable feedback socially, but tend not to believe it.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. Self-evaluative processes are ongoing for most, if not all of us.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">4. Self-evaluation is impacted by either coping or avoidanc, and that choice impacts one's sense of the adequacy. (pg 13)</p>
<p>In other words, we have two choices: We can cope, which is growth  oriented, personal development oriented, and increases understanding.  Coping involves facing and resolving life's dilemmas. Or we can avoid.  Avoiding means we stay away and hide from internal risk taking, or  interpersonal risk taking.</p>
<p>"Whether people cope or avoid dictates the positive or negative nature  of the personal psychological experience," and "Avoidance leads to  negative self-evaluations, while coping or facing leads to favorable  self-evaluations" (pg. 14). In other words, it is not what ultimately  happens in a situation, or how well someone does, but rather it is the  understanding and the sense of self that one has either chosen to avoid  or chosen to cope and do the best that they can that really someone's  their sense of self-worth and esteem. (Bednar et al.)</p>
<p>"In the self-evaluation process, people usually notice what they do, and  they often notice how they feel. What they do not often enough notice  is how they feel about themselves as a result of their choices and as a  result of how they live their lives. If one gets in the practice of  becoming aware of how they feel about themselves for doing, acting,  facing, and "following through," then they can develop a tool for  improving their self-esteem. Feelings about oneself are deeper, more  important, and more connected to the core, to the heart, and to the  individual's actual sense of self.</p>
<h4>Steps Toward Improved Self-Esteem using the "Avoidance Model"</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. Determine the level of preoccupation with peer approval and acceptance.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. Help identify and label significant avoidance patterns used in anxiety arousing conflict situations.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. Help identify and label the self-evaluative thoughts and feelings associated with those avoidance patterns.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">4. Learn to realistically break avoidance patterns.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">5. Learn to face and cope with intrapersonal conflicts.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">6. Identify new behavioral responses to conflict.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">7. Become aware of feelings about self which are associated with the  new behaviors versus feelings about self stemming from old avoidant  behaviors.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">*(Adapted from Bednar et al. (1989) (pg. 127).</p>
<p>In the process of these seven steps, the following principles can help increase the chances of success:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ask hard questions which cause reflection.                                
<ul style="margin-bottom: 0;">
<li>"How do you feel about selling yourself out?"</li>
<li>"What was it like to go  against what you felt was right?"</li>
<li>"How did you feel about yourself after  you said that?"</li>
<li>"If you continue to act in life as you did today, what  will your life be like and how will you feel?"</li>
<li>"How do you feel about  being able to face that hard situation?"</li>
<li>"Even though you are upset with  yourself, how does it feel to be honest with yourself?"</li>
<li>"Have you  noticed that you have been acting differently in the last few hours?"</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Help clients learn to ask themselves how they feel and how they feel about themselves.</li>
<li>Help clients notice and feel the emotion associated with negative and positive patterns which they enact in their lives.</li>
<li>Focus on the process, not so much on the outcome.</li>
<li>Hold up the mirror. Help them see the process that we see, and help them see the person that we see.</li>
<li>Use the therapy session and the therapeutic relationship, along  with the client's patterns within the relationship, as a microcosm for  the rest of life.</li>
<li>Do not prematurely save them from negative emotion and negative meaning in their recognition of avoidance.</li>
<li>Teach them through their own self-reflection that avoidance  validates the fear of failure, and that it has a negative impact on  self-esteem.</li>
<li>Quit trying to convince clients that they are great. Instead:                                           
<ul style="margin-bottom: 0;">
<li>Help them see their goodness and notice the small evidences of  their courage, their progress, and their willingness to avoid avoidance. </li>
<li>Correct the incorrect and move on. In other words, if an eating  disorder patient says, "I am fat," say, "I see you as beautiful, and  additionally you are in a normal weight range. I am sorry you cannot see  that." We correct and then move on instead of trying to convince. </li>
<li>Help them change the approval management façade since they will not  accept positive feedback from us on the outside, until they become more  honest and real with themselves on the inside.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Teach clients to give positive feedback and positive  recognition to themselves. Encourage clients to validate themselves  first, and then if we validate their positive self-appraisal, they may  begin to accept ours as well.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Avoidance: Research Survey</h4>
<p>In September 2005, I walked into a therapy group I was running and asked  eleven women to help me prepare to teach other professionals about the  impact of avoidance on self-esteem and on the process of recovery. They  wanted very much to help.  The women in this group ranged in age from  sixteen to twenty-four years of age, were struggling with anorexia or  bulimia, and were receiving intensive care in our residential treatment  program.</p>
<p>In the survey I asked each patient to respond in writing to the following six questions:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. What are the most important things you have avoided during your life and during your process of recovery?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. Why did you, or are you, avoiding those most important things in your life?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. What has been the cost of avoidance in the past or the present?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">4. When you have overcome the pattern of avoidance, and how did you do that?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">5. What has helped you stay out of avoidance the most?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">6. What, if anything, does avoidance have to do with your personal feelings of self-worth?</p>
<p>After the survey questions were completed, responses were reviewed. Much  can be learned from these women about the role of avoidance in their  self-esteem, and the role of avoidance or non-avoidance in the process  of recovery from an eating disorder. In the following paragraphs, I give  a summary of the conclusions which I derived from the participants'  responses. With each of the conclusions are one or two direct quotes  associated with each item to illustrate firsthand one direct comment  which led to each drawn conclusion.</p>
<h4>Summary of Conclusions from Avoidance and Self-Esteem Survey</h4>
<p align="left">Click the (+) next to each topic to learn more.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td id="plus1" onclick="expand(1)" onmouseout="hover(2, 1)" onmouseover="hover(1, 1)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>1) Patients will recognize and take ownership for their own avoidance   patterns when given a common language and a safe opportunity to talk   about it. </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden1" style="display: none;">
<p><em>"I have avoided working on my past issues, and I have avoided my   emotions. I have avoided making friends and being close to people. In   recovery, I have avoided getting better. I have been putting it off for   seven years. I have avoided trying my hardest because I am terrified of   failure."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus2" onclick="expand(2)" onmouseout="hover(2, 2)" onmouseover="hover(1, 2)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>2) Common areas for avoidance in life generally and in the process of treatment include: </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden2" style="display: none;">
<p>a. Assertiveness in relationships.</p>
<p>b. Feeling, allowing, and accepting, emotions.</p>
<p>c. Closeness and potential hurt from such in relationships.</p>
<p>d. Painful feelings or memories related to past intensive experiences.</p>
<p>e. Potential rejection.</p>
<p>f. Potential failure.</p>
<p>g. Potential loss of love from "changing or growing up."</p>
<p>h. Any interpersonal or intrapsychic conflict or turmoil.</p>
<p><em>"In  my life I have struggled with avoiding any confrontation. That has  allowed people the opportunity to walk all over me. I have also  avoided  talking about feelings related to situations that I am  uncomfortable  bringing up."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus3" onclick="expand(3)" onmouseout="hover(2, 3)" onmouseover="hover(1, 3)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>3) People embrace avoidance in an attempt to control others' responses, especially in areas of acceptance or rejection. </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden3" style="display: none;">
<p><em>"I have been avoiding my past issues because they are too painful  for me  to look at. They bring up hurt emotions. I try to avoid my  emotions  because I look at emotions as a weakness. Being weak is being a  failure.  I avoid getting close to people because I am tired of being  hurt all of  the time. I am terrified of rejection. I have put off  recovery because I  am so scared of getting fatter, and I am scared to  live a life without  my eating disorder."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus4" onclick="expand(4)" onmouseout="hover(2, 4)" onmouseover="hover(1, 4)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>4) Pretending is a common form of dishonesty with self and a common  avenue for avoidance. </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden4" style="display: none;">
<p>Some admit that the loneliness following rejection  is hurtful, yet  pretend that loneliness from self-imposed hiding is not  hurtful. Some  patients avoid by pretending that they are still small  and young.</p>
<p><em>"I  have avoided growing up because I am scared to be alone. I am scared  of  responsibility. I am scared that I will mess something up. And more   than that, I am scared that no one will love me anymore if I am not cute   and little. I feel like I have nothing to offer the world, so why  would  anyone love me if I am not an adorable, curly-headed little kid   anymore?"</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus5" onclick="expand(5)" onmouseout="hover(2, 5)" onmouseover="hover(1, 5)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>5) The price paid, or the cost of avoidance is high. </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden5" style="display: none;">
<p>Patients are most  often aware of the external costs, and sometimes they  are aware of  internal emotional costs, but less often are they aware  of the high cost  to their self-esteem.</p>
<p><em>"The  price I have paid for avoiding my past issues has been huge. I have   never been able to escape being the victim because I never dealt with   changing my mind set. People can see that and then take advantage of me.   I have lost friends and relationships with family members.  I have   forgotten how to stay present and stay in touch with my emotions. I   became so afraid of life."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus6" onclick="expand(6)" onmouseout="hover(2, 6)" onmouseover="hover(1, 6)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>6) Some of the patients have at least some recognition and   understanding that one of the highest costs of avoidance is loss of   feelings of self-worth. </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden6" style="display: none;">
<p>A few have begun to understand the reciprocal  relationship between avoidance and self-esteem.</p>
<p><em>"I  feel bad when I avoid because I feel like I am too weak to handle   life." </em></p>
<p><em>"I think avoidance makes my self-worth decrease because I feel as   though I am not respecting my own wants and desires."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus7" onclick="expand(7)" onmouseout="hover(2, 7)" onmouseover="hover(1, 7)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>7) People can overcome the tendency and pattern of avoidance. </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden7" style="display: none;">
<p><em>"I  used to avoid friendships like they were a deadly disease. But now I am  able to actively seek after relationships with others. With   self-nurturing I have developed the inner strength I need to reach out   to other people. And with goal setting, I have been able to take the   steps necessary to add friends to my life."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus8" onclick="expand(8)" onmouseout="hover(2, 8)" onmouseover="hover(1, 8)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>8) Patients have many tools and methods for overcoming avoidance, and  thereby increasing their self-esteem. </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden8" style="display: none;">
<p>They can use coping skills as an  alternative to avoidance, and these  include:</p>
<p>a. Becoming more open</p>
<p>b. Actively seeking relationships</p>
<p>c. Self-nurturing</p>
<p>d. Goal setting</p>
<p>e. Taking small steps</p>
<p>f. Talking  about true feelings in a relationship</p>
<p>g. Practice asking for what they  want</p>
<p><em>"You  have to put yourself out on a limb. If you put yourself out there,  you  don't always get what you want, but when you do, you feel great  about  yourself and others."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus9" onclick="expand(9)" onmouseout="hover(2, 9)" onmouseover="hover(1, 9)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>9) Patients can learn to notice and utilize negative and positive  affective states related to coping and avoiding. </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden9" style="display: none;">
<p>When they are being  taught, challenged, and gently invited to look  at the truth by their  therapist, this learning can be accelerated.</p>
<p><em>"What helps me avoid avoidance the most is trusting myself, others, and my Higher Power that everything will be okay."</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br />
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">Courtesy of Center For Change, Orem, Utah</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x24495" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
