<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x32988" Name="Activities" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Theatre Camp: Activities</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Theatre Summer Camp will be an excellent opportunity for those interested in theatre to explore their talents and their ability to express themselves under the helpful guidance of BYU-Idaho theatre students. Various workshops will be held on the fundamentals of theatre production. Participants will audition, rehearse, and perform as part of their experience.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>The Theatre Summer Camp will be an excellent opportunity for those  interested in theatre  to  explore their talents and their ability to  express themselves under the helpful guidance of BYU-Idaho theatre  students. Various workshops will be held on the fundamentals of theatre  production. Participants will audition, rehearse, and perform as part of  their experience.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Discover more about some of the key events and learning activities participants will enjoy while attending this summer:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#workshops">Workshops</a></li>
<li><a href="#evening">Evening Activities</a></li>
<li><a href="#main">The Main Event</a></li>
</ol></blockquote>
<h3><strong><a id="workshops" name="workshops"></a>Workshops offered:</strong></h3>
<p>All workshops are taught by trained and experienced students in the Theatre Department.  Participants will attend each workshop.</p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>Improvisation</strong><br />Learn  the main principles of improvisation, and practice these principles in  games and scene work taught by current and former members of Comic  Frenzy.</p>
<p><strong>Corrective Makeup</strong><br /> Get the basics on stage makeup for any production, from foundation  and shadowing, to how to line your eyes and pick the right lip color.</p>
<p><strong>Gore Makeup</strong><br /> From Zombie horror to cuts and bruises, you'll learn the basics of  special effects makeup that will come in handy both on stage and at the  Halloween carnival.</p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>Audition</strong><br />Knowing  how to audition is the secret to a great acting career. Pick up some  valuable tips on how to have the best audition possible and learn some  of the basic dance steps that are sure to appear in every dance  audition.</p>
<p><strong>Voice Diction</strong><br /> Develop one of the strongest tools in your acting toolbox - your  voice. This class will help you understand how breathing, posture, and  other factors can</p>
<p><strong>Script Analysis</strong><br /> Whether as an actor, director, designer, or technician, understanding  the text is the first step to creating something great. Learn about  objectives, tactics, beats, given circumstances, and everything else the  script can tell you to make your work come alive.</p>
<p><strong>Creating a Character</strong><br /> Walking, talking, gestures, tics, looks...all of this and more go into  creating a character. Learn how to make any role you play memorable and  real.</p>
<p><strong>Exploration</strong><br /> Reading the lines isn't the only way to rehearse. Learn some new  techniques that will help you discover layers of meaning beyond the  words.</p>
<p><strong>Principles of Design</strong><br /> Whether you're the director or a designer, learning how to use the  basic principles of unity, harmony, contrast, variation, balance,  proportion, and emphasis will take your work to the next level.</p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>Safety</strong><br />Working  on a production can be dangerous sometimes, whether you're hanging  lights or striking a set. Know how to keep yourself and others out of  harm's way, so that the show can go on!</p>
<p><strong>Stage Equipment</strong><br /> Ever wondered what a gobo was? Want to know how a fly system works? Find out as you explore the tools of the trade.</p>
<p><strong>Etiquette/Hierarchy</strong><br /> "Thank you, ten." "Standby 32." "Heads!" Learn the jargon of the  professional theatre world, as well as the basic rules of every theatre  production and who does what in a theatre company.</p>
<p><strong>Tools and Materials</strong><br /> Building a set, painting a prop, or hanging a light all become a lot  easier when you have the right tools. Get familiar with every tool for  every job.</p>
<p><strong>Set Design</strong><br /> Put the principles of design into practice! Learn how to create powerful and usable sets for any production and any space.</p>
<p><strong>Lights and Sound</strong><br /> Could you program the biggest sound or light board in history? Or are  you not sure what the difference between a spotlight and a source-four  is? Either way, learn the basics of designing and running lights and  sound.</p>
<h3><strong><a id="evening" name="evening"></a>Evening Activities</strong></h3>
<br />
<p><strong>Zombie Prombie</strong><br /> A chance to put your gore makeup skills to work and have a blast with  other participants! After you've made yourself up to look like you are  very accident prone, dance the night away with your fellow actors and  technicians. Be sure to bring clothes that you can transform into a  zombie costume!</p>
<p><strong> Mystery Dinner</strong><br /> No rehearsal is required for this fun, delicious who-dunnit! Step  into character, pick up your knife and fork, and start looking for  clues. You never know...the guilty party could be sitting right next to  you...</p>
<h3><strong><a id="main" name="main"></a>Main Event</strong></h3>
<br />
<p><strong>Revue Show</strong><br /> The time to put it all together! Take all of the skills you've  learned and put them into practice at the end of the week. Saturday  afternoon, parents and friends will have the opportunity to see  participants perform monologues, scene work, and even a little improv!</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28840" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28802" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
