<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x33093" Name="Tours" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Collegiate Singers - Tours</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Tour listings and details of tour events of Collegiate Singers</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2><strong>2015 tour to be announced!</strong></h2>
<h2>2013 Tour Highlights:</h2>
<h1>The Collegiate Singers just got home from a 2 week tour on April 28. They performed in Ghana, Africa. It was a great opportunity with many experiences:&nbsp;<br /><br /></h1>
<p><img height="389" src="Images/university-relations/Performance%20Tours/Collegiate%20Singers/the%20one.JPG" width="730" /></p>
<h2><strong>Members of Collegiate Singers:</strong></h2>
<h4>"Singing for the people of Ghana Africa was an experience unlike any other. Parts of the experience went as expected, but most of the experience was &nbsp;impossible to prepare for. It was hot and uncomfortable in every way, especially when it came to food (for me). The sacrifice was high, but naturally the rewards were even higher. What I learned I learned from the&nbsp;Ghanaian&nbsp;people. While these people (in general) have so little, they are also (in general) filled with joy and happiness. You would think I learned to appreciate what I have. While I did, but the higher lesson taught by the Ghanaian people was to love the Lord with all your heart. The lyrics from one of our song surely are in the hearts of these wonderful people:&nbsp;</h4>
<h4>"I love the Lord, in Him my soul delights. Upon His word, I ponder day and night."</h4>
<h3>~<strong>Andy Newman</strong>, Junior, Political Science, West Des Moines, IA</h3>
<h3></h3>
<h4>"Our first evening was spent with the BYU-Idaho Pathway students; they were one of the biggest reasons we went to Ghana in the first place. The Pathway program grants the opportunity to thousands of individuals worldwide to gain a BYU-Idaho education, and there were over 90 Ghanaians, Nigerians, and other Africans participating as current students. Though our time with them was short-lived at this point, we were able to spend more time with them in the latter end of our tour.</h4>
<h4>I believe that many of us started to realize our true mission in Ghana, that it was far outside ourselves and even outside performing for everyone. Our mission was to connect to Ghana through the Gospel of Jesus Christ and music, <em>and</em> to connect BYU-Idaho to its very own, those Pathway students! We began to realize that this is just setting a trend of involving Pathway students with on-campus students. It's something that will continue to grow and expand.</h4>
<h4>This choral tour to Africa was a wonderful experience. Ghanaians are a people full of love, joy, and contentment. Many have little by way of physical possessions, but their spiritual strength, dedication, and resilience is phenomenal. I've heard others put it this way: They have little of what's not important, and so much of what is important. And what else matters?"</h4>
<h3><strong>~Devin Cobia,</strong> Senior, Accounting, Sugar City, ID <br /><br /></h3>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x32262" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
