<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x33070" Name="Historyold" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Historyold</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A BYUI History</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style><!--
                    .top_message {
                      font-family: Georgia;
                      font-style: italic;
                      color: #60686E;
                      padding-bottom: 15px;
                      border-bottom: 1px solid #b7b7b7;
                      margin-bottom: 15px;
                      font-size: 14px;
                    }
--></style>
<div>
<p class="top_message">The BYU-Idaho story begins on a cold November day in 1888, when Latter-day Saint pioneers in the newly-settled town of Rexburg gathered for the opening of a new academy. Bannock Stake Academy, as it was first known, grew and matured over the ensuing decades. Its curriculum and name changed more than once. It forged ahead through uncertainty and difficulty to become Ricks College, the venerable institution that laid the foundation for BYU-Idaho.</p>
<img alt="BYUI History" height="216" src="Images/university-communications/History_photo.jpg" title="BYUI History" width="650" />
<p>1888 - Bannock Stake Academy established - Numerous other church academies were also set up in the Mormon communities of the western United States in commitment for education. Three teachers were appointed to provide the basics in elementary education and spiritual growth. Jacob Spori served concurrently on the faculty and as the first principal from 1888 to 1891.</p>
<p>1888-1891 - Jacob Spori serves as first principal</p>
<p>1891-1894 - Charles N. Watkins serves as principal</p>
<p>1894-1898 - George Cole serves as principal</p>
<p>1898-1901 - Douglas M. Todd serves as principal - Todd introduced a high school program the only one in the upper valley at the time. Under his administration, a building was begun which was later named after Jacob Spori.</p>
<p>1901-1914 - Ezra C. Dalby serves as principal - During his thirteen years of leadership, the Academy moved into the new rock building and became a standard high school, normal school, and commercial school.</p>
<p>1903 - Renamed Ricks Academy in honor of founder Thomas E. Ricks</p>
<p>1914-1917 - Andrew B. Christensen serves as principal - Christensen was instrumental in adding a year of college work to the curriculum, bringing water to the campus to beautify the founds, and beginning the construction of a new gymnasium</p>
<p>1917-1930 - George S. Romney serves as principal - At this time, the school was granted state certification (which allowed the graduates to teach in the State of Idaho), the Academy became Ricks Normal College, and the principal became its first president. In 1923, the school became known as Ricks College.</p>
<p>1930-1944 - Hyrum Manwaring becomes acting president of Ricks College: Ricks College in 1930 when the school was in danger of being closed or turned over to the State of Idaho. Through President Manwaring's efforts and the support of the patrons, the school remained open and became accredited by the Northwest Association of Schools and Colleges.</p>
<p>1944-1971 - John L. Clarke serves as president: Under his administration the college grew from an enrollment of 200 to 5,300 and its two original buildings multiplied to become two dozen.</p>
<p>1971-1978 - Henry B. Eyring serves as president: His administrative and public relations skills ensured the college's successful transition from a regional junior college to the nation's largest private two-year college. He oversaw the construction of additional buildings and developed new technical and vocational programs.</p>
<p>1978-1985 - Bruce C. Hafen serves as president: Under his leadership, the college acquired 130-acres in the Teton Basin for its new Outdoor Recreation program. Construction included the Fine Arts Center, Livestock Center, Outdoor Learning Center, and Viking Stadium.</p>
<p>1985-1989 - Joe J. Christensen: Christensen served during the Centennial year of Ricks College and enrollment reached 7,500.</p>
<p>1989-1997 - Steven D. Bennion serves as president</p>
<p>1997-2004 - David A Bednar serves as president: Construction during the early years of his tenure include the Spencer W. Kimball Student and Administrative Services Building, the John Taylor Building, and the Radio and Graphic Services Building.</p>
<p>June 21, 2000 - The First Presidency of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and the Board of Trustees of Ricks College announced that Ricks College would change from a two-year junior college status to a four-year institution. The school officially became known as Brigham Young University-Idaho on August 10, 2001. To meet the needs of BYU-Idaho students and the transition in academic programs, the physical facilities have been expanded to include the Gordon B. Hinckley Building, the Student Health and Counseling Center, the Henry's Fork Outdoor Learning Center, the Thomas E. Ricks Building, and University Village (family housing).</p>
<p>June 6, 2005 - Kim B. Clarke is the acting president of Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x33098" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
