<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x33652" Name="Surplus Policies and Procedures" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Surplus Policies and Procedures</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Surplus Policies and Procedures</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20140408T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p><strong><em>DISPOSITION OF SURPLUS ITEMS</em></strong></p>
</div>
<p><strong>POLICY</strong></p>
<p>Approved by: Presidents Council</p>
<p>Date of approval: March 24, 2014</p>
<p>All items which are no longer of use to the University are to be disposed of according to this policy. Items with asset tags require a "Relief of Accountability"(ROA) to account for the sale, disposal or donation. When an item is sold, the net proceeds will be returned to the authorized fund of the department submitting the item. Items that are not sold after 30 days will be reduced in price by 25 percent. Price will be reduced by another 25 percent after 60 days and another 25 percent after 90 days. After 120 days, items will be donated or discarded at the discretion of Surplus Operations personnel.</p>
<p>Initial starting price for disposal will be determined by Surplus Operations, unless a price has been stated by the account steward.</p>
<div>
<p><strong>PROCEDURES</strong></p>
</div>
<p>Policy owner: University Services-Stores, Mail, and Surplus Operations</p>
<p>Last Update: 3/7/2014</p>
<p><strong>Surplus Items</strong> - Items that no longer have value to BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p><strong>Disposal Surplus</strong> &ndash; These are items that are broken or have completed their useful life and are of no value to surplus.</p>
<div>
<p><strong>Surplus Items:</strong></p>
</div>
<p>&middot; These items require a user to submit a "Relief of Accountability" (ROA) web form, found at <a href="https://web.byui.edu/Surplus/"><strong>https://web.byui.edu/Surplus/</strong></a></p>
<p>&middot; After completion, the ROA will be sent to the budget steward for approval. If approved, the ROA is sent to the Surplus Office.</p>
<p>&middot; A surplus sticker will be delivered to the steward for placement on surplus items.</p>
<p>&middot; When possible, items will be removed when surplus stickers are given out.</p>
<div>
<p><strong>Disposable Surplus</strong> <strong>:</strong></p>
</div>
<p>Disposable surplus must be discarded and may not be given to employees or others. Surplus will pick up any items you deem disposable and will try to recycle where possible or work with E-waste where applicable.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<div>
<p><strong>Bid Items:</strong></p>
</div>
<p>The ROA initiator will be consulted for any price reduction of bid items.</p>
<div>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Donations</strong> <strong>:</strong></p>
</div>
<p>Requests may come from various entities for donations of surplus items. The following guidelines address these requests:</p>
<p>1. The first option for surplus items is to provide value for the University or other Church entities. Items can be donated to other entities if they are not sold after 30 days or there are compelling reasons for the University to make a donation before the 30 days is up.</p>
<p>2. The University does not make donations to For-Profit entities.</p>
<p>3. Donation requests from Public Schools or Government entities takes precedence over requests from non-profit entities.</p>
<p>4. Donation approval will be provided through the Donation Advisory Committee comprised of representatives from Financial Services, Internal Audit, Public Relations, Information Technology and University Services.</p>
<div>
<p><strong>Fees:</strong></p>
</div>
<p>All surplus items are assessed a 15 percent fee to cover the costs of managing surplus. The surplus fee will not exceed $450. (All items sold for more than $3,000 will be capped at $450.)</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x90436" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
