<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x33634" Name="High Credit Restriction" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">High Credit Restriction</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Details and FAQs about the high credit restriction.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2>Why Do I Have a High Credit Restriction?</h2>
<p>The purpose of this restriction is two-fold. First, to help you create a graduation plan that will allow you to graduate in a timely manner and as efficiently as possible. Second, to support the University's imperative to serve more students by ensuring that no one student is exceeding their credit allotment.</p>
<p>In order to have your high credit restriction lifted, you will need to complete the following:</p>
<ol start="1">
<li>Go online and use the <a href="http://web.byui.edu/gradplan">Grad Planner </a>(web.byui.edu/gradplan) to plan out your remaining classes. Please realize that due to your high credits, you may only plan classes required to earn your degree.</li>
<li>When you are finished planning, click on "Submit for Approval." This will automatically send your plan to your major's Advising Center for approval.</li>
</ol>
<p>Grad Plans will be reviewed in the order they are received, and processing your request will take approximately one week. Making needed changes and adjustments to your Grad Plan will add to this time. Also, please note the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be aware of the date registration opens for the next semester you are planning. Please complete your Grad Plan today so that your class registration is not delayed.</li>
<li>If you will complete your degree by the end of the current semester and do not intend to enroll in future courses, no action is needed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h2>FAQs about High Credit Restriction</h2>
<hr />
<p><strong>Q. I will graduate next semester and have already submitted my graduation application. Am I still required to fill out a Grad Plan?</strong></p>
<p>A. Yes, you still need to enter your graduation plan into the Grad Plan tool. It will only take you a few minutes to complete since you have already done your planning.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Q. I recently applied for Fastgrad and already planned my classes. Am I still required to fill out a Grad Plan?</strong></p>
<p>A. Yes, you still need to enter your graduation plan into the Grad Plan tool. The Fastgrad process is separate from the online Grad Plan. It will only take you a few minutes to complete since you have already done your planning.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Q. What if planning for my required classes doesn't allow me to maintain a full-time student status because of sequencing or prerequisites within my major? Will my financial aid, scholarships or student employment be affected?</strong></p>
<p>A. Please fill out your Grad Plan with the classes required to earn your degree and then contact your <a href="x23703.xml">Satellite Advising Center</a> to discuss your student status.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Q. I have started using the Grad Plan tool and cannot find classes I've taken or am required to take.</strong></p>
<p>A. Classes that do not show up on your degree audit can be found by selecting the elective tab and then searching for the class you need.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Q. I am a transfer student and I transferred with a high number of credits; will I still be able to graduate with the degree I declared?</strong></p>
<p>A. In most cases, yes. We are primarily concerned about monitoring BYU-Idaho resources. For the purposes of this restriction, any unused transfer courses will not count against how many credits you may take at BYU-I. Please note that the Federal Government does not give aid for bachelor degree seeking students that have earned 180.0 or more credits. If you are a transfer student seeking an Associate degree, please contact <a href="http://www.byui.edu/financialaid/">Financial Aid </a>for details.</p>
<hr />
<p>For additional information, please contact your <a href="x24269.xml" title="Locations">Academic Discovery Center</a>.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
