<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x33991" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Futsal Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x33988" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><meta content="text/html; charset=utf-8" http-equiv="Content-Type" />
<title>Untitled Document</title>
</p>
<p><strong>Rule 2: Play </strong></p>
<p><em> <em>Start of Game</em><br /><br /></em></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Before play begins, a coin is tossed and the team that wins the toss will have the choice of which goal to attack. The second half play will begin with a kickoff by the team that did not kickoff to start the game. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">After the referee has given a signal, the game shall be started. The ball is in play when it is kicked in any direction. If the ball is not properly touched, the ball will again be placed on the kickoff mark and the kickoff will be retaken. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The kicker may not touch the ball again until it has been touched by another player.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A dropped ball is a way of restarting the match after a temporary stoppage. Play may also be restarted with an indirect free kick if, in the opinion of the officials, one team had clear possession of the ball when the stoppage occurred.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Timing</em><br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The duration of the game shall be two (2) equal halves of twenty (20) minutes. Halftime shall not exceed five (5) minutes. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The addition of time will be at the discretion of the official. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Time shall be extended to permit the taking of a penalty kick awarded before the sounding of the final whistle to end each half. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Regular season games may end in a tie. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">During playoffs, the following overtime procedures will be used: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A five (5) minute sudden-death overtime period will be played. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If teams are still tied at the end of overtime, the best out of five penalty kicks will win. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Teams will decide which player takes the penalty kicks and take turns on goal with the other team. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If still tied at the end of five attempts, each team will continue to select one player at a time to kick until the score is no longer tied.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Scoring</em><br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal is scored when the whole ball has passed over the goal line, between the goal posts and under the crossbar, provided that no infringement of the rules has been committed previously by the team scoring the goal. If the official's whistle sounds before the ball passes fully into the goal, the goal shall not be allowed. </span><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"></em><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal may be scored directly from a corner kick, but only against the opposing team. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal may be scored if a goalkeeper throws, punts, or dropkicks a ball into their own goal. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal cannot be scored directly from a kick-in; it must touch a member of either team before crossing the goal line to be counted as a goal. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Goals may be scored directly from a direct kick, but must be touched by another player on an indirect kick. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When females shoot, it will count as two (2) points, a male is only one (1) point, except in the case of penalty kicks or a shoot-out situation. In a penalty kick or shoot-out situation both a female and a male goal will count as one (1) point. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal cannot be scored directly from the kick-off.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Mercy Rule</em><br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If a team is ahead by seven or more goals with two minutes remaining in the second half, the game shall be called. If a team takes the lead by seven goals during the final two minutes of the second half, the game shall be called.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Ball In and Out of Play</em><br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball is out of play when:</span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">It has completely crossed the goal line or touch line whether on the ground or in the air</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The official sounds his/her whistle </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball is in play at all other times, including when: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">It rebounds from a goalpost or crossbar and remains in the field of play </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">It rebounds off of the official when he/she is on the field of play </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">There will be no whistle to restart play except: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When a team asks the official for five (5) yards </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When play has been stopped to caution or eject a player </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">For a penalty kick o When a goal is scored </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball is out of play when it touches the ceiling or net (the restart will be an indirect kick for the opponent from the spot of last touching).</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Fouls and Misconduct</em><br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Free kicks shall be classified under two types: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Direct - from which a goal can be scored directly against the offending side. All direct kicks awarded in the penalty area shall merit a penalty kick </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Indirect - from which a goal cannot be scored unless the ball has been touched by a player other than the kicker before passing into the goal. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Offenses for which a Direct kick shall be given are: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Kicking or attempting to kick an opponent Tripping or attempting to trip an opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Jumping at an opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Charging an opponent (A fair charge is one in which a player makes non-violent shoulder to-shoulder contact with an opponent, with the arms and elbows close to his/her own body, at least one foot on the ground, and the ball within playing distance </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Striking or attempting to strike and opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Pushing an opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Holding an opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Spitting at an opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Slide tackling an opponent </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Intentionally handling, carrying, striking, or propelling the ball with a hand or arm </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Using foul or abusive language directed towards a player or an official </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Handling by the goalkeeper outside the penalty area </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Offenses for which an Indirect free kick shall be given are: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Playing the ball a second time before it has been touched by another player at the kickoff, kick-in, a drop kick, a free kick, or a corner kick. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Obstructing the progress of an opponent Playing in a dangerous manner (i.e. high kick, playing on the ground) </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the goalkeeper takes more than six seconds while controlling the ball with their hands before releasing it into play </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the goalkeeper touches the ball with their hands after receiving it directly from a kick-in taken by a teammate </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the goalkeeper touches the ball with their hands after it has been deliberately kicked to him/her by a teammate A player prevents the goalkeeper from releasing the ball from his/her hands A player commits any offense for which play is stopped to caution or dismiss a player </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When a Direct or Indirect free kick is being taken, all opposing players shall be at least five (5) yards from the ball until it is kicked unless they are standing on their own goal line. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If a Direct or Indirect free kick is kicked directly into a team's own goal, a corner kick is awarded to the opposing team. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Treat all free kicks to be taken in the goal area by the defense as a goal kick </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">An Indirect kick to be taken in the goal area by the offense shall be taken from the top of the goal area line</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Penalty Kick</em><br /><br /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Awarded for any infringement of the rules, within the penalty area, that would require a direct free kick (including kicking the ball so that it touches the ceiling). </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A penalty kick shall be taken from the penalty mark. While the kick is being taken, all players with the exception of the player taking the kick and the opposing goalkeeper shall be within the field of play but outside the penalty area and at least five (5) yards from the penalty mark. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The opposing goalkeeper may only move laterally on his/her own goal line between the goalposts, until the ball is kicked. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The player taking the kick must kick the ball forward. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Should the ball hit the goalposts or crossbar and rebound into play, the player who kicked the ball must not play it again until it has been touched by another player. Penalty: Indirect free kick </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The ball shall be deemed in play directly after it is kicked. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Kick-In:&nbsp;</em><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When the ball passes completely over a sideline, it shall be kicked in from the point where it crossed the line by a player of the team opposite to that of the player who it last touched. </span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A player shall: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Place the ball on the ground on or behind the sideline and proceed to take the kick following the rules of an indirect free kick. The ball shall be in play immediately after it has crossed over the line and may be played by any player except the one who executes the kick-in. Five (5) yards shall be given, the same as all free kick situations. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the ball is improperly kicked into play, the restart shall be taken by a player of the opposing team. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If the ball fails to enter the field of play, it shall be kicked again. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">If an opponent interferes with or in any way impedes the actions of the thrower/kicker while the kick-in is being taken, the official will administer a yellow card for unsportsmanlike conduct. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Goalkeepers cannot handle a ball that is kicked-in directly to them by their own team. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal cannot be scored directly from a kick-in. It must touch a member of either team before crossing the goal line to be counted as a goal. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Drop Ball</em><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Drop ball occurs: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When the ball is caused to go out-of-bounds by two opponents simultaneously. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Following a suspension of play for an injury or other situation in which no team has clear possession of the ball. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A foul by both teams occurring simultaneously. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The spot of the drop ball is where the ball becomes dead unless this is in the goal area, in which case the spot is the nearest point on the goal line in the field of play. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Goal Clearance</em><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal clearance shall be awarded to the defending team when the ball crosses the goal line, having last been touched by the attacking team. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal clearance shall be performed by the goalie throwing or rolling the ball outside of the penalty area. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Players opposing the kicker shall remain outside the penalty area until the ball moves out of the penalty area. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">A goal clearance must clear the penalty area and enter the field of play or the goal clearance will be retaken. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">After the goal clearance leaves the penalty area, any player except the one who executed the goal kick may play the ball. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Corner Kick</em><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">When the ball is last touched by the defending team and goes over the goal line, a member of the attacking team shall take a kick from the corner of the court. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Players of the team opposing that of the player taking the corner kick shall not approach within five (5) yards of the ball until it is in play. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">After the corner kick is first touched, any player except the one who executes the corner kick may play the ball. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Corner kicks are direct free kicks. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Slide Tackling</em><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Slide tackling shall be defined as player sliding in a way that endangers another player, i.e. sliding while trying to take the ball from another player's control or fighting for possession. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Slide tackling is prohibited, and any player in violation of this rule will be issued a sportsmanship infraction. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Depending on the severity of the slide tackle, a major or minor misconduct may be given. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Sliding is not a violation of the soccer rules, as long as it does not endanger any other players on the field. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"><em>NOTE: </em></strong><em style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">See Policy and Procedure for more information on eligibility, captain's responsibilities, participant's responsibilities, league definitions, registration information, roster information, rescheduling requests, defaults, forfeits, sportsmanship, honor code policy, protests, and post season scheduling and eligibility.</em></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
