<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x34088" Name="Service Director"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Director</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Director</strong></p>
<p>As a director, you'll have the opportunity to direct, teach, train, counsel, and provide vision to students who are building programs and events in Activities. In this position you'll learn, stretch, grow and also help grow others.</p>
<p>The Campus Service Director will lead and supervise a couple of new campus programs and oversee the investigation and proposal of new campus service opportunities.</p>
<p>The Community Service Director will lead and supervise Coordinators working with Community service events and programs.</p>
<p>The Director is responsible for selecting, training, and managing all of the student leaders in their area. it requires significant leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. On average, 10 hours each week will need to be dedicated to this position.</p>
<p><strong>General Responsibilities:</strong></p>
<p>Promote the goals and objectives of the Activities and Service Activities programs</p>
<p>Teach the doctrine of service and help instill lifelong service values</p>
<p>Supervise, coach, train, and grow Service Activities Coordinators, and ensure they are doing the same for the Program Managers they work with</p>
<p>Ensure Service Activities programs and events are well planned and managed, and that student volunteers are given ample opportunities to participate and grow through service</p>
<p>Plan and conduct weekly Service Activities meetings</p>
<p>Serve as a member of the Student Activities Council (SAC)</p>
<p><strong>Immediate Responsibilities if Selected as Director:</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Must be available to interview and select program coordinators and managers positions.</p>
<p>Must be able to plan and attend the trainings (mandatory to be a director).</p>
<p><strong>Other trainings to be announced</strong>.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
