<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x34086" Name="Service Manager"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Manager</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Managers</strong></p>
<p>Student Managers are responsible for the planning and execution of events with the help of a council of volunteers. Managers counsel with their Coordinator about their stewardship and how to meet the needs of the students.</p>
<p>Specifically, managers within Service Activities perform the following roles.</p>
<p> <strong>Blood Drive Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Red Cross Blood Drive program manager ensures the promotion of 2-3 blood drives and recruits student volunteers to become blood donors. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 3-4 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>High School Tutoring Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the High School Tutoring program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Head Start Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Head Start program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers who work with preschool children of special needs families in an educational setting. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Adopt-A-Grandparent Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Adopt-A-Grandparent program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers who will visit and serve the elderly. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Kid Connection Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Kid Connection manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers who mentor children in weekday after school programs and activities. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Project Inspire Manager</strong><br />Project Inspire is a unique program whereby students initiate their own service excursion that typically lasts multiple days during semester breaks. Students who want to initiate their own service excursion will become the manager over their own project and are expected to meet certain requirements and deadlines to qualify for the experience. A plan and proposal for your service excursion needs to be approved through the Service directors' council and Service advisors, and you will be expected to work effectively and consistently with the self-initiated service coordinator for training, coaching, and accountability.</p>
<p>To manage a Project Inspire excursion requires effective leadership and communication skills and a high degree of self-initiative, follow through, and commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to this position.</p>
<p>General Responsibilities</p>
<p>•·         Select, train, and lead a council to run your service event</p>
<p>•·         If working with a sponsoring community agency, coordinate with them through effective and consistent communication</p>
<p>•·         Teach and instill lifelong service doctrine and values in council members and volunteers.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Humanitarian Service Organization Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Humanitarian Service Organization program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers who complete humanitarian aid projects such as hygiene and educational kits. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Campus Initiated Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Campus Initiated Manager program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Merit Badge Pow Wow Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Merit Badge Pow Wow manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers who assist as merit badge counselors at the Boy Scouts' Merit Badge Pow Wow event. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 3-5 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>School Carnivals Manager</strong><br />With the assistance of a student council, the School Carnivals Manager program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Community Initiated Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Community Initiated Manager program manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities for student volunteers. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Charity Date Auction Manager<br /></strong>If selected to fill a position in the Charity Date Auction program, you will <strong>oversee</strong> a council of student volunteers that assist with the planning, organizing, and implementation of the annual Charity Date Auction event. This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Family Crisis Center Manager<br /></strong>With the assistance of a student council, the Family Crisis Center manager oversees and facilitates the planning and execution of service opportunities at the Family Crisis Center location in Rexburg, ID.  This position requires good leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally, 5-8 hours a week need to be dedicated to the manager position.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
