<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x34087" Name="Service Coordinator"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Coordinator</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coordinators</strong></p>
<p>Though not involved in the tactical planning and execution of events, coordinators oversee specific programs in Activities and lead, train, counsel and help managers succeed as they run programs and events. In Service, there are coordinator positions for Humanitarian, Community, and Campus.</p>
<p>The Service Coordinators are responsible for training, coordinatig, and supporting program managers. These positions require significant leadership and communication skills and a high degree of commitment. Generally 5-7 hours each week need to be dedicated to this position.</p>
<p> <strong>General Responsibilities</strong></p>
<p>Assist in promoting the goals and objectives of the Activities and Service Activities programs</p>
<p>Teach the doctrine of service and help instill lifelong service values</p>
<p>Supervise, coach, train, and grow Service Activities Coordinators, and ensure they are doing the same for the Program Managers they work with</p>
<p>Oversee and support 3-6 service programs</p>
<p>Ensure Service Activities programs and events are well planned and managed, and that student volunteers are given ample opportunities to participate and grow through service</p>
<p>Conduct various stewardship/training/support meetings</p>
<p>Advise on issues in Service Directors Meeting</p>
<p>In order to be eligible to apply, a coordinator must be able to meet all of the following trainings, meetings, and conditions: <br /><strong>Academic Standards Requirements: </strong></p>
<p>Be enrolled in at least one day-time class in the semester for which you are applying.</p>
<p>Have a minimum GPA of 2.5.</p>
<p><strong>Immediate Responsibilities if Selected as Coordinator:</strong></p>
<p>Must be available to interview and select all of the Community Service program manager positions prior to the begining of the next semester.</p>
<p>Must be able to plan and attend trainings (mandatory to be a coordinator)Training Date TBA:</p>
<p>Other training to be announced.</p>
<p>Must be able to attend regular meetings during the semester.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
