<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x34591" Name="Questions? " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Questions?</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently asked questions regarding regular employment at BYU-Idaho</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>ANSWERS TO COMMON QUESTIONS</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="#How do I learn about available openings">How do I learn about available openings at BYU-Idaho?&nbsp;</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a name="How_do_I_apply_for_a_position"></a><a href="#How do I apply for a position">How do I apply for a position?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#How long does my application remain active">How long does my application remain active?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="How_long_are_job_openings_advertised"></a><a href="#How long are job openings advertised">How long are job openings advertised or posted?&nbsp;</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#If the closing date for a job is extended">If the closing date for a job opening is extended, does that mean&nbsp;there were no qualified applicants?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#I just saw a job posting that closes today">I just saw a job posting that closes today, and I need to get materials ready. What can I do?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#I just found out about a job posting">I just found out about a job posting that has already closed. Can I still submit an application?&nbsp;</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#If I am a current BYU-Idaho employee">If I am a current BYU-Idaho employee applying for a different position, do I need to submit an application?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="If_I_am_applying_for_more_than_one_job"></a><a href="#If I am applying for more than one job">If I am applying for more than one job opening at the same time, will I need separate applications for each position?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#I have gotten my user name and/or password">I have forgotten my user name and/or password for the BYU-Idaho online application system. What should I do?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="If_I_already_have_an_online_user_name_an"></a><a href="#If I already have an online user name and application">If I already have an online user name and application, will I be contacted when positions open for which I am qualified?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#Do I need to complete the employment history">Do I need to complete the "Employment History" section on the application if I am submitting a resume that will include that information?</a><br /><br /><a name="What_is_the_difference_between_a_letter_"></a><a href="#What is the difference between a letter of recommendation and a reference letter">What is the difference between a letter of recommendation and a reference letter? </a>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="#Are letters of recommendation and resumes necessary">Are letters of recommendation and resumes necessary? What about cover letters?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#I know people who are employed at the university">I know people who are employed by the university. Should I use them as my references?</a><br /><a name="I_do_not_meet_the_education_requirements"></a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="#I do not meet the education requirements">I do not meet the education requirements for a position but do have related work experience. Should I still apply?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&nbsp;<a href="#Why didn't I receive an interview">Why didn't I receive an interview when I met the qualification requirements listed in the job posting?&nbsp;</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#I have applied for several openings without receiving an interview">I have applied for several openings without receiving an interview (or have been interviewed without receiving a job offer). Should I keep applying?</a>&nbsp;<br /> <br /> <a name="Can_I_receive_feedback_about_my_applicat"></a><a href="#Can I receive feedback about my application">Can I receive feedback about my application materials or about an interview?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#Can I work with or for a relative or family member">Can I work with or for a relative or family member who is currently employed at BYU-Idaho?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#Am I eligible to work for BYU-Idaho">Am I eligible to work for BYU-Idaho if I am not a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="Do_LDS_employees_need_to_hold_a_current_"></a><a href="#Do LDS employees need to hold a current temple recommend">Do LDS employees need to hold a current temple recommend to work for BYU-Idaho?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="Do_I_need_to_contact_my_bishop"></a><a href="#Do I need to contact my bishop">Do I need to contact my bishop for a worthiness interview before applying to work at BYU-Idaho?&nbsp;</a><br /> <br /> <a name="Does_BYU-Idaho_conduct_background_checks"></a> <a href="#Does BYU-Idaho conduct background checks">Does BYU-Idaho conduct background checks?</a> &nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a name="What_is_the_process_after_the_posting_ha"></a><a href="#What is the process after the posting has closed">What is the process after the posting has closed?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#How many final interview candidates are chosen">How many final interview candidates are chosen?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="Will_I_be_notified_if_I_am_not_selected"></a><a href="#Will I be notified if I am not selected">Will I be notified if I am not selected to receive a final interview?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="What_benefits_are_provided"></a><a href="#What benefits are provided">What benefits are provided for employees?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="How_are_job_offers_determined"></a><a href="#How are job offers determined">How are job offers (salaries/wages) determined?</a><br /> <br /> <a name="What_is_a_salary_range"></a><a href="#What is a salary range">What is a salary range and what is its purpose?</a><br /> <br /> <a href="#How does the university determine the market average pay rate">How does the university determine the market average pay rate for jobs?&nbsp;</a></p>
<p><em>For further assistance, contact the HR Employment Assistant at 208-496-1716.</em></p>
<p><strong><a name="How do I learn about available openings"></a>Q: How do I learn about available openings at BYU-Idaho? <br />A:</strong> Job openings are advertised on the BYU-Idaho webpage under the link "Faculty, Administration, and Staff Job Openings." Other resources can be found at LDS Employment Services (although this site is not maintained by BYU-Idaho).<br /><br /><strong><a name="How do I apply for a position"></a>Q: How do I apply for a position?<br />A:</strong> Complete the BYU-Idaho Application for Employment found on the BYU-Idaho webpage under the link "Faculty, Administration, and Staff Job Openings."<br /><br /><strong><a name="How long does my application remain active"></a>Q: How long does my application remain active?<br />A:</strong> The online system currently expires user profiles three years from its last update. An application is updated by an applicant each time it is submitted for an opening.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="How long are job openings advertised"></a>Q: How long are job openings advertised or posted? <br />A:</strong> All jobs are posted for a minimum of five business days, with staff and administrative positions typically posted for 10 to 14 days. Full-time faculty positions are usually posted for 8 weeks. Posting length depends on the position and market conditions as well as the availability of those working with the hiring process.<br /><br /><strong><a name="If the closing date for a job is extended"></a>Q: If the closing date for a job opening is extended, does that mean&nbsp;there were no qualified applicants?<br />A: </strong>That is one possible reason, but can also be due to internal scheduling or availability concerns.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I just saw a job posting that closes today"></a>Q: I just saw a job posting that closes today, and I need to get materials ready. What can I do?<br />A:</strong> Complete the application submittal process online before midnight CST (Central Standard Time) of the close date. Call the Human Resources Office (208-496-1700) for direction if optional documents (like reference letters) are not yet available. Having a complete application already in the system allows an applicant to complete a process for a specific position in just minutes.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I just found out about a job posting"></a>Q: I just found out about a job posting that has already closed. Can I still submit an application? <br />A:</strong> Once the online posting closes, applicants are no longer able to attach an application to that posting.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="If I am a current BYU-Idaho employee"></a>Q: If I am a current BYU-Idaho employee applying for a different position, do I need to submit an application?<br />A:</strong> Yes. All applicants must submit a current application, including current employees.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="If I am applying for more than one job"></a>Q: If I am applying for more than one job opening at the same time, will I need separate applications for each position?<br />A:</strong> One application (and one user profile) will be sufficient for all the posting to which you apply. Additional materials such as a resume, cover letter, or reference letters can be tailored for each position.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I have forgotten my user name and/or password"></a><a name="I have gotten my user name and/or password"></a>Q: I have forgotten my user name and/or password for the BYU-Idaho online application system. What should I do?<br />A:</strong> There is no need to create a new user name and password. You can retrieve this information by clicking on "Forgot your username or password" on the system login page. Contact the Human Resources Office (208-496-1700) if you need assistance.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="If I already have an online user name and application"></a>Q: If I already have an online user name and application, will I be contacted when positions open for which I am qualified?<br />A:</strong> A direct contact to an applicant regarding an opening is possible for recruiting purposes but this is not available as a general service to applicants. An email list service is under consideration and may be offered in the future.<br /><br /><strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;"><a name="Do I need to complete the employment history"></a>Q: Do I need to complete the "Employment History" section on the application if I am submitting a resume that will include that information?</strong><strong><a name="Do I need to complete the &quot;Employment History&quot;"></a><br /></strong><strong>A:</strong> Yes. Both an application and a resume are necessary to verify past employment. Information is requested in the application that is not generally provided on resumes. Failure to provide information could affect consideration of an applicant.<br /><strong></strong><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong><strong><a name="What is the difference between a letter of recommendation and a reference letter"></a>Q: What is the difference between a letter of recommendation and a reference letter?<br />A:</strong></strong>&nbsp;Reference letters are typically general recommendations that you provide in your application. &nbsp;Letters of recommendation are confidentially submitted recommendations that are more specific to the job posting. &nbsp;Letters of recommendation remain confidential after the hiring process.</p>
<p><strong><a name="Are letters of recommendation and resumes necessary"></a>Q: Are letters of recommendation and resumes necessary? What about cover letters?<br />A:</strong> Letters of recommendation are optional (unless otherwise indicated), but a current resume is generally required because it will usually provide different information than the application. Cover letters are optional (unless otherwise indicated) and can be a helpful way to communicate additional information.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I know people who are employed at the university"></a>Q: I know people who are employed by the university. Should I use them as my references?<br />A:</strong> Not necessarily. References are most valuable when the relationship between the applicant and the reference provider allows specific, objective information relevant to the applicant and the position being sought.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I do not meet the education requirements"></a>Q: I do not meet the education requirements for a position but do have related work experience. Should I still apply?<br />A:</strong> Anyone who is interested in a position is invited to apply; however, a person should be aware that typically other applicants will possess both the required or preferred education and work experience as outlined in the posting.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="Why didn't I receive an interview"></a>Q: Why didn't I receive an interview when I met the qualification requirements listed in the job posting? <br />A:</strong> Normally, the majority of an applicant group meets the qualification requirements. Only a small number will be processed as final interview candidates. Applicants should remember that they are not only assessed against the job requirements but also against other applicants in a competitive selection process.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I have applied for several openings without receiving an interview"></a>Q: I have applied for several openings without receiving an interview (or have been interviewed without receiving a job offer). Should I keep applying? <br />A: </strong>The decision to apply is a personal one which should be made based on the overall match of your qualifications to a job and your level of interest in employment at BYU-Idaho. Well-qualified applicants are always encouraged to persist in seeking opportunities with the university.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="Can I receive feedback about my application"></a>Q: Can I receive feedback about my application materials or about an interview?<br />A:</strong> While the university recognizes the desire of applicants to improve, specific feedback or guidance about materials will not be provided. Specific information regarding the application review, candidate selection, or interview processes will also not be disclosed.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="Can I work with or for a relative or family member"></a>Q: Can I work with or for a relative or family member who is currently employed at BYU-Idaho?<br />A:</strong> Near relatives may not normally be employed where they will work in close proximity in administrative relationships or location. They may not be employed where their positions would cause management concerns about preferential treatment of a relative in such things as hiring, promoting, allocating salary, assigning duties, arranging schedules, allocating equipment or facilities, or handling discipline or termination. &nbsp;This policy applies to full-time, part-time, student, and temporary personnel.&nbsp;The university reserves the right to make an exception to this policy.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="Am I eligible to work for BYU-Idaho"></a>Q: Am I eligible to work for BYU-Idaho if I am not a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints?<br />A:</strong> Yes. However, as a private institution BYU-Idaho reserves the right to prefer members in good standing with the Church, and requires that all employees agree to maintain LDS standards as defined by the Honor Code.<br /><br /><strong><a name="Do LDS employees need to hold a current temple recommend"></a>Q: Do LDS employees need to hold a current temple recommend to work for BYU-Idaho?<br />A:</strong> Although that is preferable, the requirement is that LDS employees must be living a life that is worthy of receiving a temple recommend.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="Do I need to contact my bishop"></a>Q: Do I need to contact my bishop for a worthiness interview before applying to work at BYU-Idaho? <br />A:</strong> No. An authorized university representative will contact your bishop to conduct an ecclesiastical reference check if you become a final candidate for a position.</p>
<p><strong><a name="Does BYU-Idaho conduct background checks"></a>Q: Does BYU-Idaho conduct background checks?<br />A:</strong>&nbsp;Yes. Background checks are conducted by a secure provider that is employed by the university.</p>
<p><strong><a name="What is the process after the posting has closed"></a></strong><strong>Q: What is the process after the posting has closed?<br />A:</strong> A review of all application materials begins and is coordinated from either the Human Resources Office (for administrative or staff positions) or from the Academic Office (for faculty positions) with the selection committee assembled for the hiring process. When final candidates are selected, then all applicants are notified of the outcome.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="How many final interview candidates are chosen"></a>Q: How many final interview candidates are chosen?<br />A: </strong>Generally three candidates are chosen, but, occasionally, more are selected.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="Will I be notified if I am not selected"></a>Q: Will I be notified if I am not selected to receive a final interview?<br />A: </strong>Once final candidates have been selected, every effort is made to send an email notification promptly to the applicants who are not receiving final interviews. If you do not provide an accurate email address on your application, this service is affected. Applicants can also check the status of the hiring process in the online application system.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="What benefits are provided"></a>Q: What benefits are provided for employees?<br />A: </strong>The university provides a benefits plan which is an important part of an employee's total compensation package. Details can be viewed <a href="x34593.xml">here</a>. &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="How are job offers determined"></a>Q: How are job offers (salaries/wages) determined?<br />A: </strong>Most offers are at or slightly above the minimum of the payscale. Job offers above the minimum reflect consideration of the employee's qualifications in comparison to the minimum requirements of the job.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="What is a salary range"></a>Q: What is a salary range and what is its purpose?<br />A: </strong>A salary range defines the minimum, average, and maximum pay rate that ought to be paid for a particular job. It helps the university determine whether employees are appropriately compensated for their job responsibilities. The average of a salary range reflects the university's assessment of the market average. Only the minimum of a payscale is released for advertising purposes.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="How does the university determine the market average pay rate"></a>Q: How does the university determine the market average pay rate for jobs? <br />A:</strong> BYU-Idaho participates in three major salary surveys each year: College and University Professional Association for Human Resources (CUPA-HR), Idaho Compensation and Benefits, and Idaho Occupational Employment and Wages. Other regional or company specific studies are done as appropriate to assess market salaries in addition to these surveys. Collectively, these surveys provide comprehensive salary data for jobs throughout the nation including within our region and state. The salary range is based on market research and internal job evaluations. Market research is a process of determining the average pay rate assigned to particular jobs in the market; internal job evaluation is a process of determining the internal equity of jobs on campus in relation to one another.<br /><br /><strong></strong><strong><a name="I still have some questions"></a></strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x26193" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
