<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x34593" Name="Employee Benefits" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Employee Benefits</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Employee benefits for full-time faculty, administrative, and staff employees at BYU-Idaho.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p><br /><strong>Employee Benefits</strong><br />&nbsp;<br /><a href="http://www.dmba.com/">DMBA</a>, a non-profit organization, administers insurance and financial benefits for full-time BYU-Idaho employees.&nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Insurance Benefits</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Medical Insurance (for employee, spouse, and dependent children)<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Dental Insurance (for employee, spouse, and dependent children)<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Supplemental Vision Insurance (for employee, spouse, and dependent children)&nbsp;<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Disability (employee coverage)<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Group Term Life Insurance (employee and dependent coverage)<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Occupational Accidental Death and&nbsp;Dismemberment Insurance (employee coverage)&nbsp;<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; 24-Hour Accidental Death &amp; Dismemberment Insurance (employee and&nbsp;dependent coverage)<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &bull;&nbsp; Long-term Care Insurance (employee and&nbsp;dependent coverage)<br /><br /><strong>Retirement and&nbsp;Savings Plans</strong><br /><br /><em>Pension Plan</em> - The Deseret Mutual Master Retirement Plan is a university-funded "defined benefit" plan. Five years of employment are required for vesting, (i.e., ownership). At retirement, benefits are calculated based on the employee's age, salary history, and years of service.<br /><br /><em>Investment Plan</em> - The Deseret Mutual Thrift Plan is a long-term, "defined contribution," retirement savings program designed to work with Social Security benefits, personal savings, and employer-funded Master Retirement Plan benefits. Employees can contribute a portion of their salary to 401(k), Roth 401(k), and 401(a) investment options. The university will match a percentage of the employee's contribution to these options. The percentage of employer match depends on several eligibility factors and the percentage of the employee contribution.<br /><br /><em>TIAA-CREF (</em>Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, College Retirement Equities Fund) provides a 403(b) savings plan for employees; however, the university does not provide matching funds for TIAA-CREF contributions.<br /><br /><strong>Flexible Spending Accounts</strong> <br /><br /><em>Flexible Spending Accounts</em> (FSAs) allow full-time employees to use pre-tax dollars to cover out-of-pocket health-related expenses (medical, dental, vision, etc.) and dependent child care expenses.<br /><br /><strong>Value Benefits</strong><br /><br /><em>Value benefits</em> provide discounts for auto and homeowner's insurance, Lasik Surgery, Dell or Epson products, vehicle purchases, cell phone services, etc.&nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Education Benefits</strong> <br /><br />Full-time employees receive 6 credit hours of <em>free tuition</em> per semester; a spouse and dependent children receive tuition waiver after the employee has completed either one year of service (for employees 27 year of age or older) or two years of service (for employees under 27). Until age 30, children of an employee may use the waiver (76 credit hours maximum applies) at BYU-Idaho, BYU, or LDS Business College for undergraduate credits.<br /><br />Full-time employees who desire to pursue graduate or doctoral degrees, thereby enhancing their performance or advancing their career opportunities, may receive <em>professional development</em> leave or tuition assistance. Assistance for advanced degrees is normally granted after years of full-time service and does require service after the benefit is provided.<br /><br /><strong>Paid Leave</strong><br /><br />Faculty members normally schedule <em>vacation</em> time during academic breaks. Full-time administrative (exempt) employees accrue 22 days of vacation annually and staff (non-exempt) employees accrue 12 days per year with accrual increases every five years (up to 15 years).<br /><br />Faculty members do not accrue <em>sick leave</em>, rather fellow faculty share the workload during a colleague's illness. All full-time administrative and staff employees accrue up to 12 days every year.<br /><br />The university observes ten <em>holidays</em> each year for which full-time employees receive compensation.<br /><br /><strong>Relocation Assistance</strong> <br /><br /><em>Relocation benefits</em> do not apply to staff (non-exempt/hourly) positions, part-time positions, one-year or temporary (6 months or less) appointments, or for persons living within a 50 mile radius of Rexburg. An employee who does not complete one full year of service must reimburse the university for moving expenses.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>1. House Hunting:</strong> The university will assist with the least expensive of the following two options:<br /><br />Airfare: The BYU-Idaho Travel Office arranges and pays for round-trip coach airfare (for employee and spouse only). Employee pays all other expenses and may use BYU-I Travel to receive discounted hotel rates.<br /><br />Vehicle: The university <em>reimburses </em>(after receipts are submitted)<em> </em>for the following:<br /><br />1. Direct mileage from residence to Rexburg and back at the approved IRS rate.<br />2. Reasonable and modest lodging (double occupancy) in Rexburg for up to two nights. Lodging is arranged by the BYU-I Travel Office.<br />3. Meal allowance is provided for up to three days at $32/day per person (for employee and spouse).<br /><br /><strong>2. Moving Expenses:</strong> The employee may choose between the following two options:<br /><br />Commercial: BYU-Idaho will arrange and pay for moving services for up to 18,000 lbs through a designated commercial carrier. This benefit is for packing and transportation of <em>household goods only</em> and does not cover other miscellaneous moving costs.&nbsp;<br /><br />Private: If an employee prefers to move individually, the university will reimburse reasonable costs for packing materials, truck rental fees and fuel, lodging and meals, and direct mileage for one personal vehicle, and will also provide $750 for miscellaneous expenses.<br /><br /><strong>3. Coordination of Relocation:</strong> House hunting and moving must be coordinated through the BYU-Idaho Human Resources Office (208-496-1700). No arrangements for faculty hires can be made until the Board of Trustees gives approval, at which time faculty hires will be contacted by the Human Resources Office.<br /><br /><br /></p>
<!--EndEditor--></div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x26193" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
