<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x34763" Name="Insurance and  Health Plan" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Insurance and  Health Plan</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Insurance and Records at the BYU-Idaho Student Health Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<style><!--
th{
	background-color: #333333;
}
td, th {
	padding: 5px;
}
--></style>
<div id="headblock">
<div id="content_header">
<div class="icons"></div>
<div class="titlehead">Insurance and Health Plan</div>
<div class="subhead"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="content_zone">
<div id="faceof" style="top: 180px;">Co. Deseret Mutual</div>
<div id="top_sec">
<div class="quote clear" style="width: 90%; margin: 5px 0 10px 15px;"><strong>The Student Health Center is not a contracted provider with any insurance company aside from the BYU-Idaho Student Health Plan. Therefore, the Student Health Center does not bill private insurance. If you have private insurance, you may be seen at the Student Health Center, but you will be responsible for the full cost of your visit. You may have an insurance form printed out that you can mail into your insurance company. They will reimburse you in accordance with their policy.</strong></div>
</div>
<div id="bot_sec">
<div id="dropMenu">
<div class="notActive">
<div class="sh" onclick="showhide('ww',null)">Click Here for changes Starting Fall Semester 2013!!!</div>
<div class="dropContent" id="ww" style="display: none; padding: 5px 15px 20px 0px;"><br />
<ul>
<li>
<h5>Check back often for more updates.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>If this is not insurance what is it?</h5>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Student Health Plan(SHP) is a student health plan offered by BYU-Idaho that continues to offer comprehensive health benefits to BYU-Idaho students and, if enrolled in coverage with an additional contribution, their dependents. The SHP will pay for medical services incurred both at the on-campus Student Health Center and from off-campus medical providers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>How do the changes affect me?</h5>
<p>Honestly, the change from the SHP being an insured plan to a self-funded plan doesn't affect you or your benefits much at all. What is covered and not covered under the SHP has not changed for the 2013-2014 year in any significant way at all. If you have any specific benefit questions, call Deseret Mutual at 801-578-5600.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Why did my contribution increase?</h5>
<p>As is done every year, contributions are calculated each year for your SHP coverage based off of the benefits offered, as well as past SHP experience (i.e. the number and amount claims that the SHP has paid in recent years). One thing that is important to remember is that neither BYU-Idaho nor Deseret Mutual make a profit from the SHP or its contributions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Why do I have a $500.00 deductible?</h5>
<p>By introducing a $500 deductible for all students covered by the SHP ($1,000 deductible per family), the SHP is able to:</p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: decimal; text-align: justify;">Keep contribution rates from increasing at a higher rate</li>
<li style="list-style-type: decimal; text-align: justify;">Still provide the currently covered preventive benefits at 100% of maximum allowable when you see contracted providers (for specific benefit questions, call Deseret Mutual at 801-578-5600)</li>
<li style="list-style-type: decimal; text-align: justify;">Simplify SHP benefits so that all students, single or married, have consistent benefits throughout the school year (i.e. a change in your marital status will no longer affect your contribution or cause you to have "new" deductible on your plan).</li>
</ul>
<p style="margin-top: 20px;"><em>*Please remember that the $500.00 deductible only applies to non-preventive services received outside of the on-campus SHC.*</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>
<h5>Why did BYU-Idaho change their health care?</h5>
<p>BYU-Idaho, like many prominent universities, including: the University of California system (UCLA, UC Berkeley, UC Santa Cruz, etc.); Harvard University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Princeton University, University of Iowa, University of Wisconsin, Yale University, as well as BYU and BYU-Hawaii is following a national trend to make the Student Health Plan (SHP) self-funded.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Did BYU-Idaho feel it was necessary to change the health care plan or did they <strong>have</strong> too?</h5>
<p>Becoming a self-funded plan allows BYU-Idaho to not only sponsor the SHP, but it also allows BYU-Idaho to be in direct control of the benefits offered by the SHP, including the way benefits and customer service are delivered to its participants. That direct control makes becoming a self-funded plan very attractive for school sponsored college health plans (see above list of notable schools that feel the same).</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>How long did it take for this change to happen?</h5>
<p>The ability for the SHP to become a self-funded plan was made possible through Idaho State legislation that was passed in the recent Spring 2013 legislative session. The Student Health Plan is currently completing the process to be self-funded to be in effect at the start of the 2013-2014 academic year.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>How does this plan benefit students better?</h5>
<p>As mentioned before, this change will put BYU-Idaho in direct control of SHP benefits. This means that BYU-Idaho will have more flexibility with plan benefits and be able to respond uniquely to its students&rsquo; specific health needs in a way that a fully-insured plan isn&rsquo;t able to.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>What have students paid in the past?</h5>
<p>An additional change to the SHP this year is the introduction of a $500 deductible for all students and their covered dependents (with a $1,000 maximum deductible per family). In the past several years, it has only been married students who have had an upfront deductible under the SHP ($750 individual; $1,500 family). Now, all students, married or single, will have an up-front deductible that is consistent. Another change is that there will be only two contributions charged: one for student-only coverage and another for student and dependent coverage. This is another example of introducing consistency, so that a student won&rsquo;t see his/her individual SHP deductible rise just because he/she gets married during the school year.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Do these changes affect international students differently?</h5>
<p>No, they do not. All students will be treated the same way that they have always been treated.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>How have students reacted to the changes?</h5>
<p>At this time we have had limited response from the students. We are trying to be proactive by delivering information as it becomes available using the SHC home web page.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Do all students have to pay the $500, even if they don&rsquo;t use the health center?</h5>
<p>All students covered by the SHP will pay the $500 up-front deductible when they receive services outside of the Student Health Center. One important exception is that currently established preventive services will be exempt from the up-front deductible, no matter where a student or their covered dependent receives those services (i.e. at the Student Health Center or through an off-campus provider).</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Who is the provider that is being rendered? Have we worked with this provider before?</h5>
<p>a. Deseret Mutual in Salt Lake City, UT will continue to process SHP claims and provide customer service support for the SHP. Deseret Mutual has performed these services for the BYU-Idaho SHP since the SHP&rsquo;s inception. Deseret Mutual has done (and continues to do) the same for the BYU and BYU-Hawaii SHPs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>How will this affect the future of BYU-Idaho&rsquo;s health center and students?</h5>
<p>The SHP will continue to provide services for the students and eligible dependents as it has done so in the past. There will be no notable changes</p>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Please review the following links:</h5>
<a href="http://www.healthcare.gov/using-insurance/understanding/index.html">Understanding Insurance</a><br /> <a href="http://www.healthcare.gov/using-insurance/understanding/basics/index.html">Insurance Basics</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<p><a href="http://www.dmba.com/nsc/Student/Handbooks.aspx">STUDENT HEALTH PLAN HANDBOOK</a></p>
<p><a href="x37061.xml">FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="240" id="footer" scrolling="no" src="Documents/health-center/footer.html" width="100%"></iframe></p>
<p><link href="Documents/health-center/css/header.css" rel="stylesheet" /> <link href="Documents/health-center/css/body.css" rel="stylesheet" /> <link href="Documents/health-center/css/insurance.css" rel="stylesheet" /></p>
<p>
<script src="Documents/health-center/js/basic-dropdown.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28441" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
