<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x34829" Name="Physicians and Staff" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physicians and Staff</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physicians and Staff of the BYU-Idaho Student Health Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div id="headblock">
<div id="content_header">
<div class="icons"></div>
<div class="titlehead">Physicians &amp; Staff</div>
<div class="subhead"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="content_zone">
<table border="0" class="clear" id="staff" style="margin: 0;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Shaun Orr" height="214" src="Images/health-center/orr.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Shaun Orr, Student Health Center Director</h4>
<p>Shaun received his Masters of Business Administration degree from Idaho State University. In his ten years at Eastern Idaho Regional Medical Center, he held several responsibilities, including budgeting and forecasting for over 100 departments and facilitating the expansion of hospital services to Yellowstone National Park. Shaun joined the Student Health Center in 2004, and currently serves as the BYU-Idaho HIPAA Security Officer.<br /><br /></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Tammy Einerson" height="214" src="Images/health-center/einerson.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Tammy Einerson, Operations Manager</h4>
<p>Tammy attended Weber State University while working in medical billing for Duchesne County Hospital. She then went on to Ashley Valley Medical Center before managing a highly successful medical billing business for over twenty years. Tammy joined the Student Health Center in 2010.<br /><br /> &nbsp; Tammy and her husband have been married for thirty-four years. They are the parents of three sons, and they currently have seven grandchildren with whom she and her husband spend much of their free time. Together, they enjoy four-wheeling, golfing, and riding their Harley Davidson motorcycle. Tammy also likes to quilt and tend to her garden.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Dr. Bradbury" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Bradbury.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Dr. Andrew Bradbury, Medical Director</h4>
<p>Dr. Bradbury, a Fellow of the American Academy of Family Physicians, received his MD degree from Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia in 1986. His lengthy military service includes Flight Surgeon in Afghanistan, Iraq, and Saudi Arabia. Dr. Bradbury joined the Student Health Center in 2000, becoming Medical Director in 2011. Dr. Bradbury also has Board certifications in Family Medicine and Emergency Medicine.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Dr. Rammel" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Rammell.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Dr. Corey Rammell, Physician</h4>
<p>Dr. Rammell, a Ricks College alumnus, is a board certified physician of the American Academy of Family Physicians. He graduated from the University of Utah School of Medicine in 1990 and completed his residency training at the University of Wyoming Family Practice Residency in Casper. Starting in 1993, he practiced full scale family medicine, served as Chief of Staff, and practiced Emergency Medicine services for Madison Memorial Hospital. Dr. Rammell joined the Student Health Center in the fall of 2011.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Steve Lemon" height="214" src="Images/health-center/Steve%20Lemons.png" style="margin-left: 7px; margin-right: 7px;" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Stephen Lemons, PA-C</h4>
<p></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Lori Parker" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Parker.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Lori Parker, RN, BSN, MSN, FNP-C</h4>
<p>Lori graduated as a Certified Family Nurse Practitioner (FNP-C) from Idaho State University in 2004. Since that time, she has worked at the Student Health Center, the Ashton Medical Clinic in Ashton, Idaho, and the RediCare Urgent Care in Idaho Falls. Lori has over twenty years of experience in a variety of patient settings, including medical/surgical, open-heart intensive care unit, trauma intensive care unit, and recovery room. <br /><br /> In her time away from the Health Center, Lori enjoys relaxing outdoor activities, including camping, skiing, and gardening. She is well-known as a loyal and enthusiastic fan of the Denver Broncos football team, and her favorite place to vacation is on the Oregon coast.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Christy Goodman" height="189" src="Images/health-center/Robson.png" style="margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 10px;" width="133" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Nicole Robson, PA-C</h4>
<p></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Christy Goodman" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Goodman.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Christy Goodman, MHS PA-C</h4>
<p>Christy graduated from Ricks College in 2000, and then proceeded to Lock Haven University of Pennsylvania, where in 2005 she received her Master of Science Degree in Health Science as a certified Physician Assistant. Christy spent a year working in cardiology, treating acute and longstanding heart patients as well as chronic disease processes, prior to joining the Student Health Center in 2006.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Terry Anderson" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Anderson.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Terry Anderson, PA</h4>
<p>Originally from Ca&ntilde;on City, Colorado, Terry received his undergraduate in zoology from BYU before graduating from Saint Louis University in 2002 with a master's degree as a Physician Assistant. Before joining the Student Health Center in 2010, Terry spent time working in rural family medicine in Irrigon, Oregon, and in emergency and urgent care medicine at at Portneuf Medical Center in Pocatello, Idaho. <br /><br /> &nbsp; Terry and his wife are the happy parents of six children. Together, they enjoy sports, music, and outdoor activities, including running, skiing, and mountain biking.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Marilyn Walker" height="214" src="Images/health-center/walker.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Marilyn Walker, RN</h4>
<p>Marilyn graduated from the Ricks College nursing program in 1980 and has worked as a medical/surgical nurse and an emergency room nurse ever since. She is certified in Advanced Cardiac Life Support, Pediatric Advanced Life Support, and is Trauma Nurse Core Course Certified. Marilyn joined the Student Health Center in 1990.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Tiffany Paepke" height="214" src="Images/health-center/paepke.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Tiffany Paepke, RN</h4>
<p>Born in Idaho and raised in Washington, Tiffany returned to Rexburg to receive two degrees from Ricks College: physical education (1986) and nursing (1989). Before joining the Student Health Center in 2005, she worked as a medical surgical nurse at Madison Memorial Hospital, and on the surgical floor as the afternoon charge nurse in same-day surgery at Bannock Regional Medical Center. Tiffany has also worked for several local Idaho providers in the clinical setting.<br /><br />&nbsp;Tiffany is the mother of three children, and she enjoys spending time with family and having outdoor adventures. She loves baking, mountain biking, and one of her favorite lazy day activities - hanging laundry on the clothesline in her yard.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Shawn Andreasen" height="214" src="Images/health-center/andreasen.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Shawn Andreasen, Pharmacy Director, R.Ph.</h4>
<p>Shawn received his bachelor's degree in microbiology with a medical emphasis from BYU, and received his Doctorate of Pharmacy degree from Idaho State University. Shawn joined the Student Health Center in 2004 after working for Albertson's pharmacy in Utah. He is the father of four children, and his family spends their free time playing baseball, gardening, hiking, and playing games as a family.<br /><br /></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Ruth Clark" height="214" src="Images/health-center/clark.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Ruth Clark, Office Assistant</h4>
<p>Ruth was born and raised in Rexburg and has been working in the medical field since 1973, holding a variety of responsibilities. She joined the Student Health Center in 1994 and currently assists with insurance billing, manages payroll, and provides specialized student support. She and her husband have been married for forty years. They are the parents of five children, and they currently have six grandchildren. Ruth enjoys cooking and playing the piano, and her family spends their time together camping, hunting, and fishing.<br /><br /></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Lorraine Cziep" height="214" src="Images/health-center/cziep.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Lorraine Cziep, MT (ASCP)</h4>
<p>Lorraine graduated from Ricks College before attending BYU Provo, where she received a Bachelor of Science degree in microbiology and chemistry. While working at Madison Memorial Hospital in Rexburg, Idaho, she was responsible for the microbiology department and worked in chemistry, hematology, serology, and blood bank. Lorraine joined the Student Health Center in 1990.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Lisa Nelson" height="214" src="Images/health-center/nelson.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Lisa Nelson, RT</h4>
<p>Lisa graduated from Ricks College with an associate's degree in health science and from Idaho State University with a bachelor's degree in radiographic science. For over thirteen years, she has worked in hospitals across the United States, including Madison Memorial Hospital, Pocatello&nbsp;Hospital, the United Health Services Hospital in Grand Forks, North Dakota, and multiple hospitals in Idaho Falls. She has covered several specialties, including radiographic procedures, surgeries, CT scans, mammograms, nuclear medicine, and MRIs. Lisa joined the Student Health Center in 1996. &nbsp;<br /><br /> She and her husband have been married for over thirty years. Together, they spend their time outdoors scuba diving, camping, golfing, and four-wheeling. They also have enjoyed travelling to many areas of the world, and Lisa includes Belize, the Cayman Islands, and Honduras as some of her favorite places to visit.&nbsp;</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Vickie Christensen" height="214" src="Images/health-center/christensen.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Vickie Christensen, RT</h4>
<p>Vickie graduated from Community College in Denver, Colorado, and became registered as a Radiologic Technologist in 1982. She then spent 10 years working at Porter Memorial Hospital in Denver, Colorado, and another 10 years working at Eastern Idaho Regional Medical Center in Idaho Falls, Idaho, gaining valuable experience in the operating room, emergency room, and cardiology catheter lab. Vickie joined the Student Health Center in 2001.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="240" id="footer" scrolling="no" src="Documents/health-center/footer.html" width="100%"></iframe></p>
<p><link href="Documents/health-center/css/header.css" rel="stylesheet" /> <link href="Documents/health-center/css/body.css" rel="stylesheet" /> <link href="Documents/health-center/css/doctor.css" rel="stylesheet" /></p>
<p>
<script type="text/Javascript">
var staff = document.getElementById("staff");

   for (var i = 0; i < staff.children[0].rows.length; i++) {
      if (i % 2 != 0) {
         staff.children[0].rows[i].className = "highlight";
      }
   }
</script>
</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28441" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
