<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x35028" Name="Submit Here" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Submit Here</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Submit Here</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><img height="127" src="Images/instructional-development/RCW/story%20pic.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="715" /></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ABSTRACT/STATEMENT REQUIREMENTS</strong></span><br /><br />You will be asked to&nbsp;submit the title of your work and an abstract that explains your research and methodology. The following is the abstract criterion you need to follow:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Must be <strong>150 words minimum-350</strong> <strong>words maximum</strong>.</em></li>
<li><em>Must use proper grammar and correct spelling.</em></li>
<li><em>Briefly describe your work and what you found (or hypothesize to find, if you have yet to complete your research results).</em></li>
<li><em>Outline your methodology--how you got your results and conclusion.&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> If your abstract or statement does not meet the minimum word count, you will be contacted to adjust and resubmit it. <em>If not completed, you will be disqualified to present in the conference.</em></p>
<p>You will also find a place to indicate the type of session you want to be in (poster, oral, written, live performance), the academic discipline that best describes your work, and what you plan to do during your presentation (PowerPoint presentation, perform a song, demonstrate a model, etc.).</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Submissions closed Friday, June 13th.</strong></h2>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Its conference time! Ready to roll out! <br /><a href="Documents/instructional_development/rcw/2014 Spring/Spring 2014 Program Full.pdf">Download the conference<br />program here.</a></strong></h1>
<p><strong style="font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; line-height: inherit;">Which Session Should I Choose?</strong></p>
<p>There are three types of sessions that students can choose from at the R&amp;CW: Oral, Poster, and Live Sessions. Students may be confused at the differences between the sessions and which one should they choose for their work. Below are descriptions for each type of session. It should be noted that we encourage students to present in the most commonly accepted medium of their field. &nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Oral Sessions</span></p>
<p>Oral Sessions normally begin on the day of the conference at 5:00 pm and run to 6:30 pm, each divided into 15-minute segments. Each presenter will have 10 minutes to present their research and 3 minutes to answer question for a total of 13 minutes per presentation with 2 minutes in between presenters allowing for the next set-up.</p>
<p>Oral presenters normally utilize a TEC Console (a computer with a projector) to help communicate their project. While Oral presenters are not required to use anything to aid their presentation, a Power point or other appropriate visual aid will help. For further questions, talk with your mentor about what type of presentation would be most appropriate for your discipline. Students who present in Oral Sessions will be grouped with those of a similar subject matter. Each session will be limited to around 6-7 presenters per session. The public is invited and welcomed to come and view the Oral presenters.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Poster Sessions</span></p>
<p>Poster sessions include any project that utilizes the aid of a poster to detail a research project, or any other type of physical project built (Mechanical Engineering to Fashion Design to Art projects).</p>
<p>Each team member does not have to be present while the poster session is open to the public from 3:00-6:00 pm. However, at least one presenter must be at their display from 4:00 pm until they have been judged. Pins, clips, and fasteners will be provided to help display projects. If a project requires additional materials, it must be noted during the abstract submitions (additional materials make include electrical outlet, extension cord, TV, easel, table, etc.).</p>
<p>Poster Sessions are comprised <span style="text-decoration: underline;">of</span> groups of up to ten projects. Presenters will have the opportunity for judges, the public, and potential employers to witness and question about their work. &nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Live Sessions</span></p>
<p>Live Sessions are normally limited to Music, Dance, and Theatre majors who perform their own work and can vary in time depending on the amount of time is required to perform their piece. The allotted time for Live Sessions normally run from between 2:00 pm - 5:00 pm and individual presentations are based upon the projects needed time. Individuals are placed in sessions according to their discipline (i.e. Dance with Dance, Music with Music) and are judged accordingly.&nbsp; If the presenters need any special accommodations for their project please notify us while submitting your project abstracts and we will work hand in hand with you to make sure that your needs are provided for within reasonable limits.</p>
<p>Students who present in Live Sessions have an opportunity to present their work before a larger audience and have their work critiqued by professionals on a professional level.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Written Sessions</span></p>
<p>Written submissions are the only session where the student participants do not have the opportunity to present their works in front of judges. Instead, conference staff will solicit the literary works from participants one to two weeks early. The judges use this time to review each of the submissions and choose the winning submissions. The first, second, and third place papers will be on display at the conference during the poster sessions.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><!--071613 xpowercomponent_Optional to xPower--></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x30942" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
