<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x35021" Name="Gateway Vision" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Realize the Vision Seminar</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Realize the Vision seminar introduces you to the mission of BYU-Idaho and how you can "realize" its prophetic fulfillment in your personal life now and throughout your life.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h1>Realize the Vision Seminar</h1>
<h2><span style="color: #333333;"><br />Preview</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">President Clark has declared:<br /><br /><img height="169" src="Images/build/Gateway%20Seminars/Realize%20the%20Vision/WEBClark_KimB.jpg" style="float: left; margin: 1px 15px; border: 3px solid gray;" width="123" /><em>Prophetic vision guides BYU-Idaho in the fulfillment of its institutional mission, which is to prepare young people for the marvelous work the Lord has in store for them. I believe two companion principles define our mission: discipleship and leadership. These principles will help prepare BYU-Idaho students for their roles in the Lord's kingdom and in the world. </em></p>
<p><em>... At BYU-Idaho, we are developing generations of disciple-leaders for the world, and for the Church in the dispensation of the fullness of times.</em> <br /><br /><br /><br /><br />This seminar introduces you to this mission and how you can "realize" its prophetic fulfillment in your personal life now and in the future.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #333333;">Preparation Activity</span></h2>
<p>The preparation activity for this seminar is to read the quotes below and prepare to participate by answering the following questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>What were the series of events that led you to BYU-Idaho? How can you see the hand of the Lord in bringing you here?</li>
<li>For what purpose do you think you were blessed to attend BYU-Idaho?</li>
<li>What can you do to more fully receive the promised blessings that are associated with being a BYU-Idaho student?</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p><img alt="picture of President Hinckley" height="180" src="Images/build/Gateway Seminars/Realize the Vision/VIP-GordonBHINCKLEY.jpg" style="float: left; margin-left: 15px; margin-right: 15px; margin-top: 3px; margin-bottom: 3px; border: 3px solid gray;" width="142" /></p>
<div>
<h3>President Hinckley's Prophetic Vision for BYU-Idaho</h3>
<p>"I see a great future for this institution. It will go forward under inspired leadership. It will grow in strength under a dedicated and able faculty. It will be increasingly recognized as its graduates move out across the world and fill positions of responsibility.&nbsp;How do I know this? I know this because this is an institution of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Its mission is well defined. That mission is to impart secular knowledge in a first-class manner while building faith in the Eternal God and His Risen Son, the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 180px;">"This Church will never fail. Jesus Christ stands at its head. And just as it will never fail, neither will its institutions and programs.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 180px;">"This university will succeed in a wonderful manner. It will take its place among the great learning facilities of our nation as we who have some attachment to it walk and work in faith. That I believe with all my heart and pray that that day will come, as it surely will." <span style="font-size: small;">(Dedication of Gordon B. Hinckley Building, BYU-Idaho, October 22, 2002)</span></p>
<hr /></div>
<h3><img alt="Picture of Henry B. Eyring" height="177" src="Images/build/Gateway Seminars/Learning Model/Eyring_web.jpg" style="float: left; margin-top: 3px; margin-bottom: 3px; margin-left: 15px; margin-right: 15px; border: 3px solid gray;" width="142" />Prophetic Promises for BYU-Idaho Students</h3>
<p>&ldquo;The students will learn from example how to keep on a steady upward course in times of great change. They will see leaders and teachers and staff members for whom the Savior and His kingdom are at the center of their lives. From that example, I make a prophesy. Now listen carefully.</p>
<p>"From that example they&mdash;you&mdash;will become life-long teachers in their families, in the Church, and in their work, and they will bless others wherever they go by what they have learned about innovating with scarce resources and treating all they have as if it were the Lord's.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 180px;">"You can imagine the joy of an employer or a Church leader when such a graduate arrives. The graduates will be at personal peace by having kept the commandments. They will be natural leaders who know how to teach and how to learn. They will have the power to innovate and improve without requiring more of what money can buy. Those graduates of BYU-Idaho will become&mdash;and this is a prophesy that I am prepared to make and make solemnly&mdash;those graduates of BYU-Idaho will become legendary for their capacity to build the people around them and to add value wherever they serve." <span style="font-size: small;">(Henry B. Eyring, &ldquo;A Steady, Upward Course,&rdquo; BYU&ndash;Idaho Devotional, September 18, 2001)</span></p>
<hr />
<h3><img alt="Picture of David A. Bednar" height="180" src="Images/build/Gateway Seminars/Realize the Vision/WEBBednar_DavidA.jpg" style="float: left; margin-left: 15px; margin-right: 15px; margin-top: 3px; margin-bottom: 3px; border: 3px solid gray;" width="144" />Preparing Disciples of Jesus Christ</h3>
<p>"Let me suggest that in Rexburg, Idaho, we are in the process of creating .... a Disciple Preparation Center&mdash;a DPC. In this special and sacred and set apart place, you and I have access to unparalleled spiritual resources that can assist us in developing and deepening our devotion as disciples of the Lord Jesus Christ. That is the primary and most important reason for the existence of Brigham Young University-Idaho and for its sponsorship by and affiliation with The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. ...</p>
<p style="padding-left: 180px;">"In the midst of an increasing downpour of devilish devastation across the earth, you are blessed to be here at one of the Lord&rsquo;s Disciple Preparation Centers. BYU-Idaho is not just a university. You are not merely university students. Studying here involves much more than taking tests and performing well in academic classes&mdash;although your academic development and performance truly are important. But there are essential lessons to be learned and preparations to be made at this DPC by the Lord&rsquo;s latter-day disciples." <span style="font-size: small;">(&ldquo;Brigham Young University-Idaho: A Disciple Preparation Center (DPC),&rdquo; BYU-Idaho Devotional, August 31, 2004)</span></p>
<hr />
<h2><span style="color: #333333;">Register</span></h2>
<p><strong>Note: This seminar will last 70 minutes because of the number of video clips viewed. Please arrive on time and plan to stay the entire 70 minutes. Thank you</strong>.</p>
<p>To register for this seminar, please <a href="http://abish.byui.edu/library/fdOrient/B_selectAction.cfm">click here</a>.<strong><strong></strong> </strong></p>
<p>Change Registration: If you want to change your seminar date or missed your seminar, you must return to the registration site, delete your existing registration and then re-register for another seminar time. To delete existing registration, <a href="http://abish.byui.edu/library/fdOrient/B_deleteRegistration.cfm">click here.</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><!--071613 xpowercomponent_Optional to xPower--></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x34838" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x18525" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
