<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Content ID="x37141" Name="Packing Details" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Packing Details and Suggestion</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Things that you probably should be packing</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>Packing Suggestions</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Academic</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Bring books, syllabi, handouts, pens, BYU-Idaho College ID card, and paper (for journal entries and notes).</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Security</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Make 2 photocopies of your passport. Take one; leave one with your parents.</li>
<li>Get a security pouch, wallet, or belt (to hold tickets, passport, money). These items should be on your person at all times.</li>
<li>Make sure your parents have a copy of the tour's itinerary and emergency contact information.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Carry-on</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Bring one carry-on bag. We will take <strong>no</strong> check-in bags.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Clothing</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Observe BYU-Idaho Standards</li>
<li>Layer clothing (shirt -- sweater/sweatshirt - windbreaker).</li>
<li>No shorts.</li>
<li>Bring shoes already proven to be comfortable.</li>
<li>Bring clothing that can dry out quickly (i.e., synthetics); for example, avoid thick cottons.</li>
<li>Nylon athletic socks work well.</li>
<li>Bring clothing that doesn't require ironing.</li>
<li>Clothing articles should be mix-and-match and multipurpose (i.e. appropriate for both church and day-to-day functions).</li>
<li>Bring plastic trash bags for dirty clothes.</li>
<li>No flip flops outdoors.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Miscellaneous Packing Considerations</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>In addition to prescriptions, bring any possible medications you anticipate needing. (Dramamine can help on flight and ferry.) <a name="a"></a></li>
<li>Bring a towel.</li>
<li>Take extra batteries.</li>
<li>Buy camera film here. Consider whether you'll want slides or photos.</li>
<li>Bring a watch or an alarm clock.</li>
<li>Bring a converter if necessary.</li>
<li>Bring leak-proof drinking and storage bottles (for shampoo, etc)</li>
<li>Use "zip-lock" baggies to individually store liquid items.</li>
<li>If you're a "shop-aholic," pack an extra bag for stuff you'll buy.</li>
<li>Leave room in your bag: you shouldn't leave on the tour with your bags stuffed to the limit.</li>
<li>Pack lightly you'll need to be able to carry everything yourself, sometimes for considerable distances.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Manners on the Tour</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Ambassadorship</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Remember, to varying degrees, you are representing yourselves, the tour, BYU-Idaho, the Church, and the United States.</li>
<li>Unofficial tour motto, suitable for screening on t-shirts: "Wherever thou art, act well thy part."</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Behaviors Europeans Detest</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Shouting. Europeans typically speak in low tones.</li>
<li>Blocking Traffic. Stay out of people's way by moving aside whenever possible.</li>
<li>Comparing life in America to life in Europe. European ways are enviable, in many cases.</li>
<li>Bragging and boasting. This is tacky. We're all nationalists. If anything, tell Europeans what you like about Europe--you'll make a friend for life.</li>
<li>Complaining about anything. Food will be different. Toilets will flush differently. Towels may not be "Downy soft." Deal with it; this is a part of the travel experience. Try new foods, new words, etc., embracing such opportunities as part of a new culture.</li>
<li>Rudeness and impatience. Europeans will expect you to be extremely courteous and polite regardless of what happens.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Behaviors Tour Directors Discourage</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Being Late. It holds up everyone--don't do it.</li>
<li>Flirting. This can be dangerous in Europe, as Europeans interpret signals differently.</li>
<li>Flashing cash. Be "street smart" and discrete when handling money. Be aware that certain people may want to take advantage of you. Theft is very common in Europe.Tourists are easy to identify and victimize. If something feels wrong, move on.</li>
<li>Mocking language, customs, mannerisms, etc. In reality, you're just as strange to them (and maybe even more so.)</li>
<li>Doing anything listed under behaviors Europeans detest.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Attitudes Tour Directors Appreciate</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Being a cooperative team player. Think in terms of what's best for the whole tour, not just yourself. You'll have considerable free time to satisfy your personal whims.</li>
<li>Assuming tour directors are doing all they can to make the tour enjoyable. Also, assuming they're only human (some things are even beyond <em>their </em>control.)</li>
<li>Being cool when things go wrong, as they inevitably will. Anticipate being flexible.</li>
<li>Being your brother's/sister's keeper. Help each other out, bear one another's burdens, look out for each other.</li>
<li>Listening to directors' instructions carefully. Most of what they say will be with your best interests in mind.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Finally, for most of you, this trip will be a once-in-a-lifetime experience. We're gone for only 25 days. Given the grandeur of what you're about to experience, you cannot afford to be anything less than excited, cheerful, pleasant, patient, tolerant, understanding, positive, fun, grateful, and gracious.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As directors, we understand the responsibilities and obligations we have to you, your parents, and BYU-Idaho. We're thrilled that you're going on this year's tour and are anxious to serve you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Passport Application Instructions</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Items Needed for First-time Passport Application</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="1" type="1">
<li>Properly completed passport application forms . Obtain new or renewal application forms at the Rexburg Courthouse or at this government site:&nbsp; <a href="http://www.byui.edu/disclaimer.asp?page=http://travel.state.gov/passport_services.html" target="_top">Passport Services Link</a></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="2" type="1">
<li>Certified birth certificate.
<ul type="circle">
<li>Obtain an official copy of your birth certificate from the Office of Vital Statistics in your state of birth.</li>
<li>Must be an official copy--photocopies are not accepted.</li>
<li>Must be sent with your application, but it will be returned with your passport.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two duplicate passport photos.
<ul type="circle">
<li>Available at Walgreens for around $10.</li>
<li>BYU-Idaho Photo Services.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Application fees.
<ul type="circle">
<li>Check form for processing fee.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Driver's license--for identification and verification.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Application Procedure</strong></p>
<ol start="1" type="1">
<li>Complete application forms. (Use your full name.) Gather all materials needed.</li>
<li>Take them to University of Idaho Extension Services Building (across from Rexburg County Courthouse).</li>
<li>Pay the clerk the $10 execution fee, in cash. The clerk will then process your materials.</li>
<li>Passport Services will send the passport to the mailing address listed on your passport form. If everything is in order, the process takes about two weeks. If things are not in order, much more time is needed. It is best to allow six weeks in case of problems.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Tips for Travelers</strong></p>
<ol start="1" type="1">
<li>Make three photocopies of your passport identification page. Leave one copy at home. Give one to Tour director. Carry the other with you in a separate place from your passport. This will facilitate replacement if your passport is lost or stolen.</li>
<li>Always carry your passport on your person, rather than stow it away in luggage.</li>
</ol><hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Pre-Trip Checklist</strong></p>
<p>It is always wise to make photocopies of you airline tickets, rail pass, the ID page of your passport, your drivers license, and the credit cards you take with you. Leave one set of photocopies at home and take another set with you, storing it in a separate place from the originals.</p>
<p>Leave a list of the serial numbers of your travelers checks at home. Take a copy of that list on your trip, but keep the list separate from the checks. As you cash each check, tally the ones that remain unredeemed. This way you can spot if there is anything missing.</p>
<p>If you wear glasses or contact lenses, pack an extra set. If there are any particular medicines you need, bring along an ample supply as well as a copy of prescription and generic names of those drugs. Keep these in your carry-on luggage. Leave medicines in their original labeled containers so as not to complicate customs processing. If any medications contain narcotics, carry a letter from your physician attesting to your need to take them. Leave a copy of your medical and dental records with a relative or friend.</p>
<p>Include a tag or label with your name and address inside each piece of luggage, and lock your bags.</p>
<p>Leave a copy of your itinerary with a relative or friend should it be necessary to contact you in case of emergency. Some people contact their consulate when traveling in a foreign country. This can be particularly helpful when traveling in dangerous or unstable regions, but is otherwise unnecessary.</p>
<p>Think about purchasing travelers checks or cash of the country in which you'll be arriving. Having $50 or $100 in local currency for hopping a cab or grabbing a bite, sure beats standing in line at the money exchange after a long flight and leaves you with one less task to worry about.</p>
<p>Find out if your insurance policies cover you for theft, loss, accident, and illness while you are in another country. If yes, write down the procedures to follow in case an accident occurs. If you're thinking about traveling to a country where there's been some unrest, you might want to check with the State Department's hotline first at (202) 647-5225 from a touch tone phone.</p>
<hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Reducing Jet Lag and DVT (Deep Vein Thrombosis or "Economy Class Syndrome")</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>What is jet lag? Jet lag is a combination of physical fatigue, disruption of the body's biolgocical clock, and mental confusion resulting from unfamiliar situations. It can make you feel entirely yucky, or it can be almost bypassed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Jet lag is not a serious condition to people in reasonably good health, but it can rob you of teh enjoyment you anticipated during the trip. Feeling droopy for a day or two is no big thing at home, but the days of the trip are too precious for that. Avoiding jet lag is worth the few easy adjustments it requires.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>CNN report on DVT (Deep Vein Thrombosis):&nbsp; <a href="http://www.byui.edu/disclaimer.asp?page=http://www.cnn.com/2001/WORLD/asiapcf/southeast/12/24/singapore.dvt/index.html" target="_top">DVT Report Link</a></p>
<p><strong>During the Few Days Before the Flight</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Take Vitamin C (500 mg per day) to reduce the possibility of coming down with a cold.</li>
<li>Alter your schedule by going to bed early and getting up early, to reduce the number of hours shock to your system (when your travel will be easterly).</li>
<li>Take naps and be thoroughly rested when the trip starts.</li>
<li>Get moderate exercise.</li>
<li>Pack well in advance and make all last minute arrangements before the last minute. Then do something diverting before the trip actually begins.</li>
<li>Review all travel plans carefully so that you can anticipate each event rather than be surprised as the trip unfolds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>During the Flight</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Wear loose, comfortable clothing.</li>
<li>Walk around now and then to stretch muscles and reduce swelling in the feet.</li>
<li>Eat sparingly. Airline food schedules and servings are geared to the hungriest.</li>
<li>Drink lots of water and fruit juices. Avoid caffeine.</li>
<li>Sleep. Airline activities are calculated to prevent rest. Rest anyway.</li>
<li>Perform leg and ankle exercises: <a href="http://www.byui.edu/disclaimer.asp?page=http://www.australiandoctor.com.au/downloads/patient/010720DVT.pdf" target="_self">Leg and Ankle Exercises Link </a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>After the Flight</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Set your watch to the new time and don't calculate what time it is back home.</li>
<li>Let the trip leader do the worrying about customs, exchange, and shuttle.</li>
<li>Lie down briefly in your room, but not longer than a couple of hours.</li>
<li>Go to bed in good time and get up early the next morning.</li>
<li>Continue the Vitamin C for a few days.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x1905" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></Content>