<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Content ID="x37278" Name="Bylaws" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Constitution Brigham Young University-Idaho
Student Chapter of the National Association of Home Builders of the United States
ACMS</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bylaws and constitution</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>ARTICLE I: NAME</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Section 1 <br /> The name of this chapter shall be the Architecture and Construction Management Society (ACMS) Student Chapter of the National Association of Home Builders of the United States, with which it is affiliated.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> The principal office of this chapter shall be located at Brigham Young University-Idaho.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE II: PURPOSE</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 Objectives</p>
<ul>
<li>To maintain high academic standards among its members.</li>
<li>To create a networking system among graduates.</li>
<li>To provide students with leadership and planning opportunities.</li>
<li>Connect students with potential employers.</li>
<li>To participate for the purpose of mutual benefit in an interchange of information and experience with the National Association of Home Builders of the United States and appropriate local and state NAHB affiliated associations.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> This chapter shall operate for the benefit of students in the Architecture and Construction Management curriculum and those engaged in allied curricula on the chapter's campus.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE III: MEMBERSHIP</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Membership in this chapter shall be open to any student in the Architecture and Construction Management curriculum or curricula related thereto, within the territorial jurisdiction of this chapter.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> This chapter shall meet the non-discrimination policies of Brigham Young University-Idaho.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE IV: OFFICERS</strong></p>
<p>Section I <br /> The officers shall be elected by the current presidency and faculty advisor and shall hold office for the term of one (2) semester from the date of election or until their successors are elected and duly qualified.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> The officers shall consist of a president, professional relations, activities/service, secretary/ treasurer and public relations.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE V: COMMITTEES</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> The committees of this chapter shall be: executive, commercial relations, residential relations, publicity, activities and service.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> The president shall appoint special committees.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE VI: FINANCES</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Dues and monies collected by this chapter shall be placed in a depository selected by the executive committee and approved by the faculty advisor.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> Payments of the funds of this chapter shall be made on the signature of the advisor and/or the president.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE VII: FACULTY ADVISOR</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> This chapter shall have a faculty advisor elected from the faculty of Brigham Young University-Idaho.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE VIII: AMENDMENTS</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Any member may propose amendments to this constitution at any regular meeting. The proposed amendment must be in writing and must lay on the table until the next meeting after its first reading.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> Adoption of an amendment must be by an affirmative vote of three-fourths (3/4) of the chapter's active membership.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>BYLAWS <br />of the <br /></strong><strong>Brigham Young University-Idaho </strong><strong>Student Chapter<br /></strong><strong>of the<br /></strong><strong>National Association of Home Builders of the United States</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>ACMS</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE I: MEMBERSHIP</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Any person who meets the membership requirements may be extended an invitation to join the chapter.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> A member may be censured, suspended, or expelled from the chapter by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the active membership if found to be in the best interest of the chapter, and the member has been afforded a reasonable opportunity to be heard.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 3 <br /> Only those members in good standing may participate in the affairs of the chapter.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE II: MEETINGS</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Meetings of the chapter shall be held on Thursday of each month or such other time as may be selected.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> Special meetings of the membership may be called at any time by the president upon reasonable advance notice.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 3 <br /> Meetings shall follow Robert's Rules of Order.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE III: OFFICERS</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> The officers shall have the following duties and responsibilities:</p>
<ul>
<li>President--shall be the chief officer of this chapter and shall preside at its meetings. He/she shall appoint all committees, shall be an ex-officio member of all committees, and shall perform all duties usual to such office.</li>
<li>Professional Relations/President Elect-shall be responsible for getting sponsors for activities and other event that the ACMS is responsible for. Recruiting volunteers for events such as the career fair. Work with activities chair for the Mini- Competition. Research available scholarships for CM and Architecture students. Attend or assign someone to attend the local home builders association meetings.</li>
<li>Public Relations-send weekly update emails about upcoming events. Design and distributes posters, signs and flyers containing information about upcoming events. Advertise applications for competition teams and presidency applications.</li>
<li>Activities/Service-- Organize at the minimum one opening, one closing and one other social per semester. Organize the contractor roundtable, mini competition which could be used as one of the "other" activities. Organized at least one service project per semester. Participate with happy factory and Habitat for Humanity.</li>
<li>Secretary/Treasurer --shall be responsible to the Association for an accounting of all monies collected and disbursed by the chapter. He/she shall be responsible for the collecting, depositing and disbursing all monies. He/she shall render periodic records to the chapter during his term of office. Shall keep a record of all the official proceedings of the chapter, maintain the membership records in coordination with the treasurer and be responsible for coordinating the communication between members. Shall also take meeting minuets and email to the executive committee. Update by-laws and procedures manual. Update the enrolment and charge the student enrollment fees. Update blackboard site. Manage ACMS email account. Record recognition points for each member.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> Only those members in good standing may be elected to office. <br /> (A) Any officer who shall fall delinquent in payment of dues during the term of office shall resign from such office.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 3 <br /> Any officer may be removed from office by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the active membership.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 4 <br /> The officers and faculty advisor shall be elected by a majority vote of the executive committee with approval of the faculty advisor .</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE IV: COMMITTEES</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> The standing committees shall be:</p>
<p>(A) Executive Committee--shall consist of the president, professional relations/president elect,     public relations, activities/service, secretary/treasurer and faculty advisor. <br /> (B) Commercial relations<br /> (C) Residential Relations</p>
<p>(D) Activities/Service</p>
<p>(E)  Publicity</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE V: FINANCES</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> The dues of this chapter shall be payable annually in advance at the first meeting of the fall term at the rate of $15 per member.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> Dues for membership in the National Association of Home Builders of the United States shall be paid by this chapter from its treasury at the rate fixed and under the terms stated by that association, as may be amended from time to time.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 3 <br /> Members who have sufficiently paid their dues shall be considered in good standing and referred to as "active."</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE VI: VOTING</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> At the meeting of the membership, only active members shall have the right to vote.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> A motion shall be carried by a majority vote of the members present, provided a quorum is in attendance, unless otherwise provided for by these bylaws.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 3 <br /> Elections shall be conducted under the rules and procedures approved by the membership in advance of the meeting at which an election is to be conducted.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE VII: NOTICES</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Members shall furnish the secretary with their addresses and the mailing of any notice to such address shall be deemed service of such notice or notices upon them as of the date of the mailing of the same.</p>
<p>
<hr />
</p>
<p><strong>ARTICLE VIII: AMENDMENTS</strong></p>
<p>Section 1 <br /> Any member may propose amendments to these bylaws at any regular meeting. The proposed amendment must be in writing and must lay on the table until the next meeting after its first reading.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Section 2 <br /> Adoption of an amendment must be by an affirmative vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the chapter's active membership.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x35993" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x30687" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></Content>