<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x40368" Name="Academic Planning Leadership" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Gateway Seminar Leadership - Academic Planning &amp; Advising</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">This is a great opportunity to continue your association with the Gateway Seminar program and to help lead and train other facilitators in conducting this inspiring seminar.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h1>Student Director and Coordinator Positions</h1>
<p><br />For the<strong> spring 2014<span> semester</span></strong><span>, we are filling a director position and 2 coordinator positions for the Gateway Seminar "Academic Planning &amp; Advising" program. This is a great opportunity to continue your association with the Gateway Seminar program and to help lead and train other facilitators in what you have learned. The director position is a paid position as he or she is responsible for the overall quality and success of this seminar; the coordinator positions are volunteer positions. </span></p>
<p>For the spring semester,&nbsp;the director employment position may serve up to 8-10 hours per week (occasionally more during Saturday training weeks); coordinators often serve up to 4-5 hours per week. The director is expected to have at least 1 hour of time each week dedicated to meeting with the program advisor to provide update and feedback and to spend time planning, organizing, and preparing for program responsibilities.</p>
<p>The responsibilities for these position will begin upon selection, which will occur around <strong>March 6th </strong>for the director and<strong> March 12th&nbsp; </strong>for the coordinators. A few hours a week will be expected this semester by the director and coordinators for interviewing and selecting the new peer facilitators for next semester.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> If you are interested in applying for one of these positions, please read the information below and complete an electronic application by clicking on the link at the bottom.</p>
<h2>Responsibilities</h2>
<p><span></span> The responsibilities for student director and coordinators are similar; however, the director has the overall responsibility of ensuring the success of each aspect of the program and will direct and delegate the work as required. The director and coordinators operate as a council and meet on a regular basis to assist in and complete the following responsibilities: recruit, interview, and select peer facilitators; plan and conduct pre-seminar training for all facilitators; partner with new facilitators to conduct seminars for training purposes; and provide ongoing training and feedback to facilitators.<br /><br /> For the current start up semester, you will spend time each week staffing your peer facilitator needs for spring semester, such as recruiting, interviewing and selecting peer facilitators. For spring semester, you will need ot have Mondays open on your schedule from 4:30 to 6:00 p.m. as a potential time for ongoing training meetings with facilitators.</p>
<h2>Qualifications</h2>
<p>Qualifications for the director or coordinator positions include the following:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>A desire to help students understand the academic resources available to help them in planning their academic path at BYU-Idaho</li>
<li>An ability to counsel with others as you organize, plan, and execute the Academic Advising and Planning seminar program</li>
<li>An ability to train and develop other student facilitators</li>
<li>Have at least a 2.8 GPA and a desire to continue to do well in school</li>
<li>A commitment to living the BYU-Idaho honor code and dress and grooming standards as an example for other students to follow</li>
<li>Name can be cleared with the Dean of Students office</li>
</ul>
<h2>Application</h2>
<p>If interested in one of these positions, please complete the <a href="https://cms.byui.edu/emp/sites/crawfordv/Lists/Academic%20Planning%20Leadership%20Application/Item/newifs.aspx?List=349ef8bf%2D3a7b%2D45ec%2D97a8%2D1eccd54f0825&amp;isdlg=1">electronic application</a> and submit it by <strong><span><span>Wednesday, February 26th. </span></span></strong><span><span>(If you have problems opening the application, please email us and let us know.)</span></span><span><br /></span></p>
<p>You will be contacted for an interview shortly after the deadline. If you have any questions, please email&nbsp;<a href="mailto:gatewayseminars@byui.edu" target="_self"><span><span><span><span><span><span>gatewayseminars</span></span></span></span></span>@<span><span><span><span><span>byui</span></span></span></span></span>.<span><span><span><span><span>edu</span></span></span></span></span></span></a> or visit us in MC 129.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x18525" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
