<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Content ID="x41111" Name="Future Careers" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Future Careers with CIT</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Future Careers with CIT</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div style="padding-left: 10px;"><strong>Where will this lead me? </strong><br /><br />
<p>Information Technology (IT) has become an integral part of modern life. Among its most important functions are the efficient transmission of information and the storage and analysis of information. Employment in these fields is projected to grow much faster than the average for all occupations and add 286,600 new jobs over the 2008-2018 decade.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 500;">Please click on a title below to learn more about it:</p>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading1');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Network Architects/Engineers</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading1">
<p>These people are the designers of computer networks. They set up, test, and evaluate systems such as local area networks (LANs), wide area networks (WANs), the Internet, intranets, and other data communications systems. Systems are configured in many ways and can range from a connection between two offices in the same building to globally distributed networks, voice mail, and e-mail systems of a multinational organization. Network architects and engineers perform network modeling, analysis, and planning, which often require both hardware and software solutions. For example, setting up a network may involve the installation of several pieces of hardware, such as routers and hubs, wireless adaptors, and cables, as well as the installation and configuration of software, such as network drivers. These workers may also research related products and make necessary hardware and software recommendations, as well as address information security issues.</p>
</div>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading2');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Network and Computer Systems Administrators</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading2">
<p>These people design, install, and support an organization's computer systems. They are responsible for LANs, WANs, network segments, and Internet and intranet systems. They work in a variety of environments, including large corporations, small businesses, and government organizations. They install and maintain network hardware and software, analyze problems, and monitor networks to ensure their availability to users. These workers gather data to evaluate a system's performance, identify user needs, and determine system and network requirements.</p>
<br />
<p>Systems administrators are responsible for maintaining system efficiency. They ensure that the design of an organization's computer system allows all of the components, including computers, the network, and software, to work properly together. Administrators also troubleshoot problems reported by users and by automated network monitoring systems and make recommendations for future system upgrades. Many of these workers are also responsible for maintaining network and system security.</p>
</div>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading3');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Database Administrators</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading3">
<p>Database administrators work with database management software and determine ways to store, organize, analyze, use, and present data. They identify user needs and set up new computer databases. In many cases, database administrators must integrate data from old systems into a new system. They also test and coordinate modifications to the system when needed, and troubleshoot problems when they occur. An organization's database administrator ensures the performance of the system, understands the platform on which the database runs, and adds new users to the system. Because many databases are connected to the Internet, database administrators also must plan and coordinate security measures with network administrators. Some database administrators may also be responsible for database design, but this task is usually performed by database designers or database analysts.</p>
</div>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading4');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Information Assurance Specialists</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading4">
<p>The defenders of information and technology. These computer security specialists plan, coordinate, and maintain an organization's information security. These workers educate users about computer security, install security software, monitor networks for security breaches, respond to cyber attacks, and, in some cases, gather data and evidence to be used in prosecuting cyber crime. The responsibilities of computer security specialists have increased in recent years as cyber attacks have become more sophisticated.</p>
</div>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading5');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Webmasters and Web Developers</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading5">
<p>Web developers are responsible for the technical aspects of Web site creation. Using software languages and tools, they create applications for the Web. They identify a site's users and oversee its production and implementation. They determine the information that the site will contain and how it will be organized, and may use Web development software to integrate databases and other information systems. Some of these workers may be responsible for the visual appearance of Web sites. Using design software, they create pages that appeal to the tastes of the site's users.</p>
<br />
<p>Webmasters or Web administrators are responsible for maintaining Web sites. They oversee issues such as availability to users and speed of access, and are responsible for approving the content of the site. Webmasters also collect and analyze data on Web activity, traffic patterns, and other metrics, as well as monitor and respond to user feedback.</p>
</div>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading6');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Computer Software Engineers and Developers</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading6">
<p>Computer software engineers design and develop software. They apply the theories and principles of computer science and mathematical analysis to create, test, and evaluate the software applications and systems that make computers work. The tasks performed by these workers evolve quickly, reflecting changes in technology and new areas of specialization, as well as the changing practices of employers. Software engineers design and develop many types of software, including computer games, business applications, operating systems, network control systems, and middleware. They begin by analyzing users' needs, and then design, test, and develop software to meet those needs.</p>
</div>
<div style="cursor: pointer;"><a onclick="switchMenu('heading7');" target="_self">
<p style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">• Computer and Information Systems Project Management</p>
</a></div>
<div id="heading7">
<p>In the modern workplace, it is imperative that Information Technology (IT) works both effectively and reliably. Computer and information systems managers play a vital role in the implementation and administration of technology within their organizations. They plan, coordinate, and direct research on the computer-related activities of firms. In consultation with other managers, they help determine the goals of an organization and then implement technology to meet those goals. They oversee all technical aspect of an organization, such as software development, network security, and Internet operations.</p>
<br />
<p>Project Managers plan and coordinate activities such as installing and upgrading hardware and software, programming and systems design, the implementation of computer networks, and the development of Internet and intranet sites. They are increasingly involved with the upkeep, maintenance, and security of networks. They analyze the computer and information needs of their organizations from an operational and strategic perspective and determine immediate and long-range personnel and equipment requirements. They assign and review the work of their subordinates and stay abreast of the latest technology to ensure that the organization remains competitive.</p>
</div>
<br />
<h4>Additional Resources</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bls.gov/oco/oco1002.htm#comp" target="_self">U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://computingcareers.acm.org" target="_self">Computing Degrees &amp; Careers</a></li>
</ul>
<br /> <br />
<script type="text/JavaScript">
// Read More Script written by Chris Staber on 12/2010

// Hide all expandable elements
var load1 = document.getElementById('heading1');
var load2 = document.getElementById('heading2');
var load3 = document.getElementById('heading3');
var load4 = document.getElementById('heading4');
var load5 = document.getElementById('heading5');
var load6 = document.getElementById('heading6');
var load7 = document.getElementById('heading7');

load1.style.display = 'none';
load2.style.display = 'none';
load3.style.display = 'none';
load4.style.display = 'none';
load5.style.display = 'none';
load6.style.display = 'none';
load7.style.display = 'none';

// Function that toggles expandable elements

function switchMenu(obj) {
	var el = document.getElementById(obj);

	if ( el.style.display != "none" ) {
		el.style.display = 'none';
	}
	else {
load1.style.display = 'none';
load2.style.display = 'none';
load3.style.display = 'none';
load4.style.display = 'none';
load5.style.display = 'none';
load6.style.display = 'none';
load7.style.display = 'none';
		el.style.display = '';
	}
}
</script>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x1844" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></Content>