<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x41812" Name="For the Family" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">For the Family</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">For the Family</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>We acknowledge that parents are the most influential teachers of their children. Because of our commitment to this premise, we provide several avenues through which parents may become involved in their child's nursery school experience:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sneak Peek - highlights major learning activities related to the theme for the week. You can prepare your child for each day's activities and discuss activities when you pick up your child.</li>
<li>Child check-in/check-out - provides opportunities for student staff and parents to visit informally about the child.</li>
<li>Home Visit - provides opportunities for student staff to become better acquainted with children and their families.</li>
<li>Posting of daily lesson plan - informs parents of scheduled activities.</li>
<li>Observation Booth - allows parents to observe their child at any time.</li>
<li>Parent Involvement - gives parents the opportunity to be involved in the classroom through sharing personal talents, sharing family culture, and assisting on field trips.</li>
<li>Individual Parent Conferences - allows parents to schedule a time to meet with a teacher or program director to observe and discuss their child.</li>
</ul>
<p>The observation booth for the Child Development Labs are open during the following times:</p>
<table border="0" style="width: 308px; height: 74px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Preschool</td>
<td>MWF Morning</td>
<td>8:20 - 10:30 am</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>MWF Afternoon</td>
<td>1:20 - 3:30 pm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>T/Th</td>
<td>8:20 - 10:30 am</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Toddler</td>
<td>T/Th</td>
<td>8:45-10:05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>T/Th</td>
<td>10:45-12:05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>W/F</td>
<td>8:45-10:05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>W/F</td>
<td>10:45-12:05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>W/F</td>
<td>12:30-1:50</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>M/Th</td>
<td>12:30-1:50</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong id="docs-internal-guid-051f5027-e359-7111-c856-10cfc58f39d3"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">BYU-Idaho Child Labs</span><br /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Policies and Procedures</span><br /></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"></span>BYU-Idaho Faculty</strong></p>
<table border="0" style="width: 356px; height: 164px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Position</strong></span></td>
<td><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Name</strong></span></td>
<td><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Phone</span></strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Program Director</td>
<td>Michael Godfrey</td>
<td>496-4013</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Lab Manager</td>
<td>Suanne Ellsworth</td>
<td>496-4009</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Preschool Faculty</td>
<td>Kaelin Olsen</td>
<td>496-4031</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Betty McQuain</td>
<td>496-4030</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>David Allen</td>
<td>496-4106</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Toddler Director</td>
<td>Jillisa Cranmer</td>
<td>496-4111</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Toddler Faculty</td>
<td>Sarah Johnson</td>
<td>496-4127</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Mackenzie Swenson</td>
<td>534-8794</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>EMERGENCIES</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In case of fire, children will exit the preschool/toddler classrooms to the playground. Fire drills will be conducted regularly. In an emergency, if evacuation of the building is necessary, children will be taken to the Smith Building and parents notified. Parents may pick up their child from the circular driveway located between the Clarke Building (near the playground) and the north end of the Smith Building.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>DRESS AND THINGS FROM HOME</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Please dress your child in comfortable play clothes that are appropriate for the weather. There will be an outside play period each day, except in <span style="text-decoration: underline;">very</span> extreme weather.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">At the beginning of the semester you may send an extra set of clothes, including socks and diapers or underwear, (some that you wouldn't worry about losing). These clothes will be returned to you at the end of the semester.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Children should NOT bring toys, gum, candy, or food to classes.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>NUTRITION</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">We will prepare a nutritious snack each day your child is in preschool/toddler lab. You will receive a copy of the snack schedule before classes begin. Inform the lab supervisor of any unique dietary restrictions or allergies. Accreditation guidelines prohibit distribution of homemade food. You should discuss any exceptions to this policy with your lab supervisor.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>HOLIDAYS, BIRTHDAYS</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">To ensure an environment of cultural respect and equality we do not include holidays and/or birthdays as part of our preschool/toddler curriculum or instruction. If you would like to bring a store purchased individually wrapped treat, we will send it home with the children.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>FIELD TRIPS</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Parents will be notified, but written permission will not be requested, when children go on walking field trips on campus (ex: for activities in the ballroom or a walk to the garden). Parents are welcome to attend on-campus field trips. Please arrange participation through your child's teacher. Due to shorter class time, toddler lab does not do field trips.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>PHOTOS/VIDEOS</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">You may make video recordings and take photos of&nbsp;<strong>your child only during preschool/toddler, with permission of a lab supervisor</strong>, provided that these are for home use only. Video recordings and photos of children in the preschool/toddler lab classrooms may be made for educational purposes and viewed by preschool/toddler lab faculty, staff and students. Occasionally preschool/toddler lab staff creates videos or take photos of the children's preschool/toddler experience that are then given to parents. If you have concerns about this practice, please contact the lab director.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>PARENT PARTNERSHIPS, BOOTH</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Parent partnerships are a valuable part of any preschool/toddler program. We hope you will take advantage of the following activities:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Home visits.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Classroom observations from the booth:&nbsp;</strong>Booths are open any time preschool/toddler lab are in session and are located in rooms 201, 215, and 221 for preschool and for toddler 275.</li>
<li><strong>Classroom involvement:&nbsp;</strong>Schedule with the supervisor how you'd like to be involved in the classroom (preschool only).</li>
<li><strong>Extending classroom learning experiences in the home:&nbsp;</strong>A preschool sneak peek page, and a toddler lab parent handout, highlighting the week's activities, will be sent home regularly. You can prepare your child for each day's activities and discuss activities when you pick up your child. Parents and families can reinforce and extend what the child is learning at school with follow-up activities at home.</li>
<li><strong>Individual parent conferences:&nbsp;</strong>Please contact a teacher or program director if you would like to schedule an individual conference.</li>
</ol>
<p></p>
<p><strong>GUIDANCE</strong></p>
<p>Our guidance policy is to "Love them, correct them, and prepare a way for them" (from Teach the Children: An Agency Approach to Education by Neil Flinders). Our goal is to help children develop self-control and problem-solving skills. To achieve this goal, we will:</p>
<ul>
<li>Structure the environment and curriculum to minimize problems.</li>
<li>Model appropriate behavior.</li>
<li>Set reasonable and positive expectations.</li>
<li>Offer choices.</li>
<li>Trust children, respect feelings and calmly talk about problems.</li>
<li>Reinforce children's success in self-control and problem solving.</li>
<li>Remind children of the rules when they forget and engage in inappropriate behavior.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Redirect inappropriate behavior to something appropriate.</li>
<li>Hold a child or remove him/her from the classroom if he/she is out of control or is resistant, but return the child to the classroom as soon as possible.</li>
</ul>
<p>We will not:</p>
<ul>
<li>Humiliate a child.</li>
<li>Isolate them in a separate room or use a time-out chair.</li>
<li>Take away food, rest, or bathoom privileges as punishment.</li>
<li>Use corporal punishment.</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p><strong>ILLNESS</strong></p>
<p>If your child is ill please keep him/her at home. This avoids exposing other children and teachers to possible illness. Notify us if your child develops a condition that might be transmitted to other children, such as chicken pox or head lice. If any of the following symptoms exist please keep your child at home:</p>
<ul>
<li>Headache</li>
<li>Diarrhea</li>
<li>Fever</li>
<li>Vomiting</li>
<li>Sore throat</li>
<li>Abdominal pain</li>
<li>Pink eye</li>
<li>Unusual spots, rash or infected skin</li>
<li>Runny nose with any colored discharge</li>
<li>Any condition that would take your child out of the mainstream and require that a teacher spend an inordinate amount of time with just your child</li>
</ul>
<p>If we notice any of the above symptoms your child will not be admitted. If your child becomes ill during preschool/toddler lab, you will be notified to pick him/her up. If parents are unavailable, alternate contacts listed on the child lab forms will be notified. In a severe emergency we will call 911 and allow emergency medical services to take appropriate action. Parents will be contacted immediately.</p>
<p>The staff is not able to administer medication to any child without wirtten directions from a physician and permission from a parent or legal guardian.</p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>PARKING, CHECK IN, AND CHECK OUT</strong></p>
<p>You will receive a parking pass permitting you to park in the disignated area in the Clarke Building parking lot. This pass can&nbsp;<strong>only</strong> be used during the time you and your child are in the lab or observation booth.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">For Toddler</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> <strong>Labs</strong></span> a teacher will greet you at the check-in table outside the classroom door. You will sign your child in, help wash their hands, and put their nametag on the back of their clothing. You may then accompany your child into the classroom as another teacher greets you both and helps your child find their locker and put their coat and backpack away. Please briefly say goodbye and let the teachers guide your child to a play activity. <strong></strong>For<strong> Check Out&nbsp;</strong>a teacher will be by the east gates on either playground with a clipboard and sign-out sheet. You are invited to come onto the playground and pick up your child after you have signed them out.&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>For Preschool Labs</strong></span> a teacher will meet you at the curb where you will sign your child in and another teacher will escort your child to the classroom. Parents may also sign in and take their own child into the classroom. For&nbsp;<strong>Check Out&nbsp;</strong>a teacher will again meet you at the curb to sign the check out form. The children will be brought out as soon as they are ready. Alternatively, parents may sign their child out and go into the classroom.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>All Labs</strong></span> If there is a line of cars in the parking lot, you can "quick" park in the 10 minute parking loop (just south of our parking area) at the Smith Building and walk to check your child in and check them out.</p>
<p>If you arrive and no one is at the check-in table or curb, your must sign your child in and bring them into the clarroom. DO NOT send your child in alone! The same person signing the child in must be the one to sign them out, unless you have left written instructions on the sign-in sheet.</p>
<p>Children will not be checked in early as the teachers are preparing.</p>
<p>Late fees of 50 cents per child per minute will begin 5 minutes after the check out time has ended.</p>
<table border="0" style="width: 378px; height: 110px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Check In</strong></td>
<td><strong>Lab Time</strong></td>
<td><strong>Check Out</strong></td>
<td><strong>Late Fee</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8:20-8:30</td>
<td>8:20-10:30</td>
<td>10:25-10:45</td>
<td>10:50 am</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8:45-8:55</td>
<td>8:45-10:05</td>
<td>10:05-10:15</td>
<td>10:20 am</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10:45-10:55</td>
<td>10:45-12:05</td>
<td>12:05-12:15</td>
<td>12:20 pm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1:20-12:30</td>
<td>1:20-3:30</td>
<td>3:25-3:45</td>
<td>3:50 pm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>12:30-12:40</td>
<td>12:30-1:50</td>
<td>1:50-2:00</td>
<td>2:05 pm</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17675" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1847" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
