<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x41813" Name="For the Students" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">For the Students</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">For the Student</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Professional Preschool Education Program (PPE)</strong></span></p>
<p>The BYUI Professional Preschool Education Program (PPE) leads to an Applied Associate's Degree. It offers students the opportunity for in-depth study and experience in teaching young children. It is intended to be a "terminal degree" (one that provides professional preparation to enter the work force). Students who seek to graduate in PPE should realize that the program is not designed to be transferrable to four-year colleges, nor to be the foundation for a teaching certificate in early childhood education. The program is well designed to help graduates become: teachers in or directors of developmentally appropriate child care centers or preschools in home and commercial settings; qualified teacher's aides in nursery schools, kindergartens, and special education/inclusion classes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/advising/advising/sequences/ug12/cehd/PPE%20%20Sequencing%20Sheet.xlsx">Faculty Recommended Sequence of Courses</a></p>
<p><strong>The four semesters of core curriculum are:</strong></p>
<p><strong>1st Semester</strong>&nbsp;- Preparation - prepare academically and learn the basics of child development and early childhood education theory and practice.</p>
<p><strong>2nd Semester</strong>&nbsp;- Support Teacher - have experience in labs (MWF) assisting in preparing and implementing lesson plans and working with children.</p>
<p><strong>3rd Semester</strong>&nbsp;- Lead Teacher - write and implement preschool lesson plans, and take responsibility for the classroom, the children, and training support teachers.</p>
<p><strong>4th Semester</strong>&nbsp;- Supervisor - observe, support and provide in-service training for the teaching team, work with parents, keep records, and maintain lab facilities.</p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>2+2 Program</strong></span></p>
<p>The 2+2 Program is for students completing the Professional Preschool Education program who wish to further their education at BYU-Idaho. If planned well, students may complete a Bachelor's Degree in Child Development in two additional years, and use the PPE degree as their minor. This is a good option for students wishing a Bachelor's Degree in Child Development, but more training and experience teaching preschool-aged children than the typical BS degree. This is also a good option for students wishing to teach in Head Start programs and other programs requiring a Bachelor's Degree.&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Early Childhood Special Education</strong></span></p>
<p>Early Childhood Education/Early Childhood Special Education (ECE/ECSE) prepares students to work with typically developing and/or children with special needs from birth through age eight. Students who successfully complete this program will be elgible to apply for the Blended Early Childhood Education/Early Childhood Special Education Idaho Teaching License, which allows them to teach general or special education classes in kindergarten through third grade. Students may also choose to work with young children and their families in home, agency, and preschool settings. Applied coursework and fieldwork involving children in a variety of settings will prepare sutdents for successful career experiences. Students will demonstrate knowledge, understanding and application of skills during four student teaching experiences with: (1) infants and toddlers, (2) preschoolers, (3) kindergarteners, and (4) first through third grade children in public schools.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/education-human-dev/R%20Fall%202012%20Early%20Childhood%20Special%20Education%20by%20Semester.pdf">Faculty Recommended Sequence of Courses</a></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Family and Consumer Science</span></strong></p>
<p>The Degree of Family and Consumer Sciences Education is a composite major that provides a holistic approach to the study of home and family in preparation to teach. Upon graduation students are secondary education certified to teach FACS in the state of Idaho with an endorsement in Professional Technical education. Students can also work as home economists in business, or continue on to graduate studies to prepare for work as a cooperative extension agent. Students participate in the BYU-Idaho Family and Consumer Association which highlights FCCLA, service, professional, and social development. A Family and Consumer Education major provides opportunity to apply professional skills to home, family, church, and community as well as prepare for a career in education, extension, or business.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/advising/advising/sequences/ug12/cehd/FCSE%20Sequencing%20Sheets.xlsx">Faculty Recommended Sequence of Courses</a></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Child Development</strong></span></p>
<p>The Bachelor of Science Degree in Child Development offers an overview of scholarship and research in the study of children. The core courses in this degree are intended to focus on knowledge about children in their environments, such as home, school, and community. Emphasis is given to the application of scholarly knowledge with the goal of helping children and their families to develop. Practicum and internships are built into the core curriculum to give practical knowledge and hands-on experience in working with children, families, and agencies that serve children and families.</p>
<p>Students pursuing this degree have many career options, but the degree is primarily designed for those who desire to work with children and their families in community or government agencies. Students should consult with their advisor about possible academic and career options such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>A focus on agencies or organizations that serve young children and their families.</li>
<li>A focus on agencies or organizations that serve adolescents and their families.</li>
<li>A focus on scholarly understanding of children and families.</li>
<li>Preparation for graduate study in the field of child development or early childhood education.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/advising/advising/sequences/ug12/cehd/Child%20Dev%20Sequencing%20Sheets.xlsx">Faculty Recommended Sequence of Courses</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17675" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1847" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
