<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x42176" Name="Section II(B): Foundations Assessment" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Assesment</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Assesment</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>Section II: Outcomes and Assessment</strong></p>
<p><strong>Part B:&nbsp;FOUR DIMENSIONS OF FOUNDATIONS ASSESSMENT</strong></p>
<p>I.&nbsp; Student Learning</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; Done at the team/course level</p>
<ol>
<li>Define outcomes that reflect the team's desires for student learning. Outcomes do not need an explicit assessment instrument to be valid.</li>
<li>Each semester use two instruments (one direct, one indirect) to assess one or more outcomes. Do not try to assess all course outcomes every semester.</li>
<li>At the end of the semester the team aggregates data and decides on one course of action based on the evidence from each assessment exercise.</li>
<li>The Foundations office will gather reports of team assessment activity and aggregate it as program-wide data.</li>
<li>Observations from these activities will be reported semi-annually to the President's Council and used to inform program decisions.</li>
</ol>
<p></p>
<p>II.&nbsp; Student evaluations-Likert scale</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>Student evaluations are collected and complied by the Office of Institutional Assessment</li>
<li>Foundations Office aggregates the data and studies patterns.</li>
<li>Patterns will be reported to President's Council and used to inform program decisions.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p>III.&nbsp; Student evaluations-comments</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>Student comments from student evaluations will be compiled, aggregated, and summarized numerically.</li>
<li>These data will be presented semi-annually to President's Council and used to inform program decisions.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p>IV.&nbsp; Class observations</p>
<ul>
<li>The Dean of Foundations, the Associate Dean of Foundations, and Foundations area chairs and team leads will make coordinated class visits.</li>
<li>The visitor will observe through the lense of student experience and respond to questions according to the following rubric:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Assessment of preparation activities<ol>
<li>&nbsp; Was the preparation activity clearly defined?</li>
<li>&nbsp; Was the assignment appropriately rigorous?</li>
<li>&nbsp; Does the assignment encourage student engagement?</li>
<li>&nbsp; Does the assignment adequately prepare the student for class?</li>
</ol></li>
<li><span style="orphans: 3; widows: 3;">Assessment of class</span><ol>
<li>Were the students prepared participate in class?</li>
<li>Was the teacher prepared to engage the students?</li>
<li>Is there an appropriate balance between the teacher sharing information and the students teaching one another?</li>
<li>What activities encouraged student engagement? During which activities did the students seem to "check out"?</li>
<li>What connections were made between the class and the preparation material; between today's assignment and the rest of the course; between what the student learns in this course and the rest of their education; and between their college experience and the rest of their lives?</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Data from the observations will be compiled, aggregated, and summarized numerically.</li>
<li>These data will be presented to semi-annually to President's Council and used to inform program decisions.</li>
</ul>
<p><img height="612" src="Images/foundations/four dimensions.png" width="805" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>PART THREE: THE ASSESSMENT REPORTING PROCESS</strong></p>
<p>I.&nbsp; Team/Course Evaluations</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">A. Each semester a team lead will report on whether or not the team is following several key practices:</p>
<p></p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>&nbsp;How often does the team meet?</li>
<li>&nbsp;How many team members did not participate in any team meetings?</li>
<li>&nbsp;Does the course have well-defined outcomes?</li>
<li>&nbsp;Does the team follow the assessment plan outlined above in Student Learning?</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">B.&nbsp; Annually the team lead will provide the Foundations office with data needed to complete the University Scorecard (See Section II below).</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">C.&nbsp; Biennially a team/course will undergo a thorough review conducted by the Dean of Foundations</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>What is the team lead doing to engage the face-to-face team?</li>
<li>What is the team lead doing to reach out to the online instructors for the course?</li>
<li>How common are the face-to-face courses?</li>
<li>How integrated are the various modes of delivery?</li>
<li>Does the course make use of the BYU-Idaho Learning model?</li>
<li>Does the team meet together often to improve student learning?</li>
<li>Does the course have clearly delineated outcomes?</li>
<li>Does the course achieve university and program-level outcomes?</li>
<li>What academic skills does the course develop?</li>
<li>Does the team follow the assessment plan outlined above in Student Learning?</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p>II.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; University Scorecard</p>
<p>Assessment data will provide the following indicators on the University Scorecard</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>Percentage of courses integrating the Learning Model</li>
<li>Percentage of courses that have syllabi content in common</li>
<li>Percentage of teams that meet regularly</li>
<li>Percentage of teams who follow an assessment plan</li>
<li>Percentage of teams engaged in peer classroom observation</li>
<li>Percentage of Foundations sections visited by the Dean, Associate Dean, Area Chair, or Team Lead within the past year</li>
<li>Percentage of faculty who received a load release to prior to teaching first semester of a course</li>
<li>Percentage of courses that have integrated delivery across all modes of delivery</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p>III. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President's Council Reports</p>
<p>The Dean and Associate Dean of Foundations will aggregate data from all Foundations assessment activity and present a report to the President's Council semi-annually</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17649" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
