<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x42177" Name="Section III(A): Leadership" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Leadership</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Leadership</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>Section III: Policies and Procedures</strong></p>
<p><strong>Part A: FOUNDATIONS LEADERSHIP</strong></p>
<p>The Dean of Foundations works with the Associate Academic Vice-President for Curriculum to oversee all Foundations activity. The Associate Dean of Foundations assists the dean in all activities, and has special responsibility for staffing Foundations classes. Area chairs are assigned oversight of the following Foundations categories:</p>
<p>Area Chair, Academic Fundamentals: FDENG and FDMAT</p>
<p>Area Chair, Cultural Awareness: FDAMF, FDHUM, FDINT, and FDWLD</p>
<p>Area Chair, Sciences: FDSCI</p>
<p>Team Lead, FDCNC 250: Represents FDCNC on the Foundations Council (see below)</p>
<p>Responsibilities of Area Chairs:</p>
<ol start="1" type="A">
<li>Overall Category Management<ol start="1" type="a">
<li>Oversee staffing of each Foundations course, working in cooperation with the Associate Dean of Foundations and the team leads for each course.</li>
<li>Schedule sections, working in cooperation with the associate dean and the team leads for each course.</li>
<li>Recommend team lead succession plan.</li>
<li>Review course and faculty evaluations for each assigned course in the category.</li>
<li>Encourage and coordinate proposals for new courses within the category.</li>
<li>Review current courses in cooperation with the dean, associate dean, and the team leads for each course.</li>
<li>Sit on the Foundations Council</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Course Quality<ol start="1" type="a">
<li>Work with team leads to ensure the development of course goals and learning outcomes for each assigned course.</li>
<li>Work with team leads to develop assessment strategies for identified course goals and learning outcomes.</li>
<li>Work with team leads on teaching team development, team meetings, commonality among sections, and course improvement plans.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p>A team lead oversees each Foundations course. Team leads usually receive one hour of administrative load per semester. Upon review by the Dean of Foundations and the respective department chair, it may be determined that more than one hour is needed. Team Leads have the following responsibilities:</p>
<ol start="1" type="1">
<li>Hold regular team meetings with all members of the teaching group.</li>
<li>Lead the team in developing common course goals, learning outcomes, and curriculum maps.</li>
<li>Lead the team in developing and implementing common assessment strategies and instruments.</li>
<li>Lead the team in developing common/master syllabi; in sharing content, practice, and pedagogy.<ol start="1" type="a">
<li>A master syllabus would include:&nbsp; common outcomes, schedule, and "reference points" (other common course elements that all faculty will cover in the course)</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Lead the team in course quality and improvement efforts.</li>
<li>Work with the Foundations leadership regarding faculty rotation on and off the teaching team.</li>
<li>Help train and orient new teaching team members.</li>
<li>Work with Foundations leadership on section scheduling.</li>
<li>Work with the online organization when requested (see <strong>ONLINE LEARNING</strong>, below).</li>
</ol>
<p>In order for Foundations to fulfill its mission it is vital that all stakeholders understand their roles.&nbsp; Specifically:</p>
<ol start="1" type="1">
<li>Departments will be given SCH and course assignments for Foundations courses, with the accompanying responsibility to make faculty available for these assignments.&nbsp; Should a faculty member need to be replaced for any reason it is the responsibility of the department chair, working in cooperation with the Associate Dean of Foundations and designated area chair and team lead to provide the needed faculty resource.&nbsp; Department courses should not be given priority over Foundations assignments. As a faculty member rotates on and off a Foundations team, the associate dean and area chair will contact the faculty member's department chair to discuss a replacement.</li>
<li>The dean, associate dean, and area chairs will have access to all Foundations course evaluations.&nbsp; As they deem it necessary and appropriate they may discuss a specific faculty member's performance with the team lead and/or the department chair, determining a course of action.</li>
</ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17649" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
