<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Content ID="x42416" Name="Assertiveness" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Assertiveness</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Assertiveness</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Infants and young children have direct ways of making their needs and  desires known.  But as we grow older, we tend to adopt less direct  styles of communicating.  On one end of the spectrum, messages we receive from society and  significant people in our lives seem to discourage "making waves," by expressing our views, desires, and needs.  On the other end of the spectrum, more and more messages from the media seem to promote aggression and disrespect as rightful means to get what we want.</span></p>
<h1 style="color: #003366; font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-size: large; font-family: helvetica;"><strong>What is Assertiveness?</strong></span></h1>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Assertiveness is neither passivity nor aggressiveness.  Assertive communication  demonstrates self-respect and self-confidence, in addition to awareness  of and respect for others.  Assertiveness begins when you look at the world from  the position that you have eternal worth and human rights AND that others  also have eternal worth and human rights.  You can take the following test to  determine whether you are assertive, passive, or aggressive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Click here to access the <a href="x32098.xml">Self-Test for Assertiveness</a></span></p>
<h1 style="color: #003366; font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-size: large; font-family: helvetica;"><strong>Communicating Assertively</strong></span></h1>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Communicating assertively is expressing positive and negative feelings  honestly and directly.  It is based on the belief that you have the  right to be listened to and taken seriously, to say no without feeling  guilty, to ask for what you want, and to make mistakes.  At the same time,  you acknowledge that the other person has identical rights.  Because you  are communicating honestly and openly, your relationships become much  more genuine.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Sometimes it is difficult to learn to communicate assertively.  You may  go to the extreme and express yourself in an accusing or angry  manner or not at all.  Becoming assertive - like any other skill - takes time and  practice.  It is important to understand that assertive communication  does not guarantee that people will agree with you or that you will  always get what you want.  It does, however, enhance your self-respect  and improve your chances for enjoyable relationships.  The key to  communicating assertively is to express yourself clearly, without  blaming or judging the other person.  An accepted and proven method for  accomplishing this is using the "I Feel" message format:</span></p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="background-color: #efefec; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px; padding-top: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;">WHEN...</td>
<td style="background-color: #efefec; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px;">Objectively describe the other person's behavior.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px; padding-top: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;">THEN...</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px;">Describe the effect of the behavior on you.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="background-color: #efefec; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px;">I FEEL...</td>
<td style="background-color: #efefec; border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px;">Name an emotion.  Do not accuse or blame.  Avoid expressing thoughts rather than emotions (for example, "I feel that").</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; width: 100px; padding-left: 20px; padding-top: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;">I PREFER...</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #e4e1d9; padding-left: 20px;">Describe the behavior you want/prefer.  "Would you be willing to...?"</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Learning this style of communication will probably feel awkward at  first, but so does learning to ride a bike.  The following examples may  help you to feel more comfortable with the "I feel" format:"</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">EXAMPLE 1:</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;"><em>You're so inconsiderate!"</em></span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">can be rephrased as</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"<strong>WHEN</strong> you do not call me when you say you will, (<strong>THEN</strong>) I imagine that something bad has happened to prevent you from calling.  <strong>I FEEL</strong> scared and anxious.  <strong>I WANT/ I WOULD PREFER</strong> that you call, even collect, when you say you will."</span></p>
<br />
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">EXAMPLE 2:</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;"><em>You're such a slob!"</em></span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">can be rephrased as</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"<strong>WHEN</strong> you don't put things away after using them, (<strong>THEN</strong>) I end up doing it and <strong>I FEEL </strong>really resentful.  <strong>WOULD YOU BE WILLING</strong> to help in keeping things in their proper storage places?"</span></p>
<br />
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">EXAMPLE 3:</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;"><em>"Don't walk away from me!"</em></span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">can be rephrased as</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"<strong>WHEN</strong> you get up and walk away while I'm talking to you, (<strong>THEN</strong>) I assume that you aren't interested in what's important to me.  <strong>I FEEL</strong> hurt and ignored.  <strong>I WOULD PREFER </strong>that you give me and our conversation your full attention."</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Assertive communication involves acknowledging the feelings of the other  person, without necessarily agreeing to do what the other person is  asking.  For example, imagine you are standing in a line at the store.   Someone behind you has one item and asks to get in front of you.  You  respond, "I realize that you don't want to wait in line, but I was here  first and I really would like to get out of here."</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: helvetica;">You can practice the "I Feel" message format by rephrasing the following messages:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"I can never count on you to do what you tell me you will do." </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Respond to this scenario: You are facing a deadline and really need  to work on your project. Your friends tell you, "Come on and go with  us. You can do your homework later."</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"I already told you I couldn't help you out tonight. Leave me alone!"</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"Get off my back!"</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"You never listen to me when I'm talking to you."</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"Stop interrupting me."</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"You never appreciate all I do for you."</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"Gee, what a surprise. You're only an hour late this time." </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">"Yeah, I guess I can take care of your kids tonight."</span></li>
</ul>
<h1 style="color: #003366; font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-size: large; font-family: helvetica;"><strong>Beliefs About Assertive Behavior</strong></span></h1>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Sometimes people have difficulty being assertive because of certain  beliefs they have. Are there beliefs that you have that sometimes  prevent you from being assertive?  You may believe that other  people's rights and feelings are more important than your own.  You may  fear that other people will be offended if you are assertive.  Being  assertive may change the nature of some of your relationships, and that  may cause you concern.  Or perhaps you believe that you are not  important enough to deserve to express your needs and feelings.  What  are some beliefs you have that may prevent you from being assertive?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Of  course, it's not necessary to always be assertive.  You can choose  whether to be assertive in a given situation by asking yourself how  important the issue is to you, how you will feel afterward, and how much  the consequences of assertiveness will "cost" you.  Be realistic--don't  scare yourself with irrational assumptions or unlikely probabilities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">One of your rights is to say "no" without having to provide an excuse.   You don't have to have reasons or answers, and you don't have to have  solutions to others' problems.  If the other person continues to press  you to comply with the request, you can use the "broken record" method.   This involves empathizing with the other person but continuing to  firmly say "no."</span></p>
<h1 style="color: #003366; font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-family: helvetica; font-size: large;"><strong>Practice Scenarios</strong></span></h1>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Using what you know about assertiveness, how would you act in the following circumstances?</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">A good friend calls and tells you that he/she desperately needs you  to canvass your apartment complex for a charity.  You do not want to do  it. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">You are working on a team project with another student, but you are doing all the planning and preparation. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">(For women) A man asks you for a date.  You have dated him once before and are not interested in dating him again. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Your parents are talking to you on the phone and would like you to  come home for a visit on a weekend when you have made other plans. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">You and a friend have planned to vacation together, but the plans  are abruptly changed by your friend and reported to you over the phone. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Your supervisor at work has just reprimanded you for your work. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">During a phone call, your roommate has interrupted you three times with something that is not urgent. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">Sitting in the row behind you at the movie is a young couple with their infant, who begins to cry. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">A friend knocks on your door during your favorite TV show--the only  one you give yourself permission to watch during the week--and asks if  you are busy. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">A friend has asked you to join her and some other friends in a service project. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">You are feeling really stressed by work, school, and extracurricular evening commitments. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: helvetica;">You made an appointment to talk with your English professor  concerning some difficulties you are having in class.  You call him the  day of the appointment to confirm, and he says he is expecting you.   Upon arriving at his office, you find him talking with another student.   Your professor asks if you would come back in an hour.</span></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h5>RESOURCES</h5>
<p><span style="font-family: helvetica;"><a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/assertive/SR00042">http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/assertive/SR00042</a></span></p>
<em> </em><span style="font-family: helvetica;"><em>The Assertiveness Workbook<em> </em>: How to Express Your <em>Ideas and Stand Up for Yourself at Work and in Relationships</em></em> by Randy J. Paterson Ph.D.</span><em><br /> <em> </em> </em>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" /></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17637" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></Content>