<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x42431" Name="Sleep" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sleep</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sleep</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3><strong style="color: #003366; font-family: helvetica; font-size: medium;"> </strong>Sleep Problems</h3>
<p>There  are several sleep problems or disorders that affect the quality and  quantity of sleep and may require treatment before you can get back on  track with restful, restorative sleep.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Insomnia  includes difficulty falling asleep, waking from sleep, or diminished  quality of sleep.  While short bouts of insomnia are quite common, if  insomnia persists for 2 to 3 weeks, you need to see a professional or  physician about treatment options.  Possible causes include stress,  depression, light, noise, heat, cold, an uncomfortable mattress,  movement of a spouse, a painful condition, medical problems, and alcohol  or drug dependency.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sleep  apnea interferes with normal breathing during sleep but not while  awake.  During sleep, breathing stops for 10 seconds or more, and then  the sufferer snorts and gasps for air and returns to sleep.  These  interruptions are repeated throughout the night.  Sleep apnea may result  in a number of various health problems and requires treatment.  See  your doctor if you suspect you have sleep apnea.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Narcolepsy  is sleep that occurs at inappropriate times.  The person experiences an  overwhelming urge to sleep, especially under monotonous, boring  conditions.  The person sleeps for 2 to 5 minutes and usually wakes  feeling refreshed.  The narcoleptic person may also occasionally wilt,  fall to the ground, and lie there conscious for a few seconds to several  minutes.  Such episodes are triggered by strong emotion or sudden  physical effort.   Medications can help some narcoleptics.</p>
</li>
<li>Sleepwalking  is usually not a serious concern, though it can lead to physical injury  due to moving about in a semi-conscious state.  Sleepwalking is usually  outgrown by late adolescence. </li>
<li>
<p>Restless-legs  syndrome is experienced as an uncomfortable, aching sensation in the  calves accompanied by an irresistible urge to move the legs.  It is felt  while awake but is worse at bedtime and often interferes with falling  asleep.  Walking and stretching often help.  More severe cases often  benefit from medication.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In  phase-delay syndrome, the person cannot seem to fall asleep until late  at night; so getting up in the morning at the desired time is not easy  (and perhaps dangerous to the roommate whom you asked to wake you in  time to get to class).  Frequent switches in bedtimes and wake up times  often lead to this problem, so as you might guess, college students and  shift workers are most likely to experience this problem.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h3>Suggestions for Improving Sleep</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Make  sleep a priority.  Experiment with keeping a regular sleep schedule for  a few weeks.  If it does not work for you, you can always go back to  the old way of doing things.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Go  to bed and get up at the same times, even on the weekends.  If you do  stay up late on Friday or Saturday night, at least get to sleep by 1  a.m., rather than staying up an extra three hours watching a video or  talking.  Consider starting dates earlier, so you can get to sleep a  little earlier.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ask  roommates who stay up late to help you by keeping the volume down on  the stereo or the conversation.  If approached in the right spirit, most  roommates will respond favorably.  Who knows?  They may even follow  your good example and get to bed a little earlier.  Earplugs or  mediation with the apartment manager may be necessary in some cases.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If  you do tend to stay up late, avoid taking early morning classes so that  you can get about eight hours of sleep each night.  If you just can't  get your eight hours at night, take a 45-minute nap in the afternoon.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If  you study in the evening, give yourself an hour of downtime before  bedtime to help you unwind.  Remember that while schoolwork is  important, your health is also important.  Lack of sleep compromises  your immune system and may lead to the flu or colds.  A sleep-deprived  you will also take much longer to read a chapter than a well rested you.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Videotape your favorite late TV shows, and watch them the next day.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Caffeine  is a stimulant.  Do not consume caffeine within 4 to 6 hours of  bedtime.  Energy drinks are likewise stimulants and should be avoided  around bedtime.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Get regular exercise, but not within 2-3 hours of bedtime.  It takes time for your body to prepare for sleep.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Keep your room dark and cool.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Avoid heavy or spicy meals around bedtime.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If  you lie down to sleep and your mind starts to think about your concerns  or schedule, do the following: a)  Keep a planner to avoid juggling  your schedule in your head.  b) Schedule 15 minutes each day to plan and  problem solve.  The scheduled time should be at least 1 hour before  bedtime. c) Focus and refocus as needed on a pleasant and relaxing  memory while drifting off to sleep.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Finally,  if you do not fall asleep within about half an hour or so (DO NOT watch  the clock), get up and do something quiet like reading until you feel  drowsy.  Then, return to bed.</p>
</li>
</ol> <ol> </ol>
<p> </p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
