<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x42430" Name="Sexual Assault" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sexual Assault</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sexual Assault</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2>What is Sexual Assault?</h2>
<p>Sexual assault is any type of sexual activity that you do not want or agree to.&nbsp; It is a crime of violence, anger, power, and control that stems from one person's determination to exercise power over another.&nbsp; It is usually not related to sexual desire.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sexual assault ranges from inappropriate touching to penetration or intercourse.&nbsp; It can also be verbal, visual, audio, textual, or any other form that forces a person to participate in unwanted sexual contact or attention.&nbsp; Sexual assault includes rape and attempted rape, child molestation, voyeurism ("peeping Top"), indecent exposure, incest, and sexual harassment.</p>
<p>All forms of sexual assault are crimes, even if you don't fight back.</p>
<h2>What is Date Rape?</h2>
<p>Date rape is also known as acquaintance rape.&nbsp; It is defined as forced sexual activity against a person's will be someone she knows.&nbsp; Date rape is as traumatic and serious as other forms of rape.</p>
<p>No matter who it is who attacks you, or what kind of relationship you have with that person, sexual assault is a crime.</p>
<h2>What is Sexual Coercion?</h2>
<p>Sexual coercion is being persuaded to have sex or participate in other forms of physical intimacy when you don't really want to.&nbsp; The person who is persuaded may believe that she is freely choosing to have sex.&nbsp; But in reality, someone or something makes her feel that she has to have sex or that sex is the right choice for her.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sexual coercion occurs in unbalanced relationships - relationships where there is unequal power.&nbsp; One person always "gives," and the other always "takes."&nbsp; Sexual coercion and aggression can occur at age stage in a relationship.&nbsp; It may take any of the following forms:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pressure - The person may say that everybody's doing it, that sex is the way to prove love, or that you've had sex before, so you can't say no now.</li>
<li>Threats - The person may threaten to hurt or leave you if you won't have sex.&nbsp; You may feel afraid to say no.</li>
<li>Flattery - Compliments can be sincere.&nbsp; But if someone keeps saying things that sound extreme or too good to be true, this may be sexual coercion.</li>
<li>Other forms include put-downs, guilt trips, buying gifts or spending money to make you feel that you "owe" sex.</li>
</ul>
<p>Remember - You <em>never</em> owe anyone sex.</p>
<h2>Who are the Offenders?</h2>
<p>Nearly 99 percent of reported offenders are male.&nbsp; Some are strangers.&nbsp; But most sexual assaults and rapes are committed by someone known to the victim.&nbsp; Offenders might include any of the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spouses or intimate partners</li>
<li>Acquaintances, such as classmates, coworkers, or employers</li>
<li>Friends</li>
<li>Family members</li>
<li>Dates, boyfriends, or former boyfriends</li>
</ul>
<p>No matter who attacks you, sexual assault is a crime.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Possible Characteristics of Men Who Rape Women They Know</h3>
<ul>
<li>Hostility or anger toward women</li>
<li>Domineering personality.&nbsp; He makes all the decisions about what you should do and where you should go.&nbsp; Perhaps he treats you as his property.</li>
<li>Wrong ideas about women.&nbsp; He views women as sex objects, thinks that women are supposed to serve others' needs, or believes that only "loose" women get raped.</li>
<li>Unrealistic views of women.&nbsp; He idolizes you and puts you on a pedestal.&nbsp; Then he feels let down and angry if you don't live up to his image of you.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Who are the Victims of Sexual Assault?</h2>
<p>Sexual assault affects women, children, and men of all ages, from infants to the elderly.&nbsp; Victims come from all racial, cultural, and economic backgrounds.&nbsp; An estimated 91 percent of the victims of rape and sexual assault are female and 9 percent are male.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The 2010 National Intimate Partner and Sexual Violence Survey, administered by the Centers for Disease Control, reported that following statistics:</p>
<p>Nearly 1 in 5 women has been raped at some time in her life.&nbsp; Approximately 80 percent of female victims of rape were first raped before age 25.&nbsp; More than one-quarter of male rape victims were first raped when they were 10 years old or younger.</p>
<p>Victims of violence (sexual violence, stalking, intimate partner violence) were significantly more likely to report physical and mental health problems than non-victims.</p>
<p>Across all forms of violence (sexual violence, stalking, intimate partner violence), the vast majority of victims knew their perpetrator (often an intimate partner or acquaintance and seldom a stranger).</p>
<h2>Where Do Sexual Assaults Occur?</h2>
<p>The offender often plans the assault ahead of time.&nbsp; Nearly 6 out of 10 rape or sexual assault incidents are reported by victims to have occurred in their own home or at the home of a friend, relative, or neighbor.&nbsp; Almost 70 percent of sexual assaults reported to law enforcement occur in the residence of the victim, the offender, or another individual.&nbsp; Rape by a date tends to occur on weekends on the offender's turf (apartment, car, etc.).</p>
<h2>How Can You Avoid Being Sexually Assaulted?</h2>
<p>The following short slideshow of the Sexual Assault Triangle simplifies how to avoid being sexually assaulted.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" height="400" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/14607178?hostedIn=slideshare&amp;page=upload" width="476"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Removing the Opportunity for Stranger Rape</h3>
<ul>
<li>Listen to the Spirit.&nbsp; Trust your feelings.</li>
<li>In general, be alert to your surroundings.</li>
<li>Walk with confidence and trust your instincts.&nbsp; Rapists often target those who appear weak or vulnerable.&nbsp; If you feel uneasy or uncomfortable in your surroundings or think you may be in danger, leave.</li>
<li>Stay where there are other people.&nbsp; Be wary of isolated spots, such as underground garages, offices after business hours, and apartment laundry rooms.</li>
<li>Avoid alcohol and drugs.&nbsp; They impair your judgment.</li>
<li>Avoid walking alone at night - even in Rexburg.&nbsp; If you must walk home from campus in the dark, contact University Security at 496-3000 for a safety escort.</li>
<li>Park in well-lighted areas.</li>
<li>Never hitchhike or pick up a hitchhiker.</li>
<li>Lock your car, and have your keys ready as you approach your car.</li>
<li>If your car breaks down, turn on your flashers, lock the doors, stay in your car, and call for help.&nbsp; If you don't have a phone, put on the flashers, lift your hood, use flares if possible, get back in the car, and lock the doors.&nbsp; If someone stops to help you, roll the window down enough so he or she can hear you.&nbsp; Ask them to call the police or a tow service.&nbsp;</li>
<li>At home, lock your doors and windows.&nbsp; Have a peephole in the door and well-lighted entrances.</li>
<li>Never open your door to strangers.&nbsp; Always check the identification of salespersons or service people before opening the door.&nbsp; It is a good idea to have another adult at home with you when service people come.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Know a neighbor you can call or rely on if something happens.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Removing the Opportunity in a Dating Situation</h3>
<ul>
<li>Listen to the Spirit.&nbsp; Trust your feelings.</li>
<li>Make it clear what your limits are <em>before</em> you get into a sexual situation.</li>
<li>Insist on being treated with respect.&nbsp; Assert yourself by standing up for your rights.</li>
<li>Take an equal role in your relationships and reject stereotypes that define women as weak.&nbsp; Keep in mind that no one has the right to touch your body without your permission.</li>
<li>Stay away from isolated places, such as parks or deserted beaches.</li>
<li>Go out with a group.</li>
<li>Avoid alcohol and other drugs.&nbsp; These harm your judgment and make it harder for you to resist coercion or otherwise stay in control of the situation.</li>
<li>Prepare your own drinks and don't let them out of your sight.</li>
<li>When out with friends at social events, never leave with someone you've just met.</li>
<li>Be wary of online relationships.&nbsp; If you arrange to meet someone you have met online, never meet him alone.</li>
<li>If you are in an abusive relationship, get out.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Ways to respond to sexual pressure:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Say no firmly or leave.&nbsp; Seek help, if needed.</li>
<li>"I really like you.&nbsp; I just don't want to do this."</li>
<li>"If you really care about me, you'll respect my decision."</li>
<li>"I said no.&nbsp; I don't owe you an explanation."</li>
</ul>
<h2>How do you handle a sexual assaulter?</h2>
<p>There are no hard and fast, right or wrong answers to handle an attacker.&nbsp; It depends on your emotional and physical state, the situation, and the attacker's personality.&nbsp; The following are some possible ways of responding.</p>
<ul>
<li>Listen to the Spirit.&nbsp; Trust your feelings.</li>
<li>Surviving is the goal.&nbsp; Sexual assault is a crime, even if you don't fight back.</li>
<li>Try to escape.&nbsp; Scream.&nbsp; Run toward light or people.</li>
<li>Be rude.&nbsp; Make noise to discourage your attacker from following you.</li>
<li>Talk, stall for time, and assess your options.</li>
<li>If the attacker has a weapon, you may have no choice but to submit.&nbsp; Do whatever it takes to survive.</li>
<li>Do something to make yourself less attractive and break into his fantasy.&nbsp; For example, pass gas, urinate, tell him that you are on your period.</li>
<li>If you decide to fight back, you must be quick, determined, and effective, without telegraphing your intentions.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Self-Defense Targets</h3>
<p>In an situation where you are attacked, you may be able to protect yourself by employing a self-defense strategy. &nbsp;This would be a time to pay attention to the Spirit because sometimes an attacker will be further excited by the attempts of his victim to fight back. &nbsp;In the movie, <em>Miss Congeniality</em>, Sandra Bullock demonstrates self-defense against a would-be attacker.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/idlBj5sivrQ" width="420"></iframe>
<p><br />Some of the body areas that you might target include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Eyes.</strong>&nbsp; Jab your index finger into his eyeball.</li>
<li><strong>Nose.</strong>&nbsp; Thrust the palm of your hand upward to the underside of his nose.</li>
<li><strong>Throat.</strong>&nbsp; Jab your index finger into his Adam's apple area.</li>
<li><strong>Groin. &nbsp;</strong>Knee, kick, punch, or elbow this sensitive body part.</li>
<li><strong>Knee.</strong>&nbsp; Sharply kick his kneecap.</li>
<li><strong>Feet.</strong>&nbsp; Stomp on the top of his foot, near the ankle.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>Learning to be confident in the use of self-defense strategies takes practice. &nbsp;If you are hesitant or somehow "telegraph" your intent, you are unlikely to be effective. &nbsp;You can learn to defend yourself in danger situations by taking the campus <a href="http://www.byui.edu/activities/wellness/rad-rape-aggression-defense-course" title="RAD Course" target="_blank">RAD (Rape Aggression Defense) course,</a> offered through the BYU-Idaho Activities program.</p>
<h2>What Should You Do If You are Sexually Assaulted?</h2>
<ul>
<li>If you're raped, you should first get to a safe place, away from your attacker, as fast as you can.&nbsp; Call a friend or family member you trust, or call a crisis center or a hotline to talk with a counselor. &nbsp;The following are helpful resources: &nbsp;
<ul>
<li><strong>Family Crisis Center.</strong> &nbsp;(208) 356-0065</li>
<li><strong>BYU-Idaho Counseling Center</strong>. &nbsp;(208) 496-9370 (during business hours) or (208) 496-HELP (4357) during non-business hours</li>
<li><strong>National Domestic Violence Hotline. &nbsp;</strong>1- (800) 799-SAFE or 1-(800) 787-3224 (TDD)&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Do not feel ashamed or guilty.&nbsp; These feelings, as well as being afraid and shocked, are normal.&nbsp; It is important to get counseling from a trusted professional.</li>
<li>Do not wash, comb, or clean any part of your body, or change clothes if possible.</li>
<li>Do not touch or change anything at the scene of the assault; it is a crime scene.</li>
<li>Go to your nearest hospital emergency room as soon as possible.&nbsp; You need to be examined, treated for any injuries, and screened for possible sexually transmitted diseases or pregnancy.&nbsp; The doctor will collect evidence that the attacker may have left behind, like clothing fibers, hairs, saliva, or semen.&nbsp; A standard "rape kit" is usually used to help collect these things.&nbsp;</li>
<li>You or the hospital staff can call the police from the emergency room to file a report.&nbsp; Unfortunately, rape is the violent crime least often reported to law enforcement.&nbsp; You may think that nothing can be done or that it was a private matter.&nbsp; You may be afraid of the police response or think that it is not important enough.&nbsp; Remember, sexual assault is against the law.&nbsp; You have the right to report this crime to the police and to be treated fairly.</li>
</ul>
<h2>What Emotional and Physical Issues Might You Face?</h2>
<p>Being raped can have a huge effect on your life.&nbsp; You may experience:</p>
<ul>
<li>Shock or denial</li>
<li>Muscle tension and headaches</li>
<li>Changes in sleeping and eating</li>
<li>Nausea and vomiting</li>
<li>Feelings of fear, shame, or guilt</li>
<li>Anger, irritability, and anxiety</li>
<li>Nightmares and flashbacks</li>
<li>A sense of worthlessness, helplessness, or loss of control</li>
<li>Loss of trust</li>
<li>Withdrawal from others and loss of interest in usual activities</li>
<li>Loss of interest in sex</li>
</ul>
<p>About half of all people who are raped say that they are depressed the first year after the attacks.&nbsp; Those who submit to the attacker often feel guilt.&nbsp; But a woman who submits to her attacker is not guilty of causing the rape, any more than the bank teller who hands money over to a bank robber is responsible for the robbery.&nbsp; No one can take your virtue from you.&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Healing</h2>
<p>Counseling can help you to heal.&nbsp; It's important that you keep your appointments with your counselor. &nbsp;Be sure to tell him or her about any physical, emotional, or sexual problems you have during this time, even if you don't think they are related to the rape.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong>&nbsp;</strong>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
