<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<CustomPageWithReturn ID="x42780" Name="Job Opportunities" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Psychology Job Opportunities</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Job Opportunities for Psychology Majors and graduates</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="LeftNavGroup" label="Left Nav Return" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><ParentName type="string" label="Parent Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></ParentName><xPower Type="Link" Link="x42780" Name="Link" label="Link" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" LinkText="Job Opportunities" Target="" Expanded="false" URL=""/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;">July 2014</span>&nbsp;</div>
<div>
<p>A former BYU-I student has sent us some information regarding a need for chaplains in the Air Force. Some of you may find the information below useful.</p>
<p><strong>From: </strong>Timothy Ng &lt;<a href="mailto:timslng8@gmail.com">timslng8@gmail.com</a>&gt;<br /><strong>Date: </strong>Monday, July 7, 2014 at 5:45 PM<br /><strong>To: </strong>Steven Dennis &lt;<a href="mailto:DennisS@byui.edu">DennisS@byui.edu</a>&gt;, "Ivers, John" &lt;<a href="mailto:IVERSJ@byui.edu">IVERSJ@byui.edu</a>&gt;, "Galer, Scott" &lt;<a href="mailto:GALERS@byui.edu">GALERS@byui.edu</a>&gt;<br /><strong>Cc: </strong>"Lamoreaux, Jeremy" &lt;<a href="mailto:lamoreauxj@byui.edu">lamoreauxj@byui.edu</a>&gt;<br /><strong>Subject: </strong>Call for Air Force Reserve Chaplains</p>
<p>Bro Ivers, Galer, and Dennis:<br />I recently completed USAF Commissioned Officer Training and am currently at the Chaplain Candidate School for the rest of the summer. The USAF Reserves is in desperate need of more chaplains, currently running at only 70% of what they need to fulfil their mission. I am currently the only LDS USAF chaplain candidate, and there are only a handful of LDS active duty and reserve chaplains in the USAF (there are more in the army and navy). If there are bright, smart, grounded and disciplined students of yours that might be able to both benefit from and contribute to both God and country by serving as a reserve chaplain in the USAF, then I would be more than happy to mentor them and get them onto the path to such a unique and esteemed service. If they are especially smart, I would recommend they apply to Yale for their M.Div degree like I did, as there is also room there for a few exceptional LDS students. I have a full scholarship at Yale, and am getting paid nicely for just being a chaplain candidate in the USAF (and there is no commitment during this period), so it's a great deal--but only the most outstanding and committed need bother to apply--but I know that BYU-I pumps out that caliber of student on a regular basis.<br /><br />When I return home from my summer tour I'll see if I can put some more succinct info together in a PPT or other format (of course, if you want to fly me out to the Pre-Professional Conference I'd be more than happy to give a presentation in person on a) how to get into Yale; b) how to become a USAF chaplain... if not, then a Skype chat would work too ;). Perhaps Bro. Lamoreaux and the Sigma Iota Rho folks might want to host a Skype presentation or something if there is enough interest.<br /><br />Anyhow, just wanted to make you aware of the nation's need, the student's possibilities, and the church's opportunity to fill the void of chaplains in the world's greatest Air Force.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />Like BYU-I, Yale, the Book of Mormon, and the USAF, if it's blue, it must be true! All the best,&nbsp;&nbsp;<br /><strong>TIMOTHY S.L. NG</strong><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><strong>‧</strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong>吳仕良&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;">May 2014</span>&nbsp; <strong>PSR/Case Manager Needed</strong>
<div>
<p>Looking to hire a graduate in a social science field to work Full-time as a Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist (PSR Worker) and Case Manager.&nbsp;&nbsp;Looking for someone who will fit in with their team.&nbsp; The company currently employs several BYUI graduates.&nbsp; Employees work in a team atmosphere which most employees find much more satisfying than a caseload of their own.&nbsp;<strong>Anyone interested may contact Eric Olson, LCPC, District 7 MH CT Coordinator at (208) 360-0262, </strong><strong>Fax: (208) 612-5036</strong></p>
</div>
</div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;">July 2013</span>&nbsp; <strong>Access Point Family Services - Idaho Falls - Now Interviewing for July Positions<br />Full-time Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialists Needed</strong> Currently hiring for full-time psychosocial rehabilitation workers. We provide mental health services to children ages 3-17. Qualifications are a four year degree in Psychology, Elementary Education, Social Work, or Child Development. <br />To find out more call at 522-4026 or go to our website at <a href="http://www.accesspointkids.com" target="_self">www.accesspointkids.com</a>. If interested, you can apply online, email your resume to <a href="mailto:april@accesspointkids.com" target="_self">april@accesspointkids.com</a>, drop off your resume in person at our office, or fax your resume to 522-4138.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;</div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;">March 2013</span></div>
<div><strong>Access Point Family Services - Idaho Falls <br />Full-time Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialists Needed</strong></div>
<div>Currently&nbsp;hiring for full-time psychosocial rehabilitation workers. We provide mental health services to children ages 3-17. Qualifications are a four year degree in Psychology, Elementary Education, Social Work, or Child Development. <br />To find out more call at 522-4026 or go to our website at <a href="http://www.accesspointkids.com" target="_self">www.accesspointkids.com</a>. If interested, you can apply online, email your resume to <a href="mailto:april@accesspointkids.com" target="_self">april@accesspointkids.com</a>, drop off your resume in person at our office, or fax your resume to 522-4138.<br /><br /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">August 2012</span><strong><br />Access Point Family Services - Idaho Falls <br />Part-time Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist Needed</strong></div>
<div>Currently opening for a part-time psychosocial rehabilitation worker.&nbsp;&nbsp; If you are interested in an internship or some experience in this field contact:<br />Ashley Burke, Developmental Therapy Manager &nbsp; <a href="mailto:[mailto:ashley@accesspointkids.com]">[mailto:ashley@accesspointkids.com]</a></div>
<div><br /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">July 2011</span><strong><br />Access Point Family Services - Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialists Needed</strong></div>
<div>We are currently hiring full time psychosocial rehabilitation workers. We provide mental health services to children ages 3-17. Qualifications are a four year degree in Psychology, Elementary Education, Social Work, or Child Development. <br />To find out more call at 522-4026 or go to our website at <a href="http://www.accesspointkids.com" target="_self">www.accesspointkids.com</a>. If interested, you can apply online, email your resume to <a href="mailto:april@accesspointkids.com" target="_self">april@accesspointkids.com</a>, drop off your resume in person at our office, or fax your resume to 522-4138.</div>
<div>
<p>*****************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">April 2011</span><br /><strong>Child and Family Resource in Rexburg is hiring PSRs to start ASAP!</strong></p>
<p>PSR stands for Psychosocial Rehabilitation , this is a program&nbsp;in which recipients learn specific skills that foster rehabilitation and recovery. A PSR will teach clients skills to help them function in everyday life and control behaviors.<br />Applicants need a degree in child development or psychology. Hiring part time and full time, Mileage is paid for.<br />Bring resume to Ron or James at:</p>
<p>Child and Family Resource<br />316 N 3rd E &middot; Rexburg<br />(208) 356-4911</p>
<p>**********************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">December 2010</span><br /><strong>Access Point Family Services - Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist Needed</strong></p>
<p>.We are currently hiring part time and full time psychosocial rehabilitation workers. We provide mental health services to children ages 3-17. Qualifications are a four year degree in Psychology, Elementary Education, Social Work, or Child Development. To find out more call at 522-4026 or go to our website at <a href="http://www.accesspointkids.com" target="_self">www.accesspointkids.com</a>. If interested, you can apply online, email your resume to <a href="mailto:april@accesspointkids.com" target="_self">april@accesspointkids.com</a>, drop off your resume in person at our office, or fax your resume to 522-4138.</p>
<p>*********************************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">March 2009</span> - Psychosocial Rehabilitation Positions:<br />This is a community based Mental Health and Behavioral treatment that is primarily provided in clients home and community, working with primary ages of 3 to 18 years. We also work with some adults with this program. Qualifications are a 4 year degree in social work or a human services field. Psychology qualifies for this position. The pay rate begins at $16.00 per billable hour plus differing benefits based upon how many hours an individual bills in a pay period. (2 weeks).</p>
<p>To apply have them fax a resume to 522-6596 attn: Bruce Hampton.</p>
<p>**********************************************</p>
<p>We are currently hiring psychosocial workers. This is a great agency that is financially stable when a lot of other mental health agencies are not. To apply contact:<br />Joseph Horner<br />(208) 201-9535<br /><a href="mailto:JosephHorner@gmail.com" target="_self">JosephHorner@gmail.com</a></p>
<p>******************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">November 2008:</span><br /><strong>Healthy Place Counseling</strong><br />Needed: A full-time female PSR worker to work with children and adults in their homes and community and can start training in December, and then begin work as a PSR worker once they've received their diploma.</p>
<p>I also need a part-time male and female worker to begin about the same time. The requirements are that they have a four year college degree with at least 21 credits in the social sciences field, and can pass a thorough background check. Our starting pay is $17 ph or doe, and we offer some benefits after three months. This is an excellent transitional job from undergrad to graduate student.</p>
<p>Contact: Dan Johnson<br />Phone: 208-520-6867</p>
<p>************************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">November 10, 2008</span><br /><strong>Full Time Research Assistant for Language Processing and Language Acquisition Studies</strong></p>
<p>JOB DESCRIPTION: Pending final budgetary approval, the research labs of Dr. John Trueswell and Dr. Lila Gleitman are hiring a full-time research assistant to help conduct language processing studies with children and adults. In many of these studies we will be recording the eye movements of participants as they respond to spoken instructions. Primary responsibilities include assisting lab members and the PIs in the running of experiments, developing experimental materials, and data management/analysis. Additional duties include management of human subject information, assisting in the reporting of information to funding institutions and Penn's Institutional Review Board (IRB), and lab scheduling. Opportunities may exist for some international travel, to collect data from children speaking languages other than English. Salary level depends on prior experience and is expected to be $27,000 to $30,000 plus full-time benefits. We hope to fill this position by January 2009. The University of Pennsylvania is an equal opportunity employer.</p>
<p>QUALIFICATIONS: A Bachelor's Degree in Psychology, Linguistics, Computer Science, or Cognitive Science is preferred. Experience is required in Microsoft Excel and statistical analysis software. Prior experience in psychology research is a plus.</p>
<p>HOW TO APPLY: All candidates for the position are required by Penn to apply directly through Penn's job posting board. Please go to <a href="http://www.hr.upenn.edu/jobs/" target="_self">http://www.hr.upenn.edu/jobs/</a> and click on open staff positions. You can search for the job posting using the following reference number:<br />081025859. You should submit your resume and a minimum of two reference contacts.</p>
<p>**********************************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">March 20, 2008</span><br /><strong>Join our Team! </strong><strong><em>CenterPointe is the choice of professionals!</em></strong><br />CenterPointe specializes in providing behavioral and mental healthcare services to children, adolescents and their families. As Idaho's premier mental healthcare facility, we actively search for top talent and professionals throughout the U.S. If you're a professional interested in making a difference in the lives of children, adolescents and their families, please familiarize yourself with our HR section and apply to join our team.</p>
<p>We are looking for energetic people with a bachelors degree in the human services field (psychology, social work, sociology, communications, etc.) that want to work with children with behavioral and emotional issues in the Boise, Idaho area. Please pass this onto anyone that may be interested in this position. I have include a link to our website for more information. <a href="http://centerpointeinc.com/professionals.html" target="_parent">http://centerpointeinc.com/professionals.html</a></p>
<p>Contact: <strong>Rick Thompson, LMSW, Director of Client Services<br />CenterPointe, Inc.<br />915 Park Centre Way, Suite 7<br />Nampa, ID 83651</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.centerpointeinc.com/" target="_parent">http://www.centerpointeinc.com/</a><br />(208) 442-7791<br />(208) 442-7792 Fax</strong><br />************************************************</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">March 11, 2008</span><br /><strong>Access Point Family Services is now hiring Developmental Therapists!!<br />Full and Part time positions available starting in April. Apply now!<br />Developmental Specialists:</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Developmental Therapy is a service that provides children with developmental disabilities the opportunity to develop life skills that will allow them to live as independent as possible. Access Point Family Services utilizes Applied Behavior Analysis (ABA) to teach these skills. Applied Behavior Analysis is the branch of Behaviorism that utilizes behavior laws in everyday settings to increase and/or decrease behaviors with humans. ABA is research based and is shown to be effective in teaching new behaviors, increasing current desired behaviors, decreasing current inappropriate behaviors, and is effective in making current behaviors more functional for humans.</p>
<p>All employees of Access Point Family Services receive training in Applied Behavior Analysis. If you are looking for an opportunity to increase your knowledge, trying to decide what realm of human services you would like to pursue for a career, or are just interested in working with children to help modify behavior and teach skills, then Access Point Family Services is the place for you. Developmental Therapy at Access Point Family Services is an entry level human services position that will allow you get exposure to behavior training and research. It is a great start to anyone wanting to pursue a career in education, OT, PT, Speech and Language Pathology, Psychology, Social Work, Counseling, and much more.</p>
<p><strong>Qualifications include:</strong></p>
<p>&middot; High School Diploma</p>
<p>&middot; Ability to pass a Health and Welfare background check</p>
<p>&middot; Valid Drivers License</p>
<p><strong>Compensation:</strong> Wage is negotiable dependent upon experience (usually 7-8 dollars per hour).</p>
<p>&middot; Vision and Dental insurance after 90 day probation period.</p>
<p>&middot; Training in Applied Behavior Analysis, Positive Behavioral Supports, Discrete Trial Training, and PECS. &middot; Experience in Human Service related work and corresponding professionals (Physicians, Clinical and School Psychologists, Social Workers, Counselors, Speech and Language Pathologists, Physical Therapists, Occupational Therapists, and Education Personnel).<br />Contact: Tamera @ 522-4026, Fax resumes to 522-4138<br />Accesspointkids.com</p>
<p>********************************</p>
<p>Dec 3, 2007<br />To Whom It May Concern:</p>
<p>We are currently looking for enthusiastic students that want to get a jump start on their career. We are currently looking for interns and hiring for Developmental therapists. There is no degree required but great experience for those going into the field. Developmental therapists will work with children ages 3-13 that have developmental delays, teaching them functional skills.<br />We are looking for part-time or full-time employees in our Idaho Falls office. We work around school schedules. Great for off track students or those needing a flexible schedule. For applications or questions please refer to our web page at <a href="http://www.accesspointkids.com/" target="_parent">http://www.accesspointkids.com/</a> or contact Stephanie or Jodi at 522-4026.</p>
<p>**********************************</p>
<p><strong>Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist<br /><em>Educational Requirements:</em></strong><br />Must be a graduate with bachelors of Psychology, Sociology, or Social work, or have education to work locally as a PSR (Psychosocial Rehabilitation) Specialist.</p>
<p><strong><em>Job Description:</em></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Working one on one with children with behavioral or emotional issues.</li>
<li>Teaching children how to cope with their mental issues.</li>
<li>Working on goals specified on a medically ordered plan of care.</li>
<li>Hours are flexible.</li>
<li>Full or part time.</li>
<li>Great Wage and Mileage Reimbursements.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><em>How do you apply?</em></strong>,</p>
<ul>
<li>Contact Child and Family Resource @ 356-4911 or</li>
<li>Fax resume to 356-5044 or</li>
<li>E-Mail <a href="mailto:reedcfr@aol.com" target="_parent">reedcfr@aol.com</a></li>
</ul>
<p>****************************************************</p>
<p><strong>March 2007 <br />Psychosocial Rehabilitation (PSR) Specialist in St. Anthony<br />Requirements:</strong><br />- Licensed Social Worker<br />OR<br />- bachelor's degree in behavioral science, education, or medicine with at least 21 credit hours in human service fields (psych, SW, special ed.)<strong><br /></strong>Send resumes/questions to Stacey Jones: <a href="mailto:pocketsj@gmail.com" target="_parent">pocketsj@gmail.com</a></p>
<p>*****************************************************</p>
<p align="left"><strong>Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist</strong><br />Position available for spring 2006</p>
<ul>
<li>Looking to hire a graduate in a social science field in the Spring of 2006 to work Full-time as a Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist (PSR Worker).</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The job would be working with clients who suffer from a severe and persistent mental illness such as schizophrenia and Bipolar Disorder. It would primarily be work in the Idaho Falls area.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Looking for someone who will fit in with their team. The company currently employs several BYUI graduates. Employees work in a team atmosphere which most employees find much more satisfying than a caseload of their own.</li>
</ul>
<p align="left"><strong>Anyone interested may contact Eric Olson at 360-0262. </strong></p>
<p align="left">*********************************************************</p>
<p align="left">The Children's Center in Ammon is offering a great opportunity for students wishing to go into therapy.<br />A position as a <strong>Developmental Therapy Tech </strong>will be available at the <em>end of June 2007</em>.&nbsp; No experience is needed.<br />Wage will be between $7.00 and $8.00 per hour.<br />Anyone interested should <em>contact</em><em> Julie Pond or Todd Adams at </em><strong>(208) 529-4300</strong> <em>beginning</em><em> </em><em>June 15th</em><em>.</em> <br />****************************************</p>
<p><strong>Psychosocial Rehabilitation Specialist</strong><br /><em><strong>Objective: </strong></em>To teach youth and their families life skills so they can be happier, healthy, and a positive part of their family. We accomplish this by working with both the youth and their family on building the skills the youth needs in order to succeed.</p>
<p><em><strong>Responsibilities:<br /></strong></em>1. Provide one-on-one time with an assigned youth on a weekly basis.</p>
<p>2. Work with family members, extended family members, school personnel, and other adults involved with the youth.</p>
<p>3. Participate in community based activities to teach the child hands-on life skills.</p>
<p>4. Follow the youth's service plan to reach the goals set for the youth.</p>
<p>5. Maintain progress notes on daily activities with the youth.</p>
<p>6. Meet with the youth's clinician to review their progress.</p>
<p>7. Make and return phone calls related to the youth as needed.</p>
<p>8. Complete reviews as necessary.</p>
<p>9. Complete 20 hours of professional development per year.</p>
<p><em><strong>Educational Requirements:</strong></em> Must hold a bachelor's degree in a human service field such as psychology, social work, or a related field. If an individual does not possess the above degrees, they may have twenty-one (21) college credit hours in human services; these credit hours must be approved by CenterPointe.<br /><em><strong>Hours:</strong></em> As arranged with assigned family<br /><em><strong>Pay</strong></em><em><strong> Range</strong></em><em><strong>:</strong></em> $14.00 - $18.00/DOE</p>
<p><strong>Benefits:</strong><strong> <br /></strong><strong><em>Offered to full-time employees (full-time is 30 hours or more per week) after 90 days of employment</em></strong></p>
<p>1. Medical and Dental Insurance.</p>
<p>2. Vacation after one year of employment (1 week after one year; 2 weeks after three years; and 3 weeks after five years).</p>
<p>3. Six major holidays off per year.</p>
<p><strong>How do you apply?<br /></strong><strong>If you are interested in applying for a position with </strong><strong>C</strong><strong>enter</strong><strong>P</strong><strong>ointe, please do one of the following:</strong></p>
<p>1. E-mail your resume and cover letter to <a href="mailto:humanresources@centerpointeinc.com" target="_parent">humanresources@centerpointeinc.com</a></p>
<p>2. Fax your resume and cover letter to 442-7792.</p>
<p>3. Mail your resume to CenterPointe, Inc. 915 Park Centre Way, Suite 7, Nampa ID 83651.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1848" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></CustomPageWithReturn>
