<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x42982" Name="Administrative Councils" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Administrative Councils</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Administrative Councils</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style type="text/css"><!--
#page{width:710px;}
  #page #content{width:78%;float:left;}
  #page #buttons{width: 18%; height: auto; min-height: 300px; float: left; padding: 1%; text-align: center;}

  #page #buttons .one,#page #buttons .two,
  #page #buttons .three{
  width: 100px; 
  height: 100px; 
  margin-left: auto; 
  margin-top: 10px; 
  margin-bottom: 10px;
  display:block;
  }
  #page #buttons .one{background-image: url('Images/student-support/SRC/Graphics/src-sprite.gif');background-position:0 100px;}
  #page #buttons .two{background-image: url('Images/student-support/SRC/Graphics/src-sprite.gif');background-position:0 304px;}
  #page #buttons .three{background-image: url('Images/student-support/SRC/Graphics/src-sprite.gif');background-position:0 510px;}


  #page #buttons .one:hover{background-image: url('Images/student-support/SRC/Graphics/src-sprite.gif'); background-position:0 202px;}
  #page #buttons .two:hover{background-image: url('Images/student-support/SRC/Graphics/src-sprite.gif');background-position:0 407px;}
  #page #buttons .three:hover{background-image: url('Images/student-support/SRC/Graphics/src-sprite.gif');background-position:0 612px;}
  #page #buttons .live_chat{
  margin-left:27px;
  padding:10px 15px;

  background-color:#D21F22;
  text-decoration:none;
  color:#fff;
  border-radius:4px;
  font-family:sans-serif;
  font-weight:bold;
  }
  #page #buttons .live_chat:hover{
  background-color:#842325;
  }
--></style>
<div id="page">
<h1><img alt="Student Representative Council" src="Images/student-support/SRC/Ambassadors_header.png" /></h1>
<div id="content">
<h1>Administrative Councils Area</h1>
<p>SRC represents student concerns by sitting on over 20 different administrative councils. University Leaders attend these councils to discuss and make decisions that affect BYU-Idaho. SRC Council Representatives that sit on each council ask questions and bring a student perspective to ensure all decisions are made in the best interests of the Student Body.</p>
<p>Two council coordinators oversee and provide training to Council Representatives to make sure each council is attended and student concerns are properly represented.</p>
<h2>Councils</h2>
<p>Currently the SRC sits and represents students on the following councils. If you have any input that you feel would benefit students if shared in one of these councils, please let us know by emailing us at src@byui.edu.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Academics Council</td>
<td>Deals with issues and information regarding academic policies that affect the student population as a whole. It is also an informative meeting to ensure that all of those sitting on the council are aware of specific policies, updated on developments with I-Learn, etc.​</td>
</tr>
<!--
        <tr>
          <td>BYU-Idaho Wellness Council</td>
          <td></td>
        </tr>
-->
<tr>
<td>Campus Planning</td>
<td>Discusses the 10-year plan of upcoming construction projects on the BYU-Idaho campus, as well as minor remodel and landscaping projects in progress, as well as needs of facilities such as furniture in various locations of the campus. Asseses the most efficient way to allocate the resources that the church has alotted to BYU-Idaho for various upkeep and upgrade needs.​</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>City Issues Coordinating Council</td>
<td>Disseminates information and coordinates the actions of the individual campus departments as they relate to the City of Rexburg.&nbsp; It does not make policy, nor have line authority over those on the council. A student representative is always welcome.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Communications Council</td>
<td>BYU-Idaho's Communication Council was organized by President's Council to better meet the need for unity and quality in institutional communication. The council oversees materials intended for official BYU-Idaho marks or identity elements. This includes internal and external institutional communication originating from all areas and organizations on campus.<br />The council operates under the guidance of President's Council and provides direction according to established university policies. The council may also review, provide input on, and develop communication policy for the entire campus.<br />Communication projects, strategies, and plans will be brought to Communication Council by its members for approval before the project is taken into production. Communication Council members have authority to approve projects that are based upon approved templates.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Computer Technology Council</td>
<td>The Computer Technology Council helps the University make technology-related policy decisions. The council reviews technology issues and special requests for technology and makes decisions. It also helps with IT strategies and major IT decisions.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Curriculum Council</td>
<td>Advises, supports, and represents the Academic Vice President in matters of learning, teaching, and curriculum; including, but not limited to, approval and oversight of programs and courses, grade rules, examination policy, catalog content, limited enrollment policies, curriculum policy and procedure, and the improvement of teaching and learning through periodic review of program and course objectives, expected learning outcomes, teaching strategies, and assessment.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Enrollment Services Council</td>
<td>The purpose of this council is to make sure that each student is getting what they need and to expand more to reach out to others. Ideas are brought about what they can do to better serve the students needs and to help them toward their majors, and further, their careers, and graduation.</td>
</tr>
<!--
        <tr>
          <td>Events Service Board</td>
          <td></td>
        </tr>
--> <!--
        <tr>
          <td>Financial Services Council&nbsp;</td>
          <td></td>
        </tr>
--> <!--
        <tr>
          <td>Financial Services Management Group</td>
          <td></td>
        </tr>
--> <!--
        <tr>
          <td>First Year Experience Council</td>
          <td></td>
        </tr>
-->
<tr>
<td>Food Services Student Board of Directors</td>
<td>The Food Services Student Board of Directors is a group of students who represent the student body in collaboration with University Food Services; thereby helping University Food Services match the diverse food service needs on our campus. The Board will play a key role in voicing the concerns and desires of students, and the University in general to Food Services.&nbsp; It will help Food Services fulfill student needs, creating a beneficial partnership.</td>
</tr>
<!--
        <tr>
          <td>Honor Advisory Council</td>
          <td></td>
        </tr>
-->
<tr>
<td>Improving the Quality of Student Services Task Force</td>
<td>To work on processes, practices, and procedures in all areas of campus to improve the quality of student services.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Learning Model Advisory Board</td>
<td>To help students better understand the learning model and help make it more useful to students.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>MC Usage Taskforce</td>
<td>Created by President's council to revise the policies on the utilization of the Manwaring building as a student center.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Parking Council</td>
<td>Discusses the needs of single and married students as well as employees and their families, and visitors, in regards to parking issues. Addresses parking concerns and oversees signage, parking tag policies etc.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>President's Council</td>
<td>Discusses future goals of the University and makes major or final decisions on issues that affect BYU-Idaho. This is attended by the Student Body President.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Student Well-Being Council</td>
<td>The council functions to be proactive in the needs of&nbsp; high risk students, and the campus community in their overall well being.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>University Council</td>
<td>Consists of approximately 65 key administrators from across the campus.&nbsp; Typically, the meeting is help once a month.&nbsp; The purpose is to share information about key initiatives under way at the university and for those with responsibility for those initiatives to seek counsel/direction/input from those who attend--a two-way communication process.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Web Strategy Council</td>
<td>This new council is being organized and charged with the responsibility of defining and overseeing a web strategy that articulates how BYU-Idaho will use standard, portal, and mobile technologies for academic, administrative, and communication purposes. The strategies developed by the new council should define how these technologies can be used effectively to serve students, faculty, and employees of the university.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Women's Advisory Council</td>
<td>Council meets monthly to discuss issues on-campus, in education, and in society that impact female students and their experience at BYU-Idaho.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Special Councils</h2>
<p>SRC also sits on the following councils that deal with specific academic student petitions.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Academic Exceptions Council</td>
<td>Approves/denies academic exception petitions from students (if there are petitions to be reviewed). Its membership and the items discussed in each meeting are confidential.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Academic Standard Council</td>
<td>To determine if a student, who is appealing to lift their academic suspension, has a reasonable cause or extenuating circumstance that would move us to lift their suspension.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<!-- <div id="buttons"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick Links: </strong> <a class="one" href="x36938.xml"></a> <a class="two" href="x36275.xml"></a> <a class="three" href="x37055.xml"></a>
<p style="margin-top: -34px;">&nbsp;</p>
<a class="live_chat" href="https://server.iad.liveperson.net/hc/1132447/?cmd=file&amp;file=visitorWantsToChat&amp;site=1132447&amp;byhref=1&amp;SESSIONVAR!skill=Student%20Support">Live Chat</a></div>
</div> -->
<p>
<script type="text/javascript">
var _gaq = _gaq || [];
      _gaq.push(['_setAccount', 'UA-33977325-1']);
      _gaq.push(['_trackPageview']);

      (function() {
        var ga = document.createElement('script'); ga.type = 'text/javascript'; ga.async = true;
        ga.src = ('https:' == document.location.protocol ? 'https://ssl' : 'http://www') + '.google-analytics.com/ga.js';
        var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(ga, s);
      })();
</script>
</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x36320" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x36315" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
