<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x43096" Name="SCOTs Program" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">SCOTs Program</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">SCOTs Program</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">SCOTs Program</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">SCOTs, Student Consults on Teaching, SCOT</MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><img height="1362" src="Images/instructional-development/SCOTs/Scot's.1_Page_1.jpg" style="float: right;" width="363" />To all faculty,</p>
<p><strong><em>We now have a small corps of students trained to help you gather data on your classroom activities. They are not experts on teaching, nor do they evaluate any aspect of your teaching. They can, however, give feedback from a student perspective or help you gain insight into aspects of your course by collecting data for you. You can, of course, direct the SCOT (Student Consult on Teaching) on what type of feedback would be most useful to you. No one else is in this loop -- just you and the student consultant. The entire process is instructor defined and driven.</em></strong> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>HERE'S HOW IT <strong>WORKS:</strong></p>
<p><em>The SCOTs have been trained to play one of several roles, according to your desires, each of which is descriptive rather than evaluative.</em></p>
<p><strong>Recorder/Observe<br /></strong>They sit in on your class and take notes about the process. They then provide you with a written report of what went on during the class, how much time was spent in various activities, who participated, what kinds and how many questions were asked, etc.</p>
<p><strong>Faux Student<br /></strong>The student consultant takes notes as if s/he were a student in the class and then gives these notes to you.</p>
<p><strong>Filmmaker<br /></strong>The student unobtrusively films the class, creating a DVD for you to review. You may invite the student to view and discuss the video with you or you may simply review it yourself.</p>
<p><strong>Interviewer<br /></strong>You leave the room for the last 15 minutes of a class while the SCOT interviews and surveys the students about their learning and their perceptions of the course. The student consultant then provides you with a written report of their findings.</p>
<p><strong>Focus Group<br /></strong>The SCOT organizes a group of your students outside of class to participate in a more in-depth interview/survey. They then generate a written report and meet with you to discuss their findings.</p>
<p><strong>Primed Student<br /></strong>The student consultant meets with you before a class for pointers on what you want them to watch for when they sit in on the class. For example: Why aren't more students participating in the discussion? Or: How effective are my follow up questions?</p>
<p><strong>BrainHoney<br /></strong>The student consultants can connect you with the right resources to help with your BrainHoney questions, from simple how-to's to complete site revamps.</p>
<p><strong>Other<br /></strong>You are welcome to request a SCOT for any activity that you feel will help you better understand the dynamics in your classroom or around your teaching. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>To request a Student Consultant, simply email Devan Barker at <em>barkerde@byui.edu</em>.</p>
<p>Please include the name of the course as well as the meeting time and place for the class. He will assign a Student Consultant. You're also welcome to request a specific student to work with you. The student will contact you to discuss your expectations and desires. They will then carry out your desired activity. Afterward, they will write up a report or meet with you to discuss their findings according to the service you've had them perform. While professional development training can be helpful, it can be difficult to apply back to your teaching.</p>
<p>Yours,</p>
<p>Devan Barker <br />Director of Instructional Development BYU-Idaho &nbsp;</p>
<p><em>The number of trained student consults is currently somewhat limited, so please respond soon to schedule a student consultant.&nbsp;</em><em>The following three-minute video shows some BYU-Idaho faculty talking about their experience with the SCOT program.</em></p>
<p><em><a href="http://bcove.me/p2o7qpqf"><img height="268" src="Images/instructional-development/SCOTs/Wide Screen BYU-I Video.png" width="478" /></a> </em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35239" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
