<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x43157" Name="Biennial Drug &amp; Alcohol Report" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Biennial Drug &amp; Alcohol Report</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Biennial Drug &amp; Alcohol Report</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: center;"></h3>
<p align="center"><strong>BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY-IDAHO</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>BIENNIAL REPORT OF</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>INSTITUTIONAL COMPLIANCE WITH THE</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>DRUG-FREE SCHOOLS AND CAMPUSES ACT</strong></p>
<p align="center"><em><strong>Period of Review: January 2011 - December 2012</strong></em></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center">&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center"><strong>COMMITTEE MEMBERS</strong></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<ul>
<li>Wynn Hill, Chair and Managing Director of Well-Being, Dean of Students Office</li>
<li>Reed Stoddard, Director of Counseling Center</li>
<li>Garth Gunderson, Director of University Security</li>
<li>Kevin Price, Director of Human Resources</li>
<li>Shaun Orr, Director of Student Health Center</li>
<li>Kristie Lords, Director of Student Honor Office</li>
<li>Jameson Rammell, BYU-Idaho Student</li>
<li>Derek Fay, Managing Director of Activities</li>
<li>Troy Dougherty, Director of Housing &amp; Student Living</li>
<li>Dave Thomas, General Counsel</li>
<li>Cheryl Calderwood, Office Assistant/Dean of Students Office<br />&nbsp;<br /><br /></li>
</ul>
<p align="center"><strong>GENERAL STATEMENT</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Brigham Young University-Idaho is affiliated with The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and is deeply committed to high standards of moral conduct and personal living as reflected by its Mission Statement.&nbsp; This personal commitment is rooted in Board of Trustees policy which requires that every student, faculty, staff and administrator sign a commitment to the Honor Code prior to admission or employment and to update the commitment on an annual basis in order to maintain their eligibility to continue at the institution in their employment or student status.&nbsp; Each member of the campus community is expected to abide by their commitment at all times and in all places and to work together in an effort to lift one another and encourage obedience and compliance with the provisions of their commitment. <br /><strong><br />&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>BYU-IDAHO DRUG POLICY</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The campus community embraces the scriptural injunction that "the worth of souls is great in the sight of God.<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title="">[1]</a><sup>"&nbsp; </sup>This principle has root in the Word of Wisdom<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2" title="">[2]</a> which is God's law of health provided to man in the latter days to promote a healthy life style by shunning those things which are addictive, habit forming, and mind altering or harmful to the body.&nbsp; Each year both students and employees have an endorsement interview with their respective ecclesiastical leader. Questions regarding the drug and alcohol policy are standard for students. Students are asked if they, "live the Word of Wisdom by abstaining from alcoholic beverages, tobacco, coffee, tea and other harmful <a>substances</a><a href="#_msocom_1" id="_anchor_1" name="_msoanchor_1">[t1]</a>&nbsp;."<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title="">[3]</a> Because of the serious nature and consequence of inappropriate substance involvement, it is important that all members of the university community understand the drug and alcohol policy. <br />&nbsp;<br /><br /></p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="file:///C:/Users/sarahjv/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/XP156OTW/BYU-I%20Biennial%20Drug%20Free%20Schools%20Report%20with%20title%20page.docx#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title="">[1]</a>&nbsp; Doctrine &amp; Covenants section 18 verse 10.<br /><br /><a href="file:///C:/Users/sarahjv/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/XP156OTW/BYU-I%20Biennial%20Drug%20Free%20Schools%20Report%20with%20title%20page.docx#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2" title="">[2]</a>&nbsp; Doctrine &amp; Covenants section 89. &nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="file:///C:/Users/sarahjv/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/XP156OTW/BYU-I%20Biennial%20Drug%20Free%20Schools%20Report%20with%20title%20page.docx#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3" title="">[3]</a> BYU-Idaho Catalog 2011-2012</p>
<p></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp; BYU-Idaho Drug-Free School Policy</strong></p>
<p>It is the policy<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title="">[4]</a> of the Board of Trustees of BYU-Idaho that as a condition of employment or enrollment all employees and students, regardless of the length of a student's program of study, completely abstain, whether on or off campus, from the possession, use, or distribution of any illegal drug or alcohol and to also abstain from the use of any controlled legal substance, without specific medical authorization, that may be harmful to or have adverse effects on the body.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The university interprets the Board of Trustees' directive as including (1) the use of illegal substances such as marijuana, cocaine, etc., (2) the intentional misuse of prescription medications, (3) the possession of illegal drugs or drug paraphernalia for use or distribution, and (4) the involvement or association with other persons in substance or alcohol use without taking deterrent action.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The university's Board of Trustees has also directed that involvement with illicit drugs will result in immediate termination of employment or suspension from the university on the first offense, except in those circumstances where the only contact with the drug was limited or brief and casual and where the employee or student has repented before disciplinary action has begun. When&nbsp; it is determined that an individual's contact with the abuse of a substance was brief or casual and where the exposure to the behavior has been decisively abandoned prior to disciplinary action being instituted, then the individual may be allowed to remain employed or enrolled at the institution on a strict disciplinary sanction. The repentance provision of board policy is interpreted as requiring confession to an appropriate ecclesiastical authority and/or requesting assistance from the BYU-Idaho Counseling Center prior to public discovery, knowledge, arrest, or initial action being taken by the university.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration recognizes there are differences between the intentional misuses of illicit and prescription drugs and the unintentional misuse of prescription drugs prescribed for medical reasons. Those individuals involved in the unintentional misuse of prescription drugs will not normally be subject to disciplinary sanctions, but rather are encouraged to seek assistance from the Counseling Center, private counseling, therapy or rehabilitation through a licensed approved program.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are substantial legal sanctions pursuant to local, state or federal law which may be levied against an individual for the unlawful use, possession, distribution or manufacturing of an illicit drug or controlled substance. Likewise criminal law prescribes penalties for a minor who possesses or uses alcohol and further defines substantial penalties for adults who dispose or provide alcohol for use by minors.&nbsp; The law often treats drug offenses as a criminal matter punishable by substantial fines, imprisonment or other severe sanctions.&nbsp; The Student Honor Office may make their own investigation of any student who is reported or found to be in violation of this policy and take appropriate disciplinary action, including separation from the university, regardless of any criminal court action. The Human Resources Office acting with or for the employing department may make their own investigation of any employee who is reported or found to be in violation of this policy and take appropriate disciplinary action, including termination from employment, regardless of any criminal court action.&nbsp; A student or employee may make contact with the Counseling Center and request assistance with their alcohol or substance problem.&nbsp; This contact would allow them to receive help under the auspices of that office. A description of the applicable legal penalties under local, state or federal law for the unlawful possession or distribution of illegal drugs and alcohol is provided via the campus <br /><br /> E-mail system directing them to the appropriate web site where the report may be found. In addition, paper copies are available for and individual desiring or requesting a copy of the information.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The health risks associated with the inappropriate use of drugs include, but are not limited to, physical and psychological addiction, physical, psychological and spiritual deterioration, disease and death.&nbsp; <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The university supports participation in programs for the prevention of the inappropriate use of illicit drugs, controlled substances and tobacco or alcohol abuse.&nbsp; The BYU-Idaho Counseling Center provides confidential assistance with drug and alcohol abuse problems.&nbsp; Assistance is available in the form of educational training programs, health information and preliminary evaluation and counseling for possible referral for outside medical assistance. Individuals may get more information about, or enter the university program through the Counseling Center located in the Student Health and Counseling Center or by calling 496-9371.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By providing this explanation of board policy, the university hopes to encourage elimination of all forms of substance abuse, to help those who currently may be involved to stop such use and get appropriate help, and to assist in stopping the spread of this behavior at our institution and in society.<br /><br /></p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="file:///C:/Users/sarahjv/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/XP156OTW/BYU-I%20Biennial%20Drug%20Free%20Schools%20Report%20with%20title%20page.docx#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title="">[4]</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; Annual Campus Security Report and Drug Policy Brigham Young University-Idaho, 2012, page 8.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>EVALUATION OF CURRENT PROGRAMS</strong></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"><strong>General</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> All university employees and specifically student personnel professionals provide input in campus programs directed at alcohol and other substance abuse. A wide range of expertise can be found on the campus in health care professionals, health care educators, licensed counselors, security personnel, students, administrative personnel, and ecclesiastical leaders. The university has chosen to make use of many of these professionals and volunteers in planning, implementing, evaluating, and leadership students plan and implement programs directed at encouraging the campus community a whole in abstinence from the use of alcohol or drugs and advocating commitment and adherence to a higher standard of personal conduct through a strong personal commitment to a compliance with the Board of Trustees Drug Policy.<br /><strong><br /> </strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong style="text-align: center;">Church Affiliation</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; The unique affiliation of BYU-Idaho with The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints provides each student with an ecclesiastical leader who oversees approximately 170-200 students within a ward (church unit) established for students, either single or married dependent on their marital status. These 122 bishoprics (three men) are members of the local communities and donate their time when they are called and assigned to assist and work with these students. These ecclesiastical leaders are very well grounded in Church protocol, gospel principle and Church and university policy. They work directly in a one to one setting with students and are very helpful in referring students who need assistance in resolving alcohol or other drug related problems to appropriate helping sources within the university.&nbsp; These leaders may also make use of community resources which may be available. It is not incumbent on ecclesiastical leaders to report to university officials' disclosures made to them by students of substance or alcohol use/abuse because of the priest/parishioner confidential relationship between the bishop and the students. Each ecclesiastical unit (stake) is assigned an advisor from the Counseling Center to assist in providing consultation and direction for ecclesiastical leaders whose members may suffer from alcohol or drug related issues.<br /><br /> <strong><br /></strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>University Programs</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; The following provides information about university departments directly involved in working with students and the programs and measures implemented throughout the university to prevent the use of alcohol or illicit substance use/misuse. The data and charts included show a summary of drug and alcohol contacts reported to or by university administrators in each area specified during the review period. Where possible; comparative figures are provided in the Comparative Assessment section in an effort to assist student personnel administrators in evaluating successes or weaknesses in programs. <br /><strong><br /><br /></strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Athletics/Activities</strong></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; </strong> On June 21, 2000 the Chairman of the Board of Trustees of Ricks College, Gordon B. Hinckley, announced that Ricks College would become a four year institution and that the name would be changed to BYU-Idaho. At the same time, President Hinckley announced that all athletic programs would be phased out and that Intercollegiate Athletics would be eliminated on the completion of all current conference contracts. By the start of the fall semester 2002 all intercollegiate athletic competition had ended.<br /><br /> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br /><br /> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong>Since the elimination of intercollegiate competition at BYU-Idaho the activities program has been enhanced and expanded to include areas such as Outdoor Activities, Fitness Activities, Social Activities, Sports Activities and Talent Activities. The organizational structure is such that programming in all of the areas is operated by student volunteers with full-time employees acting as advisors.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because of a unique peer-to-peer teaching and leadership relationship between students, there is a strong culture among students that fosters encouragement and strengthening of the commitment to university Honor Code standards. Emphasis is placed on keeping gospel and university commitments, creating a strong preventative position with regard to alcohol and drug use. Advisors are also instructed regarding the proper resources available and actions necessary if they encounter students who are at risk in various ways, including those who are in violation of university standards regarding drug and alcohol use.<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<p></p>
<p align="center"><strong>University Security</strong></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; </strong>The University Security Department, are paid university employees. University Security reports to the University Resource Vice-President. The Director of Security is also a member of the Security Council and the Well-Being Council. Security has eight well trained officers, a 24/7 dispatch center and about fifty part-time student employees. The university contributes resources to the City of Rexburg Police Department to provide for police officers that can patrol and respond in a timely manner to incidents on campus. Security and Rexburg police work closely on substance abuse cases.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the course of a year, arrests for alcohol and/or other substance use or possession violations may be made by police officers of visitors who are not affiliated or associated with the university or who are not participating in any university function. These persons generally are pedestrians passing directly through the campus or drivers driving on the periphery of campus and found to be in violation of an alcohol or other substance use/possession law. For comparative purposes the statistics shown reflect all arrests made on the campus for drug or alcohol use or misuse. Individuals arrested on campus who are not affiliated with the campus are included in the statistics and are included, as are all campus arrests, in the total arrests made within the city. <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Liquor law violations include offenses such as minor consumption, disposal to a minor, open container and similar offenses.<strong><br /><br /> </strong></p>
<p></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td rowspan="3" valign="bottom" width="186"><strong>Type Incident&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong><br /><br /> Drugs&nbsp; <br /><br /> Liquor Law Violations<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="78"><strong>2011</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="78"><strong>2012</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84"><strong>Totals</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="78">6<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="78">6<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84">12<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="78">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="78">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84">5<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Counseling Center</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the goals of the BYU-Idaho Counseling Center is to help students maintain balance in their lives by identifying and resolving emotional problems which interfere with effective spiritual, intellectual, social, or physical well-being.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Counseling Center is well staffed and professionally qualified in dealing with the treatment of alcohol and other drug problems or addictions. Students generally seek counseling on their own, but in some instances are referred to the Counseling Center by a member of the university community or a peer or they may seek assistance for a roommate or friend. Student service professionals such as Housing &amp; Student Living administrators, members of the Student Honor Office staff, health care professionals, health care educators and other university staff, faculty, and administrative employees refer students to the Counseling Center for assistance with these types of problems.<br /><br /></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width: 464px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="272"><strong>DRUG AND ALCOHOL CASES&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>2011</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>2012</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84"><strong>TOTALS</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="272">Referrals or request for counseling for alcohol use&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84">10<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="272">Referrals or request for counseling for drug use<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84">7<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="272">Referred to outside treatment programs<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84">0<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="272">TOTALS<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">8<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">9<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="84">17<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Student Honor Office</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Student Honor office is responsible for the disciplinary action of students who violate their commitment to the Honor Code. The Student Honor office investigates all reports<br />of alcohol and substance use to determine if disciplinary action is appropriate.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the 2011 and 2012 reporting period the Student Honor office investigated and adjudicated students who were found to be in violation of the university's alcohol and substance abuse policy. The following table shows the number of students who were adjudicated for alcohol or substance use during the reporting period.<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="198">&nbsp;<br /><br /></td>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" width="138">Alcohol<br /><br /></td>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" width="126">Other Substances<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">&nbsp;<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="198"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72"><strong>2011</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66"><strong>2012</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66"><strong>2011</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60"><strong>2012</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72"><strong>TOTAL</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="198">Disciplinary sanction<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">11<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="198">Suspended<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">33<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66">34<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66">18<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60">23<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">108<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="198">TOTALS<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">37<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66">36<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="66">22<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60">24<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="72">119<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>Financial Aid</strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; In general, a student who has been convicted of any offense under any federal or state law involving the possession or sale of a controlled substance <em>will not</em> be eligible to receive any grant, loan, or work assistance under this applicable federal law during the period beginning on the date of such conviction and ending after the interval specified in the following table:<br /><br /></p>
<p align="center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">&nbsp;</span></strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Student Ineligibility for Grants, Loans, or Work Assistance</span></strong></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" width="319">For <em>possession</em> of a controlled <br /><br /> Substance, ineligibility period is:<br /><br /></td>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" width="319">For <em>Sale</em> of a controlled substance,<br /><br /> Ineligibility period is:<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="199">First conviction<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="120">1 year<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="204">First conviction <br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="115">2 years<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="199">Second conviction <br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="120">2 years<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="204">Second conviction<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="115">Indefinite<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="199">Third conviction<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="120">Indefinite<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="204">&nbsp;<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="115">&nbsp;<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Health Center</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The BYU-Idaho Health Center provides full services designed to assist students with Day-to-day health care needs. The Health Center is staffed by two full-time physicians, three nurse practitioners, one physician assistant, registered nurses, registered lab and X-ray technicians, and a full-time registered pharmacist. These health care professionals are cognizant of the potential for substance abuse among the student population. The Health Center staff monitors very closely those with whom they work and the prescriptions they are issued. In addition, care is taken to ensure that prescription pads are kept on the doctor's person to prevent them from being stolen and forged. The pharmacy is secured in an enclosed area with an alarm system and walls and the ceiling are designed and reinforced to prevent intrusion. <br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>Housing &amp; Student Living Office</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Housing &amp; Student Living Office provides listings of housing options for BYU-Idaho students, offers mediation services to address student/landlord disputes, and provides specialized training for landlords, managers, and student leaders. An integral part of this training includes an emphasis on students creating an environment in which they take responsibility for themselves, roommates, and the overall culture throughout the apartment complex. <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> Single students are required to live in a BYU-Idaho "approved" housing property. This means that specific guidelines must be met by the apartment complex in the interest of student safety and well-being. This also means that the ownership and management of the complex are committed to upholding the tenets of the BYU-Idaho Honor Code. In particular, all approved housing complexes have a commitment with the University and with the students to maintain the agreement of abstinence from tobacco, alcohol, and/or substance abuse by residents as outlined in the BYU-Idaho Honor Code. Not only are students required to live the Honor Code but all on-site managers are as well.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Both managers and roommates are encouraged to assist all students to abide by the Honor Code and live lives of honor and integrity. When students do not respond to that encouragement, a referral to the Student Honor Office may be appropriately made. <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; University policy provides that when drug use is suspected in a housing complex the matter be referred to the local police. Incidents involving alcohol use are also referred to the police if any participants are under age. Additionally, violation involving drug and alcohol abuse are referred to the BYU-Idaho Student Honor Office by housing management at the complex in which the incident occurred.<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Human Resources Office</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Human Resources Office serves as a resource to campus employees in helping employees to maintain their commitment to the Honor Code. The Board of Trustees has established an ecclesiastical endorsement program requiring that each employee be endorsed annually by his ecclesiastical leader to ensure that employee conduct is in accordance with the values and standards espoused by The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. This endorsement includes a personal commitment to refrain from alcohol or other drug use at all times.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; BYU-Idaho implemented a Commercial Vehicle Drivers Drug and Alcohol Testing program in November 1997 in compliance with the regulations implementing the Omnibus Transportation Employee Testing Act of 1991. BYU-Idaho has a contract with <em>Minert &amp; Associates Inc.</em> from Meridian, Idaho, an independent company who coordinates the alcohol and drug testing according to the federal regulations. As of this report, all tests have come back negative.<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; The Human Resources Office provides Internet access to the BYU-Idaho "Campus Security Report and Drug Policy" through its website for employees to access at any time. A statement on how to access this information is explained on the employment website for perspective employees. All newly hired employees receive orientation materials which refer to this policy and tell them how to access the information. Annually, in conjunction with the Student Honor Office the Human Resources Office provides to each employee, both full and part-time, either by e-mail or regular mail, or campus mail the university annual report entitled "Campus Security Report, Drug Policy." The pamphlet reiterates the Church, Board of Trustees, and university policy regarding alcohol and other drug use and the resources available for help.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the reporting period, the Human Resources office had one employee voluntarily report an alcohol problem. The employee chose to terminate employment. There was no awareness of any other alcohol or drug problems among full or part-time employees.<br /><br /><br /></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>COMPARATIVE ASSESSMENT</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; BYU-Idaho has accumulated twenty years of data dealing with reported alcohol or substance use by students and employees. This information provides an opportunity for the administration to look at the long term reported violations of the institution's drug policy and ascertain what changes, if any, should be made in the institutional approach to this problem. A direct comparison of statistics gathered since 2001 (since the inception of BYU-Idaho as a four year university) is provided to gain an overall comparison of the effectiveness of programs adopted by BYU-Idaho in an effort to prevent or assist members of the campus community who may have difficulty in keeping their personal commitment relative to the Board of Trustees' policy regarding abstinence from alcohol and other drug use. Where applicable, comments are made by way of possible explanation in an effort to gain understanding in differences. <br /><br /><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>University Security</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At BYU-Idaho, students arrested for driving under the influence of alcohol are generally underage individuals. Students arrested for minor in possession or minor consuming alcohol and those arrested for DUI are often found to be first-time or occasional users of alcohol. Those arrested or reported by police are subject to disciplinary sanction by the university and as a result, either quit drinking and renew their personal commitment to the Honor Code or are extremely careful in their use of alcohol so as to not get caught. Many times these individuals will drink in areas removed from the campus where it is less likely that they will be caught or reported. However, some students are arrested in neighboring states and communities and the information filters back to the campus through a variety of means. If the university becomes aware of this the Student Honor Office will investigate the report and take appropriate action. No statistics are available in this regard even though some students may end up being arrested or cited for alcohol violations as they are included in statistics kept by the Student Honor Office, but not included in local police statistics.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Other drug use arrests are usually the result of reports to the police of "someone smoking marijuana" in one of the on-campus dormitories or other students reporting use of drugs by roommates or peers. An immediate follow-up investigation usually results in the arrest of the offender(s), criminal charges are filed, and disciplinary sanctions are imposed by the Student Honor Office. Criminal charges are not necessary in order for disciplinary action to be pursued through the Student Honor Office. A cooperative effort between the police, prosecutor, and the Student Honor Office results in a higher degree of student accountability for their behavior.<br /><br /></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="121"><strong>OFFENSE TYPE</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60"><strong>97-98</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>99-00</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>01-02</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>03-04</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>05-06</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>07-08</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>09-10</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54"><strong>11-12</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="121">Alcohol<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60">6<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">5<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="121">Other Drugs<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">7<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">12<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="121">TOTALS<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="60">9<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">7<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="54">17<a name="_GoBack"></a><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Counseling Center</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Referrals to the Counseling Center for alcohol or substance abuse usually are initiated by the student themselves, an ecclesiastical leader, a roommate or friend, or a parent seeking help for their child.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The number of students seeking help for alcohol or illegal substance use problems through the Counseling Center is relatively low and may be attributed to (1) the church's health code which prohibits the use of alcohol or illicit drugs, and (2) ecclesiastical leaders who are available to provide help to students and (3) a fear that if they discuss their problem with any representative of the institution it will be disclosed and they will be dismissed. In addition, some students may assume that no assistance is offered because of the strong prohibition on alcohol and substance abuse.<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width: 643px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="163"><strong>ALCOHOL AND OTHER</strong><br /><br /> <strong>DRUG CASES</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>93-94</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>95-96</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>97-98</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>99-00</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>01-02</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>03-04</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>05-06</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>07-08</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="46"><strong>09-10</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="50"><strong>11-12</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="163">Referrals or request for <br /><br /> counseling for alcohol use<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">8<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">11<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">12<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">10<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">8<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">20<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="46">15<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="50">10<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="163">Referrals or requests for <br /><br /> counseling for drug use<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">6<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">8<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">9<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">10<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">10<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="46">9<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="50">7<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="163">Referrals to outside<br /><br /> treatment programs<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48"><strong>0</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="46">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="50">0<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="163">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; TOTALS<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">10<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">17<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">16<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">21<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">20<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">13<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="48">30<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="46">24<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="50">17<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Student Honor Office</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Referrals to the Student Honor Office for violations of the Honor Code come from a variety of sources including housing, peers, roommates, local community businesses, or local citizens. The disparity between individuals referred from year to year is very evident in reviewing the statistical information. Students who drink alcohol or become involved in substance abuse at BYU-Idaho place their student status in jeopardy. A single violation may be grounds for suspension from the university. There is always a concern of the number of students who may have an alcohol or substance abuse problem that goes unreported and undetected.<br /><br /><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>Alcohol</strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185"><strong>Action Taken</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56"><strong>96-98</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61"><strong>99-00</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61"><strong>01-02</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56"><strong>03-04</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56"><strong>05-06</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57"><strong>07-08</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53"><strong>09-10</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53"><strong>11-12</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Cleared or no action<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">8<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">0<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Counsel &amp; Education<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">3<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Disciplinary Sanction<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">18<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">23<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">12<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">12<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">14<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">6<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">2<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Suspension<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">16<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">10<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">21<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">19<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">37<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">33<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">38<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">68<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185"><strong>Totals</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">37<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">39<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">44<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">35<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">52<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">36<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">44<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">73<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Other Substances</strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185"><strong>Action Taken</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56"><strong>96-98</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61"><strong>99-00</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61"><strong>01-02</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56"><strong>03-04</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56"><strong>05-06</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57"><strong>07-08</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53"><strong>09-10</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53"><strong>11-12</strong><br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Cleared or no action<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">0<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Counsel &amp; Education<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">0<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">2<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Disciplinary Sanction<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">1<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">5<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">4<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">2<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">3<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">3<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185">Suspension<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">20<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">19<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">11<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">14<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">26<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">7<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">34<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">41<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="185"><strong>Totals</strong><br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">24<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">23<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="61">21<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">21<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="56">28<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="57">9<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">37<br /><br /></td>
<td valign="top" width="53">46<br /><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>Drug and Alcohol Surveys</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To help with the evaluation process and to complete one of the goals from the previous Biennial Review, a Drug and Alcohol Student Survey was completed December of 2012. The survey was similar to one that was done in the Winter Semester of 2011. &nbsp;328 students responded to the survey, 39% male and 61% female. A fairly even mix of classes responded (28% freshman, 21% sophomore, 24% junior and 27% senior). Also, it is interesting to note that 26% of the students that responded are married. This is consistent with the general student body at BYU-Idaho.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The large majority of BYU-Idaho student indicate high levels of knowledge about the school's rules and regulations regarding drugs (89%) and virtually all students have a high level of knowledge about the health risks associated with their use (95%). On the other hand, the majority of students indicate low levels of knowledge about drug counseling programs available on campus (48%). This is likely because they simply don't use drugs and alcohol in the first place.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Virtually all students expressed a willingness to help friends with a problem (95%). Students admitted to very little use (3% alcohol, 1% marijuana and 3% prescription drugs) of illicit drugs or alcohol over the past year, and also the last 30 days. In fact no one reported any use of LSD, cocaine, methamphetamines, steroids, smokeless tobacco and spice or synthetic products. &nbsp;Students report a far greater abuse of drugs and alcohol by others than they do for themselves. The truth is probably somewhere between. Based on these reports, students observed the most used substances as being alcohol, diet pills, prescription drugs without a prescription, and cigarettes. Clearly, the front runner was alcohol at 14%, diet pills and marijuana at 8%.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Most students would use a Bishop, the ecclesiastical leader for intervention (84%) followed by the Student Health Center and Counseling Center (65%). <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The most helpful items seen to promote awareness and prevention of drugs and alcohol were academic forums, seminars or other training sessions at 78%, and brochures/awareness weeks at&nbsp; 71%.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a note of interest, the survey conducted in the winter of 2011 had similar results.<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p align="center"><strong>GENERAL ASSESSMENT</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The very nature of BYU-Idaho and its affiliation with The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints set the overall tone and attitude of students, faculty, staff and administrators relative to alcohol and other substance use. Each of these individuals adheres to a personal code of conduct and re-commit with their ecclesiastical leader on an annual basis to the abstinence from use of alcohol or illicit substances. In that sense, the alcohol and illicit substance prevention programs at BYU-Idaho do not require a great deal of emphasis because of the frequent reminders which come through ecclesiastical lines and through institutional efforts such as orientation, devotional talks and academic classes which directly deal with these issues in sociology, biology, health science and religion classes.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The focus of the university on worthiness and commitment of employees and students gives rise to the relatively low incidence of alcohol and other substance use through adherence to the doctrines of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints which require abstinence from alcohol and illicit substance use/abuse as a condition of employment or enrollment at BYU-Idaho. The direction provided by the BYU-Idaho Board of Trustees regarding illicit substance use is very strict and states:<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <em>"There is no second chance. The use or possession of illicit substances will cause for immediate dismissal from school. The same policy will apply to any person having any part in supplying illicit substances or assisting others to procure or use illicit substances." The only exception to the policy is "...except when the only contact with an illicit substance was limited (brief and casual contact) and the student has repented before disciplinary action is begun."<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title=""><strong>[5]</strong></a></em><br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When viewed in light of Church mores, Board policy and the personal commitment of the university community one would expect that there would be no issues in the area of alcohol or substance use. Likewise, to say that because there are so few reported incidents we should ignore those issues would be quite cavalier. Members of the university community should be concerned with any use, however slight; they may be because of those very mores, policies and commitments. We must be what we say we are if we are to maintain our institutional integrity. It is in that light which we should review the reports and efforts of those assigned this responsibility at BYU-Idaho.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are no known or reported incidents of alcohol or illicit substance use by employees. This does not imply that they do not occur but the nature of the ecclesiastical endorsement required of all employees to work at the university focuses on worthiness interviews with church leaders who may deal with those issues in a different setting should there be any problems.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Illicit substance use or abuse among students is not common, although each year a number of students are separated from the university because of their involvement in illicit substance use. Generally, the majority of those students report their substance use more often than not as being marijuana. Alcohol use among students, although not as rare as other substance use, is quite limited and is generally restricted to occasional or experimental use by a small portion (less than one fourth of 1 percent) of the student body. This percent is of reported cases involving alcohol use.<br /><br /><br /></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those involved with the use of alcohol that is reported to the Student Honor Office will be individually assessed as to the extent of the alcohol use. These students are generally placed on a disciplinary probation and are required to visit on a regular basis with the staff assigned to the case. In the case where there is continued use by the students and this is reported to the Student Honor Office, the students may be then subject to discipline after careful review and staffing by the staff.&nbsp; Often the students will be referred to the Counseling Center for specific counseling. Students who request help through the Counseling Center are not subject to the disciplinary sanctions of the university if they seek the help of the university in resolving a problem.</p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title="">[5]</a> Selected Clarifications of the Code of Honor and Related Procedures for C.E.S. Institutions of Higher Education, September 7, 1983.<br /><br /></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center"><strong>RECOMMENDATIONS</strong></p>
<p align="center"></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong style="text-align: left;"> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; </strong>The Biennial Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Committee makes recommendations for follow up action by various groups or individuals at the University. Some items are on-going and will not be removed while some are short term in nature and will be removed on completion.</p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><br /><br /> <strong>Recommendations for 2013-2014</strong><br />&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><br /><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">RECOMMENDATION:</span></strong><strong></strong><strong><br />Review Drug Free Policy clarifying the substance abuse policy.</strong> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br /><br /><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">RECOMMENDATION:</span></strong><strong></strong><strong><br />Maintaining the Student Catalog to show any office name changes and corrected phone numbers with an emphasis on any critical areas.</strong> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br /><br /><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">RECOMMENDATION:</span></strong> <strong><br />Another drug and alcohol survey to be completed at the end of 2014 by institutional research.</strong> &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>CERTIFICATION OF REVIEW PROCESS</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Committee met on January 23, 2013 to assess the strengths and weaknesses of the programs in place at BYU-Idaho and to ensure university compliance with the Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act and Amendment, 1989/Drug-Free Workplace Act, 1988. The review of policy documents noted the following: <br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><br /> 1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The institution appears to be in overall compliance with the regulation. There is a drug and alcohol use policy in place directed towards the prevention of illicit drugs and the misuse of alcohol and drugs.<br /><br /> 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The university distributes its alcohol and drug policy and to all employees and students via e-mail within two weeks of the start of each new semester or term.<br /><br /> 3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The university has helps available for those seeking help with drug or alcohol problems. The primary sources of help are through the Counseling Center, the Student Honor Office, ecclesiastical leaders, and academic programs. This united effort lends to a deep commitment in promoting a drug-free environment for the university community.<br /><br /> 4.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The biennial review of university drug prevention programs and policy is conducted at the conclusion of each biennial period. (This report covers January 2011 through December&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2012.) The review is designed to ensure effectiveness of the policy and the programs which are in place as well as to recommend measures which can be implemented to ensure that the programs are effective.<br /><br /> 5.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The review process is designed to look at disciplinary action which has been taken during the biennial period for consistency with university policy to ensure that sanctions are consistent and utilized. During this period, the committee noted that the Student Honor Office utilized a broad range of disciplinary sanctions which reflected the university policy in regard to alcohol or substance use.<br /><br /> 6.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Various university departments track the number of drug- and alcohol-related offences which occur on campus or are reported to departments. Statistics are gathered without disclosing the names of those involved in compliance with the students FERPA rights.<br /><br /> 7.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President's Council should review the report as in past years and need to formally adopt the report adding the President signature to the report.<br /><br /> <br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><br />This report reflects an accurate review of the policies, programs, and review process in effect at BYU-Idaho for the review period January 2011 through December 2012.<br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><br />&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&shy;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; ________________________________<br />Wynn Hill, Managing Director of Well-Being</p>
<p>Dean of Students Office<br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><br />________________________________<br />Date<br /><br /></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong><strong>CERTIFICATION OF ADOPTION AND ACCEPTANCE</strong><br /><br /><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President's Council met on April 29, 2013 and reviewed the Biennial Report of Institutional Compliance with the Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations. The review of the acceptance of that report as the official document for the university in compliance with applicable federal regulations was made on that date. The Council supports the drug and alcohol policies of the university and encourages employees and students who may have difficulties with these issues to seek assistance through appropriate channels. <br /><br />&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<p><br />__________________________________<br />Kim B. Clark, &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />President, Brigham Young University-Idaho<br /><br />&nbsp;</p>
<p><br />_________________________________________<br />Date <br /><br /></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: center;"><strong>Compliance Checklist</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"></p>
<p>PART 86, Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations Compliance Checklist<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title="">[6]</a><br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the institution maintain a copy of its drug prevention program?<br /><br /> Yes X &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> If yes, where is it located?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At BYU-Idaho, the drug prevention program is kept in the Dean of Students Office. <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the institution provide <em>annually to each employee and each student</em>, who is taking one or more classes for any type of academic credit except for continuing education units, written materials that adequately describe and contain the following?<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> a)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Standards of conduct that prohibit unlawful possession, use, or distribution of illicit drugs and alcohol on its property or as a part of its activities.<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> b)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A description of the health risks associated with the use of illicit drugs and the abuse of alcohol<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> c)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A description of the applicable legal sanctions under local, state, or federal law<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> d)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A description of applicable counseling, treatment or rehabilitation or re-entry programs<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> e)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A clear statement of the disciplinary sanctions the institution will impose on students and employee, and a description of those sanctions<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> We expend a great deal of effort to ensure that each student and each employee have access to a copy of the report. We are unable to document who does not receive a copy and are looking at ways to accomplish this distribution process more precisely. The report is e-mailed to every students and every employee at the beginning of each semester or block. In addition, the report is posted on the BYU-Idaho web site by going to <a href="http://www.byui.edu/securityreport">www.byui.edu/securityreport</a>. It is also available at the Dean of Students web site at all times and is referenced through a variety of searches and indices.<br /><br /></p>
<p></p>
<p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are the above materials distributed to students on one of the following ways?<br /><br /><br /><br /> a)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mailed to each student (separately or included in another mailing)<br /><br /> Yes O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> b)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Through campus post office boxes<br /><br /> Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> c)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Class schedules which are mailed to each student<br /><br /> Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> d)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During freshman orientation<br /><br /> Yes O No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> e)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During new student orientation<br /><br /> Yes O No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> f)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In another manner (<em>describe</em>) BYU-Idaho has chosen to distribute the materials to all students via e-mail during each new semester. Students may request a copy of the current report via mail or in person by contacting the Dean of Students office.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 4.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do the means of distribution provide adequate assurance that each student receives the materials annually?<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 5.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are the above materials distributed to staff and faculty in one of the following ways?<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> a)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mailed<br /><br /> Staff:&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Faculty:&nbsp; Yes O No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> b)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Through campus post office boxes<br /><br /> Staff:&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Faculty:&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> c)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During new employee orientation<br /><br /> Staff:&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Faculty:&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> d)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In another manner (<em>describe</em>) Faculty and staff receive the material via electronic e-mail. Those who do not have e-mail receive a printed copy. Those who receive it via e-mail may request a printed copy by contacting the Dean of Students office.<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 6.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the means of distribution provide adequate assurance that each staff and faculty member receives the materials annually:<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff:&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Faculty:&nbsp; Yes X No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 7.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the institution's distribution plan make provisions for providing these materials to staff and faculty who are hired after the initial distribution?<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff:&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Faculty:&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> 8.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In what ways does the institution conduct biennial reviews of its drug prevention program to determine effectiveness, implement necessary changes, and ensure that disciplinary sanctions are enforced?<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> a)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Conduct student alcohol and drug use survey<br /><br /> Yes &thorn;&nbsp; No o <br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> b)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Conduct opinion survey of its students, staff and faculty<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> c)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Evaluate comments obtained from a suggestion box<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> d)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Conduct focus groups<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> e)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Conduct intercept interviews<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> f)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Assess effectiveness of documented mandatory drug treatment referrals for students and employees<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes O&nbsp; No X<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> g)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Assess effectiveness of documented cases of disciplinary sanctions imposed on students and employees<br /><br /> Students:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Staff and Faculty:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X&nbsp; No O<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> h)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Other (<em>please list</em>)&nbsp; The Student Honor Office staff reviews each drug and alcohol case at all steps of the discipline process to ensure continuity of action and to provide a broad base of input in the decision-making process.<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title="">[7]</a> Note: The above Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations Compliance Checklist was taken from <em>Complying with the Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations</em> <em>[34CFR Part 86]</em>, a publication of the Higher Education Center for Alcohol and Other Drug Prevention, funded by the U.S. Department of Education.<br /><br /><br /></p>
<p></p>
<p>9.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who is responsible for conducting these biennial reviews?&nbsp; BYU-Idaho has established an on-going committee who is responsible for the biennial review. During the 2011-2012 review period the committee assignments were as follows:<br /><br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> Wynn Hill, Chair and Managing Director of Well-Being, Dean of Students Office<br /><br /> Reed Stoddard, Director of the Counseling Center<br /><br /> Garth Gunderson, Director of University Security<br /><br /> Kevin Price, Director of Human Resources<br /><br /> Kristie Lords, Director of the Student Honor Office<br /><br /> Shaun Orr, Director of the Student Health Center<br /><br /> Jameson Rammell, BYU-Idaho Student<br /><br /> Troy Dougherty, Director of Housing &amp; Student Living<br /><br /> Derek Fay, Managing Director of Activities &amp; Spirit Events&nbsp; <br /><br /> Dave Thomas, General Counsel<br /><br /> Cheryl Calderwood, Office Assistant/Dean of Students Office<br /><br /> <br /><br /></p>
<p>10.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If requested, has the institution made available, to the Secretary and the public, a copy of each requested item in the drug prevention program and the results of the biennial review?<br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes X No O<br /><br /></p>
<p></p>
<p>11.&nbsp; Where is the biennial review documentation located: &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Name:&nbsp; Wynn Hill&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Title: Managing Director of Well Being, Dean of Students Office &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Department: Dean of Students &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Phone: (208) 496-9200 E-mail: <a href="mailto:hillw@byui.edu">hillw@byui.edu</a> &nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<p>12.&nbsp; Comments &nbsp;</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho is committed to a zero tolerance of alcohol and other drug use and takes positive steps to help both students and employees maintain their employment and student commitment. Disciplinary sanctions are spelled out will and efforts are made to assist those who seek help to change their behavior. Annual statistics have not varied much over the years. The University is not satisfied with any alcohol or other drug use in light of the personal commitment each student and employee makes as a condition of their student status or employment. Significant energy is expended in quiet ways to reinforce the policies in place through new student orientation, talks, devotionals, activity group efforts and ecclesiastical leaders. Any use is too much.<br /><br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><br />Note: the above Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations Compliance checklist was taken from <em>Complying with the Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations</em> [34CFR Part 86], a publication of the Higher Education Center for Alcohol and Other Drug Prevention, funded by the U.S. Department of Education.</p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="file:///C:/Users/sarahjv/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/XP156OTW/BYU-I%20Biennial%20Drug%20Free%20Schools%20Report%20with%20title%20page.docx#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title=""></a><em></em><em></em></p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> Doctrine &amp; Covenants section 18 verse 10.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2">[2]</a> Student Handbook 2007-2008.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3">[3]</a> Doctrine &amp; Covenants section 89.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref4" name="_ftn4">[4]</a> Campus Security Report and Drug Policy Brigham Young University-Idaho, 2003, pages 31-32.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref5" name="_ftn5">[5]</a> lbid, pages 35-37.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref6" name="_ftn6">[6]</a> lbid, pages 37-38.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref7" name="_ftn7">[7]</a> lbid, pages.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref8" name="_ftn8">[8]</a> Selected Clarifications of the Code of Honor and Related Procedures for C.E.S. Institutions of Higher Education, September 7, 1983.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref9" name="_ftn9">[9]</a> Note: The above Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations Compliance Checklist was taken from <em>Complying with the Drug-Free Schools and Campuses Regulations</em> <em>[34CFR Part 86]</em>, a publication of the Higher Education Center for Alcohol and Other Drug Prevention, funded by the U.S. Department of Education.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43094" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x42756" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
