<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x43591" Name="Academic Transitions" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Welcome to Academic Transitions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Academic Transitions</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://courses.byui.edu/AcademicSupport/transitions/pics/transitions_cap.jpg" style="float: left;" /></p>
<p>Academic Transitions is a unique program at BYU-Idaho which is based on the belief that all admitted students can succeed.&nbsp; It is composed of carefully designed math, English, and college success courses to help bridge the gaps that many students have when they enter BYU-Idaho for the first time.</p>
<p>These courses are available to ALL students, but, based on entrance exam scores, some students are <strong>required</strong> to take transitional classes within their first 30 credits at BYU-Idaho.&nbsp; For these students, the transitional class becomes a prerequisite for the related Foundations of English 101 and/or Foundations of Math 108 classes.</p>
<p>New students should also register for the GS105 College Success course (2 credits) within the first 30 credits at the university.</p>
<h2>English 106 - Basic Writing</h2>
<p><img src="http://courses.byui.edu/AcademicSupport/transitions/pics/writing.jpg" style="float: right; margin-left: 15px; margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 5px;" /></p>
<p>Contact the BYU-Idaho English department with your questions at <a href="mailto:englishs@byui.edu">englishs@byui.edu</a> or (208) 496-4360.</p>
<p>Students with an <strong>ACT English sub score</strong> <strong>less than 16</strong> or an <strong>SAT Critical Reading sub score less than 390</strong> are <strong>required</strong> to take English 106.&nbsp; These students must receive a passing grade in English 106 before they can register for Foundations of English 101.</p>
<p>If the registration system indicates you must take ENG 106 as a prerequisite to FDENG 101, and you feel that you are prepared for FDENG 101 without a preparatory basic writing course, you may take the BYU-Idaho Basic Writing Exam to possibly "test out" of the ENG 106 requirement. Scoring 80 or higher on the exam will allow you to register for FDENG 101. The exam may not be taken more than one time per semester. For more information, contact <a href="mailto:byuionlinewriting@gmail.com">byuionlinewriting@gmail.com</a> </p>
<p>If you have previously completed a college or university level English course, or if you have scored above the required minimum sub scores listed, you may be eligible for a waiver of the English 106 requirement.</p>
<h2>Math 100A - Arithmetic and Math 100B - Beginning Algebra</h2>
<p><img src="http://courses.byui.edu/AcademicSupport/transitions/pics/math.jpg" style="float: left; margin-right: 15px; margin-top: 5px;" /></p>
<p>Contact the BYU- Idaho Math department with your questions at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/mathematics">http://www.byui.edu/mathematics</a> or (208) 496-7521.</p>
<p>Students with an <strong>ACT math sub score less than 18</strong> or an <strong>SAT math sub score less than 430</strong> are <strong>required </strong>to take a short online refresher math course before coming to campus.&nbsp; Information about the course and how and where to take it is available at the following website: <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.byui.edu/mathematics/aleks" target="_blank">http://www.byui.edu/mathematics/aleks</a></span>.&nbsp; These students should visit this web site and take the refresher course as soon as they are admitted to BYU-Idaho.</p>
<ul style="clear: both;">
<li>These students will not be able to register for any Foundations Math course until they take this online refresher course and score appropriately.</li>
<li>Students wishing to register for FDMAT 108 must score 120/142 in the online refresher course.&nbsp; Students who do not score at least 120/142 in the online refresher course will be required to take Math 100A or Math 100B.&nbsp; These students must then receive a "B" grade or better in Math 100B before they can register for FDMAT 108.</li>
<li>Students wishing to register for any higher Foundations of Math course (FDMAT 109, FDMAT 110, FDMAT 112, and FDMAT 119) must score 142/142 in the online refresher course.&nbsp; Students who do not score 142/142 in the online refresher course will be required to take Math 101.&nbsp; These students must then receive a "B" or better in Math 101 before they can register for a higher-level Foundations of Math course.</li>
</ul>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;">Note:</p>
<ul>
<li>Students with an Associate of Science or Associate of Arts degree before arriving at BYU-Idaho may disregard this requirement.</li>
<li>Students with college credit for Intermediate Algebra (with a "B" grade or better), College Algebra, or Pre-Calculus may disregard this requirement.</li>
<li>Students who already have credit for Math 100B at BYU-Idaho with a "B" grade or better may disregard this requirement.</li>
</ul>
<h2>General Studies 105 College Success</h2>
<p><img src="http://courses.byui.edu/AcademicSupport/transitions/pics/study.jpg" style="float: right; margin-left: 15px; margin-top: 5px;" /></p>
<p>The purpose of this course is to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduce students to the BYU-Idaho Learning Model and culture</li>
<li>Equip students with basic college study skills</li>
<li>Familiarize students with campus resources</li>
<li>Connect students with academic planning tools and their best major and career options.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sections of GS105 college Success will be visible on the registration system on the day that new freshmen are eligible to register.</p>
<h2>More about the Academic Transitions program</h2>
<p>Students in Academic Transition classes are fully matriculated and the credits count towards graduation.&nbsp; Students may take other major, foundation, and elective classes at the same time they are taking transitional classes.&nbsp; The transitional courses are kept to 25 students and are taught by highly nurturing and qualified faculty members who are transitional experts in their disciplines.&nbsp; In addition to the individual attention given by the faculty, the math and English courses use embedded tutors in order to give each student the additional individual attention they want and need.</p>
<h2>Other elective classes to consider</h2>
<ul>
<li>English 107 College Reading (3 credits)</li>
<li>English 109 Writing for International (second language) Students</li>
<li>English 151 Introduction to Literature (3 credits)</li>
<li>General Studies (GS) 102 Study Skills (1 credit)</li>
<li>GS 103 A-F Study Skills Online Modules (.5 credits each)</li>
<li>GS 100 Career Exploration (1 credit)</li>
<li>GS 101 Principles of Personal Achievement (2 credits)</li>
<li>Communications 175 (2 credits)</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x25860" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
