<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x43735" Name="Careers in Animal Science" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Careers in Animal Science</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Careers in Animal Science</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Career Opportunities</strong></p>
<p>Students earning a B.S. degree with a major in animal science are qualified for a wide variety of challenging careers. In fact, there are over 500 different job classifications for animal science graduates. Graduates find employment in academic teaching and research, industrial research in the food and feed industries, in laboratory research programs with governmental and international agencies, private corporations, and in industrial or institutional management positions requiring a high level of scientific training. In government positions, graduates can help draft regulations governing the agriculture industry, or work directly in research. Other traditional employment can be found with feed manufacturers, animal breeding companies, meat packers, pharmaceutical companies, consulting firms, universities, or in primary production. An agricultural science degree is also the gateway to a multitude of possibilities in the growing agricultural biotechnology industry.</p>
<p><strong>What Career Opportunities Are Available?</strong></p>
<p>By majoring in animal sciences, you can prepare yourself for one or more of the many careers related to animal agriculture. Depending on the particular program of study you choose, rewarding career opportunities are available in business, industry, government, education, and research:</p>
<p>Allied animal industries such as feed and equipment manufacturers, artificial breeding associations, pharmaceutical firms, meat processors, and food distributors employ animal scientists in various technical, managerial, administrative, public relations, and sales positions.</p>
<p>Breeding and livestock marketing organizations employ animal scientists as field representatives, managers, consultants, market forecasters, and public relations specialists.</p>
<p>Extension educators with animal sciences training find professional teaching positions as state and area livestock specialists and county agricultural agents.</p>
<p>Food processors, meat packers, and related industries seek persons with meat science background for positions in management, product and process development, purchasing, quality assurance, technical and consumer services, advertising, and sales.</p>
<p>Formal training in the basic animal sciences provides essential background for professional careers in veterinary medicine.</p>
<p>Government agencies employ persons with undergraduate or advanced training in the animal sciences as administrative or technical specialists in livestock marketing, forecasting, environmental regulation, animal health, disease control, meats inspection, and public information.</p>
<p>Livestock breeders and feedlot operators seek persons with strong animal sciences and business training for positions in production management, animal nutrition, physiology, and behavior.</p>
<p>Researchers and laboratory technicians are employed by many government agencies and private firms, working in such specialized fields as animal breeding and reproduction, health maintenance and disease control, animal nutrition, computer modeling, animal housing, waste management, environmental quality, and processing, handling, and quality control with meat, milk, eggs, and other animal products.</p>
<p>Self-employed persons with animal sciences training develop professional careers in such diverse fields as farm and feedlot operation, management services, consulting, livestock marketing, animal breeding, and kennel or clinic operations.</p>
<p>State and national organizations such as the National Cattlemen's Association, National Pork Producers Council, the National Dairy Herd Improvement Association, and others employ animal scientists to promote, educate, and work in the public sector with consumers of animal products; other service organizations employing animal scientists in educational, communications, and public relations roles include banking, insurance, and real estate firms.</p>
<p>Universities, colleges, and other educational organizations employ persons with advanced animal sciences training as teachers, researchers, laboratory technicians, and extension specialists.</p>
<p>Vocational agriculture educators with animal sciences backgrounds find professional careers in secondary schools, area vocational centers, and community colleges.</p>
<p>Writers and communicators with animal sciences training are employed by the various animal industries in advertising, publications work, and public information activities.</p>
<p>Zoos, kennels, animal clinics, horse farms, animal preserves, and similar facilities offer many positions as animal caretakers, technicians, gamekeepers, and veterinary assistants.</p>
<p>Recent advances in genetic engineering, molecular biology, and other biotechnology areas relating to animal production, care, and use underline the significant changes in today's animal agriculture and its growing importance to society as a whole. As new career opportunities emerge, many trained animal scientists will be needed to assume these challenging roles.</p>
<p><a name="titles"></a></p>
<p><strong>Job Titles</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="245">
<p>Livestock Production Manger<br /> - Beef<br /> - Dairy<br /> - Poultry<br /> - Sheep<br /> - Swine<br /> Animal Health Product Sales<br /> Feed Sales/Management<br /> Livestock Equipment Sales/Mgt<br /> Livestock Procurement<br /> Field Representative<br /> Consultant<br /> A.I. Breeding Technician<br /> Livestock Feedlot Operator<br /> Research and Lab Technician<br /> Public Relations Specialist<br /> Market Forecaster<br /> Sales</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Technical Representative<br /> Teacher<br /> Researcher<br /> Extension Specialist<br /> Livestock Marketing Specialist<br /> Housing &amp; Environmental Quality Specialist<br /> Livestock Insurance Representative<br /> Animal Scientist<br /> Food/Meat Product Development<br /> Quality Assurance<br /> Food Service Management<br /> Farm Management<br /> Dairy Equipment Specialist<br /> Stable Management<br /> Market Reporter<br /> Meat Grade<br /> Financial Analyst<br /> Financial Representative</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a name="types"></a></p>
<p><strong>Types of Employers</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="245">
<p>Self employed<br /> Feed companies<br /> Animal health firms<br /> Livestock equipment companies<br /> Commercial feedlots<br /> Food/meat processing companies<br /> Universities<br /> Private research firms<br /> Breeding firms<br /> Marketing/commission firms<br /> Insurance companies<br /> Companion animal industry<br /> Stockyard companies<br /> Purebred breed associations<br /> Poultry processors<br /> Zoos<br /> Community colleges<br /> Riding stables<br /> Racetracks<br /> Livestock publications<br /> Radio/TV stations<br /> Veterinary supplies<br /> Federal and State government<br /> Grain companies<br /> Commercial banks<br /> Farm organizations</p>
</td>
<td width="245">
<p>Livestock production<br /> Beef cattle<br /> Cow/calf operations<br /> Stocker or grower programs<br /> Feedlot<br /> Dairy<br /> Milk production<br /> Swine<br /> Farrowing operations<br /> Grower/finisher operations<br /> Farrow to finish<br /> Sheep<br /> Ewe flocks<br /> Wheat pasture growing/finishing programs<br /> Poultry<br /> Broiler production<br /> Egg production<br /> Horses<br /> Mare Breeding Farm<br /> Training facility<br /> <br /> Livestock feed<br /> Production<br /> Sales<br /> Distribution<br /> <br /> Financial institutions<br /> Banks<br /> Lending agencies</p>
</td>
<td width="245">
<p>Veterinary Medicine<br /> Practice<br /> Research<br /> Product development<br /> Teaching<br /> Inspection<br /> <br /> Meat or dairy foods<br /> Production<br /> Product development<br /> Quality control<br /> Distribution and marketing<br /> <br /> Livestock promotion and marketing<br /> Breed organizations<br /> Livestock publications<br /> Livestock sales<br /> Market reporting<br /> <br /> Sales<br /> Feed<br /> Pharmaceuticals<br /> Agricultural chemicals<br /> Livestock supplies<br /> <br /> Management<br /> Livestock production enterprises<br /> Sales/marketing companies<br /> Food production/distribution</p>
</td>
<td width="245">
<p>Service organizations<br /> Extension<br /> Agriculture agents<br /> 4-H agents<br /> Teaching (high school, junior college or university)<br /> Feed/slaughter inspection<br /> Private consulting<br /> <br /> Technology development and application (Biotechnology)<br /> Laboratory technical support<br /> Animal caretakers<br /> Research scientists<br /> Genetics and Animal Breeding<br /> Population genetics<br /> Molecular genetics<br /> Genetic engineering<br /> Reproductive management<br /> Endocrinology<br /> Cloning<br /> Embryo technology<br /> Nutrition<br /> Feeding programs<br /> Nutrition/reproduction interactions<br /> Nutrition/health/immunity interactions<br /> Food Science<br /> Product development<br /> Food processing<br /> Fermentation</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Career Planning and Professional Development: Career Tools</strong></p>
<p>FASS Job Resource Center; <a href="http://www.fass.org/job.asp">http://www.fass.org/job.asp</a><br /> Lists all jobs currently advertised in both the <em>Journal of Animal Science</em> and the <em>Journal of Dairy Science</em>, as well as industry internships.</p>
<p>America's Job Bank; <a href="http://www.ajb.dni.us/">http://www.ajb.dni.us/</a><br /> Links the 1,800 State Employment Service offices. It provides job seekers with the largest pool of active job opportunites.</p>
<p>Catapult; <a href="http://www.jobweb.org/catapult/catapult.htm">http://www.jobweb.org/catapult/catapult.htm</a><br /> Links to job listings, internships, post graduate options, and provides information on help guides and career library resources.</p>
<p>College Grad Job Hunter; <a href="http://www.collegegrad.com/">http://www.collegegrad.com/</a><br /> This site is an online version of the print guide. It is designed to give college students and college graduates one-stop shopping for jobs on the Internet.</p>
<p>Contact Center Network; <a href="http://www.idealist.org/">http://www.idealist.org/</a><br /> A nonprofit, non-partisan organization that has the most comprehensive directory of nonprofit resources on the Internet, with links to over 5,000 sites arranged by issue and geographic region.</p>
<p>Continental Search; <a href="http://www.consearch.com/">http://www.consearch.com/</a><br /> A customer-focused recruiting firm specializing in animal nutrition, animal health and vertically integrated food companies. Continental Search combines the art of matchmaking and the science of recruiting to bring talented individuals to great companies.</p>
<p>FedWorld; <a href="http://www.fedworld.gov/jobs/jobsearch.html">http://www.fedworld.gov/jobs/jobsearch.html</a><br /> This site contains a service that allows you to search a database of about 1,500 U.S. Government job announcements updated 5 days a week.</p>
<p>JobWeb; <a href="http://www.jobweb.org/">http://www.jobweb.org/</a><br /> Sponsored by the National Association of Colleges and Employers, this site provides information about entry-level jobs as well as industry information.</p>
<p>Guide to Job Resources on the Internet (Riley); <a href="http://www.dbm.com/jobguide/">http://www.dbm.com/jobguide/</a><br /> A listing of job resources in such areas as business, internships, government, science, environment, social sciences and many more. Resources are accessible by state and international areas.</p>
<p>Find a job, scholarship, career information, or post your resume at Jobtrak; <a href="http://www.jobtrak.com/">http://www.jobtrak.com/</a></p>
<p>Monster.com, Online Career Center; <a href="http://www.occ.com/">http://www.occ.com/</a><br /> An enormous database of job listings that can be search by geographic regions or key words. There is a resume bank where you can submit your resume at no cost via e-mail.</p>
<p>CareerPath; <a href="http://www.careerpath.com">http://www.careerpath.com</a><br /> This site includes job advertisements placed in the following major U.S. newspapers: The Boston Globe, Chicago Tribune, Los Angeles Times, The New York Times, San Jose Mercury News, The Washington Post, Philadelphia Inquirer, and the Southern Florida Sun-Sentinel. You will need to register your name at no charge.</p>
<p>CareerWeb; <a href="http://www.cweb.com/resources/">http://www.cweb.com/resources/</a><br /> This site hosts information for both the job seeker and employer/agencies. Also contains a database searchable by state and category.</p>
<p>Adams JobBank Online; <a href="http://www.careercity.com/">http://www.careercity.com/</a><br /> Current openings listed in computers, finance-consulting, general management, healthcare, office, sales/marketing/public relations, education, social work, and technical non-computer related.</p>
<p>Career Mosiac; <a href="http://www.careermosaic.com/">http://www.careermosaic.com/</a><br /> Job listings can be searched by key word or select a company and view their current available positions. Information about companies is included. Resumes are accepted for inclusion in their resume bank at no charge.</p>
<p>Chronicle of Higher Education Job Openings; <a href="http://chronicle.com/jobs/">http://chronicle.com/jobs/</a><br /> Openings for various positions in higher education. Search using by job listing, area, or key word. Site includes search for outside the U.S.</p>
<p>Foundation Center; <a href="http://fdncenter.org/">http://fdncenter.org/</a><br /> The Center's mission is to foster public understanding of the foundation field by collecting, organizing, analyzing, and disseminating information on foundations, corporate giving, and related subjects.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.animalsciencejobs.com/">Animal Science Jobs</a></p>
<p>Other careers in Animal Science - <a href="FARMandRANCHJOBS.com">FARMandRANCHJOBS.com</a> <br /> <br /> <a href="http://www.agcareers.com/">Agcareers Jobs</a></p>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1833" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
