<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x44209" Name="A Collaborative Approach to Online Learning - Part 1" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A Collaborative Approach to Online Learning – Part 1</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">With Alan Young</subTitle><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Part one of a three part series, which focuses on the campus faculty’s role in the collaborative approach to learning online.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="150" Height="76" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">instructional-development/News/stories/07-2012/ComputerIT-071210.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="230" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="176" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">instructional-development/News/stories/07-2012/Young and Eaton.jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120817T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rob Eaton</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>BYU-Idaho's approach to creating and teaching courses online is designed to harness the subject matter expertise of its on-campus faculty, the instructional design and operational "know-how" of its online team, and the dedication and instructional skills of its remote instructors.</p>
<p>Having so many parties involved in such a creative process can be challenging, but the synergy of these critical ingredients allows BYU-Idaho to create a high-quality learning experience online for&nbsp; growing number of students.</p>
<p>For this collaborative approach to succeed, it's important for everyone who contributes to understand their role - and to respect the expertise and experience of others. This article is part of a three part series that will provide a high-level explanation of relative roles and responsibilities. Part one focuses on campus faculty, part two on the role of the online team, and part three on online instructors.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Campus Faculty</span></strong></p>
<p>Department chairs and faculty are the chief stewards of content. Among other things, they do the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Help decided which courses get created online.</li>
<li>Collaborate with the online team in creating great courses, helping improve them over time, and keep them synchronized with what's being taught on campus.    
<ul>
<li>&nbsp;This is accomplished through councils that include online instructors and curriculum designers. Council members listen to each other's ideas with open minds and debate proposals respectfully and rigorously.</li>
<li>On matters of content, such as deciding on the critical learning outcomes for the course, faculty members have the final say.</li>
<li>No substantive changes to the content of any course should ever be made without approval of the responsible on-campus faculty.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Screen online instructor applicants to make sure they have sufficient expertise and appropriate credentials to teach courses in the discipline.    
<ul>
<li>No online instructor should ever be hired without a department chair or Foundations team lead approving their hire.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Help provide, as needed, content and discipline-specific training to online instructors.</li>
<li>Provide critical input to the online team if any content-related concerns arise about an instructor's performance.</li>
<li>Look for opportunities to reach out to online instructors in their discipline or course and invite them to participate, when possible, in content-specific discussions and training, without underwhelming instructor's reporting relationship to the online team.</li>
</ul>
<p>The entirety of these articles, along with a table that outlines the approval process for online activities, can be found in the Fall 2012 issue of Perspective Magazine.</p>
<ul>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x35693" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>