<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><NewsDetail ID="x44215" Name="Drilling Holes in Critical Thinking" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Drilling Holes in Critical Thinking</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Reflections on Traveling with the Learning and Teaching Travel Committee </Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" /><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="150" Height="90" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">instructional-development/News/stories/07-2012/this one.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="230" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="323" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">instructional-development/Romrell, Danae.jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120808T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Danae Romrell – Winter 2012 Issue of Perspective Magazine</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Learning and Teaching Committees provide a variety of resources and activities that facilitate faculty efforts at BYU-Idaho.&nbsp; For instance, the Collaboration Committee coordinates Learning Communities and oversees the Spori Summit retreats, while the Dialogue Committee organizes brown bag discussions and the annual Faculty Conference.&nbsp; All of these provide valuable opportunities for faculty from all disciplines to come together and share their current insights and best teaching practices.&nbsp; For its part, the Travel Committee helps enhance the quality of learning and teaching at BYU-Idaho by sending groups of faculty to teaching conferences or training workshops that occur off-campus at a variety of locations around the country.&nbsp; Over the past three years we have sent 123 faculty members to 22 different conferences or workshops.&nbsp; All of the conferences have been attended by interdisciplinary groups of faculty from across campus.&nbsp; Some of the conferences have included presentations and talks on a variety of topics relating to the scholarship of teaching and learning, while others have focused on a specific topic, such as "Critical Thinking" or "Learning and the Brain".</p>
<p>This past July, I was one of five faculty members who attended the 31<sup>st</sup> International Conference on Critical Thinking in Berkeley, California.&nbsp; The other faculty members attending were from the physics, religion, communications, and chemistry departments.&nbsp; My experience attending the conference was beneficial not only because of what I learned, but also because of the relationships I forged with other faculty members from across campus.</p>
<p>While attending the critical thinking conference, I heard a fabulous story from another conference participant who teaches in the automotive department at a community college in Alberta, Canada.&nbsp; During a lunchtime conversation he shared the story of a student who was learning to patch a tire.&nbsp; The automotive shop at the college had tires mounted on rims, attached to the wall that were intended to be used by students to practice patching a tire.&nbsp; A student would remove a tire from the rim, drill a hole in it (so that they would have a hole to repair), and then patch the hole and remount the tire.&nbsp; This particular student had finished the training, had demonstrated proficiency in all of the steps, and was very capable of repairing a hole in a tire.&nbsp; One day, he asked if he could bring in his personal vehicle and use the shop to repair a leak in his tire.&nbsp; The teacher agreed.&nbsp; The student brought in the car, raised it on the lift, removed the tire, and then proceeded to drill a hole in his tire.&nbsp; It was clear that the student knew the process of repairing a tire, but didn't have any idea <em>why</em> the process worked.</p>
<p>As a math teacher I think my students often approach solving a math problem by "drilling a hole in it".&nbsp; They learn all the steps to some mathematical process and show they are able to follow all of the steps.&nbsp; But then in a different context, they use that technique without making sure they understand whether the technique is appropriate for that situation.&nbsp; For example, students learn that 2x / 2 = x, so they incorrectly assume that 2x + 1 / 2 = x + 1.&nbsp;I want to encourage my students to think critically about a mathematical process.&nbsp; I want them to understand why it works.&nbsp; When they understand why it works they will better understand when it is appropriate to use that method in other contexts.&nbsp; At the critical thinking conference I gained a few ideas about how to help my students think critically.&nbsp; I have been working with my students on "critical reading".&nbsp; Using techniques I learned at the conference, I am trying to help them carefully read each sentence of a given passage, paraphrase it, and elaborate on it before they move on to the next sentence.&nbsp; I am also encouraging metacognition skills with my students.&nbsp; <em>Metacognition</em> is defined as the process of thinking about your thinking process.&nbsp; I hope that as my students consciously make an effort to think about the process of their thinking, they will learn to better recognize when they don't understand the concept behind a mathematical process.&nbsp; Recognizing when they don't understand a concept helps them avoid "drilling a hole" by applying the concept incorrectly.</p>
<p>I love attending conferences because they give me the opportunity to think critically about my teaching.&nbsp; I return excited and encouraged to improve and try something new.&nbsp; I hope I am never guilty of "drilling a hole" in my instructional methods.&nbsp; I hope I don't choose to teach a particular way just because that is how I have always done it.&nbsp; I appreciate the opportunity that attending a conference gives me to step back and examine my teaching from a new viewpoint.</p>
<p>For more information on the Learning and Teaching Travel Committee and upcoming conferences, please contact a member of the committee or visit the Travel Committee website at <a href="http://beta.byui.edu/learning-teaching/faculty-committees/travel">http://beta.byui.edu/learning-teaching/faculty-committees/travel</a>.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x35693" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" /><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="" /></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query="" /><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl" /></NewsDetail>