<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x44574" Name="Bylaws" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bylaws</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bylaws of Society and Officer Duties</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1 align="center"><strong>Bylaws of the</strong></h1>
<h1 align="center"><strong>Brigham Young University-Idaho Chapter of Student Affiliates</strong></h1>
<h1 align="center"><strong>of the American Chemical Society</strong></h1>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><strong>Revised:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></strong>05.October.2012<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><link href="prebuilt/stylenew/css/OpenClose.css" media="screen, projection" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" /></p>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h3><strong>Articles I - IX</strong><strong style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;</strong></h3>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p><strong>Article I. Name</strong></p>
<p>The name of this organization shall be the Brigham Young University-Idaho Chapter of Student Affiliates of the American Chemical Society or Chemistry Society for short.</p>
<p><strong>Article II. Objects</strong></p>
<p>The objects of this chapter shall be to afford an opportunity for students of a chemical science to become better acquainted, to secure the intellectual stimulation that arises from professional association, to obtain experience in preparing and presenting technical material before chemical audiences, to foster a professional pride in the chemical sciences, and to foster an awareness of the responsibilities and challenges facing the modern chemist.</p>
<p><strong>Article III. Membership</strong></p>
<p>The membership of this organization shall be composed of Student Affiliates of the American Chemical Society and Associate Members of the American Chemical Society. Students who are not ACS Student Affiliates or associate members may be chapter members but their voting power shall extend only to electing Officers and not to the ratification of amendments. All members must register their membership with the acting Secretary to exercise their voting power.</p>
<p>Article IV. Officers</p>
<p>The officers of this chapter shall be President, Vice-President, Secretary, Treasurer, Historian, Web Manager, and Public Relations (PR), who shall constitute the Executive Committee. The officers shall be elected at the first meeting of each semester. Officers must become ACS members upon being elected. Officers shall have claim to their post for two semesters, after which candidates may contend for the position. Service in one position shall be limited to four consecutive semesters.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article V. Duties of Officers</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The duty of each elected Officer is to become familiar with and to help fulfill the Objects of the Society outlined in Article II. More specific responsibilities of each Office are generally outlined in Appendix I.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article VI. Faculty Advisor</strong></p>
<p>The chapter will have one or more Faculty Advisors who are faculty members and are members of the American Chemical Society. Their duties shall be to advise the chapter both in its local activities and in its relations with the Society. The advisor(s) shall be kept informed of all chapter activities and shall advise the chapter on any policy matters.</p>
<p>Article VII. Meetings</p>
<p>Meetings of the society shall be held every two weeks on Wednesday at 5:30 pm. The executive committee shall meet at least weekly to plan and organize the activities of the society.&nbsp;<strong><strong><strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong></strong></strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Article VIII. Annual Reports</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>These bylaws may be amended by a two-thirds vote of ACS Student Affiliate members, provided that the amendments have been proposed at least one meeting previous to the time of voting. Such amendments shall conform to the ACS regulations established for the Student Affiliates Chapters. These bylaws will be reviewed and updated by the elected Executive Committee once a year during the fall semester. Any changes or amendments will also be ratified by a two-thirds vote of the current ACS Student Affiliate members;&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">Appendix I</h1>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Responsibilities of Chapter Officers</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>President</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The chapter president acts as the primary coordinator for all chapter activities, and is expected to fulfill or oversee the fulfillment of the following responsibilities</p>
<p>&bull; prepare and distribute the agenda for each meeting;</p>
<p>&bull; learn and enforce parliamentary procedures;</p>
<p>&bull; preside at all meetings and chapter functions;</p>
<p>&bull; conduct regular meetings with the officers and the advisor;</p>
<p>&bull; coordinate the membership recruitment campaign;</p>
<p>&bull; plan the chapter's calendar for the year;</p>
<p>&bull; establish committees and appoint chairs to carry out assignments;</p>
<p>&bull; monitor the progress of activities;</p>
<p>&bull; encourage cooperation and participation of chapter members;</p>
<p>&bull; be available to listen to problems, suggestions, and complaints of chapter members;</p>
<p>&bull; file the chapter's annual report; and,</p>
<p>&bull; represent the chapter at special university or community events.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Vice President</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The Vice President assists and coordinates with the President in fulfilling the duties of the President. The Vice President presides in the absence of the President.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Secretary</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The secretary is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull; record the minutes of all meetings;</p>
<p>&bull; compile the membership roster;</p>
<p>&bull; list committee assignments;</p>
<p>&bull; compile calendars of activities;</p>
<p>&bull; handle chapter correspondence; and,</p>
<p>&bull; submit an organized set of chapter records to the faculty advisor at the end of the year.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Public Relations</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The PR is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull; be the chapter contact with school officials and programs;</p>
<p>&bull; announce meetings and keep the members updated about chapter activities;</p>
<p>&bull; handle chapter correspondence;</p>
<p>&bull; develop and carry out a documented recruitment and retention campaign; and,</p>
<p>&bull; become familiar with and use marketing resources available on campus.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Web Manager</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The Web Manager is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull; learn and become proficient in the use of Ingeniux;</p>
<p>&bull; keep all contact and event information up to date on the society webpage;</p>
<p>&bull; create, post and maintain web content;</p>
<p>&bull; fulfill Web Policy requirements as stated on the Academic Societies webpage;</p>
<p>&bull; train a new Web Manager before leaving office</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Historian</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The Historian is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull; keep an accurate record of all society activities;</p>
<p>&bull; attend all society activities and photograph members and activities;</p>
<p>&bull; work with the web manager to upload pictures onto the society webpage and;</p>
<p>&bull; assist the secretary in constructing and submitting an organized set of chapter records to the faculty advisor at the end of the year.;</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Treasurer</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The Treasurer is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull; manage the society's monetary funds;</p>
<p>&bull; establish a semester budget for all expenses;</p>
<p>&bull; keep an accurate record of funds coming in and going out of the society;</p>
<p>&bull; provide other society officers with a current standing of the budget;</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Other Officers</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>Other officers can be created and filled for the purpose of fulfilling the Objects of the Society in Article II of the Bylaws.</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43928" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43869" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43821" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x30773" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
