<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x44549" Name="Prefered Bylaws if they fix issue" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bylaws</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bylaws and Officer Duties of Society</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120801T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1 align="center"><strong>Bylaws of the</strong></h1>
<h1 align="center"><strong>Brigham Young University-Idaho Chapter of Student Affiliates</strong></h1>
<h1 align="center"><strong>of the American Chemical Society</strong></h1>
<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<link href="prebuilt/stylenew/css/OpenClose.css" media="screen, projection" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h3><strong>Articles I - IX</strong><strong style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;</strong></h3>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p><strong>Article I.</strong> Name The name of this organization shall be the Brigham Young University-Idaho Chapter of Student Affiliates of the American Chemical Society.</p>
<p><strong>Article II.</strong> Objects The objects of this chapter shall be to afford an opportunity for students of a chemical science to become better acquainted, to secure the intellectual stimulation that arises from professional association, to obtain experience in preparing and presenting technical material before chemical audiences, to foster a professional pride in the chemical sciences, and to foster an awareness of the responsibilities and challenges facing the modern chemist.</p>
<p><strong>Article III.</strong> Membership The membership of this organization shall be composed of Student Affiliates of the American Chemical Society and Associate Members of the American Chemical Society.  Students who are not ACS Student Affiliates or associate members may be chapter members but may not have voting power.</p>
<p><strong>Article IV.</strong> Officers The officers of this Chapter shall be a President, a Vice-President, a Secretary, and a Public Relations, who shall constitute the Executive Committee.  The officers shall be elected at the first meeting in September from nominees chosen from the floor.  They shall take office in September and shall hold office for one year or until their successors are duly elected.</p>
<p><strong>Article V. </strong> Duties of Officers The duties of the officers and the executive committee may be set forth in detail or in broad outline. (See Appendix 1 for description of duties).</p>
<p><strong>Article VI.</strong> Faculty Advisor The Chapter will have a volunteer Faculty Advisor, who is a faculty member and is a member of the American Chemical Society.  Their duties shall be to advise the Chapter both in its local activities and in its relations with the Society.  The Advisor shall be kept informed of all Chapter activities and shall advise the Chapter on any policy matters.</p>
<p><strong>Article VII.</strong> Meetings Regular meetings shall be held at least once a month at 6:00p.m., Thursday (time is a subject to change).  Special events may be arranged through the Executive Committee.  There shall be at least four activities per year.</p>
<p><strong>Article VIII.</strong> Annual Reports The Chapter shall send to the Department of Higher Education/Student Affiliates Program an annual report of its activities.  This report shall be submitted on the Student Affiliates Chapter annual report form sent to the chapter in the spring.  The Society shall be informed promptly of the results of all elections of officers and Faculty Advisors.</p>
<p><strong> Article IX.</strong> Amendments These bylaws may be amended by a two-thirds vote of the members, provided that the amendments have been proposed at least one meeting previous to the time of voting.  Such amendments shall conform to the ACS regulations established for the Student Affiliates Chapters.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">Appendix I</h1>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Responsibilities of Chapter Officers</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>President</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>Chapter presidents must realize that the organization of the chapter ultimately rests on their shoulders. This position provides the president with an opportunity to develop strong leadership and administrative skills. At the beginning of a term, the president should ask these questions: what is the president's role? how can the talents of the officers and members be used most effectively? what kind of assistance and guidance will be required from the faculty advisor? (A close liaison between the officers and the faculty advisor is essential.) The chapter president acts as the primary coordinator for all chapter activities, and is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull;	prepare and distribute the agenda for each meeting;</p>
<p>&bull;	learn and enforce parliamentary procedures;</p>
<p>&bull;	preside at all meetings and chapter functions;</p>
<p>&bull;	conduct regular meetings with the officers and the advisor;</p>
<p>&bull;	coordinate the membership recruitment campaign;</p>
<p>&bull;	plan the chapter's calendar for the year;</p>
<p>&bull;	establish committees and appoint chairs to carry out assignments;</p>
<p>&bull;	monitor the progress of activities;</p>
<p>&bull;	encourage cooperation and participation of chapter members;</p>
<p>&bull;	be available to listen to problems, suggestions, and complaints of chapter members;</p>
<p>&bull;	file the chapter's annual report; and,</p>
<p>&bull;	represent the chapter at special university or community events.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Vice President</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The vice president acts for the president when the president is unavailable for chapter activities. The vice president should help oversee committees and generally share the workload of the president. The vice president often serves as program chair.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Secretary</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The secretary is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull;	record the minutes of all meetings;</p>
<p>&bull;	compile the membership roster;</p>
<p>&bull;	list committee assignments;</p>
<p>&bull;	compile calendars of activities;</p>
<p>&bull;	handle chapter correspondence; and,</p>
<p>&bull;	submit an organized set of chapter records to the faculty advisor at the end of the year.</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Public Relations</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>The PR is expected to:</p>
<p>&bull;	be the chapter contact with school officials and programs.</p>
<p>&bull;	announce meetings and keep the members updated about chapter activities.</p>
<p>&bull;	handle chapter correspondence</p>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Web Manager</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
<div class="close_text hide">
<p>Enter Hidden Text Here</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
