<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<NewsDetail ID="x44575" Name="Civil Engineering Student" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Civil Engineering Student</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></subTitle><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Civil Engineering Major Now Offered</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="150" Height="150" Alignment="" Border="" Expanded="true" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">mechanical-engineering/civil150.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" List="Image" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="230" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="129" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">mechanical-engineering/newcivildegree.jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20111129T19:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sam Clemence</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>BYU-Idaho will offer a civil engineering emphasis starting Fall Semester 2012 for students studying mechanical engineering.</p>
<p>"This has been the most requested degree by students, their parents  and the industry in general," said Garth Miller, faculty in the Department  of Mechanical Engineering. "When we meet with professionals, they're  constantly asking for civil engineering majors. The need for engineers  who can update the nation's aging roads, bridges and other  infrastructures has never been greater."</p>
<p>The new program promises to be a great help for those students who are seeking to earn a degree in civil engineering at BYU-I.</p>
<p>"Guys don't have to go down to Provo or anywhere else anymore," said  Daniel Adams, a junior studying mechanical engineering. "Guys that get  accepted here can stay here and get their civil engineering degree as  opposed to doing a couple prerequisites and then transferring."</p>
<p>The university currently offers bachelor's degrees in mechanical  engineering and welding and fabrication technology. The university  teaches classes on civil engineering, but only offers an associate  degree.</p>
<p>Previously, students that desired to earn a bachelor's degree or  higher in civil engineering had to transfer to BYU or another university  after earning an associates degree.</p>
<p>Offering a bachelor's degree in civil engineering at BYU-I will most  likely lower the cost for students not wishing to transfer to another  university.</p>
<p>Creation of a new degree also means that the school will hire new faculty to teach the subject.</p>
<p>One new job for a civil engineering faculty member is already posted on <em>www.byui.edu</em> and another will likely be added by 2013, Miller said.</p>
<p>New classes on civil engineering will be added along with the new faculty.</p>
<p>Eight new upper division classes are already being planned and will open for registration Fall Semester 2012.</p>
<p>Mechanical engineering places more emphasis on physics and moving  parts, which in turn are used to design all classes of vehicles,  machinery, and structures like power plants or dams.</p>
<p>Civil engineering is the science of designing and building static structures, or structures that don't involve moving parts.</p>
<p>Examples of civil engineering in action are in the construction of  bridges, skyscrapers, roads and water systems. It is one of the oldest  forms of engineering and has been a study of engineers dating back  thousands of years.</p>
<p>According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, a degree in civil  engineering will be more valuable in the coming years, because the  position will become more necessary as the country's population  continues to grow.</p>
<p>It is expected that civil engineering jobs will increase much faster  than the average of all occupations through 2018, according to <em>www.bls.gov</em>.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1882" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
