<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x44679" Name="Piano" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Piano</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Piano</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>The Department of Music promotes an active program in both piano performance and pedagogy (teaching). It also sponsors an active student chapter of the <a href="http://www.mtna.org/" title="MTNA" target="_blank">Music Teachers National Association</a>. Students experience musical leadership and professional involvement in music teaching. <a href="x44635.xml" title="Scholarships">Scholarship</a> assistance is available for <a href="x46637.xml" title="Piano Audition information">auditioning</a> students considering piano as a major.</p>
<hr />
<h1><strong>Degree information for piano</strong></h1>
<p>The four-year <strong>Bachelor in Music: Piano Performance (B.M.)</strong> offers preparation for the student desiring advanced training and performance experience. This degree serves the student who has a strong interest in graduate studies in piano.</p>
<p>The four-year <strong>Bachelor of Musical Arts: General Music (B.M.A.)</strong> offers preparation for the student desiring to combine piano skills with advanced training in composition. Students take two years of applied piano lessons and then continue with applied composition studies to complete the degree. Senior recitals in this degree program may include both piano performance and the student&rsquo;s compositions. This degree serves the student who has a strong interest in graduate studies in composition.</p>
<p>The four-year <strong>Bachelor of Arts (B.A.)</strong> combines the flexibility of a liberal arts degree with the first two years of the music major with additional music electives.</p>
<p>The <strong>Piano Pedagogy Minor</strong> offers the option of developing piano teaching skills in addition to pursuing another major. It provides an attractive option for students wishing to supplement income working in a home business.</p>
<p>The <strong>Piano Pedagogy Cluster</strong> offers the student an experience in piano teaching that includes all of the piano teaching classes as well as private piano instruction.</p>
<p>Please reference our <a href="http://www.byui.edu/music/degrees" title="Music catalog" target="_blank">degree programs</a>&nbsp;for more information regarding degrees and to access the current course catalog.</p>
<p><strong>Performance Opportunities</strong></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho is rich in opportunities for pianists. The Student Afternoon Recital (StAR) program and the Piano Majors Recital provide students many opportunities to perform. Accompanying skills are developed in private music lessons, the Piano Ensemble class, and through the many collaborative experiences associated with an active music program. Students look forward to the concerto festival/competition where they may win the privilege of performing a major work with the BYU-Idaho Symphony Orchestra.</p>
<p>The remodeled Eliza R. Snow Center for the Performing Arts has approximately 50 practice rooms and a number of specialized teaching studios. This includes practice studios with grand pianos for piano majors. Both major performance areas, the Barrus Concert Hall and the Recital Hall, are noted for their magnificent musical acoustics. The department houses several fine instruments including two 9-foot Steinway pianos and two 9-foot Yamaha pianos.</p>
<p><strong>Collaborative Piano (formerly Piano Ensemble)</strong></p>
<p>Collaborative Piano is a course designed primarily for piano music majors for the improvement of piano skills in the areas of vocal and instrumental collaboration, sight reading, and piano duet/duo ensemble. The emphasis on the course is on accompanying with use of piano duet/duo literature to augment skills of accompanying, critical listening and ensemble.</p>
<p>The course is divided into three units: 1) duet/duo ensemble, 2) vocal accompanying, and 3) instrumental accompanying. Each of these three areas includes lecture and assignments in keyboard skills related to particular aspects of ensemble playing.</p>
<p><strong>Piano Teaching</strong></p>
<p>Piano Teaching (Pedagogy) provides the opportunity to learn piano teaching skills and create a professional piano studio. Students have first-hand experience teaching beginning students in the Community Piano Lab in both private and group settings. Open to all students regardless of major.</p>
<hr />
<h1><strong>Community Piano Lab</strong></h1>
<p>Community Piano Lab is a piano teaching laboratory sponsored by the BYU-Idaho piano area. The lab provides opportunities for piano pedagogy students to teach beginning and intermediate children in a supervised setting.</p>
<p>Currently the Community Piano Lab does not offer instruction for beginning piano to adults.</p>
<h4>Beginning Piano Students (8-11 years of age)</h4>
<ul>
<li>Beginning level is defined as no or minimal musical training.</li>
<li>This is a lab experience for college students enrolled in the piano teaching classes at BYU-Idaho. For enrolled community students the lab includes individual lessons, group games and instruction, and a recital at the end of the semester. There are approximately 9 lessons beginning about the fourth week of each semester and concluding one week before the end of the semester.</li>
<li>Classes are held Wednesdays at 4:30-5:30 in the Snow Building Room 159. Additionally, students must be available at least once during the semester on either Monday or Friday 3:15 &ndash; 4:15 for teaching demonstrations.</li>
<li>Fee is $75. Materials are not included (about $25).</li>
<li>If you are interested, please fill out the application form. Although timeliness of application is a factor in student selection, the most important concern is creating homogenous and compatible classes. We may not be able to include all who apply or express interest. You will be notified of admission shortly after the deadline.</li>
<li><a href="mailto:allens@byui.edu" title="Email Steve Allen">Email Steve Allen</a> if you have any questions.</li>
<li><a href="x47156.xml" title="Community Piano Lab application" target="_blank">Application</a> for Beginning Students</li>
</ul>
<h4>Intermediate Piano Students (12 years and older - no upper limit)</h4>
<ul>
<li>Intermediate level is defined as a minimum training of 3 to 4 years and the ability to read and play easier hymns. Advanced student playing includes the ability to play all hymns with ease and a minimum study of 5 years.</li>
<li>This is a lab experience for students enrolled in the piano teaching classes at BYU-Idaho. For enrolled community students the lab includes approximately 10 individual lessons and a few master class sessions. Lessons begin about the fourth week of the semester and conclude one week before the end of the semester.</li>
<li>Lessons will be arranged according to student and teacher availability. However, students must be available a few times during the semester for teaching demonstrations on either Monday 4:30-5:30 or Wednesday 3:15 &ndash; 4:15. Lessons will be in the Snow Building.</li>
<li>Fee is $75. Materials are not included (about $25).</li>
<li>If you are interested, please fill out the application form. Although timeliness of application is a factor in student selection, the most important concern is creating homogenous and compatible classes. We may not be able to include all who apply or express interest.</li>
<li><a href="mailto:allens@byui.edu" title="Email Steve Allen">Email Steve Allen</a> if you have any questions.</li>
<li><a href="x47156.xml" title="Community Piano Lab application" target="_blank">Application</a> for Intermediate Students</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Component" Component="x46447" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1900" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
