<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x44624" Name="Student FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Student FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Student FAQ</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2><img alt="Student Waitlist" height="220" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/Student.jpg" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="#1" target="_self">What is waitlisting?</a></li>
<li><a href="#4" target="_self">How does waitlisting work?</a></li>
<li><a href="#5" target="_self">Does getting on a waitlist guarantee I'll be able to be in the class?</a></li>
<li><a href="#6" target="_self">How do I add myself to a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#7" target="_self">Will every course have a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#8" target="_self">Can I waitlist all the classes I want</a></li>
<li><a href="#9" target="_self">If I really need one specific course, can I waitlist multiple sections of that course?</a></li>
<li><a href="#10" target="_self">Can I adjust or rearrange my waitlisted courses?</a></li>
<li><a href="#11" target="_self">If I waitlist multiple sections of the same course and then I am able to register for one or more sections, What happens to my other sections for that course?</a></li>
<li><a href="#12" target="_self">If I am registered for one section of a course, but prefer another section, can I join that waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#13" target="_self">Can I waitlist a course if I have a hold on my account?</a></li>
<li><a href="#14" target="_self">Can I waitlist a course if I don't meet the pre-requisite or requirements?</a></li>
<li><a href="#15" target="_self">Can I waitlist a course that conflicts with another course I have already registered for or waitlisted?</a></li>
<li><a href="#16" target="_self">If I'm not allowed to waitlist a course, will the registration system tell me why?</a></li>
<li><a href="#17" target="_self">Can an instructor still authorize me into a class so I don't have to join a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#18" target="_self">How can I see what courses I have waitlisted?</a></li>
<li><a href="#19" target="_self">How do I know who's ahead of me on a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#21" target="_self">If a seat becomes available and I am first on the waitlist, will I automatically be added to the course?</a></li>
<li><a href="#22" target="_self">How will I be notified if a seat is available for me?</a></li>
<li><a href="#23" target="_self">How long do I have to add a waitlisted section?</a></li>
<li><a href="#24" target="_self">What if I can't or don't add a waitlisted class within the 24-hour period?</a></li>
<li><a href="#25" target="_self">What if I accidentally remove myself from a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#27" target="_self">What if I waitlist one or more courses and then decided I no longer want or need those courses?</a></li>
<li><a href="#28" target="_self">Do I have to drop my waitlisted sections if I intend to withdraw from BYU&minus;Idaho?</a></li>
</ol><hr />
<p><a name="1" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>WHAT IS WAITLISTING?</strong></p>
<p>If a course has filled, students can add themselves&mdash;in order&mdash; to an electronic list. A waitlist allows the first student on the list to have priority registration into the course if a seat becomes available. BYU&minus;Idaho's waitlist feature was developed at the request of both students and faculty. Many students requested a more efficient and fair way to waitlist, and faculty members wanted a better option than manually maintaining a paper list based on student email requests<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">.</span></p>
<p><a name="4" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>HOW DOES WAITLISTING WORK?</strong></p>
<p>Waitlisting allows students to add themselves to an electronic waitlist instead of contacting the instructor or department to seek an authorization into the course. Once a seat becomes available, the first student on the waitlist will be notified that a seat is being held for them to add. If a student does not add the course within 24 hours, the student is removed from the waitlist, and a notification is sent to the next student on the waitlist.</p>
<p><a name="5" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>DOES GETTING ON A WAITLIST GUARANTEE I&rsquo;LL BE ABLE TO BE IN THE CLASS?</strong></p>
<p>No. Even though you are able to join a waitlist, you still may not be able to get into the class.</p>
<p><a name="6" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>HOW DO I ADD MYSELF TO A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>The waitlisting feature was designed to be very similar to the current registration process. You can add yourself to a waitlist in the same way you register for classes on your my.byui.edu Student Tab, Add/Drop Portal. If you are eligible for a course but the course is full, the waitlist option may be displayed.</p>
<p><a name="7" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>WILL EVERY COURSE HAVE A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>No. Some instructors may opt to continue using a manual waitlist or to handle course overfill on the first day of class. Students will be able to determine if a waitlist is available on the add/drop page. In the example below, FDCNC250 sections 01 and 02 are both full, but section 02 does not have a waitlist and is therefore closed. If a course is not waitlisted, students will need to continually check back to see if someone drops the section and a seat becomes available.</p>
<p><img alt="student faq 1" height="206" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/studentfaq1.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="8" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>CAN I WAITLIST ALL THE CLASSES I WANT?</strong></p>
<p>No. In order for waitlisting to be effective, students need to be selective about the courses they really need. Therefore, each student is limited to the total number of credits that can be waitlisted:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>DAY (on-track or off-track), ONLN, or CTED 12 credits</p>
<p>Part-time or non-matriculating 9 credits</p>
<p>Academic Start and High School Concurrent Enrollment 6 credits</p>
<p>Your add/drop portal on my.byui.edu will tell you how many credits you can use and how many you have already waitlisted:</p>
<p><img alt="student faq" height="128" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/studentfaq2.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="9" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>IF I REALLY NEED ONE SPECIFIC COURSE, CAN I WAITLIST MULTIPLE SECTIONS OF THAT COURSE?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. Students can use their allotted waitlist credits in several ways. For example, if you have a maximum of 12 waitlist credits, you may opt to waitlist several different sections of different courses or waitlist multiple sections of the same course to improve your chances of getting into a section of a course that is really needed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="10" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>CAN I ADJUST OR REARRANGE MY WAITLISTED COURSES?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. Just as with registration, you are welcome to adjust your waitlisted options as necessary so long as you don&rsquo;t exceed your maximum number of waitlisted credits. For example, if your maximum waitlist credits is 12 and you have already waitlisted 10 credits but want to waitlist a three-credit course, you will need to drop at least one credit before waitlisting the three-credit course.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="11" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>IF I WAITLIST MULTIPLE SECTIONS OF THE SAME COURSE AND THEN I AM ABLE TO REGISTER FOR ONE OF THE SECTIONS, WHAT HAPPENS TO MY OTHER WAITLISTED SECTIONS FOR THAT COURSE?</strong></p>
<p>Once you register for any section of a given course, you will be automatically dropped from the waitlists of other sections of that same course. You cannot be both registered and waitlisted in sections of the same course.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="12" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>IF I AM REGISTERED FOR ONE SECTION OF A COURSE, BUT PREFER ANOTHER SECTION, CAN I JOIN THAT WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>No. Once registered for any section of a course, you cannot waitlist another section. If you prefer another section, you will first have to drop the registered section and then waitlist the other section. However, there is an obvious risk that you will not be able to get into the second section.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="13" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>CAN I WAITLIST A COURSE IF I HAVE A HOLD ON MY STUDENT ACCOUNT?</strong></p>
<p>No. You must meet the same conditions to waitlist a course that you would have to meet to register for the course. Therefore, you will have to resolve all absolute holds before you will be allowed to either register or waitlist courses.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="14" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>CAN I WAITLIST A COURSE IF I DON&rsquo;T MEET THE COURSE PRE-REQUISITES OR REQUIREMENTS?</strong></p>
<p>No. Just as with holds, you must meet the same conditions to waitlist a course that you would have to meet to register for the course. Therefore, if you have not taken the required pre-requisites or do not meet all course requirements (majors only, minimum GPA, etc.) you will not be able to waitlist.</p>
<p>If an instructor is willing to override the course requisites or requirements for you&mdash;but is not willing to overfill the course&mdash;the instructor may grant you both requisite and requirement authorizations, but not a capacity authorization. This would then allow you to join the waitlist, but would not allow you to fully add the course until a seat becomes available and you are notified by email.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="15" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>CAN I WAITLIST A COURSE THAT CONFLICTS WITH ANOTHER COURSE I HAVE EITHER ALREADY REGISTERED FOR OR WAITLISTED?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. You will be able to waitlist sections with conflicting schedules. However, once you are approved to add a course, you will have to either drop the course for which you are already registered or remove yourself from the waitlist, indicating that you no longer need the waitlisted section.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="16" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>IF I&rsquo;M NOT ALLOWED TO WAITLIST A COURSE, WILL THE REGISTRATION SYSTEM TELL ME WHY?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. Attempting to add yourself to a waitlist functions in the same way as adding a class. If you are not eligible for the course, the registration system will display a warning messaging explaining the conflict.</p>
<p><img alt="student faq 3" height="144" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/studentfaq3.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="17" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>CAN AN INSTRUCTOR STILL AUTHORIZE ME INTO A CLASS SO I DON&rsquo;T HAVE TO JOIN A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, an instructor always has the authority to authorize a student directly into a course. However, to be fair with the waitlisting process, instructors are encouraged to allow the automated waitlist process to determine who is next in line for an available seat. Students with a compelling reason to be added to a course in front of those on a waitlist may seek an authorization from the instructor.</p>
<p><a name="18" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>HOW CAN I SEE WHAT COURSES I HAVE WAITLISTED?</strong></p>
<p>You can see your waitlisted courses in the same location as you see your registered schedule on your my.byui.edu Student Tab under the Add/Drop Portal. Waitlisted courses are clearly marked:</p>
<p><img alt="student faq 4" height="308" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/studentfaq4.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="19" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>HOW DO I KNOW WHO&rsquo;S AHEAD OF ME ON A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>Before adding yourself to a waitlist, you will be able to see the number of students already waitlisted for that course. However, the names of those on a waitlist are not viewable. This number will help you determine if it is wise to add yourself to the waitlist of a particular section. For example, a waitlist that has only two students on it may be easier to get into than a waitlist that has 72 students on it.</p>
<p><img alt="student faq 5" height="141" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/studentfaq5.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="21" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>IF A SEAT BECOMES AVAILABLE AND I AM FIRST ON THE WAITLIST, WILL I AUTOMATICALLY BE ADDED TO THE COURSE?</strong></p>
<p>No. Once a seat becomes available to the first person on the waitlist, an automated email will be sent to the student&rsquo;s BYU&minus;Idaho email address. As with all registration, it is then the student&rsquo;s responsibility to add the course. This is done in case the student has changed his mind and no longer wants or needs the course.</p>
<p><a name="22" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>HOW WILL I BE NOTIFIED THAT A SEAT IS AVAILABLE FOR ME?</strong></p>
<p>Once a seat becomes available, an automated email will be sent to your BYU&minus;Idaho email account. It is important for students to monitor their registration routinely to determine how quickly a waitlist is processed for a particular section. Even if you are 36th on a waitlist on Monday, you may advance all the way up to the 5th spot by Tuesday due to others dropping themselves from the waitlist or additional seats being added to the section by the department. <strong><span style="color: red;">It is the student&rsquo;s responsibility to closely monitor their waitlists to prevent missing their opportunity to add a needed course.</span></strong></p>
<p>Since BYU&minus;Idaho students can be found worldwide, please realize that a waitlisted seat may become available to you during the weekend-including Sundays. It is not feasible for waitlisting to be turned off on Sundays in the Mountain Time Zone because that time will not be Sunday for other students in other time zones.</p>
<p><a name="23" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>HOW LONG DO I HAVE TO ADD A WAITLISTED SECTION?</strong></p>
<p>24 hours. The Add/Drop Portal on your Student Tab will show the deadline by which you will have to register before the seat is offered to another student.&nbsp;The deadline by which you must add a waitlisted seat will also be displayed in the authorization email you receive.</p>
<p><a name="24" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>WHAT IF I CAN&rsquo;T OR DON&rsquo;T ADD A WAITLISTED CLASS WITHIN THE 24-HOUR PERIOD?</strong></p>
<p>You will lose your spot on the waitlist. If you still need the course, you will have to re-add yourself to the bottom of the waitlist. Students cannot be added back to the top of any waitlist</p>
<p><a name="25" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>WHAT IF I ACCIDENTALLY REMOVE MYSELF FROM A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>The system is designed to prevent the accidental removal from a waitlist by requesting confirmation of the drop before the removal is completed. Unfortunately, if you do mistakenly drop yourself from a waitlist, you will have to re-add yourself to the bottom of the list. Because of the automated nature of waitlisting and the impact on other students on the waitlist, students will not be able to be added back into their original place on the waitlist.</p>
<p><img alt="student faq 6" height="181" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/studentfaq6.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p></p>
<p><a name="27" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>WHAT IF I WAITLIST ONE OR MORE COURSES BUT THEN DECIDE I NO LONGER WANT OR NEED THOSE COURSES?</strong></p>
<p>To make waitlistist the most efficient and effective, students are encouraged to carefully monitor their waitlisted courses. If you determine a waitlisted course is no longer needed, please promptly drop it so the course can become available sooner to another student lower down the waitlist who may still need the course.</p>
<p><a name="28" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /> <strong>DO I HAVE TO DROP MY WAITLISTED SECTIONS IF I INTEND TO WITHDRAW FROM BYU&minus;Idaho?</strong></p>
<p>While it is not essential to do so, it is encouraged so others can advance up the waitlist more quickly.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17143" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
