<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x44627" Name="Instructor FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Instructor FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Instructor FAQ</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3><img alt="Instructor Waitlist" height="220" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/Instructor.jpg" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></h3>
<ol>
<li><a href="#1" target="_self">What is waitlisting?</a></li>
<li><a href="#2" target="_self">How does waitlisting work?</a></li>
<li><a href="#3" target="_self">What are the advantages of using an electronic waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#6" target="_self">How do students add themselves to a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#7" target="_self">Am I required to waitlist every section I teach?</a></li>
<li><a href="#8" target="_self">Can students waitlist all the classes they want?</a></li>
<li><a href="#9" target="_self">Can a student waitlist multiple sections of the same course?</a></li>
<li><a href="#10" target="_self">Can a student waitlist a course if they have a hold on their student account?</a></li>
<li><a href="#11" target="_self">Can a student waitlist a course if they don&rsquo;t meet the course pre-requisites or requirements?</a></li>
<li><a href="#12" target="_self">Can a student waitlist a course that conflicts with another course they have already registered or waitlisted?</a></li>
<li><a href="#13" target="_self">How can I see who is on my waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#15" target="_self">If a seat becomes available, will the first waitlisted student be automatically added to the course?</a></li>
<li><a href="#16" target="_self">How will students be notified that a seat is available for them?</a></li>
<li><a href="#17" target="_self">How long does a student have to add a waitlisted section?</a></li>
<li><a href="#18" target="_self">What if a student can&rsquo;t or doesn&rsquo;t add a waitlisted class within the 24-hour period?</a></li>
<li><a href="#19" target="_self">What if a student accidentally removes himself from a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#20" target="_self">Can I still authorize a student into a class so he doesn&rsquo;t have to join a waitlist?</a></li>
<li><a href="#21" target="_self">Can I as the instructor remove someone from a waitlist?</a></li>
</ol><hr />
<p><a name="1" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><strong>WHAT IS WAITLISTING?</strong></p>
<p>If a course has filled, students can add themselves&mdash;in order&mdash;to an electronic list. A waitlist allows the first student on the list to have priority registration into the course if a seat becomes available. BUI&mdash;Idaho's waitlist feature was developed at the request of both students and faculty. Many students requested a more efficient and fair way to waitlist, and faculty members wanted a better option than manually maintaining a paper list based on student email requests.</p>
<p><a name="2" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>HOW DOES WAITLISTING WORK?</strong></p>
<p>Waitlisting allows students to add themselves to an electronic waitlist instead of contacting the instructor or department to seek an authorization into the course. Once a seat becomes available, the first student on the waitlist will be notified that a seat is being held for them to add. If a student does not add the course within 24 hours, the student is removed from the waitlist, and a notification is sent to the next student on the waitlist.</p>
<p><a name="3" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>WHAT ARE THE ADVANTAGES OF USING AN ELECTRONIC WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>Electronic waitlists eliminate the need for instructors to respond to individual student requests and the need to track manual lists&mdash;a great time savings. Waitlisting benefits students by providing continual information about the probability of them getting into certain courses.</p>
<p><a name="6" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>HOW DO STUDENTS ADD THEMSELVES TO A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>The waitlisting feature was designed to be very similar to the current registration process. Students can add themselves to a waitlist in the same way they register for classes on their my.byui.edu Student Tab, Add/Drop Portal. If they are eligible for a course but the course is full, the waitlist option may be displayed.</p>
<p><a name="7" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>AM I REQUIRED TO WAITLIST EVERY SECTION I TEACH?</strong></p>
<p>No. Some instructors may opt to continuing using a manual waitlist or to handle course overfill on the first day of class. Students will be able to determine if a waitlist is available on the add/drop page. If one is not, the section will simply close. If a course is not waitlisted, students will need to continually check back to see if someone drops the section and a seat becomes available.</p>
<p><img alt="instructor faq 1" height="206" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq1.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="8" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN STUDENTS WAITLIST ALL THE CLASSES THEY WANT?</strong></p>
<p>No. In order for waitlisting to be effective, students need to be selective about the courses they really need. Therefore, each student is limited to the total number of credits that can be waitlisted:</p>
<p>DAY (on-track or off-track), ONLN, or CTED 12 credits</p>
<p>Part-time or non-matriculating 9 credits</p>
<p>Academic Start and High School Concurrent Enrollment 6 credits.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="9" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN A STUDENT WAITLIST MULTIPLE SECTIONS OF THE SAME COURSE?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. Students can use their allotted waitlist credits in several ways. For example, if a student has a maximum of 12 waitlist credits, he may opt to waitlist several different sections of different courses or waitlist multiple sections of the same course to improve his chances of getting into a section of a course that is really needed. Once a student registers for any section of a given course, he will be automatically dropped from the waitlists of other sections of that same course. Students cannot be both registered and waitlisted in sections of the same course.</p>
<p><a name="10" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN A STUDENT WAITLIST A COURSE IF THEY HAVE A HOLD ON THEIR STUDENT ACCOUNT?</strong></p>
<p>No. Students must meet the same conditions to waitlist a course that they would have to meet to register for the course. Therefore, they will have to resolve all absolute holds before they will be allowed to either register or waitlist courses.</p>
<p><a name="11" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN A STUDENT WAITLIST A COURSE IF THEY DON&rsquo;T MEET THE COURSE PRE-REQUISITES OR REQUIREMENTS?</strong></p>
<p>No. Just as with holds, students must meet the same conditions to waitlist a course that they would have to meet to register for the course. Therefore, if they have not taken the required pre-requisites or do not meet all course requirements (majors only, minimum GPA, etc.) they will not be able to waitlist.</p>
<p>If you are willing to override the course requisites or requirements for a student&mdash;but are not willing to overfill the course&mdash;the instructor may grant a student both requisite and requirement authorizations, but not a capacity authorization. This would then allow the student to join the waitlist, but would not allow them to fully add the course until a seat becomes available and they are notified by email.</p>
<p><a name="12" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN A STUDENT WAITLIST A COURSE THAT CONFLICTS WITH ANOTHER COURSE THEY HAVE ALREADY REGISTERED OR WAITLISTED?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. Students will be able to waitlist sections with conflicting schedules. However, once they are approved to add a course, they will have to either drop the course for which they are already registered or remove themselves from the waitlist, indicating that they no longer need the waitlisted section.</p>
<p><a name="13" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>HOW CAN I SEE WHO IS ON MY WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>There are three locations in which you can see your full waitlist:</p>
<p>1. On your Faculty Tab at my.byui.edu, select the new &ldquo;Waiting List&rdquo; option from the drop-down menu.&nbsp;<img alt="instructor faq 2" height="223" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq2.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /><img alt="instructor faq 3" height="385" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq3.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p>2. You can also access a &ldquo;Class List&rdquo; and change &ldquo;Set Options&rdquo; to &ldquo;Include Waitlisted.&rdquo;&nbsp;<img alt="instructor faq 4" height="222" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq4.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /><img alt="instructor faq 5" height="266" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq5.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p>3. You can see who has reached the top of the list and has been granted a waitlist authorization by looking at the authorizations portal.<img alt="instructor faq 6" height="161" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq6.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="15" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>IF A SEAT BECOMES AVAILABLE, WILL THE FIRST WAITLISTED STUDENT BE AUTOMATICALLY ADDED TO THE COURSE?</strong></p>
<p>No. Once a seat becomes available to the top person on the waitlist, an automated email will be sent to the student&rsquo;s BYU&ndash;Idaho email address. As with all registration, it is then the student&rsquo;s responsibility to add the course. This is done in case the student changes his mind and no longer wants or needs the course.</p>
<p><a name="16" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>HOW WILL STUDENTS BE NOTIFIED THAT A SEAT IS AVAILABLE FOR THEM?</strong></p>
<p>Once a seat becomes available, an automated email will be sent to the student&rsquo;s BYU&ndash;Idaho email account. It is important for students to monitor their registration routinely to determine how quickly a waitlist is processed for a particular section. Even if a student is 36th on a waitlist on Monday, he may advance all the way up to the 5th stop by Tuesday due to others dropping themselves from the waitlist or additional seats being added to the section by the department. <strong><span style="color: red;">It is the student&rsquo;s responsibility to closely monitor their waitlists to prevent missing their opportunity to add a needed course.</span></strong></p>
<p>Since BYU-Idaho students can be found worldwide, waitlisted seats may become available to students during the weekend-including Sundays. It is not feasible for waitlisting to be turned off on Sundays in the Mountain Time Zone because that time will not be Sunday for other students in other time zones.</p>
<p><a name="17" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>HOW LONG DOES A STUDENT HAVE TO ADD A WAITLISTED SECTION?</strong></p>
<p>24 hours. The Add/Drop Portal on the Student Tab will show the deadline by which they will have to register before the seat is offered to another student.&nbsp;The deadline by which a student must add a waitlisted seat will also be displayed in the authorization email they receive.</p>
<p><a name="18" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>WHAT IF A STUDENT CAN&rsquo;T OR DOESN&rsquo;T ADD A WAITLISTED CLASS WITHIN THE 24-HOUR PERIOD?</strong></p>
<p>The student will lose their spot on the waitlist. If they still need the course, they will have to re-add themselves to the bottom of the waitlist. Students cannot be added back to the top of any waitlist.</p>
<p><a name="19" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>WHAT IF A STUDENT ACCIDENTALLY REMOVES HIMSELF FROM A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>The system is designed to prevent the accidental removal from a waitlist by requesting confirmation of the drop before the removal is completed. Unfortunately, they will have to re-add themselves to the bottom of the waitlist. Because of the automated nature of waitlisting and the impact on other students on the waitlist, students will not be able to be added back into their original place on the waitlist.</p>
<p><img alt="instructor faq 7  " height="181" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/Department Info/instructorfaq7.png" style="border: 0px;" width="710" /></p>
<p><a name="20" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN I STILL AUTHORIZE A STUDENT INTO A CLASS SO HE DOESN&rsquo;T HAVE TO JOIN A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, an instructor always has the authority to authorize a student directly into a course. However, to be fair with the waitlisting process, you are encouraged to allow the automated process to determine who is next in line for an available seat. Students with a compelling reason to be added to a course in front of those on a waitlist may still contact you, seeking an authorization.</p>
<p><a name="21" target="_self"></a></p>
<p><br /><strong>CAN I AS THE INSTRUCTOR REMOVE SOMEONE FROM A WAITLIST?</strong></p>
<p>No. However, you can see who is on the waitlist and who has reached the top of the waitlist and is scheduled to add the course.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17143" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
