<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x44919" Name="Implementation Model" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Implementation Model</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Implementation Model</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<!-- WARD & STAKE LEADERS NAV BAR -->
<div><img src="Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/blank.png" width="63" /><a class="intLink" href="x8708.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/H.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/H-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/H.png" width="148" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44817.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/S.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/S-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/S.png" width="111" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44860.xml"><img src="Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/W-active.png" width="161" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44861.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/A.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/A-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/A.png" width="159" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44863.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/M.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/M-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/wardstakeleaders/M.png" width="246" /></a></div>
<!-- END NAV BAR -->
<div>
<div><a class="intLink" href="x44863.xml"></a><img height="89" src="Images/housing/Student%20Living/Ward%20Stake%20Leaders/Implementation%20Model/bannerIM.png" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="800" /></div>
<div><img height="470" src="Images/housing/Student%20Living/Ward%20Stake%20Leaders/Implementation%20Model/Implementation-Guide.png" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="940" /></div>
<div><a href="x44863.xml"> </a>
<p><strong>Ecclesiastical Training</strong></p>
<p>The vertical sequence from Area Seventy down to Students represents direct teaching and training that occurs at each respective level (e.g., Area Seventy instructs Stake Presidents, Stake Presidents instruct Bishops, Bishops instruct Home Evening Coordinators, etc.). It is especially important that the Home Evening Group Leaders receive instruction from a bishop in relation to their responsibilities within the ward pertaining to Student Living when they are called. A high councilor is assigned within each stake to ensure that the Student Living model is being properly implemented. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The Home Evening Coordinator</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Typically, each ward has two Home Evening Coordinators, male and female.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Home Evening Coordinators attend Ward Council and report to the bishop on the participation and strength of the ward Home Evening program and individual members.</li>
<li>Attend a monthly stake meeting with Student Living instructors.</li>
<li>Teach and discuss the purpose, principles, expectations, and desired outcomes of Student Living with ward members through Home Evening and existing ward meetings and in other settings as prescribed by the bishop (e.g., sacrament meetings, EQ/RS meetings, priesthood/auxiliary meetings, etc.).</li>
<li>Invite and challenge all ward members to <em>apply</em> the principles of Student Living (1) <em>in their own apartments</em>, (2) <em>throughout the apartment complex</em>, and (3) <em>"at all times and in all things"</em> (Mosiah 18: 9).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The BYU-Idaho Student Living Instructor</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This is a university, student leadership position responsible for material development and instruction.&nbsp; These students also serve as employees of the Housing and Student Living Office.</li>
<li>Instruct ward Home Evening Coordinators in monthly stake meetings and prepare them to go back into the ward to teach Home Evening Group Leaders.</li>
<li>Instruct apartment managers in monthly meetings, preparing them to teach the principles of Student Living through formal and informal interaction with students in their complex.</li>
<li>Respond to invitations from ecclesiastical leaders to participate in Student Living training and instructional meetings.&nbsp; They participate in campus efforts to promote and teach Student Living and &nbsp;to develop new materials.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Apartment Manager</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Though not considered university employees (they are hired by apartment owners), managers are required to have an ecclesiastical endorsement and attend monthly housing forums focused on the principles and application of Student Living.</li>
<li>Primarily responsible to teach, counsel, and uphold Housing Guidelines and the tenets of the Honor Code within the apartment complex.</li>
<li>Respond to Honor Code violations and determine the appropriate level of intervention (e.g., personal contact w/student, contact with the apartment as a whole, referral to the Student Honor Office, phone call to the bishop, and/or a combination of any of these interventions).&nbsp;</li>
<li>Work within the organization of the ward (bishops, EQ/RS presidencies) for reporting an issue of concern for a tenant within the complex.</li>
<li>Facilitate the implementation of the Student Living model through check-ins, apartment meetings, formal/informal gatherings, and other outreach efforts. Encourage students to live by the commitments they have made.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Implementation Outline</strong></p>
<p>When Student Living is taught early, consistently and thoroughly, the students are more familiar with the principles and more likely to put them into practice in their own lives and in their apartments.&nbsp; This reduces the number of concerns that are then passed onto ward leaders and apartment managers.</p>
<p>It is the responsibility of the stake High Councilor to ensure that the implementation model is followed within each ward and provide feedback on implementation, participation and attendance to the bishops and stake presidency.</p>
<p><em>Scheduling of Stake Student Living Meetings;</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Each stake is to schedule 3 to 4 training meetings which will occur throughout the semester where University Student Living Instructors train Home Evening Coordinators.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Students report that they prefer to have all the training meetings scheduled in advance and a schedule given at the beginning of the semester so that they can plan the semester accordingly.&nbsp; Scheduling month to month decreases attendance and commitment to the trainings.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Timeframe for stake meetings;</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Typically, one of the first of these meetings is held in conjunction with Stake Auxiliary Training and ideally within the first two to three weeks of school starting. &nbsp;</li>
<li>The second is most effectively held one to two weeks immediately following the first meeting to start the implementation of the model in home evening groups.&nbsp;</li>
<li>The mid-semester meeting is held for improved teaching and to respond to observed needs within the stake/wards.&nbsp;</li>
<li>The concluding meeting of the semester is held the last few weeks of school and may provide feedback for improvement in subsequent semesters but also to generalize the application of Student Living to all areas of life. &nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p><em>The outline for the four meetings may follow the below suggested topic development.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>The Ministry - Introducing the principles of Student Living, the purpose, sharing the purpose and intended outcomes of the Home Evening program, caring for the 'ONE'.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Administration - Clarifying roles and responsibilities, ward council interaction, training of group leaders, observation and reporting.</li>
<li>Teaching - Improving teaching and facilitation of Home Evening Coordinators to Group Leaders and to ultimately improve the teaching within each group.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Application - Extending learning and generalized application for students in their apartments, classes, future homes and families, employments and church service.&nbsp;<img height="5" src="Images/housing/blank.png" width="500" /></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div></div>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9764" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9287" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
