<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x45506" Name="Emergency Action Plan" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Emergency Action Plan</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Emergency Action Plan</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p align="left"><strong><a name="Index"></a>General Emergency Guidelines</strong><a href="#What to Do"><br /> What to do in case of an       Emergency</a><br /> <a href="#What Not">What not to do in an Emergency</a><br /> <a href="#Reporting">Reporting an Emergency</a><br /> <a href="#Medical">Medical Emergencies<br /> </a><a href="#Personal Security">Personal Security Checklist</a><br /> <br /> <strong>Specific Emergency Guidelines</strong><br /> <a href="#Bomb Threat">Bomb Threats</a><br /> <a href="#Chemical Spills">Chemical Spills<br /> </a><a href="#Earthquake">Earthquake</a> <a href="http://www2.byui.edu/safety/emergency%20preparation/General%20Emergency%20Guidelines.htm#Chemical%20Spills"><br /> </a> <a href="#Fire">Fire<br /> </a><a href="#Floods">Flood</a><br /> <a href="#Fumes">Fumes/Vapors/Gas leaks</a><br /> <a href="#Radioactive Spills">Radioactive Spills<br /> </a><a href="#Robbery/Assault">Robbery/Assault<br /> </a><a href="#Utility Failure">Utility Failure</a><br /> <a href="#Vehicular Accidents">Vehicular Accidents</a><a href="#WINTER STORMS :"><br /> Winter Storms</a></p>
<p align="left"><strong>BYU-Idaho General Emergency Guidelines       for Employees</strong></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho is committed to providing as       safe, crime-free, and productive an environment as possible for university       students, faculty,       and staff.&nbsp; Employees should be prepared to cope with the hazards and disasters that       threaten the day-to-day functions<br /> of the university. Fires, natural disasters, bomb threats, accidents, robberies, and assaults       can and will occur. During such times, telephone lines may be overloaded or damaged. The       following instructions were prepared to help you know what to do until help is available.       &nbsp; If you have questions or need further information regarding emergency procedures,       contact the Safety Office at extension 2457.</p>
<p><a name="What to Do"><strong>DO The Following During An Emergency:</strong></a></p>
<p>1. Avoid panic, remain calm, use common sense, and       render assistance as required. <br /> 2. To report emergencies call <strong> 911</strong> (you can also reach the BYU-Idaho Police at&nbsp;496-3000). <br /> 3. Evacuate buildings immediately upon request of authorities, upon hearing an alarm, or       when remaining becomes life-threatening. <br /> 4. Know the location of at least two emergency exits in your working/living areas. <br /> 5. Keep a flashlight nearby (in work and living areas). <br /> 6. Tune to KBYR 91.5 FM (BYU-Idaho Emergency Broadcast System station). <br /> 7. Every university building has a full-time <a href="http://www2.byui.edu/safety/emergency%20preparation/Building%20Coordinators.htm">Emergency Building Coordinator</a>. Know who       he/she is. Follow their instructions.<br /> <br /> <a href="#Index">Return to Index</a></p>
<p><strong> <a name="What Not">What NOT To Do During An Emergency: </a></strong></p>
<p>1. Do not use the telephone except to report       emergencies. <br /> 2. Do not wait to report an emergency to the University Police and your <a href="http://www2.byui.edu/safety/emergency%20preparation/Building%20Coordinators.htm">Emergency Building Coordinator</a>. <br /> 3. Do not use elevators or attempt to exit stalled elevators. <br /> 4. Do not jeopardize your life or the lives of others by attempting to save personal or       university property.<br /> 5. Do not cross police barriers without authorization. <br /> 6. Do not exceed your training or knowledge when attempting to render first aid.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="Reporting">Reporting an Emergenc</a>y</strong>:<br /> <br /> Dial       <strong> 911</strong> and the appropriate medical, fire, or police agency will be notified.<br /> 1. Before taking any action, be sure you are not endangering yourself. Avoid unstable       structures, radiation hazards, electrical wires, toxic fumes, chemical spills, fire, etc.       Do not jeopardize your life or the lives of others in attempting to save personal or       university property.<br /> 2. When you call, give your name, telephone number and location, and the nature and       location of the emergency.<br /> 3. Don't hang up until the person answering the call ends the conversation.<br /> 4. If there is a generalized emergency and phone lines are dead, take a message to       University Police, room 150 in the Kimball Building.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <strong><br /> <a name="Medical">Medical Emergencies</a>:</strong><br /> <br /> Do not exceed your training or knowledge when attempting to render first aid. Immediately       dial       <strong> 911</strong> and report the nature of the illness or injury. <br /> <br /> <strong>Poisoning or Drug Overdose</strong> <br /> The Poison Control phone number is       <strong> 1-800-860-0620.</strong><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong>They will recommend actions       you should take or notify paramedics if the poisoning presents a significant medical       emergency.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <strong><a name="Fire">Fire</a>: </strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Be Prepared</strong><br /> 1. Know how to activate the fire alarm.<br /> 2. Know the locations of fire extinguishers and how to use them.<br /> 3. Know all building exit routs. Elevators should not be used for exit in the event of a&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;       fire. Keep exit routes free of obstructions.<br /> 4. Have emergency telephone numbers attached or posted by telephones. <br /> <br /> <strong>If fire is suspected or Discovered:</strong> <br /> 1. Notify your supervisor or <a href="http://www2.byui.edu/safety/emergency%20preparation/Building%20Coordinators.htm">building coordinator</a>. <br /> 2. Activate the fire alarm and call       <strong>911</strong>. Give as much information as possible,<br /> including the building name and number and the location of the possible fire. <br /> 3. Never attempt to fight a fire alone.<br /> 4. Where there is no alarm, warn other occupants by knocking on doors and shouting a       warning.<br /> 5. Leave the building. As you exit, close doors and windows behind you to prevent the       fire's spread. Go to the nearest exit or stairwell. Do not use elevators. If the nearest       exit is blocked by fire, heat or smoke, go to the alternate exit.<br /> 6. If there is smoke in your room or in the corridors, stay down near the floor.<br /> 7. Before opening a door, feel the door and/or knob. if either is hot, do not open the       door.<br /> 8. Open doors slowly. If heat or heavy smoke is present, close the door and stay in the       room. Open a window to let heat and smoke out and fresh air in.<br /> 9. If you are trapped in your room, call       <strong> 911</strong> and give your location.&nbsp; Hang an object       out the window to attract attention.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="Bomb Threat">Bomb Threat</a>: </strong><br /> <br /> <strong>If you receive a threatening call:</strong><br /> 1. Ascertain as much information from the caller as possible. Use the checklist provided       to assist you in recording information obtained from a telephone bomb threat.<br /> 2. Notify University Police at       <strong>911</strong> or extension       3000 immediately.<br /> 3. Notify your supervisor.<br /> 4. Do NOT activate the building alarm system to evacuate. <br /> <br /> <strong>How to recognize a suspicious parcel</strong>:<br /> A letter or parcel that is unexpected or unknown with any of the following       characteristics:<br /> 1. Foreign mail, air mail, and special delivery<br /> 2. Restrictive markings such as Confidential or Personal, etc.<br /> 3. Excessive postage<br /> 4. Handwritten or poorly typed address<br /> 5. Incorrect titles<br /> 6. Titles but no names<br /> 7. Misspellings of common words<br /> 8. Oily stains or discolorations<br /> 9. No return address<br /> 10. Excessive weight.<br /> 11. Rigid envelope<br /> 12. Lopsided or uneven envelope<br /> 13. Protruding wires or tin foil<br /> 14. Excessive securing materials such as masking tape or string<br /> 15. Visual distractions<br /> <br /> <strong>What to do with suspicious parcels...</strong><br /> 1. Contact University Police at 496-3000<br /> 2. Move people in the immediate area away, but do NOT activate the fire alarm system.<br /> 3. Do NOT move or open the package.<br /> 4. Do NOT investigate too closely.<br /> 5. Do NOT cover or insulate the package.<br /> <br /> <strong>If you are asked to evacuate...</strong><br /> 1. Check your work area for unfamiliar items. Do NOT touch suspicious items; report them       to Police or other campus authorities on the scene.<br /> 2. Take personal belongings with you, such as keys, bags, etc.<br /> 3. Leave doors and windows open; Do NOT turn light switches on or off.<br /> 4. Do NOT make cell phone calls.<br /> 5. Use stairs only; Do NOT use elevators.<br /> 6. Move well away from the building.<br /> 7. Do NOT reenter until authorization to do so is issued by University Police.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a><br /> <br /> <strong><a name="Robbery/Assault">Robbery/Assault</a>: </strong><br /> <br /> These procedures should be followed to help assure your safety:<br /> 1. Cooperate. Give the person exactly what he/she asks for, nothing more.<br /> 2. Remember distinguishing traits: color of clothing; hat or no hat; beard or moustache;       race; approximate height, weight and age.<br /> 3. Notice the type of weapon used.<br /> 4. Listen carefully to voice characteristics and to what is said. <br /> 5. Note direction of travel or flight after the confrontation. Check vehicle type and       license number if possible.<br /> 6. Notify Campus Police at       <strong>911</strong> or extension 3000 immediately.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <strong><a name="Vehicular Accidents">Vehicular Accidents</a>:</strong> <br /> <br /> <strong>Unattended Vehicles</strong><br /> If you collide with an unattended vehicle, stop immediately, attempt to locate the       vehicle's owner, or notify University Police at 3000. If this is not possible, leave a note       with your name, address, and telephone number.<br /> <br /> <strong>Damage under $1,000</strong><br /> If you are involved in an accident resulting in damage under $1,000, you must stop and       give the following information to the owner/operator of the other vehicle: 1. Your name;       2. Your address; 3. Registration number of your vehicle: 4. Your driver's/chauffeur's       license number. <br /> <br /> <strong>Damage over $1,000, injury or death</strong><br /> If an accident results in damage over $1,000, if there is a question about the amount of       damage, or if an accident results in injury or death, notify University Police at       <strong>911</strong> or extension 3000 immediately. <br /> <br /> <strong>University Vehicles</strong><br /> Report immediately all collisions involving university vehicles to       University Police (3000),       regardless of the amount of damage.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index<br /> </a> <br /> <strong><a name="Chemical Spills">Chemical Spills</a>: </strong><br /> <br /> 1. All chemical spills should be reported immediately to Safety Office at ext.       2457 or 2414.<br /> 2. If the spill is life-threatening or presents a fire hazard, evacuation should take       place immediately and the University Police should be notified by calling       <strong>911</strong> or extension 3000.<br /> 3. While waiting for Public Safety representatives to arrive, keep the area free of       nonessential personnel.<br /> 4. Do not allow smoking or an open flame near a chemical spill.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <a name="Fumes"><strong>Fumes/Vapors/Gas Leaks</strong></a> <br /> <br /> If a vapor, fume, or gas leak enters your work place and you cannot determine the source,       leave the area immediately. Post a "DO NOT ENTER" sign and notify       University Police at       <strong>911</strong> or extension 3000 or the Safety Office at 2457.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <strong><a name="Radioactive Spills">Radioactive Spills</a>:</strong><br /> <br /> 1. Your first responsibility is to your own safety. Loss or damage of materials and       equipment, under emergency conditions, is a secondary consideration. Take immediate       measures to prevent the spread of contamination only if they can be completed safely.<br /> 2. Evacuate the room or area immediately and seal it off to prevent entry. Post a "DO       NOT ENTER" sign.<br /> 3. Notify University Police by calling       <strong>911</strong> or extension (3000) and the Safety Office (2457), as well as the area       supervisor immediately.<br /> 4. Do not begin decontamination procedures until the situation is evaluated by a       Radiological Health officer, unless the accident involves contaminated wounds.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <a name="WINTER STORMS :"><strong>Winter Storms:</strong></a><br /> <br /> When a severe winter storm occurs on campus during normal school hours, the President's Council decides whether the campus       will close or whether personnel should leave work early. Personnel are notified through       supervisory channels and university radio stations. If a class is in       session when the storm hits, do not dismiss class.&nbsp; Wait for further       instructions as to when it is safe to venture out of the safety of the       buildings. When notified it is safe to leave campus, please do       so without delay.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Students, faculty, and staff who question whether the university will be open after a major       overnight storm should tune in the campus radio stations (KBYI FM 100.5 or       KBYR       FM 91.5)</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="Earthquake">Earthquake:</a> </strong><br /> <br /> Idaho is a semi-active earthquake zone. Actions taken before, during, and immediately       after an earthquake may mean the difference between life and death. The following rules       should be observed:</p>
<p><strong>Before the tremor:</strong></p>
<p>Most casualties result from partial building       collapse, falling objects and debris, like toppling chimneys, falling bricks, ceiling       plaster and light fixtures. Many of these conditions can be prevented by taking a few       steps now to prepare. A brief survey of your home and office will indicate what hazards       exist.</p>
<p>1. Secure fixtures such as lights, cabinets,       bookcases and top heavy objects to resist moving, coming lose or falling during shaking.       Place large and heavy objects on lower shelves, securely fasten shelves to walls. Special       care should be taken to remove hazardous objects from above sleeping areas. Do not hang       plants in heavy pots that could swing free of hooks. <br /> 2. Store bottled goods, glass, and other breakables in low or closed cabinets and use       nonskid padded matting, hold-fast putty or velcro whenever possible. <br /> 3. Hold drills so each member of the department knows what to do in an earthquake.<br /> 4. Prepare an office emergency kit. <br /> <br /> <strong>During the tremor</strong>:<br /> 1. Don't panic. The motion is frightening, but unless it causes something to fall on you,       it is relatively harmless.<br /> 2. If you are indoors, stay indoors. Get under a desk, door frame, table or bench, or       against an inside wall. <br /> 3. Stay away from glass.<br /> 4. Do not use candles, matches, or other open flames either during or after the tremor.       Douse all fires.<br /> 5. Do not be surprised if the electricity goes out.<br /> 6. If you are outside, move away from buildings and utility wires. Once in the open, stay       there until the shaking stops. <br /> 7. Do not run through or near buildings. The greatest danger from falling debris is just       outside doorways and close to outer walls.<br /> 8. If you are in a vehicle, stop as quickly as safety permits. Stay in the vehicle. The       car will move a great deal, but it is a relatively safe place to be. <br /> <br /> <strong>After the tremor</strong>:<br /> 1. Check for injuries. Do not attempt to move seriously injured persons unless they are in       immediate danger of additional life-threatening injury.<br /> 2. If the building is severely damaged, leave it immediately.<br /> 3. Do not turn on utilities, including light switches. Do not use any type of open flame       for lighting purposes. If you smell gas, open windows and leave the building. Do not       re-enter the building until officials say it is safe.<br /> 4. Do not use telephones except to report an emergency.<br /> 5. If your supervisor is available, contact him/her for further instructions.<br /> <br /> <strong>General Instructions</strong>:<br /> 1. Do not go sightseeing.<br /> 2. Use a transistor radio to receive up-to-date emergency bulletins.<br /> 3. Do not use the telephone except to report medical or fire emergencies, safety hazards,       or violent crime emergencies.<br /> 4. Keep streets clear for emergency vehicles.<br /> 5. Be prepared for aftershocks. Most of these are smaller than the main quake, but some       may be large enough to do additional damage.<br /> 6. Cooperate with Public Safety officials. Do not go into damaged areas unless your help       is requested. <br /> <br /> At the university, an additional hazard exists due to the number of chemicals and gas lines       in laboratories. Leave the area immediately if chemical containers are broken or if gas       lines or tanks are ruptured.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In case of severe damage or loss of life, the Campus       Emergency Coordination Team will implement emergency procedures as soon as possible. The       director will coordinate all campus operations and activities.&nbsp; Housing, food,       medical care, and other emergency provisions will be made as needed.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <a name="Utility Failure"><strong>Utility Failure:</strong></a> <br /> <br /> In case of power outages during disaster situations, these procedures should be followed:<br /> 1. Do not light matches or other flames inside buildings. Gas lines may be damaged and       explosions or fire could occur.<br /> 2. If you are trapped in an elevator, do not panic. Personnel will arrive as soon as       possible to assist you. <br /> 3. Stay away from downed power lines and broken high-temperature waterlines.<br /> 4. Shut off the gas and electricity in your assigned work area. <br /> 5. Report major problems to the Campus Electrical Shop at 2431.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a> <br /> <br /> <a name="Personal Security"><strong>Personal Security       Checklist:</strong></a><br /> <br /> Observing the following guidelines will help you avoid crime situations:<br /> 1. Always lock your car and trunk. Store valuables out of sight in your trunk.<br /> 2. Never leave keys in your car or "hide" a spare key in a wheel well or bumper.<br /> 3. Never leave your car/apartment keys, purse, backpack, or other personal items       unattended.<br /> 4. Carry car keys separately from house keys. Never put your name or address on your keys.<br /> 5. Lock your bicycle in racks outside campus buildings (not to trees or railings); use a U       lock or case-hardened lock and chain. Take easy-to-steal items (helmet, pump, bottles,       quick-release seat, etc.) with you.<br /> 6. Engrave your bike frame and wheels with your driver's license number to discourage       theft.<br /> 7. Us well-lit walkways at night, walk in pairs or groups, or call       University Police at extension 3000 for an escort to your car.<br /> 8. Report suspicious activities or persons to University Police at       extension 3000.<br /> 9. Lock the outside door of campus offices when (a) leaving after work, (b) the office       will be unoccupied during the work day, or (c) working alone at night or on weekends.</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a></p>
<p><strong> <a name="Floods">Flood:</a></strong></p>
<p>1. If you are in low lying areas, immediately move       to higher ground. <br /> 2. Follow directions from the BYU-Idaho Police, your Emergency Building       coordinator and local government authorities.<br /> 3. Prepare to render volunteer aid to evacuees coming to the university seeking higher       ground (this will be many of the citizens of Rexburg).</p>
<p><a href="#Index">Return to Index</a></p>
</blockquote>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
