<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x45505" Name="Workplace Fire Hazards" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Workplace Fire Hazards</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Workplace Fire Hazards</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>It is the intent of this university to assure that hazardous  accumulations of combustible waste materials are controlled so that a  fast developing fire, rapid spread of toxic smoke, or an explosion will  not occur. Employees should contact the safety office (496-2414) for  information concerning the hazardous properties of materials in their  workplaces, and the degree of hazard each poses.</p>
<p>Accumulated hazardous wastes should be managed in harmony with the  institutional toxic and hazardous wastes contingency plan which can be  viewed on the safety office web page. Quantities should be kept to a  minimum and the safety office should be promptly notified when disposal  is needed (496-2414).</p>
<p>Fire prevention measures are developed for all fire hazards found. Once  employees are made aware of the fire hazards in their work areas, they  must be trained in the fire prevention measures developed and use them  in the course of their work. For example, oil soaked rags must be  treated differently than general paper trash in office areas. In  addition, large accumulations of waste paper or corrugated boxes, etc.,  can pose a significant fire hazard. Accumulations of materials which can  cause large fires or generate dense smoke that are easily ignited or  may start from spontaneous combustion, are the types of materials with  which this fire prevention plan is concerned. Such materials include  paints, solvents, aerosols and other flammable or combustible materials  that may be easily ignited by matches, welder's sparks, cigarettes and  similar low level energy ignition sources. It is the intent of this  university to prevent such accumulation of materials.</p>
<p>Certain equipment is installed at specific locations to control heat  sources or to detect fuel leaks. An example is a temperature limit  switch found on deep-fat food fryers found in cooking operations. There  may be similar switches for high temperature dip tanks, or flame failure  and flashback arrester devices on furnaces and similar heat producing  equipment. If these devices are not properly maintained or if they  become inoperative, a definite fire hazard exists. Again employees and  supervisors should be aware of the specific type of control devices on  equipment involved with combustible materials in their workplaces and  should make sure, through periodic inspection or testing, that these  controls are operable. Manufacturer's recommendations should be followed  to assure proper maintenance procedures.</p>
<p>Fuels and flammable gases are used throughout the university physical  plant as energy sources for various systems or equipment. Generators,  snow removal equipment, grounds maintenance equipment, small internal  combustion engines, motor vehicles, laboratory gas appliances, welding  acetylene, stored liquid or gaseous fuels, etc. are located within and  without many campus buildings. These fuels or compressed gases can be a  significant fire hazard and must be monitored and controlled by the  employees responsible for the use.</p>
<p>Potential fire hazards typically exist in the following locations on the campus of BYU-Idaho:</p>
<ul>
<li>Chemistry Chemical Storage Room, Romney Building; flammable and combustible chemicals </li>
<li>Biology Department Chemical Storage Room, Benson Building; flammable and combustible chemicals </li>
<li>Physical Plant Paint Shop; combustible paints and flammable solvents </li>
<li>Physical Plant Vehicle Maintenance; combustible and flammable fuels, oil and solvents </li>
<li>Automotive Laboratories, Austin and Farm/Agriculture Buildings, combustible and flammable fuels and oil </li>
<li>Welding Operations, Austin Laboratory, Physical Plant shops; acetylene and oxygen cylinders </li>
<li>Stores and Receiving; institutional storage of solvents and oil for various campus entities </li>
<li>Art Department, Spori Building; combustible and flammable paints and solvents </li>
<li>Theater Scene Shop, Snow Building; combustible and flammable paints and solvents </li>
<li>Food Services, Manwaring Center; combustible cooking oils and kitchen operations </li>
<li>Home Economics, Clarke Building; combustible cooking oils and kitchen operations </li>
<li>Residential Housing Units; hair dryers, curling irons, kitchen ranges, microwave ovens, etc. </li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
