<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x45549" Name="Fire Prevention" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fire Prevention</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fire Prevention</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dealing with kitchen fires</strong></p>
<p>These are dramatic videos about how to&nbsp; deal  with a common kitchen fire ... oil in a frying pan. Please read the&nbsp;  following introduction and then watch the show .. It's a real  eye-opener&nbsp; !!<br /> At the&nbsp; Fire&nbsp; Fighting Training school they would&nbsp; demonstrate this with  a deep fat fryer set on the fire field. An&nbsp; instructor would don a fire  suit and using an 8 oz cup at the end of a 10&nbsp; foot pole toss water  onto the grease fire. The results got the attention&nbsp; of the students.<br /> The water, being heavier than the oil, sinks to&nbsp; the bottom where it  instantly becomes superheated. The explosive force of&nbsp; the steam blows  the burning oil up and out. On the open field, it became a&nbsp; thirty foot  high fireball that resembled a nuclear blast. Inside the&nbsp; confines of a  kitchen, the fire ball Hits the ceiling and fills the entire&nbsp; room.<br /> Also, do not throw sugar or flour on a grease&nbsp; fire. One cup creates the explosive force of two sticks of&nbsp; dynamite.<br /> Please view these video clips <a href="x45564.xml"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Responsibilities of the Safety Office </strong></p>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Safety Office is responsible for the following activities:</p>
<ol>
<li>&nbsp;  	<ol>
<li>Development of the written fire prevention plan for regular and after-hours work conditions.</li>
<li>Immediate notification of the campus police and Rexburg Fire  department, and the campus emergency operations counsel in the event of a  fire affecting the university.</li>
<li>Integration of the fire prevention plan with the existing general emergency plan covering the occupied facilities.</li>
<li>Dissemination of procedures for reporting a fire, the location of fire exits, and evacuation routes to each employee.</li>
<li>Provision of training with respect to drills to acquaint employees with fire procedures.</li>
<li>Facility inspections and fire code compliance consultation.</li>
<li>Training of designated employees in the use of fire extinguishers and the application of medical first-aid techniques.</li>
<li>Facilitation of planning and training with campus police,  university personnel and local fire officials to promote a coordinated  response to fire emergencies and accessibility of equipment and  resources needed for management of the fire scene and displaced persons.</li>
<li>Monitoring fire response activities and communication of pertinent information to the university emergency operations counsel.</li>
<li>Training of building coordinators with respect to evacuation procedures to ensure that:</li>
</ol> </li>
</ol> 
<ul>
<li>&nbsp;
<ul>
<li>
<p>All employees are notified and a head count is taken to confirm total evacuation of all employees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When practical, equipment is placed and locked in storage rooms or desks for protection.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Appropriate security protection is provided at fire scenes to protect persons and property.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<strong><a href="x45503.xml" target="_parent">Fire Prevention Plan</a></strong>
<p>OSHA's Fire Prevention Plan regulation, found at 29 CFR 1910.38, 29 CFR  1926.24 and Subpart F requires a written plan that contains specific  program elements. This plan addresses fire emergencies that could  possibly occur on the campus of BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a href="x45505.xml" target="_parent">Workplace Fire Hazards</a> </strong></p>
<p>It is the intent of this university to assure that hazardous  accumulations of combustible waste materials are controlled so that a  fast developing fire, rapid spread of toxic smoke, or an explosion will  not occur. Employees should contact the safety office (496-2414) for  information concerning the hazardous properties of materials in their  workplaces, and the degree of hazard each poses.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a href="x45546.xml" target="_parent">Potential Ignition Sources </a></strong></p>
<p>Flammable or combustible materials will generally not ignite without an external source of ignition.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Fire Protection Equipment </strong></p>
<p>The following fire detection, notification and suppression equipment is  installed, inspected and maintained in operational condition in campus  facilities.</p>
<ol>
<li>Fire extinguishers are installed pursuant to NFPA standards in all campus buildings. They are inspect on a monthly basis.</li>
<li>Smoke and heat detectors are installed in pertinent campus areas and are inspect on an annual basis.</li>
<li>Heat activated sprinkler systems are installed in many, but not all  campus buildings and water flow is tested on a quarterly basis.</li>
<li>Fire hose cabinets, although not required by current fire code regulations, are located in many older facilities.</li>
<li>Warning horns and/or strobe lights are installed in campus buildings and are tested on an annual basis.</li>
<li>A computerized notification system is monitored on a 24 hour-a-day  basis by the university police department. The system has generator back  up and a redundant capability.</li>
<li>Emergency phones with direct notification to the university police  communications enter are strategically located throughout campus and in  all elevators.</li>
<li>The university telephone system has an enhanced 911 capability that  immediately notifies the university police communications center of the  location of any emergency call.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Maintenance of Fire Protection Equipment </strong></p>
<p>As indicated, campus fire protection systems are periodically inspected  to insure functionality by the university fire protection officer. Any  maintenance issues are immediately reported to the Physical Plant fire  systems maintenance technician through a computerized work order system  and needed repairs are promptly accomplished.</p>
<p>The safety office web page has an electronic hazard reporting system  that is accessible to all university students and employees. Individuals  are encouraged to use the system to promptly report any observed  hazards or needed equipment repairs. People can also telephone the  safety office directly at 496-2481 to report observations.</p>
<strong>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</strong>
<p><strong>Housekeeping Procedures </strong></p>
<p>The university endeavors to control accumulations of flammable and  combustible waste materials and residues so that they do not contribute  to fire hazards. University waste generators should follow the  instructions contained in the <a href="x46502.xml"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Toxic and Hazardous Waste Contingency Plan</span></a> located on the safety office web page and periodically notify the  safety office for the transportation and disposal of hazardous waste  accumulations. At no time should individual waste generators accumulate  more that 55 gallons of hazardous waste at their respective workplaces  and they are encouraged to request removal and disposal whenever five or  more gallons of flammable or combustible waste is generated. Hazardous  waste shall be accumulated by the safety office at a remote campus site  and shall be disposed of according to EPA and DOT regulations by a  contracted, licensed transportation, storage and disposal company.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Regulated accumulations of flammable and combustible liquids should be  stored in UL listed flame retardant storage cabinets pursuant to fire  code regulations. Any questions concerning regulated accumulations  should be conveyed to the safety office (496-2457).</p>
<p>All university employees are expected to maintain their work areas in a  relatively clean and orderly condition so as to minimize the unwarranted  accumulation of combustible materials.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong>
<p>Fire Safety Training</p>
<strong>&nbsp;</strong><ol> </ol></strong><ol>
<li>Fire Prevention Plan - At the time of a fire, employees should know   what type of evacuation is necessary and what their role is in carrying   out the plan. In cases where the fire is large, total and immediate   evacuation of all employees is necessary. In smaller fires, a partial   evacuation of nonessential employees with a delayed evacuation of others   may be necessary for continued plant operation. Employees are expected   to take the personal initiative to learn what is expected of them  during  a fire to assure their safety. The safety office web page is a  valuable  resource for information concerning fire protection and  emergency  evacuation. Safety office personnel may be contacted at  496-2481 to  provide individualized training, to answer questions and to  otherwise  assist students and employees with learning fire safety  procedures. The  safety office also conducts periodic fire safety  training available to  all university personnel. The schedule is  disseminated via the  institutional e-mail system and the faculty and  staff bulletin. </li>
</ol><ol> </ol>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><br />Fire safety training includes:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; What to do if employee discovers a fire</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Demonstration of alarm, if more than one type exists</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; How to recognize fire exits</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Evacuation routes</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Assisting employees with disabilities</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Measures to contain fire (e.g., closing office doors, windows, etc. in immediate vicinity)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Head count procedures (see EAP for details)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Return to building after the "all-clear" signal</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">Any  students or employees who do not understand the available training   information are encouraged to contact the safety office for additional   instruction. Because failure to comply with university policy concerning   fire prevention can result in OSHA citations and fines as well as   employee injury, an employee who does not comply with this program may   be subject to disciplinary action through established procedures.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2.&nbsp; Fire Prevention Equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Types of fires</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Types of fire prevention equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Location of fire prevention equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; How to use fire prevention equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Limitations of fire prevention equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Proper care and maintenance of assigned fire prevention equipment and</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&deg;&nbsp; Risk minimization techniques</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Employees must demonstrate an understanding of the training and the   ability to use the equipment properly before they are allowed to use of   the equipment.</p>
<p>If a previously trained employee does not have the understanding or   skill required to utilize fire protection equipment, the employee must   be retrained.</p>
<p>All persons who receive fire protection training shall be tested for   verification of attendance at a training session and shall sign a   training record as documentation of the receipt of such training.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</strong>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
