<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x45903" Name="Physical Therapist Assistant" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physical Therapist Assistant</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physical Therapy Assistant</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><a href="x47836.xml"><img src="Images/health-recreation-human-performance/Physical%20Therapist%20Assistant/banner2.gif" /></a></h1>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">THE BYU-IDAHO PHYSICAL THERAPIST ASSISTANT PROGRAM IS NOW ACCEPTING APPLICATIONS&nbsp;</h1>
<div style="font-family: verdana,geneva; font-size: 10pt;">
<p><strong><br />**The information posted in these web pages is intended to help the student body understand our plans and process for delivering the Physical Therapist Assistant (PTA) program. &nbsp;PLEASE be aware that as the program develops it is very likely that policy may change, especially in the early stages of this development, so please check back often or contact us to become aware of updates**.<br /><br />BYU-Idaho intends to offer an Associate of Applied Science (AAS) degree for the occupation of a Physical Therapist Assistant. AAS degrees are generally 60 to 70 credits and they have reduced foundations requirements. &nbsp;For this reason, the AAS degree may not transfer to other colleges or universities. You may contact the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academic-discovery-center/about-us/contact-us" target="_blank">Academic Discover Center</a> if you would like to learn more about what an AAS degree is. &nbsp; &nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong><strong>Graduation from a physical therapist assistant education program accredited by the </strong><strong>Commission on Accreditation in Physical Therapy Education (CAPTE), 1111 North Fairfax </strong><strong>Street, Alexandria, VA&nbsp; 22314; phone; 703-706-3245; accreditation@apta.org is necessary </strong><strong>for eligibility to sit for the licensure examination, which is required in all states.</strong><br /><br /> <strong>Brigham Young University - Idaho is seeking accreditation of a new physical therapist assistant education program from CAPTE.&nbsp; The program has submitted an Application for Candidacy, which is the&nbsp;formal application required to start an accreditation process.&nbsp; Submission of this document does not&nbsp;assure that the program will be accredited. &nbsp;T</strong><strong>hough achievement of Candidate for Accreditation status signifies satisfactory progress toward accreditation, it does not assure that a program will be granted accreditation. </strong><br /> <br />Therefore, it is VERY IMPORTANT that students understand the following...&nbsp;<br /></strong></p>
<p><strong>**Even though the faculty and administrators are committed to achieving the goal of full accreditation by the time our first class of graduates is ready to take the licensure exam, there is No Guarantee that this will happen. &nbsp;It is possible that students could finish the physical therapist assistant program training, but be unable to sit for the national licensure exam.**</strong> <br /><br /><strong>The BYU-Idaho PTA program is working towards the following milestones. &nbsp;<br /></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>It is expected that the BYUI-Idaho Physical Therapist Assistant program will achieve status as a formal "Candidate" for accreditation in the spring /summer of 2014. &nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong>The program will accept applications for the first cohort of students until July 29th, 2014. &nbsp;You can see how the application process works by clicking on the Menu item "<a href="x47836.xml">How to Apply</a>"&nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong>Students who apply and are accepted to the first cohort for this program are scheduled to begin formal training in Fall Semester 2014. &nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong><strong>The BYUI-Idaho PTA program will continue to work on accreditation requirements with the goal to achieve full accreditation by the end of Fall 2015. &nbsp;Assuming that all goes according to plan, students enrolled in the first cohort will be able to sit for the national licensure exam soon after graduating at the end of Fall Semester 2015.</strong></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong></strong><strong>In the event that the above milestones are not achieved as planned, students who complete PTA course work will still be able to count their PTA course credits towards a variety of bachelors degrees on campus. If necessary, advising for this option will be made available to students.<br /><br />Students take a risk when they apply for this first cohort, therefore, we encourage you to think carefully about your academic plans, goals and needs. &nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Any time that a change in the BYU-Idaho Accreditation status occurs, notification will be made on this web page within 30 days.</strong></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1837" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
