<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46362" Name="Students" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Students</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Students</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Students (ST):</strong>&nbsp;This function pertains to activities of the University's students, including student records, honor, and services.</p>
<p><em>The Student Records Office holds primary responsibility for a student's academic record. Academic departments are involved in the creation, use, and administration of student records, but they should look to the Student Records Office as the repository of vital student records. The Student Records Office actively scans and preserves student's academic records.</em></p>
<p><em>While many of the records listed below may pass through a department's office and be maintained by that office for administrative purposes for a specified time period, the final repository of most student academic records is the Student Records Office. Student academic records held by the Student Records Office include transcripts, . If you have any of these records and are unsure if the Student Records Office has the record, contact the Student Records Office to ensure they have it, if they do, you may destroy the record once it no longer meets an administrative need in the office. </em></p>
<ul>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Advising" title="Academic Advising">Academic Advising</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Petitions_&amp;_Requests" title="Academic Petitions &amp; Requests">Academic Petitions &amp; Requests</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Standing" title="Academic Standing">Academic Standing</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Admissions" title="Admissions, Enrolled">Admissions, Enrolled</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Admissions,_Not_Enrolled" title="Admissions, Not Enrolled">Admissions, Not Enrolled</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#BYU-I_Transcripts" title="BYU-I Transcripts">BYU-I Transcripts</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Career_&amp;_Placement" title="Career &amp; Placement">Career &amp; Placement</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Certification_&amp;_Testing" title="Certification &amp; Testing">Certification &amp; Testing</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Class_Lists_&amp;_Schedules" title="Class Lists &amp; Schedules">Class Lists &amp; Schedules</a></li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Disability_Services" title="Disability Services">Disability Services</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a href="#FERPA" title="FERPA">FERPA</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a href="#Graduation" title="Graduation">Graduation</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a href="#Grade_Change" title="Grade Change">Grade Change</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a href="#Grade_Reports_&amp;_Rosters" title="Grade Reports &amp; Rosters">Grade Reports &amp; Rosters</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Instructors' Grade Books" title="Instructors' Grade Books">Instructors' Grade Books</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#International_Students" title="International Students">International Students</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a href="#Internships" title="Internships">Internships</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Military_&amp;_Veterans" title="Military &amp; Veterans">Military &amp; Veterans</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Name_&amp;_Demographic_Changes" title="Name &amp; Demographic Changes">Name &amp; Demographic Changes</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Registration_&amp;_Tracking_" title="Registration &amp; Tracking">Registration &amp; Tracking</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Scholarships" title="Scholarships">Scholarships</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Special Academic Programs" title="Special Academic Programs">Special Academic Programs</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Student_Coursework" title="Student Coursework">Student Coursework</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Student_Honor" title="Student Honor">Student Honor</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Student_Organizations" title="Student Organizations">Student Organizations</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Student_Well-Being" title="Student Well-Being">Student Well-Being</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Transcript_Requests_&amp;_Authorizations" title="Transcript Requests &amp; Authorizations">Transcript Requests &amp; Authorizations</a></div>
</li>
<li>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a class="anchorLink" href="#Verifications" title="Verifications">Verifications</a><strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong></strong></div>
</li>
</ul>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Academic_Advising"></a>Academic Advising </strong>(see also <a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Standing" title="Academic Standing">Academic Standing</a> and <a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Petitions_&amp;_Requests" title="Academic Petitions &amp; Requests">Academic Petitions &amp; Requests</a>)</p>
<p>Records document student's academic progress and are maintained for the convenience of the student academic advisors. Records may include applications for program admission, notices of admission, grade reports, degree program requirement lists, departmental course waiver forms, program advisors' reports showing progress towards academic degrees, advising checklist forms, advisors' notes, copies of transcripts, Program Planning Sheets, advanced standing examination reports, official graduation audits, curriculum posting sheets, recommendation letters, suspension notices, re-admission notices, comprehensive exam results, awards, cluster approval forms and applications, Course Substitution/Waiver, Double Major/Minor, Graduation and Residency Requirement Petition, Name Change / Change in Marital Status, Vertical Credit, 3rd Party Release Form, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>The Student Records Office is the repository of records related to academic standing and petitions and requests. Copies held with Academic Discovery Center and related advising offices should be transferred to Student Records upon completion of the activity; all other records should be securely destroyed after retention.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Graduation</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Academic_Petitions_&amp;_Requests"></a><strong>Academic Petitions &amp; Requests </strong>(see also <a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Standing" title="Academic Standing">Academic Standing</a>)</p>
<p>Records of student petitions and formal written requests associated with academic standing and enrollment. Records may include petitions regarding credit limits, over 75 credit major change, academic renewal, academic suspension, academic exception, residency, student petitions for re-evaluation, and medical enrollment deferment and requests regarding waive requirement, change in final grade, major change, Major Petition Form, Custom Cluster Form, Request to Waive or Substitute Course Requirements, Fast Grad Form (Admissions), and University Studies Major Application Form.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office. Department offices should hold records until completion of the action (such as petitions and requests) then transfer items to the Student Records Office. </em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Graduation</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Academic_Standing"></a><strong>Academic Standing</strong></p>
<p>Records document student academic standing, including academic probation, leave of absence, or dismissal from the University. Records may include reports containing student names, grade point averages (GPAs), grade point deficiencies, and numbers of previous suspensions and probations; report of student progress toward academic readmission/removal of probation status at other institutions; academic honors and awards; and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office. Department offices should hold records until completion of the action (such as petitions and requests) then transfer items to the Student Records Office. </em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Graduation</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Admissions"></a><strong>Admissions, Enrolled</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with the application process for undergraduate and international applicants who applied, were accepted, and enrolled. Records may include CES applications, fast grad applications, academic transcripts from other institutions, test scores, letters of admittance, deferment forms, appeals, acceptance letters, letters offering financial aid or scholarships, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Applicable records should be transferred to the Student Records Office for inclusion in student academic records; official, final reports generated from summary information should be transferred to archives. </em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Matriculated</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Admissions,_Not_Enrolled"></a><strong>Admissions, Not Enrolled</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with the application process for undergraduate and international applicants who applied, but were not accepted, or who were accepted, but did not enroll. Records may include CES applications, academic transcripts from other institutions, test scores, letters of admittance, deferment forms, appeals, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="BYU-I_Transcripts"></a><strong>BYU-I Transcripts</strong></p>
<p>Official transcript constituting the student's permanent academic record at the University. A log of requests is kept permanently. These are considered vital records.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Permanent</p>
</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Career_&amp;_Placement"></a><strong>Career &amp; Placement</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with student career and graduate school placement. Records may include reference letters, student teaching reports, transcripts, contact information, professional program certificates, personal data sheets and resumes, College Interview Forms, reports and questionnaires on placement, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Academic Discovery Center and related advising offices.</em> <em>Official, complete copies of placement reports should be transferred to the archives after 3 years.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Certification_&amp;_Testing"></a><strong>Certification &amp; Testing</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with preparing students for certifications for licenses or professions, and exams for admission into programs or to substitute coursework. Exam scores or reports including IB or AP test results and ACT, SAT, LSAT, MCAT, GRE scores, and Placement Test Exception Forms. Records may include applications for admission to a program, registration for practicum hours and evidence of the completion of the practicum, transcripts, narrative evaluations on practicum, notice of completion of hours required for certification, recommendations and evaluations, testing rules and regulations, rosters of test takers, seating charts, supervisors' reports, and vouchers for payment of testing, and related correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Class_Lists_&amp;_Schedules"></a><strong>Class Lists &amp; Schedules</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with students enrolled in courses taught. The series can be used to cross-check students who have enrolled against those who have registered as well as in the generation of statistical reports. Records may include student names, Student ID Number, semester, and enrollment/registration status.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office; other copies held with academic departments as needed.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 semester</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Disability_Services"></a><strong>Disability Services</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with student participation in the Services for Students with a Disability program. Records may include health professional evaluation reports, documentation of disorders, recommendations for student applicants, high school transcripts and academic work-sheets, autobiographical essays, copies of applications for admission, copies of notices of admission, special admissions applications checklists, questionnaires, physicians' statements and letters of recommendation, counseling interview notes and referrals, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Disability Services Office. Admissions records will be held in Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Graduation</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="FERPA"></a><strong>FERPA</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with student information release requests and consent authorizations or denials in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act. Records may include but are not limited to requests for formal hearings, requests for release of personally identifiable information, records of disclosures made to third parties, student statements regarding hearing panel decisions, written decisions of the hearing panel, written consent of the student to disclose records, waivers for rights of access; and related documentation and correspondence. This series may also contain student requests for non-disclosure of directory information and memorandum distributed to pertinent departments informing units which might have pertinent information not to disclose that information.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Permanent in office</p>
</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Graduation"></a><strong>Graduation</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with preparing for and applying for graduation. Records may include Graduation Applications, Course Substitution/Waiver, cluster approval forms, official graduation audit forms that list students' names, colleges, majors, degrees, minors, clusters, course loads, grade point averages, and deans' recommendations/ comments and signatures, mailing addresses for diplomas, fees paid, and student listings, work sheets, transcripts, and transfer course evaluations.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Grade_Change"></a><strong>Grade Change</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with grade changes. Records may include grade change requests and forms, verification documents, and associated correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office. Other offices hold records as long as administratively necessary then transfer to Student Records.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Grade_Reports_&amp;_Rosters"></a><strong>Grade Reports &amp; Rosters </strong>(see also <a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Standing" title="Academic Standing">Academic Standing</a>)</p>
<p>Records associated with routine grade submissions that serve as a basis for the student's academic record. Records may include the record copy of reports distributed to students at the end of each semester, which includes student names and student ID numbers, course titles and numbers, sections, grades awarded, and instructors' signatures.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office. Instructors may hold information in grade books, grade confirmation reports, grade confirmation and change records, and final grade rosters for up to 2 years.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 semester</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Instructors' Grade Books"></a>Instructors' Grade Books</strong> (see also <a class="anchorLink" href="#Grade_Reports_&amp;_Rosters" title="Grade Reports &amp; Roster">Grade Reports &amp; Rosters</a>)</p>
<p>Records associated with determining a student's grade for a course. Records document test scores, class work scores, and final grades for students, and may be used as back-up to the official student records held by the Registrar.&nbsp;A Learning Management System (LMS) used across campus is one method of maintaining these records. The current LMS, BrainHoney (with I-Learn), can be used&nbsp;to document&nbsp;course&nbsp;grades. Records may include test and assignment scores, grade books, grade confirmation reports, grade confirmation and change records, and final grade rosters.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with instructors. Instructors should keep records as long as administratively necessary, at least 2 years. While the IT department supports backup of these records indefinitely, it is recommended that instructors save their gradebook data by exporting it at the end of the semester. Past records can be requested, but take time to retrieve. </em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>2 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="International_Students"></a><strong>International Students</strong> (see also <a href="#Admissions" title="Admissions">Admissions</a> and <a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Standing" title="Academic Standing">Academic Standing</a>)</p>
<p>Records associated with international students. Records may include immigration documents such as letters of inquiry and official replies, completed applications and admittance forms, visas, passports, I-20, I-94, scholarship information, institution admissions forms, transcripts of previous college work, international student advisors' notes, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy of transcripts held with Student Records Office; all other records maintained by the Admission Office. Retain records 7 years for enrolled students then destroy, retain records 1 year for non-enrolled students then destroy.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Matriculated</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>7 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Internships"></a><strong>Internships</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with the administration of student internship, practicum and cooperative education programs. Programs may be within the institution or off campus and for class credit and/or pay. Records may include but are not limited to applications for internships inside and external to the institution, agreements with departments, postings/notices, student resumes, transcripts, copies of contracts, proposed institution listings, notes, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Academic Discovery Center and related advising offices.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Military_&amp;_Veterans"></a><strong>Military &amp; Veterans</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with any military documents submitted by enrolled students. Records may include individual veteran student records that certify to the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs that the student is eligible for educational benefits, is currently enrolled at the institution in a qualifying curriculum, and is maintaining standards required to receive entitlements, veterans attendance reports, and related forms, documentation, and correspondence.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years (after last activity)</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Name_&amp;_Demographic_Changes"></a><strong>Name &amp; Demographic Changes</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with students' or applicants' name changes, address changes, or other demographic changes reported to the admissions or registrar's offices by students. Records may include letters requesting change in name, name change forms, lists or reports of students with changed names, address change forms, permanent and local address updates, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Registration_&amp;_Tracking_"></a><strong>Registration &amp; Tracking </strong>(see also <a href="#Admissions" title="Admissions">Admissions</a> and <a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic_Standing" title="Academic Standing">Academic Standing</a>)</p>
<p>Records associated with registration and changes in enrollment and admissions for students. Records may include registration forms, registration change forms (add/drop forms), withdrawal forms, audit forms, pass/fail, application for re-admission forms, holds or encumbrances placed on student accounts, and grading basis (unsatisfactory/satisfactory) change forms.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Scholarships"></a><strong>Scholarships</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with the application, recruitment, selection, processing, and awarding of scholarships. Records may include correspondence, applications, disbursement documentation, selection criteria, and related documentation.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Special Academic Programs"></a>Special Academic Programs</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with the progress of students participating in special academic programs. Records may include application documentation, personal information, medical and health documentation, admission and non-acceptance documentation, recommendations and evaluative materials, copies of academic records, counseling and advising notes and documentation, risk release and insurance forms, immigration and citizenship documentation, financial responsibility records, reports; and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Graduation or last date of enrollment</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>7 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Student_Coursework"></a><strong>Student Coursework</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with student mastery in university courses not returned to the student. Records may include examinations and answers, quizzes and answers, homework assignments, course papers, term papers, and essay assignments.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 semester</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Student_Honor"></a><strong>Student Honor</strong></p>
<p>Records document aspects of student honor including ecclesiastical endorsements, violations, research into violations, and actions taken. Records may include student notes, incident reports, evidence, notifications, ecclesiastical endorsements, suspension files, probation files, or case files.</p>
<p><em>Records maintained primarily by the Student Honor Office. Department offices should retain only records that serve immediate administrative purposes. </em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>7 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Student_Organizations"></a><strong>Student Organizations</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with campus student organizations. Records may include annual review forms; minutes; constitutions and bylaws; committee, subcommittee, and task-force records; Student Senate bill and resolution files; budgets; handbooks; officer and member rosters; scrapbooks; photographs; and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held in the office that supports the organization.</em></p>
<p><em>To determine if any of these records should be transferred to Special Collections, see </em><a href="x46982.xml" title="Transfer Guidelines for Organizations"><em>Transfer Guidelines for Records of Student, Faculty, and Staff Organizations</em></a></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Permanent Holdings (see above)</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Student_Well-Being"></a><strong>Student Well-Being</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with incidents, grievances, and other student concerns that do not result in litigation. Incidents and grievances may pertain to academic issues, housing, affirmative action and equal opportunity, student conduct, emergencies, illnesses, and other issues. Records may include emergency notifications, notices of grievance, informal discussion notes, grievance responses, formal hearing notes (including audio tapes), final summary statements, settlement agreements, appeals documentation, incident reports, arbitration files, and related records and correspondence.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Transcript_Requests_&amp;_Authorizations"></a><strong>Transcript Requests &amp; Authorizations</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with the request and order of student's transcripts, as well as document holds on transcripts and academic reporting information placed by the institution for a number of reasons. Records may include transcript order forms, payment receipts, and forms authorizing the holding of academic records and information.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><a name="Verifications"></a><strong>Verifications</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with proving or verifying status and enrollment. Records may include requests for verification of enrollment, education verifications, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Record copy held with Student Records Office.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Completion of activity</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x45982" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
