<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x46358" Name="Permanent Library Holdings Policy" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Permanent Library Holdings Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Permanent Library Holdings Policy for University Records</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20121015T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1 align="center">Permanent Library Holdings Policy for University Records</h1>
<h6 align="center" style="text-align: center;">Office of Special Collections and Records Management, David O. McKay Library, Brigham Young University-Idaho</h6>
<p><strong>I. Introduction</strong></p>
<p><a class="intLink" href="x47637.xml" title="Special Collections" target="_blank">Brigham Young University-Idaho Office of Special Collections and Records Management (SCRM)</a> is the repository of the non-current records of Brigham Young University-Idaho. Its primary role is to document the administrative history of the University through corporate records. SCRM also collects materials that document the activities of students, faculty, and staff at the University. The records begin with the founding of the institution in 1888 and continue to the present.</p>
<p>The permanent library holdings exist to create an institutional memory for Brigham Young University-Idaho and its predecessors. SCRM supports administrative and legal reference as well as research and teaching concerning the history of Brigham Young University-Idaho. It documents the role that Brigham Young University-Idaho has played in the worldwide growth of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and its relationship with the local pioneer community.</p>
<p><strong>II. Position Responsible for Collecting Decisions</strong></p>
<p>The Special Collections Librarians are responsible for filtering and selecting materials to be acquired by SCRM. Campus personnel having records management duties report to Special Collections Librarians.</p>
<p><strong>III. Scope and Focus of Collecting</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>SCRM seeks to support administrative and legal reference in the historic records of the University.</li>
<li>SCRM seeks to support teaching and research through the undergraduate level in the following major areas of emphasis:<ol>
<li>Bannock Stake Academy, Fremont Stake Academy, Ricks Academy, and Ricks Normal College history</li>
<li>Ricks College history</li>
<li>Brigham Young University-Idaho history</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>IV. Priorities and Limitations</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Priorities<ol>
<li>Primary Area of Specialization: Administrative history</li>
<li>Secondary Areas of Specialization<ol>
<li>Faculty (See <a class="intLink" href="x46443.xml" title="Faculty Papers Collecting Policy">Faculty Papers Collecting Policy</a>)</li>
<li>Students</li>
<li>Relationship with The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and the local pioneer community</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Major curricular needs covering the above listed priorities</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Limitations<ol>
<li>SCRM is the corporate archives of Brigham Young University-Idaho and its primary role is documenting the administrative history of the University. This limits time and resources available to document other aspects of the University's history.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>V. General Selection Guidelines</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Treatment of Subject Depth<ol>
<li>SCRM collects the administrative records necessary to document the roles and responsibilities of Brigham Young University-Idaho. SCRM also attempts to collect enough records to support curriculum and undergraduate research into the history of Brigham Young University-Idaho.</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Specific Delimitations<ol>
<li>Physical Format<ol>
<li>Paper-based records: Collected Extensively<ol>
<li>Paper-based records include microfilm.</li>
<li>Imaging and digitization are rigorously done to preserve record information</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Photographs: Collected Selectively<ol>
<li>Photographs required for only a limited time to ensure the completion of a routine action or the preparation of a subsequent record are not collected</li>
<li>Photographs are collected if content within them is easily identifiable or otherwise identified</li>
<li>Photographic content should relate to the office, person, activity, or event of the collection wherein they belong</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Film and audiovisual material: Collected Moderately</li>
<li>Electronic Records: Collected Selectively&nbsp;<ol>
<li>As ability to collect and maintain electronic information grows, more electronic records will be collected by SCRM</li>
<li>Records not collected are maintained on campus servers that are maintained with direction from SCRM</li>
</ol></li>
</ol></li>
<li>Date: Records and manuscripts are collected from the founding of Bannock Stake Academy in 1888 to the present</li>
<li>Geographical focus<ol>
<li>Materials generated at the main campus in Rexburg, Idaho: Collected Extensively</li>
<li>Materials generated in other locations related to Brigham Young University-Idaho: Collected Selectively</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Subject Emphasis<ol>
<li>Bannock Stake Academy, Fremont Stake Academy, Ricks Academy, Ricks Normal College: Collected Extensively</li>
<li>Ricks College<ol>
<li>Administration: Collected Extensively</li>
<li>Faculty: Collected Selectively</li>
<li>Students and student organizations: Collected Selectively</li>
<li>Campus activities (performing arts, athletics, symposia, etc.): Collected Selectively</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Brigham Young University-Idaho<ol>
<li>Administration: Collected Extensively</li>
<li>Faculty: Collected Selectively</li>
<li>Students and student organizations: Collected Moderately</li>
<li>Campus activities (performing arts, symposia, etc.): Collected Moderately</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Languages<ol>
<li>English: Collected Extensively</li>
<li>Languages other than English: Collected Selectively</li>
</ol></li>
</ol></li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>VI. Deaccessioning Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>A Special Collections Librarian may present a proposal to deaccession materials to the Library Director. Materials may be deaccessioned if they do not comply with the Brigham Young University-Idaho Permanent Library Holdings Policy for University Records or if they are duplicative of material already in permanent library holdings.</p>
<p><strong>VII. Storage and Access</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>SCRM houses non-current records in printed form and provides access, when appropriate, to reading room patrons.</li>
<li>Department offices are their own records centers and hold their current and non-current records. Offices must follow the <a class="intLink" href="x46258.xml" title="CRS">Campus Retention Schedule </a>and be familiar with<ol>
<li>The length of time a particular category of records must be maintained</li>
<li>The final disposition of a record through destruction, digitization, or transfer to SCRM</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Electronic Records<ol>
<li>Special Collections Librarians have access to all digital collections across campus.</li>
<li>Special Collections Librarians cooperate with librarians and appropriate IT staff to ensure digital preservation and access as necessary.</li>
<li>While some server space will be maintained by library staff for access to selected records, not all campus electronic records will be collected by SCRM.</li>
<li>Other records should be maintained on appropriate campus servers following guidance from the Special Collections Librarians and IT staff. This pertains to born digital and digitized information.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>VIII. Restrictions</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Records may be open to, or restricted from, use by the general public depending on the purposes and audience for which they were originally created, the presence or absence of confidential information, and the age of the records.</li>
<li>Restrictions result from<ol>
<li>Privacy and confidentiality concerns (apply to most University records)</li>
<li>Physical condition (fragile, etc.) of material</li>
<li>The value of material</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Official departmental personnel of the department having original custody can access records of their office in permanent library holdings.</li>
<li>
<p>Access to restricted items is subject to approval by the College Dean over the department or other administratively authorized personnel.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>IX. Cooperation with other Institutions</strong></p>
<p>Brigham Young University-Idaho works cooperatively with other Church-affiliated institutions and institutions in Idaho to ensure that the history of Brigham Young University-Idaho is adequately documented.</p>
<p><strong>X. Cooperation with other Record Keepers</strong></p>
<p>The Brigham Young University-Idaho Special Collections Librarians work cooperatively with other librarians in the David O. McKay Library and campus personnel appointed to records management duties to ensure that the history of Brigham Young University-Idaho is adequately documented. Special Collections Librarians work particularly closely with the IT staff to ensure that electronic materials are properly stored and, as deemed necessary, made accessible.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x89348" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x45982" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
