<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46453" Name="FAQ test" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ test</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ test</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<link href="http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Cambo" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
<script src="https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.7.1/jquery.min.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<script type="text/javascript">
window.jQuery || document.write('<script src="prebuilt/stylenew/js/libs/jquery-1.7.min.js" _mce_src="prebuilt/stylenew/js/libs/jquery-1.7.min.js" src="prebuilt/stylenew/js/libs/jquery-1.7.min.js" _mce_src="prebuilt/stylenew/js/libs/jquery-1.7.min.js"><\/script>')
</script>
<script src="prebuilt/stylenew/js/mylibs/scrolling_events_bar.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<script src="Documents/student-records-and-registration/ibox2.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<link href="Documents/student-records-and-registration/srrcss3.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
<div id="faq1" style="display: none;">
<h3>How do I search/register for classes?</h3>
<p>Log in to my.byui.edu, then click the blue Student tab at the top of the page. From there, scroll down the page and click the Add/Drop or Course Search button. You can fill in the search fields to find the specific course(s) you want to find or add. NOTE: If you do not have log-in information, you can go to <a class="underline" href="www.byui.edu">www.byui.edu</a>, then click Quick Links, then click Class Schedule. This option brings you to the Course Search page where you can simply look for courses, but you won&rsquo;t be able to add unless you have a username, password, and valid admission status.</p>
<h3>Why don't I have any add/drop boxes?</h3>
<p>If you do not have any add/drop boxes, this usually means one of the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>You have a hold on your account that prevents registration (adding/dropping) until you resolve the hold;</li>
<li>You do not have registration clearance, and you need to call the Student Records and Registration Office to obtain clearance; or</li>
<li>You are not currently admitted to BYU&ndash;Idaho.</li>
</ol>
<h3>What if my son/daughter is on a mission and needs to register?</h3>
<p>Your son or daughter can designate you to register for classes for them, as long as they release their username and password to you so you can access the registration website.</p>
<h3>What if I won&rsquo;t be able to access a computer on my priority registration date? Can I register over the phone or in person?</h3>
<p>Registration needs to be done by students online, whether they visit a local library or internet caf&eacute; for internet access, or they are welcome to come to campus and use the computers available here. If you require specific accommodations for a disability, please contact the Disability Services Center to determine your eligibility: (208) 496- 4283.</p>
<h3>What if I don&rsquo;t know my username and/or password?</h3>
<p>On all of the log-in screens, you can click the &ldquo;Forgot password&rdquo; link to fill in some personal information fields in order to receive your username and/or password. For assistance, please contact the Computer Help Desk: (208) 496-9000.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq2" style="display: none;">
<h3>How do I know when I can register?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>What if I miss my designated registration time?</h3>
<p>If a student misses their designated registration time, they may still register for classes but risk less availability of class selection. Students can add classes to their schedules through the first week of the semester.</p>
<h3>How do I know how many credits I have?</h3>
<p>Students can log into my.byui.edu, click the Student tab, and on the left side of the page, click the gray Unofficial Transcript tab to pull up their academic history. This will indicate how many credits a student has earned, then the student can add their currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits (if any) to this total to determine how many credits they have to determine their priority registration date.</p>
<h3>Do my currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits count towards my priority registration date?</h3>
<p>Yes.</p>
<h3>Do my transfer credits count towards my priority registration date?</h3>
<p>Yes, as long as your transfer credits are recorded on your BYU&ndash;Idaho transcript. Transfer courses must be completed (with final grades) and recorded on your BYU&ndash; Idaho transcript for them to calculate into your priority registration date. Transfer credits that you are currently enrolled in cannot be calculated into this date.</p>
<h3>Why do freshmen register last?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level. Seniors, juniors, and sophomores have increasingly fewer class options as they advance in their academic careers, thereby necessitating their need to register earlier and have top pick of the classes they need in order to graduate. Freshmen have a wide range of options between all of the Foundations courses and major courses they still need to take, so they register after everyone else for this reason.</p>
<h3>Can I register for classes if I&rsquo;m on Academic Warning?</h3>
<p>Yes, you may register for classes while on Academic Warning. Please visit this website for more information: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm</a>.</p>
<h3>Can I register for classes if I&rsquo;m on Academic Probation?</h3>
<p>Yes, but you may only register for up to 12 credits. Please visit this website for more information: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm.</a></p>
<h3>Can I register for classes if I&rsquo;m on Academic Suspension?</h3>
<p>No. You must fulfill the terms of your suspension before you will be eligible to register for any classes (including night and online classes) at BYU&ndash;Idaho. Please visit this website for more information: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm</a>.</p>
<h3>Can I register for classes if I am no longer admitted?</h3>
<p>No. You must be admitted as a type of student (e.g., Day, Part-time, Continuing Education, etc.) to be able to register for any academic classes offered at BYU&ndash;Idaho.</p>
<h3>How many credits can I register for?</h3>
<ul>
<li>12 credits are required to be considered a full-time student</li>
<li>14 credits are required to be eligible for university scholarship</li>
<li>15 credits are required to graduate in eight semesters or four years and for the Fast Grad program.</li>
<li>21 credit hours is the maximum a student can take.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Do I have to take at least 12 credits?</h3>
<p>No, students do not have to take at least 12 credits. To remain admitted to BYU&ndash; Idaho, students must take a least one class during their on-track semesters. To be considered a full-time student, however, students must be registered for at least 12 credit hours per semester.</p>
<h3>Can I take more than 21 credits during a single semester (or more than 10.0 credits during a block/term)?</h3>
<p>Twenty-one credit hours is the recommended maximum. Students must obtain permission from the Student Records and Registration Office to take more than 21 credits per semester or 10 credits per block/term. Students must demonstrate a successful academic history to qualify (e.g., a cumulative 3.0 GPA or higher, a history of high course loads in 2+ consecutive semesters, etc.).</p>
<h3>What if I can only take a few classes? How many credits do I need to keep my admission status?</h3>
<p>On-track students need to take at least one class (or at least 0.5 credits) to maintain their admission status. Half credits are charged the same as one full credit.</p>
<h3>I think I may want to audit one of my classes. What does auditing a class mean?</h3>
<p>Students who audit a class are not responsible for attendance, daily preparations or examinations, and no grade is reported or recorded on the permanent record. Tuition for audit classes is assessed on the same basis as for credit classes. An &ldquo;I&rdquo; grade may not be made up by repeating the class as an audit. Departments have the right to refuse to allow students to audit individual courses. Registered students who drop all credit classes and only have audit classes remaining are considered withdrawn from the University effective the latest drop 5 date of the non-audit classes. Students will need to re-apply through the Admissions Office for the next semester. Compliance with deadlines is required, unless a deferment is obtained.</p>
<h3>How do I change my enrollment in a class to audit?</h3>
<p>Students must first register for the class for credit and then contact the Student Records and Registration Office by emailing, registration@byui.edu, to change the course to audit. Students may not change class status from credit to audit or from audit to credit after the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W.&rdquo;</p>
<h3>I&rsquo;m in a variable credit class and need to change how many credits I&rsquo;m enrolled in. How do I do that?</h3>
<p>Students may contact the Student Records and Registration Office for assistance with changing their credit amount in a variable credit class. Please note that students may increase the amount of credits they are enrolled in at any time in the semester; however, students may only decrease the amount of credits they&rsquo;re enrolled in as long as the decrease request is before the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W.&rdquo;</p>
<h3>I need to switch from one section to another (e.g., from FDENG 101-02 to FDENG 101-03). How do I do that?</h3>
<p>If a student is switching from one section to another before the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W,&rdquo; all they need to do is drop the section they&rsquo;re in and then add the section they want. They may need an instructor authorization to be able to add the section they want. If a student is switching from one section to another after the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W,&rdquo; the instructor of the class they want to add needs to contact the Student Records and Registration Office for assistance so the student does not receive an inaccurate W grade for the section they drop. NOTE: This only applies to students switching from one section to another of the same course. This does not apply to students who are switching into a different course (e.g., switching from a lower level class to a higher level class, or vice versa). If switching from a different course, the W grade will be applied to the class dropped if it is after the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a W.</p>
<h3>I&rsquo;m enrolled in one religion class, but I&rsquo;d like to add a second one. When can I do so?</h3>
<p>Students who wish to take two religion classes in a given term may attempt to do so after the first day of the class (or block) if there is available seating and they have obtained clearance to do so from the Religion Department Chairman. Students can then add the course to their schedules, or, if necessary, meet with the instructor of that class to receive any needed authorization(s). Students who wish to take more than two religion classes in a given term must obtain clearance from the Religion Department Chairman. The Chairman then contacts the Student Records and Registration Office to register the student for the class.6</p>
<h3>I want to take classes during first block (or second block) only. How many credits do I need to be considered a full-time student?</h3>
<p>The full-time equivalency for block registration is 6 credit hours.</p>
<h3>Can I get an excused absence for University activities, sickness, or other personal emergencies?</h3>
<p>Students are responsible for class attendance. No absences, whether approved by the University for participation in University-sponsored activities or necessitated by sickness or other personal emergencies, are &ldquo;excused&rdquo; in the sense that the student is relieved from class work assigned during the absence. To ensure continuity, students must make up missed work. In most cases, repeated absences will result in a lower grade or failure.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq3" style="display: none;">
<h3>I want to add a specific class, but it&rsquo;s full. What do I do?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class that is full, they need to either keep checking back for openings, or they can contact the course instructor. The instructor may, at his/her discretion, grant a Capacity Authorization to the student to add the full class or some instructors have waiting lists.</p>
<h3>I want to add a specific class, but I have not taken its prerequisite(s). Can I still take the class?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class, but they haven&rsquo;t met the prerequisite(s), they may contact the instructor and request a Course Requisite Authorization; however, it is the instructor&rsquo;s decision whether he/she will (or can) allow students to add certain classes without having taken the prerequisite(s).</p>
<h3>I want to add a specific class, but it overlaps with another class I&rsquo;m already registered for (e.g., there is a 15-minute time conflict). Can I still take the class?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class, but it conflicts with another one of their classes, they may contact the course instructor for the class they want to add and request a Schedule Conflict Authorization; however, it is the instructor&rsquo;s decision whether he/she will allow students to add their class and accommodate time conflicts.</p>
<h3>I want to add a specific class, but I do not meet the requirements (e.g., 2.5 GPA, junior standing, instructor authorization required, etc.). Can I still take the class?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class, but they haven&rsquo;t met the requirement(s), they may contact the instructor and request a Course Requirement Authorization; however, it is the instructor&rsquo;s decision whether he/she will (or can) allow students to add certain classes without having met the requirement(s).</p>
<h3>The instructor has authorized me to add a class, but I still can&rsquo;t add it. What do I do?</h3>
<p>There are many reasons that could keep a course authorization from working. Such reasons include the following: 1) You are trying to add a different section from what the instructor has authorized you to add; 2) You have only been authorized for the Capacity Authorization when in fact you may also need a Course Requirement Authorization or other authorization to be able to add that section; 3) You are not able to add the class because you are an off-track student trying to add a DAY section or vice-versa; 4) There is a hold on your account preventing you from registering (adding/dropping) classes.</p>
<h3>I&rsquo;ve contacted the instructor about an authorization, but it&rsquo;s been several days, and I&rsquo;ve received no response. What do I do?</h3>
<p>A follow-up phone call or e-mail sometimes helps you get in touch with an instructor. If after several attempts you still cannot reach him/her, you may contact the department secretary for that instructor&rsquo;s department to see if she can assist you in contacting the instructor.8</p>
<h3>I can&rsquo;t find a specific class that I want to add. What do I do?</h3>
<p>Make sure you have cleared all of your search criteria and conducted more general searches (e.g., if you&rsquo;re specifically looking for a math class, simply search under the Mathematics discipline; don&rsquo;t search for anything more specific than that). If you still cannot find it, it&rsquo;s possible that the specific course you&rsquo;re looking for is not available this semester or has been discontinued. You may contact the Student Records and Registration Office for assistance.</p>
<h3>I&rsquo;m trying to add a class, but there are no add boxes next to the classes. What&rsquo;s wrong?</h3>
<p>If you do not have any add boxes, this usually means one of the following: 1) You have a hold on your account that prevents registration (adding/dropping) until you resolve the hold; 2) You do not have registration clearance, and you need to call the Student Records and Registration Office to obtain clearance; or 3) You are not currently admitted to BYU&ndash;Idaho.</p>
<h3>Can I add a class if I have a hold on my account?</h3>
<p>No. Most holds prevent students from registering (adding/dropping classes) until they resolve the hold. Keep in mind, however, that the following holds do not prohibit registration: Academic Warning (WARN), Academic Probation (PROB), Achieving Academic Success Workshop (AASW), No School Address (NOLO), Academic Advising Plan (PLAN), Endorsement Notification (SHWA), and Invalid U.S. SSN (SSN) holds.</p>
<h3>Can I add a class after the add deadline?</h3>
<p>Yes, as long as you have received at least a Course Requirement Authorization, in addition to any other authorizations you may need, from the instructor.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq4" style="display: none;">
<h3>I need to drop a class, but will I be charged for dropping?</h3>
<p>No. We no longer charge students a fee for dropping classes.</p>
<h3>I need to drop a class, but it&rsquo;s after the deadline to drop classes without a W grade. What is a W grade and how does it affect my transcript?</h3>
<ul>
<li>W grades are placed on your academic record (transcript) if you drop a class anytime after the 22 nd day in a semester (or after the 15 th day in a block/term) up until the final drop deadline, for any reason.</li>
<li>W grades are NOT calculated into your grade point average (GPA).</li>
<li>W grades remain on your transcript even if you retake the class at a later date.</li>
<li>W grades are considered non-progress grades and are calculated into the 75% progress requirement.</li>
<li>If you are receiving Federal Financial Aid, you must check with that office to determine how W grades affect your eligibility.</li>
</ul>
<h3>I need to drop a class, but there are no drop check-boxes next to the class. What's wrong?</h3>
<p>If you do not have any drop boxes, this usually means one of the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>You have a hold on your account that prevents registration (adding/dropping) until you resolve the hold;</li>
<li>You do not have registration clearance, and you need to call the Student Records and Registration Office to obtain clearance; or</li>
<li>It is past the deadline to be able to drop or withdraw from classes.</li>
</ol>
<h3>I need to drop a class, and I want to know how much tuition I&rsquo;ll receive back. How do I find out?</h3>
<p>Students need to pay attention to the posted registration deadlines for each semester/term to determine whether they will receive a full tuition refund or pro-rated tuition refund, based on when they are dropping their class(es). Students may contact the Accounting Office for more information about tuition and refunds: (208) 496-1900.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq5" style="display: none;">
<h3>The DAY class I want to add is full, but there are seats open in the CTED (Continuing Education or night) section. Can I add a CTED class as an on-track student?</h3>
<p>No, on-track students CANNOT add CTED (or night) sections. There are no exceptions.</p>
<h3>I won&rsquo;t be able to be on campus this semester. Can I take just ONLN classes?</h3>
<p>Yes, students can take a full course load of ONLN classes if they wish.</p>
<h3>I won&rsquo;t be able to take any classes this semester, but I want to attend during my next ontrack semester. What can I do to keep my admission status so I don&rsquo;t have to re-apply?</h3>
<p>We encourage students to do everything they can to arrange their schedules in such a way that they are able to attend their on-track semesters as full-time students. Taking a single class during your on-track semester to &ldquo;hold your spot&rdquo; is discouraged, because it extends the amount of time it will take for you to graduate, and it prevents other students from attending BYU&ndash;Idaho because you&rsquo;re taking up a spot that may have otherwise been used by a student who takes advantage of their time here. We realize that students encounter extenuating circumstances that prevent them from taking classes during one of their on-track semesters, and in those situations, students may request a semester deferment from the Admissions Office: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/admissions/current-students/deferments-time-off">http://www.byui.edu/admissions/current-students/deferments-time-off</a></p>
</div>
<div id="faq6" style="display: none;">
<h3>Can I register for classes during my off-track?</h3>
<p>Yes, off-track students can take CTED (Continuing Education or night) and ONLN (online) classes during their off-track. Off-track students can take up to 21.0 credits of CTED and ONLN classes, if they wish.</p>
<h3>When can I register for CTED or ONLN classes?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level, no matter whether you&rsquo;re on-track or off-track. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>The class I want to take is not offered as a CTED or ONLN section. Is there any way I can take the DAY section as an off-track student?</h3>
<p>If you are off-track and have completed 60 credits and at least 6 BYU-I credits, you can register for 300-400 level DAY as well as CTED and ONLN sections starting 24 business hours before the semester starts. If you have not met those requirements then off-track students CANNOT take DAY sections. The only other way off-track students can take DAY classes is if they get on Fast Grad or if they receive some other track override from the Admissions Office. If off-track students get placed on Fast Grad or receive a track override, then they are eligible to take only DAY or ONLN classes, not CTED classes.</p>
<h3>I want to drop all the classes I&rsquo;m taking during my off-track. Will doing this withdraw me from BYU&ndash;Idaho?</h3>
<p>No, unless you choose the option to withdraw from BYU&ndash;Idaho on the withdrawal page. Otherwise, when you&rsquo;re withdrawing from classes during your off-track, you would just be withdrawn from the semester.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq7" style="display: none;">
<h3>When can I register for classes?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level, no matter whether you&rsquo;re on-track or part-time. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash; Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>What types of classes can I register for?</h3>
<p>Part-time students can register for any combination of DAY, CTED, or ONLN classes.</p>
<h3>How many credits can I take?</h3>
<p>Part-time students can take up to 9.0 credits per semester. There are no exceptions.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq8" style="display: none;">
<h3>What is the Continuing Education Program?</h3>
<p>Continuing Education Evening School classes are offered during the Fall and Winter Semesters and are available for those that are 1) seeking to begin college, 2) seeking to return to college, or 3) a current off-track student wanting additional credits. For more information, please visit <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/ce/evening/">http://www.byui.edu/ce/evening/</a>.</p>
<h3>When can I register for classes?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level, no matter whether you&rsquo;re off-track or a Continuing Education student. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>What types of classes can I register for?</h3>
<p>Continuing Education students can register for CTED (Continuing Education or night) or ONLN (online) classes.</p>
<h3>How many credits can I take?</h3>
<p>Continuing Education students can take up to 21.0 credits per semester.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq9" style="display: none;">
<h3>What types of online degree programs are offered?</h3>
<p>BYU&ndash;Idaho currently offers the following online degree programs: Associate in General Studies (AGS), Bachelor of University Studies (BUS), and Bachelor of Science in Applied Management (BSAM). Please visit this website for more information: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/OD/">http://www.byui.edu/OD/</a>.</p>
<h3>When can I register for classes?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level, no matter whether you&rsquo;re on-track or an online degree student. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>What types of classes can I register for?</h3>
<p>Online Degree students can take online (ONLN) classes and Continuing Education (CTED or night) classes.</p>
<h3>How many credits can I take?</h3>
<p>Online Degree students can take up to 21.0 credits per semester.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq10" style="display: none;">
<h3>What is the Pathway Program?</h3>
<p>BYU&ndash;Idaho and Institutes of Religion have received permission from the Church Board of Education to bring interactive online courses to select Institute buildings on a trial basis. The goal is to provide a pathway to educational opportunities to young adults regardless of where they live or where they may ultimately receive their degree. For more information, please visit this website: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/pathway/">http://www.byui.edu/pathway/</a>.</p>
<h3>Who is eligible to apply for the Pathway Program?</h3>
<p>Please visit this website for information about eligibility for the Pathway Program: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/pathway/apply.htm">http://www.byui.edu/pathway/apply.htm</a>.</p>
<h3>When can I register for classes?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level, no matter whether you&rsquo;re on-track or a Pathway Program student. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>What types of classes can I register for?</h3>
<p>Pathway students may register only for Academic Start (ACST) courses and any other courses approved in the Academic Start outline: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/pathway/assets/documents/Academic%20Pathway.pdf">http://www.byui.edu/pathway/assets/documents/Academic%20Pathway.pdf</a>.</p>
<h3>How many credits can I take?</h3>
<p>Pathway students may register for five credits during each semester as outlined in the Academic Start program (<a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/pathway/assets/documents/Academic%20Pathway.pdf">http://www.byui.edu/pathway/assets/documents/Academic%20Pathway.pdf</a>). Beyond Academic Start, students may apply to become matriculated students and work with their advisors on how many credits they can take from then on.</p>
</div>
<div id="faq11" style="display: none;">
<h3>What is the Prospective Missionary Program (PMP)?</h3>
<p>PMP is a BYU&ndash;Idaho academic program to serve potential missionaries prior to their missions. It enables students to attend specific classes during their first off-track semester. It does not allow students to register for regular day school classes or change their currently assigned track. For more information, please visit this website: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/ce/pmp/">http://www.byui.edu/ce/pmp/</a>.</p>
<h3>Who is eligible to apply for PMP?</h3>
<p>PMP is for admitted students of BYU&ndash;Idaho who are either on the Winter/Spring or the Spring/Fall track. After applying for PMP, students must then also register for classes. For more information, please visit this website: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/ce/pmp/">http://www.byui.edu/ce/pmp/</a>.</p>
<h3>When can I register for classes?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level, no matter whether you&rsquo;re on-track or a PMP student. Credits earned plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash; Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration credit count.</p>
<h3>What types of classes can I register for?</h3>
<p>PMP students will be registered for their designated PMP courses. PMP students may also register for CTED (Continuing Education or night) or ONLN (online) classes.</p>
<h3>How many credits can I take?</h3>
<p>PMP students can take up to 21.0 credits per semester.</p>
</div>
<img alt="FAQ Banner" height="140" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/FAQ1.jpg" width="510" /> <img alt="Question Mark Logo" height="140" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/FAQ1.png" width="167" /> <br />
<div id="bar"><img alt="bar" height="4" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/bar1.png" width="710" /></div>
<div class="sectionstwo">
<div class="tabz"><a class="current" href="x43953.xml">Registration</a> <a href="x46090.xml">Transfer Evaluation</a> <a href="x46089.xml">Enrollment Verification</a> <a href="x46088.xml">Graduation</a></div>
<div class="box visible">
<ul>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq1" rel="ibox" title="How to Register FAQ">How to Register FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="x46660.xml" title="General Registration FAQ">General Registration FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="x46680.xml" title="Adding Classes / Instructor Authorizations FAQ">Adding Classes / Instructor Authorizations FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq4" rel="ibox" title="Dropping Classes FAQ">Dropping Classes FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq5" rel="ibox" title="On-track Students FAQ">On-track Students FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq6" rel="ibox" title="Off-track Students FAQ">Off-track Students FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq7" rel="ibox" title="Part-time Students FAQ">Part-time Students FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq8" rel="ibox" title="Continuing Education Students FAQ">Continuing Education Students FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq9" rel="ibox" title="Online Programs FAQ">Online Programs FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq10" rel="ibox" title="Pathway Students (Academic Start) FAQ">Pathway Students (Academic Start) FAQs</a></li>
<li><a href="student-records-and-registration/faq-test#faq11" rel="ibox" title="PMP Students (Prospective Missionary) FAQ">PMP Students (Prospective Missionary) FAQs</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="span-18 last" id="events_bar_horizontal">
<div class="span-18 last" id="window">
<div id="events_bar_control"><span class="prev">&nbsp;</span><span class="next">&nbsp;</span></div>
<div id="pane"><!--THE BEGING OF THE EVENTS-->
<div class="single_event"><a class="event_link"><span class="event_date"><span class="cal_day">31</span><br /><span class="cal_month">Oct</span></span></a>
<p style="color: #303030;">First block final grades due by 12:00 noon by faculty.</p>
</div>
<div class="single_event"><a class="event_link"><span class="event_date"><span class="cal_day">1</span><br /><span class="cal_month">Nov</span></span></a>
<p style="color: #303030;">First block final grades available to students online at my.byui.edu</p>
</div>
<div class="single_event"><a class="event_link"><span class="event_date"><span class="cal_day">3</span><br /><span class="cal_month">Nov</span></span></a>
<p style="color: #303030;">Last day to withdraw completely from Fall Semester Classes and receive a pro-rated tuition refund.</p>
</div>
<div class="single_event"><a class="event_link"><span class="event_date"><span class="cal_day">5</span><br /><span class="cal_month">Nov</span></span></a>
<p style="color: #303030;">Last day to withdraw from Full Semester Classes and receive a "W" grade and not the grade earned.</p>
</div>
<div class="single_event"><a class="event_link"><span class="event_date"><span class="cal_day">5</span><br /><span class="cal_month">Nov</span></span></a>
<p style="color: #303030;">Winter Registration opens.</p>
</div>
<div class="single_event"><a class="event_link"><span class="event_date"><span class="cal_day">15</span><br /><span class="cal_month">Nov</span></span></a>
<p style="color: #303030;">Dec 2011 grad app deadline. Must apply for names to be printed in the program and be eligible for honors</p>
</div>
<!--THE END OF THE EVENTS--></div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="email" style="display: none;">
<p>For any questions please email us at <a href="mailto:registrar@byui.edu"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">registrar@byui.edu</span></a></p>
</div>
<div id="phone" style="display: none;">
<p>For any questions please call us at (208)-496-1000</p>
</div>
<img alt="Bar" height="2" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/bottomBar.jpg" width="710" />
<div class="barb"><img alt="Bar" height="2" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/bottomBar.jpg" width="710" /></div>
<div id="bottomContact">
<ul>
<li><img alt="Email Link" height="15" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/envelope.png" width="23" /><a href="#email" rel="ibox" title="Email Information"> Email Us</a></li>
<li><img alt="Phone Link" height="15" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/phone.png" width="23" /><a href="#phone" rel="ibox" title="Phone Information"> Call Us</a></li>
<li><img alt="Visit Link" height="15" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/visit.png" width="23" /><a href="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/byuidahoMap.jpg" rel="ibox"> Visit Us</a></li>
<li><img alt="Facebook Link" height="16" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/facebook.png" width="16" /><a href="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/SecondLevelPage/FacebookInfo.png" rel="ibox"> facebook</a></li>
<li><img alt="Live Chat Link" height="16" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/livechat.png" width="18" /><a href="https://server.iad.liveperson.net/hc/1132447/?cmd=file&amp;file=visitorWantsToChat&amp;site=1132447&amp;byhref=1&amp;SESSIONVAR!skill=SRR&amp;imageUrl=https://web.byui.edu/admissions/liveperson/large" onclick="window.open('https://server.iad.liveperson.net/hc/1132447/?cmd=file&amp;file=visitorWantsToChat&amp;site=1132447&amp;byhref=1&amp;SESSIONVAR!skill=SRR&amp;imageUrl=https://web.byui.edu/admissions/liveperson/large&amp;referrer='+escape(document.location),'chat1132447','width=472,height=320');return false;" target="chat1132447"> Live Chat</a></li>
<li><img alt="Site Index Link" height="17" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Student Record and Registration/HomePage/index.png" width="18" /><a href="x43952.xml"> Index</a></li>
</ul>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17143" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
