<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46502" Name="Hazardous Waste Management" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Hazardous Waste Management</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Hazardous Waste Management</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left"><strong>Hazardous       Waste Management &amp; Emergency Response</strong></p>
<p align="left"><strong>&nbsp; (HAZWOPER)</strong></p>
<p align="left">&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>General University Policy</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>The purpose of this program is to inform       faculty and employees,  that the university is complying       with EPA requirements for  preparing and maintaining a Hazardous Waste       Contingency Plan under  the hazardous waste regulations, Title 40, Code of       Federal  Regulations 265.50-.56 by providing a written plan that describes        the equipment, human resources and procedures for responding to a        discharge of hazardous waste.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho has developed this program to handle       hazardous wastes  at various campus sites, because they can pose       significant safety  and health risks to students and employees, if not       handled  properly.</p>
<p>This program applies to all pertinent       operations of the  university where students or employees may be exposed to       potential  discharge or spill situations involving hazardous waste under        normal working conditions or during an emergency situation.</p>
<p>The contingency plan is designed to minimize       hazards to human  health or the environment from fires, explosions or any       unplanned  sudden or non-sudden release of hazardous waste or hazardous       waste  constituents to air, soil or surface water. The provisions of the        plan are to be carried out immediately whenever there is a fire,  explosion       or release of hazardous waste or hazardous waste  constituents that could       threaten human health or the environment.</p>
<p>The university generates hazardous wastes which       are governed  either under conditionally exempt small quantity generator       (less  than 100 kilograms per month) regulations or&nbsp; small quantity generator  (100-1000 kilograms per month)       regulations, depending on the type  and volume of hazardous waste generated       in a given period of  time.&nbsp; Hazardous wastes are accumulated from       generation sites on  campus and&nbsp; stored temporarily at the university       hazardous  materials storage area on First West,&nbsp; pending timely       disposal  pursuant to EPA regulations. The institution is not a       permitted  transportation, storage and disposal (TSD) facility.</p>
<p><strong>Routine university hazardous waste       generation sites, materials and responsible parties include:</strong></p>
<p>A.&nbsp; Physical Plant Paint Shop--Waste       paints and solvents--Lead Painter</p>
<p>B.&nbsp; Physical Plant Custodial Department--       Off Specification cleaning materials--Custodial Manager</p>
<p>C.&nbsp; Chemistry Department-- Waste solvents       and off specification chemicals-- Chemicals Inventory Manager</p>
<p>D. Theater Department--waste paints and       solvents-- Scene shop construction manager</p>
<p>E.&nbsp; Biology Department--Off specification       chemicals--Biology Department Chairperson</p>
<p>F.&nbsp; Art Department--Waste paints and       solvents--Art Department Chairperson</p>
<p><strong>Other university entities that may       occasionally  generate hazardous wastes are also instructed to follow the        procedures listed in this Toxic and Hazardous Wastes Contingency Plan.</strong></p>
<p>General hazardous waste generators on       campus shall be  instructed and equipped to accumulate up to,       but no more that 55  gallons of&nbsp; waste at their respective generation       points.&nbsp;  Satellite location containers should be labeled as hazardous        waste.&nbsp; When containers reach capacity, generators shall promptly notify  the       safety office (496-2457) which will then transfer, within 3  days, the wastes       to the contiguous First West Hazardous Materials  Temporary Storage Area for profiling, bulking and packaging for  disposal.       Bulk&nbsp; accumulations shall then be transported off campus  for disposal by contracted       and licensed TSD companies within 270  days from the start of accumulation       at the First West Storage  Area.</p>
<p>University faculty or employees who plan to       discard solid  waste, but are not certain whether or not the waste is       hazardous,  shall promptly (within 30 days) notify the safety office (496-2457) for  analysis       of the waste and determination of any possible hazardous  components.&nbsp;       Possible hazardous wastes shall not be disposed of  without prior analysis       and authorization by the university safety  office.&nbsp; Proper storage       containers and labels can be obtained from  the university safety office.</p>
<p>The university encourages any suggestions that       employees may  have for improving the Hazardous Waste Written Contingency       Plan,  as the institution is committed to developing and maintaining an        effective plan. The university strives for clear understanding, safe        behavior and involvement in the plan from every operational level.</p>
<p><strong>Administrative Duties</strong></p>
<p>The university Safety Office is responsible for       the development  and maintenance of the hazardous waste written contingency       plan.  Copies of the written plan may be obtained from the Safety Office,        Physical Plant Room 136 and on the BYU-Idaho Intranet site under        Employees/Safety Office/Policies and Procedures/Hazardous Waste.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Brigham Young University-Idaho, in care of the       university  president, is the owner or operator of campus facilities       and  properties. The Office of Safety and Fire Protection is responsible for  ensuring       that the written plan is complete, kept up to date, and  made available to       appropriate authorities. The plan is available  to the BYU-Idaho University       Police, the City of Rexburg Police  Department, the Rexburg Fire       Department, Madison Memorial Hospital  and Idaho Bureau of Disaster       Services as well as to all  employees, students and community patrons of       the university.</p>
<p><strong>Emergency Equipment and Procedures</strong></p>
<p>It is the policy of the university to operate       the campus in a  safe and responsible manner. University operations are       continually  reviewed to minimize the possibility of a fire, explosion, or       an  accidental release of a hazardous materials or waste. The university has  an       emergency fire plan accessible to all students and employees  on the Safety       Office web page.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Notification</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Because of the nature of the hazardous waste       the university  generates, facilities are equipped with alarm systems which       are  capable of providing immediate emergency evacuation notification to        students and employees. BYU-Idaho facilities are protected by smoke        detectors, heat detectors, fire alarm pull stations and emergency        telephones which are interconnected to the central computerized  alarm       system which reports to and is monitored continuously by  University Police       dispatch personnel.</p>
<p>In the event of a major hazardous       materials or waste release        or other emergency, persons should immediately activate an alarm  system,       notify the University Police communications center by  calling <strong>911</strong> on       a campus telephone and evacuate  the area of the spill.&nbsp; A police officer       will be immediately  dispatched to initially manage the scene and other       emergency  response personnel will be dispatched as needed.&nbsp; In the event of       a  major emergency caused by a       hazardous materials or waste spill or  release, the responding police       officer or safety officer will  immediately advise the university police communications       center to  initiate hazardous       incident command procedures and insure that  established emergency       response, containment, disposal and  decontamination procedures are       implemented in a timely and  effective manner. After determining that the       facility has had a  release, fire or explosion that threatens human health       or the  environment, the university police communications       officer shall  immediately initiate notification of the Rexburg Fire Department        (359-3010), the Rexburg Police Department (359-3020), the Madison County        Sheriffs Department (359-3008), and the Idaho Bureau of Disaster  Services       (745-8641). The respective law enforcement agencies will  notify       appropriate government officials and convene emergency  operations centers       if warranted.</p>
<p>In the event of       a small, contained release of hazardous  materials or waste, the safety       office can be contacted directly at  496-2457 or through the University       Police       communications  center at 496-3000. In either case, the safety officer will        promptly respond and facilitate containment, clean up and proper  disposal.       Safety Office personnel are trained and certified in  hazardous waste operations       and emergency response (HAZWOPER).&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Equipment</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The        university's fire control equipment consists of fire  extinguishers  located throughout       buildings; sprinkler systems  installed in many, but not all  buildings; fire hose cabinets are also  located throughout many of the&nbsp;       facilities. Spill control  equipment consists of a variety of       absorbent materials and  containers for small spills which are  available       from the Safety  Office. The Rexburg Fire Department will be  summoned to       deal with  larger containment issues and the state emergency  response team        (Idaho State Police 525-7277) will be summoned in the event of a  major  hazardous       materials incident. Decontamination control equipment  consists of       disposable coveralls, decontamination tubs and barrels  for  disposal of       contaminated material.</p>
<ul>
<li>Personal Protective Equipment</li>
</ul>
<p>Emergency response personnel shall use appropriate personal  protective       equipment for each assigned job.&nbsp; The following  personal protective       equipment shall be available from the Safety  Office for use depending on the requirements of the       situation and  the training of the individual response personnel:</p>
<ol>
<li>Positive pressure self-contained breathing apparatus; </li>
<li>Chemical resistant gloves and boots; </li>
<li>Air purifying half-mask or full-face respirator with appropriate           cartridges; </li>
<li>Chemical resistant total body coverall Tyvek suits; </li>
<li>Chemical resistant goggles </li>
</ol> 
<ul>
<li>
<p>Maintenance</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Procedures have been established for regularly       checking and  maintaining water pressure and volume to make sure that they       are  sufficiently adequate to supply water hose streams, automatic        sprinklers or water spray systems. The Safety Office, in conjunction  with       HVAC and Mechanical shop personnel, tests water flow  pressures in facility       sprinkler systems and standpipes on a  quarterly basis. Fire hydrants on       campus are tested semi-annually  for functionality and pressure. Alarm       actuation and notifications  systems, fire control equipment, spill control       equipment and  decontamination equipment are inspected on an annual basis       to  ensure accessibility and proper function. The computerized emergency        reporting system is monitored continuously. Fire extinguishers are        installed in university facilities pursuant to NFPA regulations and  are       inspected on a monthly basis. Test and inspection records are  maintained       in the Safety Office.</p>
<p>Respiratory protection is in stock and       available at Stores.  Required fit testing and training is provided upon       request by the  Safety Office. Emergency and personal protection equipment       such as  protective coveralls, gloves, goggles and respiratory protection,        including SCBA is readily accessible at the Safety Office for employees        involved in hazardous waste operations.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Inspections</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Routine inspections of university facilities are       conducted  periodically by the Office of Safety and Fire Protection to ensure that  adequate aisle       space is maintained to allow for the unobstructed  movement of personnel       and the transporting of equipment during an  emergency and to promote       compliance with egress and emergency  access fire code regulations. When       egress restrictions are  noticed, appropriate supervisory personnel are       advised to make  necessary corrections to maintain adequate clearance in       aisles and  hallways, etc.. Major events are monitored by the University Police        and Ticket Office ushers to insure clear aisle ways during such  events.       Persons who observe potential egress obstructions or  safety hazards are       encouraged to immediately notify the university  Safety Office by phone       (496-2457 or 496-2481) or       via the  Safety Office web page electronic hazard report form.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Incident Management</strong></p>
<p>The Rexburg Fire Department, Idaho State Police Hazardous Incident     Response Team and/or the Idaho Bureau of Disaster Services shall serve as     the emergency response team for major hazardous materials incidents     occurring on university property.&nbsp; Although university safety office     personnel are HAZWOPER trained and certified, the university does not have     sufficient trained personnel to provide a fully constituted emergency     response team.&nbsp; It shall be the responsibility of university safety     office personnel to assist responding emergency services personnel by     providing available information, equipment and other resources related to     the following incident management factors.</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Incident Site Characterization and Analysis</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The following factors shall be considered during the preliminary     evaluation to assist in determining the appropriate plan     of action:</p>
<ol>
<li>Whether the incident could involve a fire, spill, release or leak; </li>
<li>The quantity of the material and its harmful nature; </li>
<li>The type of container and its condition; </li>
<li>The location, time and weather conditions; </li>
<li>Any exposures to life, property, and the environment; and </li>
<li>Available resources.</li>
</ol>
<p>To determine the appropriate plan of action, the following reference     materials are recommended:</p>
<ol>
<li>Area blueprints; </li>
<li>Chemical inventory list; </li>
<li>Computerized MSDS system to help evaluate chemicals and materials         present in the site area; </li>
<li>Poison Control Center to help evaluate chemicals and possible exposure         effects to on-site victims and response personnel; </li>
<li>NIOSH Pocket Guide to Hazardous Materials; </li>
<li>National Fire Protection Association Handbook of Hazardous Materials; </li>
<li>University Fire Safety Plans and Building Coordinator Lists.</li>
</ol>
<p>During an incident, a more detailed evaluation of the site's specific     characteristics shall be performed by emergency response personnel.&nbsp;     First responders shall identify existing site hazards to the On-Scene     Incident Commander.&nbsp; This information will aid in the selection of     appropriate engineering, containment and clean-up controls, as well as the     selection of personal protective equipment for remaining response team     members and support staff members.</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Site Control</span></li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Purpose</p>
</em>
<p>To prevent employee/visitor contamination and harm during emergency     response activities, the following shall take place.&nbsp; Site control     activities shall include the following information:</p>
<ol>
<li>Site maps (e.g., blueprints, floor exit plans); </li>
<li>Designation of hot, warm and cold zones; </li>
<li>Communication Center (a central location where all communications and         plans will originate); and </li>
<li>Emergency decontamination protocol.</li>
</ol>
<p>The site shall be controlled and maintained by the University Police     and/or Rexburg Police Department personnel.&nbsp; The On-Scene Incident Commander shall use information provided from the     site characterization and analysis survey to determine the three emergency     response zones (Hot Zone, Warm Zone, and Cold Zone).&nbsp; The     aforementioned zones shall be determined by using the following guidelines.<em> </em></p>
<p><em>Hot Zone</em></p>
<em> </em>
<p>The area containing the incident itself, including the product and its     container.&nbsp; This area may be immediately dangerous to life and health (IDLH).&nbsp;     Personnel permitted in this zone shall be dressed in the appropriate     personal protective equipment.</p>
<em>
<p>Warm Zone</p>
</em>
<p>A larger geographical area surrounding the Hot Zone that is considered     safe for workers to enter with limited personal protective equipment unless     assigned a task requiring increased protection.</p>
<em>
<p>Cold Zone</p>
</em>
<p>The area adjacent to the Warm Zone that is restricted to administration     and emergency response personnel.&nbsp; Minimum personal protective     equipment may be required such as protective gloves and Tyvek coveralls.</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Spill Control</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Basic Control</em></p>
<p>Basic Control is the first step taken to prevent further release of the     hazardous materials.&nbsp; Basic control may include shutting off a valve or     shutting down a piece of machinery.</p>
<em>
<p>Extinguishment</p>
</em>
<p>When a hazardous material incident involves fire, the following procedure     shall be initiated:</p>
<ol>
<li>Notify the Fire Department by calling the University Police at <strong>911</strong> or 496-3000; </li>
<li>Determine the type of hazardous material in the fire; </li>
<li>Before attempting to extinguish the fire, determine if the hazardous         material involved is compatible with the extinguishing media.&nbsp; The         Material Safety Data Sheet and other references will assist you in         determining what type of extinguisher can be used.</li>
</ol> <em>
<p>Containment</p>
</em>
<p>There are four types of procedures that can be taken to keep the involved     material in its container.</p>
<ol>
<li>Shut-off Valves:&nbsp; Shut-off valves may cause spills or releases.&nbsp;         Ensure that all shut-off valves on the affected cylinder and/or drums         are properly closed and secured. </li>
<li>Plugging:&nbsp; Plugging devices may be placed or pounded into a         penetration to stop a leak.&nbsp; Pieces of wood, golf tees, soap or         stakes wrapped with cloth may be used.&nbsp; Metal objects shall not be         used for plugging purposes due to the possibility of sparking. </li>
<li>Patching:&nbsp; Materials like clay or putty may be used to patch a         leak.&nbsp; Look for decomposition of the patching compound as well as         the possibility of the build-up of internal pressure, which could cause         the patch to fail. </li>
<li>Overpacking:&nbsp; Overpacking is accomplished by placing a damaged         container into a larger undamaged container.</li>
</ol> <em>
<p>Confinement</p>
</em>
<p>There are three types of procedures which can be used to keep a material     in a confined area.</p>
<ol>
<li>Diking:&nbsp; Materials like sand, earth, straw or absorbent material         can be placed around the perimeter of the leak.&nbsp; The type of diking         material used shall be compatible with the spilled hazardous material. </li>
<li>Blocking:&nbsp; Drains, ditches or storm sewers shall be covered or         diked to prevent run-off of spilled materials.&nbsp; Blocking can be         accomplished with absorbent pads or a heavy piece of plastic. </li>
<li>Absorption:&nbsp; Run-off can sometimes be absorbed with dirt, sand,         soda ash, saw dust, vermiculite or other absorbent materials.&nbsp; The         absorbent material shall be positioned so that the spilled material runs         into it.&nbsp; Care shall be taken to ensure that the absorbent is         compatible with the spill.</li>
</ol> 
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Monitoring Equipment</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Quantitative measurements of hazardous materials within the environment     shall be made prior to any entry.&nbsp; Monitoring shall be conducted at the     completion of a response to determine if the area is safe for re-entry.</p>
<p>The following quantitative instruments shall be used in hazardous     atmospheric assessments.</p>
<ol>
<li>TMX412 Gas Meter to determine if the atmosphere is at an explosive         level and if adequate oxygen is present; </li>
<li>Dragger Tubes to determine and/or identify the         concentration of chemicals present in the atmosphere; </li>
<li>pH paper to determine the pH of a substance for proper neutralization;         and </li>
</ol> 
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Decontamination</span></li>
</ul>
<p>All clothing, equipment or person(s) assigned to duties in the Hot or     Warm Zones shall be decontaminated to remove the presence of any hazardous     materials encountered.&nbsp; The decontamination area shall be set-up prior     to the mitigation of the incident.</p>
<p>Decontamination can be accomplished by:</p>
<ol>
<li>Physically removing contaminants (e.g., liquid rinse, evaporation); </li>
<li>Inactivating contaminants by chemical detoxification (e.g.,         neutralizing agents); and </li>
<li>Disinfecting/sterilizing infectious or biological materials (e.g.,         bleach solution).</li>
</ol>
<p>The decontamination procedures shall be initiated by the On-Scene     Incident Commander.&nbsp; To ensure that the proper decontamination     procedures are initiated, the Incident Commander shall make reference to     following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Material Safety Data Sheets; </li>
<li>The National Fire Protection Association Hazardous Materials Handbook; </li>
<li>The chemical manufacturer; </li>
<li>Chemtrec; and </li>
<li>Other related reference materials.</li>
</ol>
<p>Once the proper decontamination procedures are determined, the On-Scene     Incident Commander shall designate an area within the Warm Zone to set up     the decontamination process.&nbsp; The equipment shall consist of portable     wash tubs, sprayers, heavy gauge plastic tarp and disposable scrub brushes.</p>
<p>The following eight steps constitute the decontamination process for     personnel involved in the remediation of the incident.</p>
<ol>
<li>All personnel exiting the Hot Zone shall place monitoring equipment,         hand tools and other equipment in this area.&nbsp; A recovery drum         and/or tarp shall be set in place so all tools and equipment can be put         aside for further decontamination.&nbsp; All equipment and tools shall         be decontaminated when work is concluded in accordance with the <em>Decontamination         of Equipment</em> section in this policy.&nbsp; Personal protective         clothing, self-contained breathing apparatus and/or respirators worn by         personnel are excluded at this stage and shall remain worn by personnel. </li>
<li>After placing equipment and tools in the recovery drum or on tarps,         all persons who have been within the Hot Zone shall be washed down with         the appropriate solution, as determined by the Material Safety Data         Sheet, while wearing all personal<strong> </strong>protective equipment.&nbsp; All         water used in this step shall be contained in a recovery drum or         decontamination pool while this process is carried out and treated as         hazardous waste at the completion of the decontamination process. </li>
<li>After emergency response personnel are completely washed down, they         shall remove their protective clothing.&nbsp; The protective clothing         shall be placed in a recovery drum or approved bag and labeled with a         tag as to their contents.&nbsp; Support personnel may be required to         assist personnel being decontaminated with removing their protective         clothing. </li>
<li>After removing protective clothing, personnel being decontaminated         shall remove their self-contained breathing apparatus or respirators.&nbsp;         The breathing apparatus shall be placed on a tarp for further         decontamination.&nbsp; For decontamination procedures of breathing         apparatus and respirators, refer to the section in this policy for the         Decontamination of Self Contained Breathing Apparatus. </li>
<li>Upon removing the personal protective equipment, the emergency         response personnel shall remove any clothing that may have become         contaminated.&nbsp; The clothing shall be placed in recovery drums or         approved bags and labeled as to its contents. </li>
<li>Emergency response personnel shall shower thoroughly if it has been         determined that personal protective equipment has failed to protect the         user. </li>
<li>Emergency response personnel and persons that were in the Hot Zone and         Warm Zone shall receive a post-medical evaluation by a qualified         individual if overexposure or injury occurs. </li>
<li>If it is determined that emergency response personnel or persons         involved with the incident need further medical attention,         transportation shall be arranged by the On-Scene Incident Commander.</li>
</ol> 
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Decontamination of Equipment</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Decontamination of equipment shall be performed by using portable wash     tubs, sprayers, and disposable scrub brushes.&nbsp; Any equipment that     cannot be thoroughly decontaminated along with the contents from the wash     tub shall be considered hazardous and shall be stored and disposed of in     accordance with the university's Hazardous Waste Management policy.</p>
<em>
<p>Monitoring Equipment</p>
</em>
<p>If monitoring equipment becomes contaminated, it shall require special     cleaning techniques.&nbsp; Methods for decontamination shall be obtained     from the EPA's Regional Office or the equipment's manufacturer.</p>
<em>
<p>Hand Tools</p>
</em>
<p>Emergency response hand tools shall be cleaned as appropriate by chemical     or physical means.&nbsp; The EPA's Regional Office may be consulted for     specific methods of decontaminating the hand tools.&nbsp; At the end of the     incident, if the hand tools cannot be decontaminated, they shall be disposed     of as hazardous waste.</p>
<em>
<p>Office and Laboratory Items</p>
</em>
<p>Use the same decontamination techniques used for hand tools and monitors.</p>
<p>Equipment that cannot be decontaminated shall be disposed of as hazardous     waste.&nbsp; The equipment shall be replaced immediately or as funding is     secured.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Follow Up</span></li>
</ul>
<p>As soon as practical, after an emergency, the       emergency coordinator will meet with members of the university emergency       operations center and aid in the development of post emergency strategies       and follow up operations. He/she will also initiate an investigation into       the causal factors of the emergency and prepare a comprehensive report for       the university administration which describes the causes of the emergency,       its effects and the effectiveness of the response to the emergency.</p>
<p>In the event of an emergency caused by a       hazardous waste spill or discharge, it is the university administration's       responsibility to provide sufficient fiscal and human resources for       effective response to and management of any hazardous waste emergency so       as to minimize risk of injury to persons, destruction of property or       damage to the environment.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
