<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46507" Name="Used Oil Policy" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Used Oil Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Used Oil Policy</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong>Used Oil       Management Plan</strong> <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong>
<p>Properly managing used oil is       important for four main reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li> To protect the environment.</li>
<li>To protect human health.</li>
<li>To protect against liability for environmental damages.</li>
<li>To reuse, rather than waste, a valuable resource.</li>
</ul>
<p>Used oil, even when not       classified as a hazardous waste under RCRA, can have harmful effects if it       is released into the environment. In addition, people's health can be       affected if used oil is handled improperly.</p>
<p>Superfund regulations allow       the federal government to hold any party that creates or contributes to       the creation of a hazardous waste spill (including some used oil)       financially responsible for cleanup costs.</p>
<p>Used oil is a valuable       resource because it has lubrication value and heat value. When treated to       remove contaminants, the used oil can be used as a base stock to produce       new lubricating oil. Used oil also has heat value and can be burned as       fuel. Properly burning used oil keeps its heat value from being wasted       and saves virgin heating oil that would be burned instead.</p>
<p><strong>Purpose:</strong></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho has developed this       plan to properly handle used oil at various campus sites. This plan       informs employees about the university's compliance with Environmental       Protection Agency (EPA) requirements (<a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hazmat/40 CFR 279 Used Oil.pdf" target="_blank">40 CFR       279</a>) for used oil       generators.</p>
<p>This plan provides a written       description of used oil management procedures, disposal methods, and       transportation requirements. We encourage any suggestions that our       employees have for improving our written plan for used oil management, as       we are committed to developing and maintaining an effective protocol. We       strive for clear understanding, environmentally sound practices, and       involvement in the plan from every level of the company.</p>
<p><strong>Administrative Duties:</strong></p>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Safety Office       is responsible for developing the written used oil management plan; for       ensuring that our written plan is complete, kept up to date, and made       available to applicable or required authorities; and for maintaining used       oil management records. A copy of our used oil management plan may be       reviewed by employees. It is located on the Safety Office Web Page which       can be accessed from the main university web site.</p>
<p><strong>Used Oil Defined</strong></p>
<p>The EPA defines used oil as       "any oil that has been refined from crude oil or any synthetic oil       that has been used and as a result of such use is contaminated by physical       or chemical impurities." Used oil can be generated from automotive       sources, or during Physical Plant maintenance operations. This includes       oils that are used as hydraulic fluid as well as oils that are used to       lubricate automobiles and other machinery, cool engines, or suspend       materials in industrial processes. Oils used for these purposes can become       contaminated with physical materials (such as metal particles from engine       wear) or chemical contaminants (such as gasoline combustion products, like       toluene).</p>
<p><strong>Used Oil Management</strong></p>
<p>At this facility, used oil is       generated from Facilities Management Service Station, HVAC Shop, Electrical Shop       and Vehicle Maintenance Shop as well as from the Farm Mechanics facility,       the Austin Building automotive labs and livestock center operations.</p>
<p>The university adheres to the       following practices. University personnel are expected to:</p>
<p>==&gt; Never dump or       dispose of used oil in the trash, in sewers, storm drains, or on the ground.</p>
<p>==&gt; Make sure our collection and storage set-up is       leak proof, spill proof, and       that tanks have lids or are covered to prevent water from entering.&nbsp;       The storage set-up must also include a spill containment area/container.</p>
<p>==&gt; Control access to prevent dumping of materials into a storage container       when it is not supervised.</p>
<p>==&gt; Maintain our collection containers regularly, comply with local fire and       safety regulations, and avoid leaks and spills.</p>
<p>==&gt; Label storage tanks "Used Oil."</p>
<p>==&gt; Clean up any used oil spills or leaks. This includes providing soak-up       material (e.g., kitty litter, or a commercial sorbent product) for minor       spills. It keeps the area clean and helps prevent personal injury.</p>
<p>==&gt; Keep records of used oil transported by contractors for recycling or       disposal.</p>
<p><strong>Storing Used Oil</strong></p>
<p>The university stores used oil       in specifically designed and labeled waste oil drums with secondary       containment. Drum storage for waste oil is utilized because generators       accumulate a relatively small amount of used oil each month, or used oil       is accumulated from different sources which must be segregated until it       can be tested for contaminates. This facility follows these storage       practices. University personnel are expected to:</p>
<p>Never mix used oil with any other material. This facility keeps gasoline,       solvents, degreasers, paints, and so on, from making the used oil a       hazardous waste and increasing collection costs.</p>
<p>Carefully record the amount of used oil placed into and removed from       storage devices. Record keeping plays an important role in leak detection       for ASTs, USTs, and drums.</p>
<p>Have constructed secondary containment around our drums/tanks with a       capacity for 100 percent of the contents of the drums we store; the base       of the containment area is sloped so that any spilled oil may be       recollected and removed.</p>
<p>Equip storage containers with wide-mouth, long-necked funnels to reduce       spills during filling.</p>
<p>Equip storage containers with a pressure relief valve to reduce a build up       of pressure, which could cause leaks.</p>
<p>Keep sorbent materials nearby to clean up any spills that occur.</p>
<p>Keep the area near the storage devices neat and clean.</p>
<p><strong>Responding to Releases of       Used Oil</strong></p>
<p>Even though all steps have       been taken to prevent leaks or spills from occurring, the university is       also prepared to respond to spills of used oil. We instruct workers to use       the following protocol to manage spills of used oil and provide any       necessary equipment:</p>
<p><strong> Stop the release.</strong> This action will vary depending on why the release is       occurring. For example, if the spill occurs because a 55-gallon drum has       been knocked over, the drum should be righted to stop more used oil from       being released.</p>
<p>If the spill occurs because a valve on a storage device has been left       open, the valve should be closed. If a leak is a result of a puncture in       the tank or drum, rags or similar materials should be used to plug the       leak.</p>
<p><strong> Contain the release.</strong> We strive to prevent the used oil that has been       released from spreading. For example, a sorbent should be spread over the       spilled used oil.</p>
<p><strong> Clean up the release.</strong> Depending on the extent of the release, cleaning up       the used oil can be a simple or a complicated task. For small spills on       the ground, the soil can be dug up and disposed of. (The soil must be       tested to determine if it exhibits hazardous characteristics.) For larger       spills where puddles of used oil have formed, vacuum-type machinery can be       used to collect the used oil before the soil is dug up for disposal.       Because releases that contaminate a great deal of soil or ground or       surface water are very difficult to clean up, the university contacts       professionals to conduct the cleanup operation.</p>
<p>Properly manage the used oil that has been cleaned up. Any leaked or       spilled used oil is managed just like any other used oil under 40 CFR 279.</p>
<p>Properly manage the solid materials generated during the cleanup. We place       solid materials used to clean up a spill of used oil in a sieve-like       container to allow the used oil to drip from the solid materials into a       storage device. In addition, we compact the materials to remove the used       oil. (Removal is complete when there are no more signs of free-flowing       oil.) Materials contaminated with used oil that are burned can be managed       in the same manner as used oil.</p>
<p>Contaminated materials that will not be burned for energy are tested to       determine if they exhibit hazardous waste characteristics. If they do not       test hazardous, they are disposed of in a RCRA subtitle D facility. If       they are hazardous, they are disposed of in a RCRA subtitle C facility.</p>
<p>Remove the storage device from service and repair or replace it.</p>
<p><strong>Managing and Disposing of       Used Oil Filters</strong></p>
<p>Whenever university personnel       change the oil in a fleet vehicle, the oil filter is also changed to keep       the solid contaminants of the old oil from immediately contaminating the       new oil. Used oil filters can contain 10 to 16 ounces of used oil,       therefore proper management of this source of used oil is a concern of the       university. Used oil filters are not considered a hazardous waste under       RCRA if they are not terne-plated and have been properly drained of oil.</p>
<p>When used oil filters are       removed from a warm engine, the university uses the Gravity draining -       when the filter is removed from the engine, it should be placed with its       gasket side down in a drain pan. If the filter has an anti-drain valve,       the "dome end" of the filter should be punctured with a       screwdriver (or similar device) so that the oil can flow freely. The       filter should then be allowed to drain for 12 to 24 hours. method to drain       the filter.</p>
<p>We store our drained used oil       filters in a covered, rainproof container to prevent used oil from being       washed from the filters to the surrounding environment. Our used oil       filters are then recycled or properly disposed of.</p>
<p><strong>Shipping/Transporting Used       Oil</strong></p>
<p>All used oil transported from       the BYU-I campus is managed through the University Safety Office -       Hazardous Materials Specialist.</p>
<p>The used oil management       standards define a used oil transporter as any person who transports used       oil, any person who collects used oil from more than one generator and       transports the collected oil, and owners and operators of used oil       transfer facilities." BYU-Idaho has chosen Safety Kleen to transport       our used oil. Our transporter has an EPA ID number and complies with all       relevant used oil regulations, including maintaining tracking records of where       the used oil is collected and where it will be transported to.&nbsp;</p>
<p>When       working with our transporter, we:</p>
<p>Ensure that the hauler has a current EPA ID number.</p>
<p>Measure the level of oil in a tank before and after the hauler collects it       to be certain the oil collected matches the amount the hauler reports       collecting.</p>
<p>Make sure a company representative signs and dates the hauler's tracking       sheet.</p>
<p>Receive a receipt from the transporter that states how much used oil was       collected from our facility and where the used oil will be taken.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Make sure that the hauler maintains storage tanks/containers; labels       containers "Used Oil"; stores used oil over oil-impervious       surfaces; has secondary containment structures in place; stores used oil       for no more than 35 days; tests waste in out-of-service tanks; closes       out-of-service tanks containing hazardous waste according to EPA       standards.</p>
<p><strong>Employee Training</strong></p>
<p>Although training is not required under the regulations, we have designated the Safety       Office to train personnel who will handle used oil. Direct any questions       concerning used oil training to this office.</p>
<p>Under this plan, employees       are informed of used oil management procedures relevant to the positions       in which they work. This training occurs both in the classroom and on the       job.</p>
<p>We keep records of job titles       and written job descriptions for all positions related to used oil       management and the names of employees filling each job. We also keep       records describing the type and amount of training provided.</p>
<p><strong>Related Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Related regulations that we       must still comply with include:</p>
<p>Underground Storage Tank regulations (40 CFR 280)</p>
<p>Spill Prevention Control and Countermeasures requirements (40 CFR 112)</p>
<p>Hazardous Materials Transportation Act regulations (49 CFR 130)</p>
<p>Resource Conservation and Recovery Act requirements (40 CFR 260-268)</p>
<p>Polychlorinated Biphenyls (PCBs) Manufacturing, Processing, Distribution       in Commerce, and Use Prohibitions (40 CFR 761).&nbsp; 40 CFR 761.20(e), contains restrictions, and testing and       record keeping requirements for marketers and burners.</p>
<p>Please see related documents       for information on how the university meets these additional requirements.</p>
<p><strong>Reporting</strong></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho performs the       following reporting activity:</p>
<p>Reports are       submitted&nbsp; to the Idaho Division of Environmental Quality as required       and       to the Idaho Division of Hazardous Materials pursuant to established       reporting procedures.</p>
<p><strong>Record keeping</strong></p>
<p>The University Safety Office       is responsible for keeping the following records:</p>
<p>The Idaho Hazardous Waste       Generator Annual Report, the Emergency and Hazardous Chemical Inventory       Report and waste disposal records.</p>
<p><strong>Maintaining the Plan</strong></p>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Safety Office       is responsible for:</p>
<p>Conducting periodic site audits.</p>
<p>Keeping records of all inspections and reports.</p>
<p>Reviewing and updating the plan as needed by incorporating any necessary       updates resulting from major changes in our facility's operation or       maintenance or by changes in government regulations.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
