<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46660" Name="General Registration FAQs" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">General Registration FAQs</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">General Registration FAQs</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style><!--
ul#navi li{
list-style-type:disc;
}
--></style>
<ul id="navi">
<li><a href="#faq1">How do I know when I can register?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq2">What if I miss my designated registration time?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq3">How do I know how many credits I have?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq4">Do my currently enrolled BYU-Idaho credits count towards my priority registration date?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq5">Do my transfer credits count towards my priority registration date?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq6">Why do freshmen register last?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq7">Can I register for classes if I'm on Academic Warning?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq8">Can I register for classes if I'm on Academic Probation?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq9">Can I register for classes if I'm on Academic Suspension?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq10">Can I register for classes if I am no longer admitted?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq11">How many credits can I register for?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq12">Do I have to take at least 12 credits?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq13">Can I take more than 21 credits a semester (or more than 10.0 credits during a block/term)?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq14">What if I can only take a few classes? How many credits do I need to keep my admission status?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq15">I think I may want to audit one of my classes. What does auditing a class mean?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq16">How do I change my enrollment in a class to audit?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq17">I'm in a variable credit class. How do I change how many credits I'm enrolled in?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq18">How do I switch from oone section to another that? (e.g., from FDENG 101-02 to FDENG 101-03).</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq19">I'm enrolled in one religion class, but I'd like to add a second one. When can I do so?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq20">I want to take block classes only. How many credits do I need to be considered a full-time student?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq21">Can I get an excused absence for University activities, sickness, or other personal emergencies?</a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
</ul>
<h3><a name="faq1"></a>How do I know when I can register?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level. Credits earned  plus currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits are calculated into the priority registration  credit count.</p>
<h3><a name="faq2"></a>What if I miss my designated registration time?</h3>
<p>If a student misses their designated registration time, they may still register for  classes but risk less availability of class selection. Students can add classes to their  schedules through the first week of the semester.</p>
<h3><a name="faq3"></a>How do I know how many credits I have?</h3>
<p>Students can log into my.byui.edu, click the Student tab, and on the left side of the  page, click the gray Unofficial Transcript tab to pull up their academic history. This  will indicate how many credits a student has earned, then the student can add their  currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits (if any) to this total to determine how many  credits they have to determine their priority registration date.</p>
<h3><a name="faq4"></a>Do my currently enrolled BYU&ndash;Idaho credits count towards my priority registration date?</h3>
<p>Yes.</p>
<h3><a name="faq5"></a>Do my transfer credits count towards my priority registration date?</h3>
<p>Yes, as long as your transfer credits are recorded on your BYU&ndash;Idaho transcript.  Transfer courses must be completed (with final grades) and recorded on your BYU&ndash; Idaho transcript for them to calculate into your priority registration date. Transfer  credits that you are currently enrolled in cannot be calculated into this date.</p>
<h3><a name="faq6"></a>Why do freshmen register last?</h3>
<p>Student registration for classes is by priority according to credit level. Seniors,  juniors, and sophomores have increasingly fewer class options as they advance in  their academic careers, thereby necessitating their need to register earlier and have  top pick of the classes they need in order to graduate. Freshmen have a wide range of  options between all of the Foundations courses and major courses they still need to  take, so they register after everyone else for this reason.</p>
<h3><a name="faq7"></a>Can I register for classes if I&rsquo;m on Academic Warning?</h3>
<p>Yes, you may register for classes while on Academic Warning.  Please visit this website  for more information: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="faq8"></a>Can I register for classes if I&rsquo;m on Academic Probation?</h3>
<p>Yes, but you may only register for up to 12 credits. Please visit this website for more  information: <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm.</a></p>
<h3><a name="faq9"></a>Can I register for classes if I&rsquo;m on Academic Suspension?</h3>
<p>No. You must fulfill the terms of your suspension before you will be eligible to  register for any classes (including night and online classes) at BYU&ndash;Idaho. Please visit  this website for more information:  <a class="underline" href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/AcademicStandards.htm</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="faq10"></a>Can I register for classes if I am no longer admitted?</h3>
<p>No. You must be admitted as a type of student (e.g., Day, Part-time, Continuing  Education, etc.) to be able to register for any academic classes offered at BYU&ndash;Idaho.</p>
<h3><a name="faq11"></a>How many credits can I register for?</h3>
<ul>
<li>12 credits are required to be considered a full-time student </li>
<li>14 credits are required to be eligible for university scholarship </li>
<li>15 credits are required to graduate in eight semesters or four years and for the Fast  Grad program. </li>
<li>21 credit hours is the maximum a student can take.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="faq12"></a>Do I have to take at least 12 credits?</h3>
<p>No, students do not have to take at least 12 credits. To remain admitted to BYU&ndash; Idaho, students must take a least one class during their on-track semesters. To be  considered a full-time student, however, students must be registered for at least 12  credit hours per semester.</p>
<h3><a name="faq13"></a>Can I take more than 21 credits during a single semester (or more than 10.0 credits during  a block/term)?</h3>
<p>Twenty-one credit hours is the recommended maximum. Students must obtain  permission from the Student Records and Registration Office to take more than 21  credits per semester or 10 credits per block/term. Students must demonstrate a  successful academic history to qualify (e.g., a cumulative 3.0 GPA or higher, a history  of high course loads in 2+ consecutive semesters, etc.).</p>
<h3><a name="faq14"></a>What if I can only take a few classes? How many credits do I need to keep my admission  status?</h3>
<p>On-track students need to take at least one class (or at least 0.5 credits) to maintain  their admission status. Half credits are charged the same as one full credit.</p>
<h3><a name="faq15"></a>I think I may want to audit one of my classes. What does auditing a class mean?</h3>
<p>Students who audit a class are not responsible for attendance, daily preparations  or examinations, and no grade is reported or recorded on the permanent record.  Tuition for audit classes is assessed on the same basis as for credit classes. An &ldquo;I&rdquo;  grade may not be made up by repeating the class as an audit. Departments have the right to refuse to allow students to audit individual  courses. Registered students who drop all credit classes and only have audit classes  remaining are considered withdrawn from the University effective the latest drop 5 date of the non-audit classes. Students will need to re-apply through the Admissions  Office for the next semester. Compliance with deadlines is required, unless a  deferment is obtained.</p>
<h3><a name="faq16"></a>How do I change my enrollment in a class to audit?</h3>
<p>Students must first register for the class for credit and then contact the Student  Records and Registration Office by emailing, registration@byui.edu, to change the  course to audit. Students may not change class status from credit to audit or from audit to  credit after the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><a name="faq17"></a>I&rsquo;m in a variable credit class and need to change how many credits I&rsquo;m enrolled in. How do I  do that?</h3>
<p>Students may contact the Student Records and Registration Office for assistance  with changing their credit amount in a variable credit class. Please note that students may  increase the amount of credits they are enrolled in at any time in the semester;  however, students may only decrease the amount of credits they&rsquo;re enrolled in as  long as the decrease request is before the deadline to withdraw from a class without  earning a &ldquo;W.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><a name="faq18"></a>I need to switch from one section to another (e.g., from FDENG 101-02 to FDENG 101-03).  How do I do that?</h3>
<p>If a student is switching from one section to another before the deadline to  withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W,&rdquo; all they need to do is drop the section  they&rsquo;re in and then add the section they want. They may need an instructor  authorization to be able to add the section they want.  If a student is switching from one section to another after the deadline to  withdraw from a class without earning a &ldquo;W,&rdquo; the instructor of the class they want to  add needs to contact the Student Records and Registration Office for assistance so  the student does not receive an inaccurate W grade for the section they drop. NOTE: This only applies to students switching from one section to another of the  same course. This does not apply to students who are switching into a different  course (e.g., switching from a lower level class to a higher level class, or vice  versa). If switching from a different course, the W grade will be applied to the  class dropped if it is after the deadline to withdraw from a class without earning a W.</p>
<h3><a name="faq19"></a>I&rsquo;m enrolled in one religion class, but I&rsquo;d like to add a second one. When can I do so?</h3>
<p>Students who wish to take two religion classes in a given term may attempt to do  so after the first day of the class (or block) if there is available seating and they have  obtained clearance to do so from the Religion Department Chairman. Students  can then add the course to their schedules, or, if necessary, meet with the instructor  of that class to receive any needed authorization(s). Students who wish to take more than two religion classes in a given term must  obtain clearance from the Religion Department Chairman. The Chairman then  contacts the Student Records and Registration Office to register the student for the  class.6</p>
<h3><a name="faq20"></a>I want to take classes during first block (or second block) only. How many credits do I need  to be considered a full-time student?</h3>
<p>The full-time equivalency for block registration is 6 credit hours.</p>
<h3><a name="faq21"></a>Can I get an excused absence for University activities, sickness, or other personal  emergencies?</h3>
<p>Students are responsible for class attendance. No absences, whether approved by  the University for participation in University-sponsored activities or necessitated by  sickness or other personal emergencies, are &ldquo;excused&rdquo; in the sense that the student  is  relieved from class work assigned during the absence. To ensure continuity, students  must make up missed work. In most cases, repeated absences will result in a lower  grade or failure.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17143" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
