<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46646" Name="Department Recovery Plan" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Department Recovery Plan</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Department Recovery Plan</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left">The ____________________________ Department fills an       important role at BYU-Idaho.&nbsp; Key personnel in the       ________________________________ Department have put together the following procedures to       insure the Department is capable of restoring critical functions after any disaster. These       procedures include a summary of the critical functions performed by the       ____________________________ Department, which other departments must be involved in       recovering these functions, which employees should be active in the recovery process, what       steps those employees should follow, and what resources are required to perform those       steps. It is vital that each employee be familiar with the actions they will be required       to perform following a disaster. These procedures will be tested and revised on a regular       basis to insure viability. <br /> <br /> <strong>DEPARTMENT DISASTER PHILOSOPHY </strong><br /> <br /> The primary function of the ____________________________ Recovery Team is to assist the       Recovery Director in the recovery process by restoring the critical business functions       listed below within an acceptable period of time. <br /> <br /> <strong>CRITICAL FUNCTIONS</strong> <br /> <br /> Critical business functions are those functions which, if not performed due to a disaster,       would cause serious or irreparable harm to BYU-Idaho in terms of lost revenue and       profits, research grants, or loss of customers, and market share. The critical functions       performed by the ____________________________ Department are:</p>
<p align="left"><strong>CRITICAL FUNCTION RECOVERY WINDOW </strong><br /> <br /> 1.<br /> 2.<br /> <br /> This should be a prioritized list of descriptions of the functions performed by this       department. Descriptions should include which services/products would be affected in what       way if the functions could not be performed following a disaster. <br /> <br /> <strong>DEPENDENCIES OF CRITICAL FUNCTIONS </strong><br /> <br /> 1. Systems <br /> <br /> A.<br /> B.<br /> <br /> This should be a list of the systems which must be operational for the critical functions       to be performed. Ex:&nbsp; Services, accounting systems, phones systems, utility systems. <br /> <br /> 2. Supporting Departments <br /> <br /> A.<br /> B.<br /> <br /> This should be a list of departments which support these functions and what the supporting       department must do. Ex. Physical Plant must provide a reasonable working environment. <br /> <br /> 3. Departments supported <br /> <br /> A.<br /> B.<br /> <br /> This should be a list of departments supported by these functions. Ex. ________ function       must be performed before the Payroll Department can release funds. <br /> <br /> <strong>TEAM COMPOSITION </strong><br /> <br /> Complete Personal Profile sheets for each member on the department's recovery team. List       team position, i.e. Coordinator, Alt. Coordinator, team member.       <br /> <br /> <strong>NOTIFICATION AND ASSESSMENT </strong><br /> <br /> 1. Team Notification Procedures:&nbsp; Details; who calls who, when, and where they should       report. A basic telephone tree. <br /> 2. Assessment Procedures:&nbsp; What assessments need to be made before action is taken?       When and if you are allowed into the building what needs to happen? <br /> 3.Emergency Call Lists:&nbsp; <br /> A. For a listing of key department contacts.</p>
<p align="left"><strong>RECOVERY PROCEDURES</strong> <br /> <br /> Outline the necessary steps by whom that need to be taken to restore the critical       functions of the group. <br /> <br /> <strong>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURES</strong> <br /> <br /> 1.Maintain a record of the hours team members work and their work location. <br /> 2.Record any personal expenses incurred during the recovery process. Receipts should be       kept for proper reimbursement. <br /> 3.Submit periodic written reports on the recovery status of your department to the       Disaster Operations Center. <br /> <br /> <strong>SITE RECOVERY MANAGEMENT </strong><br /> <br /> Site recovery functions are the anticipated activities required for the resumption of       normal levels of operations and production. These recovery functions may have to be       carried out with a diminished level of resources. In response to a catastrophic event, the       recovery effort may encompass a time period of a few weeks to several months and must be       coordinated between various service departments to ensure that business interruption is       minimized. <br /> <br /> The site service recovery teams will consist of the following departments: <br /> <br /> 1.Facilities <br /> 2.Telecommunications <br /> 3.Human Resources <br /> 4.Purchasing <br /> 5.Security / Safety <br /> <br /> <strong>FACILITIES </strong><br /> <br /> The Physical Plant will be responsible for the following functions: <br /> <br /> 1.Damage Assessment:&nbsp; This encompasses assessing structural and non-structural       damage, specific production and damage to building equipment, utility and communication       systems, as well as including photographs of all damages. Facilities must also identify       the potential need for contracted services, labor, and material for damage repair and       restoration of operations. <br /> 2.Estimated repair costs and recovery schedules will be developed and distributed to Risk       Management and insurance underwriters. <br /> 3.Building Repairs Provide technical direction on damage repair performed by in-house and       contracted personnel.&nbsp; Facilities will also obtain and provide engineering and       architectural drawings to the personnel responsible for doing repairs.&nbsp; <br /> 4.Facilities will be responsible for the following functions: <br /> A. Electricity <br /> B. Gas <br /> C. Water <br /> D. Heating / Air Conditioning <br /> 5.Facilities will be responsible for salvaging capital assets equipment from damaged       buildings. <br /> <br /> <strong>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</strong> <br /> <br /> Telecommunications personnel are responsible for the recovery of the phone systems. They       will be responsible for evaluating the extent of the damage and interfacing with the       appropriate vendors. During the recovery, the Telecommunications Recovery Team may need to       perform, or oversee, any or all of the following processes in order to successfully       recover the site. <br /> <br /> 1. Recovery plan agreements with selected vendors to restore all switching and cabling       requirements for reconstruction. <br /> <br /> <strong>HUMAN RESOURCES </strong><br /> <br /> Human Resources is responsible for providing employee information to the Disaster       Operations Center. The Human Resources Recovery Team may perform, or oversee, any or all       of the following processes to support site recovery. <br /> <br /> 1.Coordinate employee assistance and benefit programs for affected employees and family       members. <br /> 2.Provide professional counseling and guidance for employees dealing with the disaster. <br /> 3.Coordinate additional temporary labor as needed. <br /> <br /> <strong>PURCHASING </strong><br /> <br /> It must be assumed that a substantial amount of equipment will not be salvageable in the       event of a disaster.&nbsp; Accordingly, Purchasing will be responsible for facilitating       the procurement of necessary equipment on short notice. The Purchasing Department will be       responsible for the following functions. <br /> <br /> 1.Replacing damaged equipment necessary to restore critical functions. <br /> 2.Processing departmental requests for contract services, materials, and labor. <br /> <br /> <strong>SECURITY SERVICES </strong><br /> <br /> Campus Police will maintain ongoing security coverage for the facilities throughout all       site recovery activities. They will be responsible for the following functions to assist       in the site recovery. <br /> <br /> 1.Restore security access control systems. <br /> 2.Contract security vendors and volunteers will provide additional support as needed.       Safety personnel will be available to assist in the various site recovery responsibilities       that may arise.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
