<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46622" Name="Bloodborne Pathogen Summary" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bloodborne Pathogen Summary</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bloodborne Pathogen Summary</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><a href="x46621.xml">Bloodborne       Policy</a><br /> <a href="x46624.xml">Hepatitis       B Vaccine Refusal Form</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Summary of the BYU-Idaho Bloodborne Pathogens Exposure       Control Plan<br /> </strong>In Compliance With 29 CFR 1910.1030<br /> October 26, 1999</p>
<p>Departments whose employees are at risk of occupational exposure       or work with blood or body fluids whether through professional or academic work are       required to follow this institutional policy.</p>
<p><strong>Department Supervisor Responsibilities:</strong></p>
<p>1. <strong>Exposure Determination List.</strong> Departments with employees       who may be at risk of occupational exposure shall prepare an exposure determination, <a href="x46621.xml#4. Exposure determination.">see section 4.0 of the Bloodborne Pathogens Policy</a>. A copy of this list should be submitted to the Campus Safety Office for       record maintenance.</p>
<p>2. <strong>Exposure Control Plan.</strong> Each department shall develop a       written Exposure Control Plan, a copy should be submitted to the Campus Safety Office.</p>
<p>3. <strong>Engineering and Work Practice Controls.</strong> Department       supervisors are responsible to ensure that engineering and work practice controls to       eliminate or reduce employee exposure are enacted and followed, <a href="x46621.xml#5. General Work Practices and Procedures.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 5.</a></p>
<p>4. <strong>Cleaning and Decontamination.</strong> Develop and follow a       written cleaning and decontamination schedule that reduces the chance of accidental       exposure to blood,<br /> <a href="x46621.xml#7 Housekeeping.">see Bloodborn Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 7.</a></p>
<p>5. <strong>Employee Training</strong>. Departments whose work or academic       endeavors may present occupational exposure risks to employees must provide employee       training on bloodborne pathogens <a href="x46621.xml#12 Communication of Hazards to Employees.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 12</a>, and the Training Regulations. Employee       training should also include the following:</p>
<p>(A) Make employees aware of risks involved and precautions         necessary to protect themselves</p>
<p>(B) Inform employees that the college is required to provide them         with personal protective clothing and equipment to help them work safely, <a href="x46621.xml#6 Personal Protective Equipment.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 6.</a></p>
<p>(C) Proper fitting, care, removal, and destruction of personal         protective equipment.</p>
<p>(D) Inform employees that employees at risk of occupational         exposure can be vaccinated for HBV, at no charge to them, <a href="x46621.xml#11 Hepatitis B vaccination and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 11</a>.</p>
<p>(E) Proper handling of contaminated laundry.</p>
<p>(F) The college, through department supervisors, must maintain         medical and training records on all at-risk employees.</p>
<p>(G) Training is to be done an annual basis or more often as         nature of work indicates.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Use of Universal Precautions.</strong> Department supervisors       shall see instruct employees at risk of occupational exposure to observe Auniversal       precautions@ to prevent contact with blood or other potentially infections materials.       Universal precautions means that employees should treat all human blood and certain body       fluids as if they were known to contain HIV (AIDS) or HBV (Hepatitis B), or other       bloodborne pathogens, <a href="x46621.xml#5. General Work Practices and Procedures.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 5.</a></p>
<p>7. <strong>Regulated Waste.</strong> Department supervisors are responsible       ensuring that proper disposal containers and methods of disposing of contaminated waste       are followed within their areas, <a href="x46621.xml#8 Regulated Waste.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 8</a>. The BYU-Idaho Health Center serves as the clearinghouse for all       contaminated and regulated waste. Departments should contact the Health center and       establish a protocol for their disposal of waste.</p>
<p>8. <strong>Laundry.</strong> Contaminated laundry shall not be washed with       other normal laundry. Departments which routinely have contaminated laundry must ensure       compliance with <a href="x46621.xml#9 Laundry.">Section 9 of the Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy.</a> Departments which require the laundering of contaminated laundry shall       work with the Campus Health Center to ensure compliance.</p>
<p>9. <strong>Labeling.</strong> Warning labels shall be affixed to containers       of regulated waste, refrigerators and freezers containing blood or other potentially       infectious material; and other containers used to store, transport or ship blood or other       potentially infectious materials, <a href="x46621.xml#12 Communication of Hazards to Employees.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 12. </a></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p>10. <strong>Hepatitis B Vaccination. </strong>BYU-Idaho     provides       the hepatitis B vaccine and vaccination series to all employees who have occupational       exposure, and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up to all employees who have had an       exposure incident. Department supervisors should familiarize themselves with the protocol       and record keeping required with providing vaccinations. Employees who reject the option       of being vaccinated are required to fill out a <a>vaccination rejection form</a>.</p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p>11. <strong>Recordkeeping.</strong> Departments shall establish and       maintain an accurate record for each employee with occupational exposure, records should       be in accordance with <a href="x46621.xml##13 Record Keeping.">Section 13 of the Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy.</a></p>
<p>12. <strong>Training Records.</strong> Departments are responsible for       keeping and maintaining training records which should include <strong>(</strong><a href="x46621.xml##13 Record Keeping.">see Bloodborne Pathogens Safety Policy, Section 13.2</a><strong>)</strong> the following:</p>
<p>(A) The dates of the training sessions;</p>
<p>(B) Contents or a summary of the training sessions;</p>
<p>(C) The names and qualifications of persons conducting the         training; and</p>
<p>(D) The names and job titles of all persons attending the         training sessions.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
