<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46600" Name="Asbestos Management Policy" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Asbestos Management Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Asbestos Management Policy</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="x46601.xml">Abestos Summary</a><br /> <a href="x46602.xml">Appendix 1 - Asbestos Inventory</a></span></p>
<hr />
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong><a name="Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><br /> </strong> </span><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="#1.0 Purpose">1.0 Purpose</a><br /> <a href="#2.0 Scope">2.0 Scope</a></span><span style="color: #000000;"><strong><br /> </strong></span><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="#3.0 References">3.0 References</a><br /> <a href="#4.0 Definitions">4.0 Definitions</a></span><span style="color: #000000;"> <br /> </span><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="#5.0 Asbestos Inspections and Inventory">5.0 Asbestos Inspections and Inventory</a></span><br /><a href="#6.0 Requirements for Asbestos Work">6.0 Requirements for Asbestos Work</a><br /> <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="#7.0 Requirements for Class IV Asbestos Work">7.0 Requirements for Class IV Asbestos Work</a><br /> <a href="#8.0 Personal Protective Equipment">8.0 Personal Protective Equipment</a><br /> <a href="#9.0 Training">9.0 Training</a><br /> <a href="#10.0 Waste Disposal">10.0 Waste Disposal</a><br /> <a href="#11.0 Notification to Regulatory Agencies">11.0 Notification to Regulatory Agencies</a><br /> <a href="#12.0 Communication of Asbestos Hazards">12.0 Communication of Asbestos Hazards</a><br /> <a href="#13.0 Signs and Labels">13.0 Signs and Labels</a><br /> <a href="#14.0 Air Monitoring">14.0 Air Monitoring</a><br /> <a href="#15.0 Responsibilities">15.0 Responsibilities</a><br /><a href="#16.0 Non-Construction Asbestos Activities">16.0 Non-Construction Asbestos Activities</a><br /> </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><span style="color: #000000;"> </span></span></p>
<hr />
<p><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;"><strong>BYU-Idaho Asbestos Management Plan</strong></span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="1.0 Purpose">1.0 Purpose</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">BYU-Idaho is committed to providing a safe work place for all       individuals working in college facilities. The primary purpose of this plan is to ensure       that BYU-Idaho employees, students, and visitors are protected from asbestos hazards,       and that applicable asbestos regulatory requirements are followed. Ricks will fulfill the       requirements of 29 CFR 1926.1101 by conducting, or having conducted an asbestos survey on       each of the pre-1981 buildings that exist on campus. Furthermore, in our continuing effort       to provide for the protection of human health and the environment, Ricks will conduct       asbestos inspections on any campus buildings that were constructed prior to 1981 before       they are renovated or demolished. Ricks will also test any suspect material that becomes       damaged, dislodged, or disturbed within a pre-1981 building for which an asbestos survey       has not yet been completed. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="2.0 Scope">2.0 Scope</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">This plan (except section 22) applies to all       university personnel       engaged in the removal, inspection, disturbance, or maintenance of asbestos containing       materials (ACM) or presumed asbestos containing materials (PACM) in       university facilities. Certain reporting requirements also apply to non-Ricks construction personnel       working in BYU-Idaho facilities. Section 22 of this plan applies only to Ricks       personnel engaged in asbestos brake and/or clutch repair, or custodial employees who are       exposed to asbestos as part of their cleaning or housekeeping duties. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></span></p>
<p><a href="#3.0 References"><strong> </strong></a><strong><a name="3.0 References"></a><a href="#3.0 References">3.0 References</a></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">3.1 29 CFR 1926.1101</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">3.2 29 CFR 1910.134</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">3.4 40 CFR 61(subpart M)</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">3.5 29 CFR 1010.1001</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><a name="4.0 Definitions">4.0 Definitions<br /></a></strong></p>
<strong><em> </em></strong>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Aggressive method</span> means removal or disturbance of       building material by sanding, abrading, grinding or other method that breaks, crumbles, or       disintegrates intact ACM.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Amended water</span> means water to which surfactant       (wetting agent) has been added to increase the ability of the liquid to penetrate ACM. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Asbestos</span> includes chrysotile, amosite, crocidolite,       tremolite asbestos, anthophyllite asbestos, actinolite asbestos, and any of these minerals       that has been chemically treated and/or altered. For purposes of this standard,       "asbestos" includes PACM, as defined in this section.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Asbestos-containing material (ACM)</span>, means any       material containing more than one percent asbestos.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Authorized person</span> means any person authorized by       the employer and required by work duties to be present in regulated areas.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Building/facility owner</span> is the legal entity,       including a lessee, which exercises control over management and record keeping functions       relating to a building and/or facility in which activities covered by this standard take       place. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Category I non-friable asbestos-containing material       (ACM)</span> means asbestos-containing packings, gaskets, resilient floor covering, and       asphalt roofing products containing more than 1 percent asbestos as determined using the       method specified in appendix A, subpart F, 40 CFR part 763, section 1, Polarized Light       Microscopy. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Category II non-friable ACM</span> means any material,       excluding Category I non-friable ACM, containing more than 1 percent asbestos as determined       using the methods specified in appendix A, subpart F, 40 CFR part 763, section 1,       Polarized Light Microscopy that, when dry, cannot be crumbled, pulverized, or reduced to       powder by hand pressure.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Certified Industrial Hygienist (CIH)</span> means one       certified in the practice of industrial hygiene by the American Board of Industrial       Hygiene. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Class I asbestos work</span> means activities involving       the removal of TSI and surfacing ACM and PACM. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Class II asbestos work</span> means activities involving       the removal of ACM which is not thermal system insulation or surfacing material. This       includes, but is not limited to, the removal of asbestos-containing wallboard, floor tile       and sheeting, roofing and siding shingles, and construction mastics. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Class III asbestos work</span> means repair and       maintenance operations, where "ACM", including TSI and surfacing ACM and PACM,       is likely to be disturbed. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Class IV asbestos work</span> means maintenance and       custodial activities during which employees contact but do not disturb ACM or PACM and       activities to clean up dust, waste and debris resulting from Class I, II, and III       activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Clean room</span><em> </em>means an uncontaminated room       having facilities for the storage of employees' street clothing and uncontaminated       materials and equipment. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Closely resemble</span> means that the major workplace       conditions which have contributed to the levels of historic asbestos exposure, are no more       protective than conditions of the current workplace. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Competent person</span> means, one who is capable of       identifying existing asbestos hazards in the workplace and selecting the appropriate       control strategy for asbestos exposure. This person has the authority to take prompt       corrective measures to eliminate hazards, as specified in 29 CFR 1926.32(f). In addition,       for Class I and Class II work the "competent person" is specially trained in a       training course which meets the criteria of EPA's Model Accreditation Plan (40 CFR 763)       for supervisor, or its equivalent and, for Class III and Class IV work, is trained in a       manner consistent with EPA requirements for training of local education agency maintenance       and custodial staff as set forth at 40 CFR 763.92 (a)(2).</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Critical barrier</span> means one or more layers of       plastic sealed over all openings into a work area or any other similarly placed physical       barrier sufficient to prevent airborne asbestos in a work area from migrating to an       adjacent area. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Decontamination area</span> means an enclosed area       adjacent and connected to the regulated area and consisting of an equipment room, shower       area, and clean room, which is used for the decontamination of workers, materials, and       equipment that are contaminated with asbestos.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Demolition</span> means the wrecking or taking out of any       load-supporting structural member and any related razing, removing, or stripping of       asbestos products. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Disturbance</span> means activities that disrupt the       matrix of ACM or PACM, crumble or pulverize ACM or PACM, or generate visible debris from       ACM or PACM. Disturbance includes cutting away small amounts of ACM and PACM, no greater       than the amount which can be contained in one standard sized glove bag or waste bag in       order to access a building component. In no event shall the amount of ACM or PACM so       disturbed exceed that which can be contained in one glove bag or waste bag which shall not       exceed 60 inches in length and width. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Employee exposure</span> means exposure to airborne       asbestos that would occur if the employee were not using respiratory protective equipment. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Equipment room (change room)</span> means a contaminated       room located within the decontamination area that is supplied with impermeable bags or       containers for the disposal of contaminated protective clothing and equipment. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Fiber</span> means a particulate form of asbestos, 5       micrometers or longer, with a length-to-diameter ratio of at least 3 to 1. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Glovebag </span>means not more than a 60 x 60 inch       impervious plastic bag-like enclosure affixed around an asbestos-containing material, with       glove-like appendages through which material and tools may be handled. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">High-efficiency particulate air (HEPA) filter </span>means       a filter capable of trapping and retaining at least 99.97 percent of all mono-dispersed       particles of 0.3 micrometers in diameter.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Homogeneous area</span> means an area of surfacing       material or thermal system insulation that is uniform in color and texture. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Industrial hygienist</span> means a professional qualified       by education, training, and experience to anticipate, recognize, evaluate and develop       controls for occupational health hazards. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Intact</span><em> </em>means that the ACM has not crumbled,       been pulverized, or otherwise deteriorated so that the asbestos is no longer likely to be       bound with its matrix. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Modification</span><em> </em>means a changed or altered       procedure, material or component of a control system, which replaces a procedure, material       or component of a required system. Omitting a procedure or component, or reducing or       diminishing the stringency or strength of a material or component of the control system is       not a "modification" for purposes of this section. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Negative Initial Exposure Assessment</span> means a       demonstration by the employer, which complies with the criteria of this section, that       employee exposure during an operation is expected to be consistently below the PELs. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">PACM means</span> "presumed asbestos containing       material" see below. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Presumed Asbestos Containing Material</span><em> </em>means       thermal system insulation and surfacing material found in buildings constructed no later       than 1980. The designation of a material as "PACM" may be rebutted pursuant to       this section. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Project Designer</span> means a person who has       successfully completed the training requirements for an abatement project designer       established by 40 U.S.C. Sec. 763.90(g). </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Regulated asbestos-containing material (RACM)</span><em> </em>means       (a) Friable asbestos material, (b) Category I non-friable ACM that has become friable, (c)       Category I non-friable ACM that will be or has been subjected to sanding, grinding,       cutting, or abrading, or (d) Category II non-friable ACM that has a high probability of       becoming or has become crumbled, pulverized, or reduced to powder by the forces expected       to act on the material in the course of demolition or renovation operations regulated by       this subpart. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Regulated area</span> means: an area established by the       employer to demarcate areas where Class I, II, and III asbestos work is conducted, and any       adjoining area where debris and waste from such asbestos work accumulate; and a work area       within which airborne concentrations of asbestos, exceed or there is a reasonable       possibility they may exceed the permissible exposure limit.&nbsp; </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Removal</span> means all operations where ACM and/or PACM       is taken out or stripped from structures or substrates, and includes demolition       operations.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Renovation</span> means the modifying of any existing       structure, or portion thereof.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Repair</span> means overhauling, rebuilding,       reconstructing, or reconditioning of structures or substrates, including encapsulation or       other repair of ACM or PACM attached to structures or substrates.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Surfacing material</span> means material that is sprayed,       troweled-on or otherwise applied to surfaces (such as acoustical plaster on ceilings and       fireproofing materials on structural members, or other materials on surfaces for       acoustical, fireproofing, and other purposes).</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Surfacing ACM</span> means surfacing material which       contains more than 1% asbestos.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Thermal system insulation (TSI)</span><em> </em>means ACM       applied to pipes, fittings, boilers, breeching, tanks, ducts or other structural       components to prevent heat loss or gain. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Thermal system insulation ACM</span> is thermal system       insulation which contains more than 1% asbestos.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><br /> <br /></span></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="5.0 Asbestos Inspections and Inventory">5.0 Asbestos Inspections and Inventory</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">BYU-Idaho will determine the presence, location, and quantity       of ACM and or PACM in all university facilities. This determination shall be primarily       accomplished through inspections and bulk sample analysis of all building materials       installed prior to1981. Suspect building material (installed prior to 1981 that could       contain asbestos or that in the opinion of a competent person could contain asbestos )       shall be considered and treated as ACM unless it is determined to be non-ACM through       sample analysis, building records, or other methods in accordance with 29 CFR 1926.1101.       Bulk sample collection will be performed by those who have completed an accredited       asbestos inspector training course and are licensed by the Idaho Division of Air Quality.       All bulk samples will be analyzed at laboratories accredited by the AIHA and NVLAPS for       asbestos analysis. Once completed, the asbestos inventory will be available at the       Safety Office and the&nbsp; Physical Plant Construction Office.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="6.0 Requirements for Asbestos Work">6.0 Requirements for Asbestos Work</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">All asbestos assessment and abatement work shall be done in       accordance with state and federal regulatory requirements. Ricks personnel do not perform       Class I, II, or III work. All Class I, II, and III asbestos work (abatement) shall be       performed by asbestos abatement contractors that are certified, licensed, bonded, and       insured to work in the state of Idaho. Non-Ricks abatement contractors will be solely       responsible for the training, respiratory protection, exposure monitoring, and medical       surveillance of their own workers.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1 The following are general requirements for working with       asbestos containing materials:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.1 All asbestos work in regulated areas shall be supervised by         a competent person.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.2 Eating, drinking, smoking, chewing tobacco or gum, or         applying cosmetics, is prohibited in regulated areas.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.3 Access to regulated areas is limited to authorized persons         only.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.4 A competent person shall perform an exposure assessment         immediately before the initiation of any asbestos work.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.5 Unless a negative exposure assessment is determined,         personal monitoring shall be conducted to assess employee exposures.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.6 Vacuums equipped with HEPA filters shall be used to collect         all dust and debris containing ACM.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.7 Sanding, dry sweeping or other dry clean up, compressed         air, mechanical chipping, or other abrasive methods shall be prohibited on all ACM or         PACM.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.8 Wet methods, or wetting agents shall be used on all         asbestos work.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">6.1.9 Breaking, crumbling, or any other activity that generates         airborne asbestos fibers shall be avoided to the extent feasible. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a href="7.0 Requirements for Class IV Asbestos Work" name="7.0 Requirements for Class IV Asbestos Work">7.0 Requirements for Class IV Asbestos Work</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Class IV asbestos work consists of maintenance or custodial       activities during which employees contact but do not disturb ACM or cleanup waste and       debris resulting from Class I through III activities. Class IV work includes the following       additional requirements:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">7.1 When asbestos containing roofing material is removed, it       shall not be dropped or thrown to the ground, but shall be hand carried to the ground or       lowered to the ground in a covered, dust-tight chute. Such material must be removed no       later than the end of the work shift. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="8.0 Personal Protective Equipment">8.0 Personal Protective Equipment</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">As university personnel do not perform Class I, II, or III asbestos       work, it is not expected that respirator use will be required.       Non-university workers who       perform abatement work at BYU-Idaho facilities will be responsible for their own       respiratory protection programs. Should it become necessary for university       personnel to wear       respirators for asbestos concerns, the applicable portions of the BYU-Idaho       Respiratory Protection Program will be followed.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="9.0 Training">9.0 Training</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Training will be provided to all university employees engaged in Class       IV asbestos work.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">9.1 Training will be provided prior to the initial assignment and       at least annually thereafter.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">9.2 Training for Class IV workers will be asbestos awareness       training and will consist of approximately 2 hours of training.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><a name="10.0 Waste Disposal"><strong>10.0 </strong></a><strong><a href="#10.0 Waste Disposal">Waste Disposal</a></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">ACM waste shall be collected and disposed of in sealed, labeled,       impermeable bags or other containers. Asbestos abatement contractors shall dispose of the       asbestos waste in accordance with all federal, state, and local regulations.       The BYU-Idaho Safety Office&nbsp; shall ensure that asbestos waste from       university facilities is disposed of properly.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="11.0 Notification to Regulatory Agencies">11.0 Notification to Regulatory       Agencies</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Prior to any demolition or renovation project, the       university safety office or an asbestos contractor will make a determination of the total quantity of RACM       that will be disturbed or removed during the project. He will insure that proper       notifications are sent (by himself or by the Asbestos Abatement Contractor) to the       Division of Air Quality if at least 80 linear meters (260 linear feet) on pipes or at       least 15 square meters (160 square feet) on other facility components, or at least 1 cubic       meter (35 cubic feet) of facility components where the length or area could not be       measured previously, are stripped, removed, dislodged, cut, drilled, or similarly       disturbed. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1 The following information will be included in the       notification:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.1 An indication of whether the notice is the original or a         revised notification. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.2 Name, address, and telephone number of both the facility         owner and operator and the asbestos removal contractor owner or operator. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.3 Type of operation: demolition or renovation. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.4 Description of the facility or affected part of the         facility including the size (square meters (square feet) and number of floors), age, and         present and prior use of the facility. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.5 Procedure, including analytical methods, employed to         detect the presence of RACM and Category I and Category II non-friable ACM. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.6 Estimate of the approximate amount of RACM to be removed         from the facility in terms of length of pipe in linear meters (linear feet), surface area         in square meters (square feet) on other facility components, or volume in cubic meters         (cubic feet) if off the facility components. Also, estimate the approximate amount of         Category I and Category II non-friable ACM in the affected part of the facility that will         not be removed before demolition. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.7 Location and street address (including building number or         name and floor or room number, if appropriate), city, county, and state, of the facility         being demolished or renovated. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.8 Scheduled starting and completion dates of asbestos         removal work (or any other activity, such as site preparation that would break up,         dislodge, or similarly disturb asbestos material) in a demolition or renovation; planned         renovation operations involving individual nonscheduled operations shall only include the         calendar year included from January 1 to December 31 as the beginning and ending dates of         the report period.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.9 Scheduled starting and completion dates of demolition or         renovation. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.10 Description of planned demolition or renovation work to         be performed and method(s) to be employed, including demolition or renovation techniques         to be used and description of affected facility components. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.11 Description of work practices and engineering controls to         be used to comply with the requirements of this subpart, including asbestos removal and         waste-handling emission control procedures. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.12 Name and location of the waste disposal site where the         asbestos - containing waste material will be deposited. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.13 A certification that at least one person trained as         required by the National Emission Standard for Hazardous Air Pollutants will supervise the         stripping and removal described by this notification.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.14 Description of procedures to be followed in the event         that unexpected RACM is found or Category II non-friable ACM becomes crumbled, pulverized,         or reduced to powder. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">11.1.15 Name, address, and telephone number of the waste         transporter. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="12.0 Communication of Asbestos Hazards">12.0 Communication of Asbestos Hazards</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Before any asbestos work is begun, BYU-Idaho       safety personnel shall determine the presence, location, and quantity of ACM or PACM. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">12.1&nbsp; The university safety office shall notify the       following individuals of its presence, location, and quantity:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">12.1.1 Prospective employers applying or bidding for work in         areas containing such material;</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">12.1.2 BYU-Idaho employees who will work in or adjacent to         areas containing such material;</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">12.1.3 Non-BYU-Idaho employers of workers who will be         performing work in or adjacent to areas containing such materials;</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">12.1.4 Tenants who will occupy areas containing such materials.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">12.2 In addition, all employers who discover ACM or PACM on a       worksite shall convey information concerning the presence, location, and quantity of such       newly discovered material to the Physical Plant Construction Manager       and/or the Safety Officer as soon as feasible. If asbestos is accidentally disturbed and could       present a hazard to workers or building occupants, those who disturbed or discovered the       material shall immediately contact the university safety office so that       appropriate precautions can be implemented. If Safety Office personnel are       unavailable then the Campus Police should be contacted. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="13.0 Signs and Labels">13.0 Signs and Labels</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">All regulated areas shall be posted with warning sign(s) in       accordance with 29 CFR 1926.1101, section k.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">13.1 Signs shall also be posted at the entrance(s) to mechanical       rooms or other such areas which employees can be expected to enter and which contain       thermal system insulation or surfacing ACM or PACM. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">13.1.1 These signs shall identify the material which is present,         its location, and appropriate work practices to be followed to avoid asbestos disturbance. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">13.2 Labels shall be affixed to all products containing asbestos       and to all containers of ACM waste. This does not apply to asbestos fibers that have been       modified by a bonding agent or coating provided that the asbestos manufacturer       demonstrates that no fibers in excess of the PEL will be released during any reasonably       foreseeable use or handling. Labels shall be marked in accordance with 29 CFR       1926.1101,(k)(8). </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">13.3 Asbestos warning signs, as noted above, may be used in lieu       of labels so long as they convey the information required for labeling. Such signs and       labels shall be attached in areas where they will clearly be noticed by employees who are       likely to be exposed, such as at the entrance to mechanical rooms/areas. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="14.0 Air Monitoring">14.0 Air Monitoring</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Air sampling will be conducted for university personnel       engaged in asbestos work who have the potential to be exposed to asbestos concentrations       above the PEL. This exposure determination, as well as the actual air sampling will be       performed by the Safety Office. Air monitoring will be conducted in       accordance with NIOSH or other nationally recognized methods. Sample analysis will be       performed at laboratories accredited by AIHA for asbestos analysis. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">14.1 BYU-Idaho shall notify affected employees of monitoring       results as soon as possible following receipt of laboratory results. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="15.0 Responsibilities">15.0 Responsibilities</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1 Duties of the BYU-Idaho Safety Office:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.1 Coordinate all asbestos abatement activities at         university facilities.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.2 Serve as the point of contact between BYU-Idaho and regulatory         agencies.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.3 Request asbestos clearance sampling from         Safety Office or from a qualified consultant.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.4 Ensure that all persons performing asbestos work are         following the requirements in this plan as well as applicable State, Federal, and local         requirements.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.5 Coordinate asbestos abatement activities and contracts         with non-university employers and employees and inform them of possible asbestos         hazards.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.6 Ensure that ACM is disposed of in accordance with         regulations.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.1.7 Ensure that clearance sampling is performed for all         asbestos abatement projects performed by non-university employees. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2 The BYU-Idaho Safety Office will       have the following duties:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.1 Perform clearance sampling as requested by         university personnel </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.2 Conduct asbestos awareness training for         university personnel. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.3 Conduct personal air sampling of         university employees         exposed to asbestos as applicable.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.4 Review and/or revise the BYU-Idaho Asbestos Management         Plan on a regular (at least annual) basis.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.5 Develop and maintain a current inventory of the amount,         type and location of ACM by means of surveys, analysis of material and using consultants         when necessary.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.6 Attach labels and signs to ACM in accordance with section         13.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.7 Perform assessments of BYU-Idaho workers involved in         asbestos activities to determine if any employees are exposed at or above the PELs.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">15.2.8 Inform university employees of their exposures after         receiving sampling results.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"> <a name="16.0 Non-Construction Asbestos Activities">16.0 Non-Construction Asbestos       Activities</a></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">This section only applies to those who are engaged in asbestos       brake and/or clutch repair or custodial employees whose housekeeping or cleaning duties       entail exposure to asbestos containing material. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.1 The Safety Office will assess the exposures of such       personnel exposed to asbestos in non-construction activities to determine if any employees       are exposed above the PELs.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.1.1 If any university personnel are exposed at or above the PELs,         then an air monitoring program, respiratory protection program, and several additional         controls as specified in 29 CFR 1910.1001 will be implemented. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.2 Employees engaged in ACM brake and/or clutch repair shall       receive asbestos training. This training will include the specific requirements found in       29 CFR 1910.1001, Appendix F. These requirements are found in Appendix 5 of the       BYU-Idaho Asbestos Management Plan. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.3 For employees who perform housekeeping duties in areas which       contain ACM or PACM the following requirements shall be followed:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.3.1 Employees shall receive asbestos hazard communication         training. They shall be informed of the presence and location of ACM and PACM in their         work areas, and steps they can take to minimize disturbing the asbestos.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.3.2 Sanding of ACM floor tile is prohibited.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.3.3 Stripping of finishes shall be conducted using low         abrasion pads at speeds lower than 300 rpm and wet methods.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.3.4 Dry buffing may be performed only on ACM flooring which         has sufficient finish so that the pad cannot contact the ACM.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">16.3.5 ACM that is visibly dusty or deteriorated shall not be         dusted, swept dry, or vacuumed without using a HEPA filter.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><a></a><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a> </span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
