<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46680" Name="Adding Classes / Instructor Authorizations FAQs" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Adding Classes / Instructor Authorizations FAQs</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Adding Classes / Instructor Authorizations FAQs</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style><!--
ul#navi li{
list-style-type:disc;
}
--></style>
<ul id="navi">
<li><a href="#faq1">I want to add a specific class, but it&rsquo;s full. What do I do?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq2">I want to add a specific class, but I have not taken its prerequisite(s). Can I still take the class?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq3">Can I take a class if it overlaps with another class I&rsquo;m already registered for?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq4">Can is still take a class even if I don't meet the requirements?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq5">The instructor has authorized me to add a class, but I still can&rsquo;t add it. What do I do?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq6">I&rsquo;ve contacted the instructor about an authorization, and received no response. What do I do?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq7">I can&rsquo;t find a specific class that I want to add. What do I do?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq8">I&rsquo;m trying to add a class, but there are no add boxes next to the classes. What&rsquo;s wrong?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq9">Can I add a class if I have a hold on my account?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq10">Can I add a class after the add deadline?</a></li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="faq1"></a>I want to add a specific class, but it&rsquo;s full. What do I do?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class that is full, they need to either keep checking back for  openings, or they can contact the course instructor. The instructor may, at his/her  discretion, grant a Capacity Authorization to the student to add the full class or some  instructors have waiting lists.</p>
<h3><a name="faq2"></a>I want to add a specific class, but I have not taken its prerequisite(s). Can I still take the  class?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class, but they haven&rsquo;t met the prerequisite(s), they may  contact the instructor and request a Course Requisite Authorization; however, it is the  instructor&rsquo;s decision whether he/she will (or can) allow students to add certain classes  without having taken the prerequisite(s).</p>
<h3><a name="faq3"></a>I want to add a specific class, but it overlaps with another class I&rsquo;m already registered for  (e.g., there is a 15-minute time conflict). Can I still take the class?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class, but it conflicts with another one of their classes, they  may contact the course instructor for the class they want to add and request a  Schedule Conflict Authorization; however, it is the instructor&rsquo;s decision whether  he/she will allow students to add their class and accommodate time conflicts.</p>
<h3><a name="faq4"></a>I want to add a specific class, but I do not meet the requirements (e.g., 2.5 GPA, junior  standing, instructor authorization required, etc.). Can I still take the class?</h3>
<p>If students want to add a class, but they haven&rsquo;t met the requirement(s), they may  contact the instructor and request a Course Requirement Authorization; however, it is  the instructor&rsquo;s decision whether he/she will (or can) allow students to add certain  classes without having met the requirement(s).</p>
<h3><a name="faq5"></a>The instructor has authorized me to add a class, but I still can&rsquo;t add it. What do I do?</h3>
<p>There are many reasons that could keep a course authorization from working. Such  reasons include the following: 1) You are trying to add a different section from what  the instructor has authorized you to add; 2) You have only been authorized for the  Capacity Authorization when in fact you may also need a Course Requirement  Authorization or other authorization to be able to add that section; 3) You are not  able to add the class because you are an off-track student trying to add a DAY section  or vice-versa; 4) There is a hold on your account preventing you from registering  (adding/dropping) classes.</p>
<h3><a name="faq6"></a>I&rsquo;ve contacted the instructor about an authorization, but it&rsquo;s been several days, and I&rsquo;ve  received no response. What do I do?</h3>
<p>A follow-up phone call or e-mail sometimes helps you get in touch with an instructor.  If after several attempts you still cannot reach him/her, you may contact the  department secretary for that instructor&rsquo;s department to see if she can assist you in  contacting the instructor.8</p>
<h3><a name="faq7"></a>I can&rsquo;t find a specific class that I want to add. What do I do?</h3>
<p>Make sure you have cleared all of your search criteria and conducted more general  searches (e.g., if you&rsquo;re specifically looking for a math class, simply search under the  Mathematics discipline; don&rsquo;t search for anything more specific than that). If you still  cannot find it, it&rsquo;s possible that the specific course you&rsquo;re looking for is not available  this semester or has been discontinued. You may contact the Student Records and  Registration Office for assistance.</p>
<h3><a name="faq8"></a>I&rsquo;m trying to add a class, but there are no add boxes next to the classes. What&rsquo;s wrong?</h3>
<p>If you do not have any add boxes, this usually means one of the following: 1)  You  have a hold on your account that prevents registration (adding/dropping) until you  resolve the hold; 2) You do not have registration clearance, and you need to call the  Student Records and Registration Office to obtain clearance; or 3) You are not  currently admitted to BYU&ndash;Idaho.</p>
<h3><a name="faq9"></a>Can I add a class if I have a hold on my account?</h3>
<p>No. Most holds prevent students from registering (adding/dropping classes) until  they resolve the hold. Keep in mind, however, that the following holds do not prohibit registration: Academic Warning (WARN), Academic Probation (PROB),  Achieving Academic Success Workshop (AASW), No School Address (NOLO), Academic  Advising Plan (PLAN), Endorsement Notification (SHWA), and Invalid U.S. SSN (SSN)  holds.</p>
<h3><a name="faq10"></a>Can I add a class after the add deadline?</h3>
<p>Yes, as long as you have received at least a Course Requirement Authorization, in  addition to any other authorizations you may need, from the instructor.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17143" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
