<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46745" Name="Hearing Conservation Program" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Hearing Conservation Program</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Hearing Conservation Program</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left"><strong>Purpose</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>To protect university employees from noise exposures; to conserve       hearing ability; and to prevent occupational hearing loss.</p>
<strong>
<p align="left">Sources</p>
</strong>
<p><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/1910-95 Occupational noise exposure.pdf" target="_blank">29 <em>Code of Federal Regulations</em> &sect;1910.95</a></p>
<p><strong>Appendices:</strong> <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Noise exposure computation - Appendix A.pdf" target="_blank">A         - Noise Exposure computation</a>;&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Methods for estimating the adequacy of hearing protector attenuation - Appendix B.pdf" target="_blank">B         - Methods for estimating adequacy</a>;&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Audiometric measuring instruments - Appendix C.pdf" target="_blank">C         - Audiometric Measuring Instruments;</a>&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Audiometric test rooms - Appendix D.pdf" target="_blank">D         - Audiometric Test Rooms;</a>&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Acoustic calibration of audiometers - Appendix E.pdf" target="_blank">E         - Acoustic Calibration;</a>&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Calculations and application of age corrections to audiograms - Appendix F.pdf" target="_blank">F         - Calculations and Application of Age Corrections;</a>&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Monitoring noise levels - Appendix G.pdf" target="_blank">G         - Monitoring Noise Levels;</a>&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Availability of referenced documents - Appendix H.pdf" target="_blank">H         - Availability of Documents;</a>&nbsp; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/Hearing Conservation/Definitions - Appendix I.pdf" target="_blank">I         - Definitions</a></p>
<em> </em>
<p align="left"><em>&nbsp;</em><strong>Applicability</strong></p>
<p>University employees who are exposed to noise greater than 85 decibels       (dBA) on the A scale and/or employees who work in areas where excessive       noise levels, or the potential for excessive noise levels, may exist.</p>
<strong>
<p align="left">Policy</p>
</strong>
<p>BYU-Idaho provides hearing protection to employees, when needed, to       prevent occupational exposure to noise levels that exceed or may exceed       established permissible exposure limits established by the U.S.       Occupational Health and Safety Administration. Administrative and/or       engineering control measures, e.g., enclosures, damping with absorbents,       sound insulating, job rotation, etc., must be considered and implemented,       when feasible, prior to the use of hearing protection. If administrative       and/or engineering controls are not feasible, appropriate hearing       protection must be used.</p>
<p>An employee whose job function requires the use of hearing protection       should receive an initial audiogram examination and training before his or       her initial assignment, and annually thereafter.</p>
<hr size="1" />
<strong>Responsibilities of the University</strong>
<p>BYU-Idaho maintains the Hearing Conservation Program (HCP) for university       employees who may be exposed to excessive noise levels during the       performance of their duties. The HCP is designed to achieve regulatory       compliance and to provide a means for employees to be better informed       about and protected from excessive noise levels and hearing loss.</p>
<hr size="1" />
<strong>Responsibilities of the University Safety Office</strong>
<p>The Safety Office develops, implements, updates, and       maintains the university's HCP, assists departments       with evaluating hearing hazards, and provides guidance on suitable control       measures (including, but not limited to, engineering controls,       administrative guidelines, and appropriate personal protective equipment). In addition, the       safety office reassesses work areas as necessary and provides employee       training.</p>
<p>Safety Office personnel will perform an evaluation of the noise levels       in suspected work areas. When measurement results indicate that any       employee's noise exposure may equal or exceed an 8-hour time-weighted       average (TWA) of 85 dBA, monitoring is conducted to document the exposure       and determine whether the employee should be included in the HCP.       Screening and additional monitoring is repeated whenever a change in       production, process, equipment or controls increases the noise exposures.       Employees who are exposed above an 8-hour TWA of 85 dBA are notified       of the results.</p>
<hr size="1" />
<strong>Responsibilities of the Departments</strong>
<p>Departments, shops and other university entities must identify       employees who may be exposed to excessive noise levels and ensure that       these employees are provided the protection required by the HCP. In       addition, departments must determine whether administrative and/or       engineering controls can be used in lieu of hearing-protective equipment       and implement these controls when feasible; establish and maintain written       standard operating procedures; ensure that only properly trained employees       use hearing-protective equipment; and document and maintain all records       pertaining to employee audiometric examinations and training.</p>
<p>Department supervisors are responsible for identifying potentially       harmful noise levels at their work areas. Supervisors may suspect       potentially harmful noise levels when noise in the work area routinely       interferes with verbal communication; when noise routinely startles,       annoys, or disrupts an employee or interferes with his or her ability to       concentrate; or when it is the suspected cause of noticeable hearing loss       or pain. Whenever a harmful noise level is suspected, the supervisor       should notify the university Safety Office.</p>
<p>All employees who are exposed to a TWA of greater than 85 dBA should       receive audiometric testing and an initial audiogram examination by a       qualified physician, otolaryngologist, audiologist, or certified       technician. This examination consists of a baseline audiogram and annual       audiograms thereafter.</p>
<p>Before using earplugs and/or earmuffs, each employee who is exposed to       noise levels above an 8-hour TWA of 85 dBA should receive training.       Training will be provided by supervisors and/or Safety Office personnel to       employees upon initial work assignment to areas that are identified as       excessively noisy, and annually thereafter or upon request. Information       provided in the annual training program is updated to be consistent with       any changes in regulation, personal protective devices and work processes.</p>
<p>The training includes, but is not limited to, the following       topics:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>the effects of noise on hearing</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>the purpose of hearing protectors; the advantages, disadvantages,           and attenuation of various types; and instructions on selection,           fitting (hands-on), use, and care&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>the purpose of audiometric testing, and an explanation of the test           procedures.</li>
</ul>
<hr size="1" />
<strong>Responsibilities of Employees</strong>
<p>University personnel who work in noisy areas during the performance of       their duties must use safe work practices, wear appropriate hearing       protection while performing job functions, attend training on noise and       hearing protection, report changes in workplace or "noisy"       conditions to their supervisors, and comply with all provisions of the HCP.</p>
<p>In addition, employees can assist the safety office by doing the       following when possible:</p>
<ul>
<li>identify potential noisy areas of concern and contact the           Safety Office to schedule an evaluation</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>review the university's Hearing and Conservation Program (HCP) and           ensure compliance with all requirements</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>determine whether administrative and/or engineering controls can be           used in lieu of protective hearing equipment and implement these           controls when feasible</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>establish and maintain written standard operating procedures and           ensure that employees whose job functions require the use of hearing           protection are trained on the use of hearing-protective equipment</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>ensure that employees are provided with and use proper protective           hearing equipment</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>ensure that employees whose job functions require the use of hearing           protection receive an initial audiogram examination and an examination           annually thereafter</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>document and maintain all records pertaining to employee medical           examinations, training, and audiometric testing within the department.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The University Safety Office is responsible to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>develop and implement a written hearing conservation program</p>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>
<p>perform noise monitoring upon request from the individual           departments that are concerned with noisy areas</p>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>
<p>provide guidance on written standard operating procedures, assist           departments with evaluating noise and hearing hazards, and provide           guidance on suitable control measures including appropriate protective           equipment</p>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>
<p>provide training and retraining for employees as requested by           individual departments</p>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>
<p>document and maintain employee training</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>reassess work areas as necessary.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>arrange for the annual on-site           audiometric testing</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The employee should:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>ensure that he or she is provided with the appropriate training,           medical examinations, and hearing protection if performing duties that           require the use of hearing protection</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>wear appropriate hearing protection while performing job functions           that require its use</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>report changes in workplace or hearing loss to supervisor</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>comply with all provisions of this policy as it applies to employees           who are exposed to noise greater than 85 decibels (dBA) on the A scale           and/or employees who work in areas where excessive noise levels, or           the potential for excessive noise levels, may exist.</li>
</ul>
<p>Safety Office personnel are available to conduct departmental or       individual training relative to any of the listed safety topics upon       request.&nbsp; Please <a href="mailto:harmstone@byui.edu">contact the safety       office</a> with your request or with any questions regarding information       on the Safety Web Page.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
