<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46758" Name="Housekeeping Policy" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Housekeeping Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Housekeeping Policy</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1 style="text-align: center;">General Housekeeping Policy</h1>
<h2><strong><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #084b8a;">I. PURPOSE</span></strong></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To establish the requirement and responsibilities for routine         housekeeping to ensure that work areas are maintained in a clean manner         and present an acceptable appearance.</p>
<br />
<h2><strong><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #084b8a;">II. POLICY</span></strong></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The university strives to provide a safe and healthy         environment for its students, faculty, staff, and visitors. Good housekeeping is a major         factor in minimizing occupational&nbsp; injuries and         illnesses. The guidelines outlined in this document represent acceptable housekeeping practices for the         university. All employees are encouraged to take personal initiative in following the         procedures outlined in         this document and to continually contribute to a safe, clean and orderly         environment.</p>
<br />
<h2><strong><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #084b8a;">III. SCOPE</span></strong></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">This policy applies to all personnel and facilities of the         university.</p>
<br />
<h2><strong><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #084b8a;">IV. REFERENCES</span></strong></h2>
<ol style="margin-left: 30px;">
<li>OSHA Standard, 29 CFR 1910.22 General Requirements</li>
<li>OSHA Standard, 29 CFR 1910.141 General Environmental Controls</li>
<li>OSHA Standard, 29 CFR 1926.25 Housekeeping</li>
</ol>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong><span style="font-size: 16px; color: #084b8a;">V. PROCEDURE</span></strong></h2>
<div style="margin-left: 30px;">
<p><strong> A. GENERAL</strong><br /> <br /> All personnel will work towards maintaining their respective workplaces         in a clean and orderly manner. Housekeeping encompasses all activities related to the cleanliness of         university facilities, materials, and equipment and the elimination of         nonessential materials and hazardous conditions. The following general         housekeeping practices must be applied to all areas within the         university and all areas where employees perform maintenance,         construction, or other activities:</p>
<ol>
<li>Garbage, scrap, debris and other trash materials are to be properly    disposed of in designated containers and shall be removed on frequent and regular intervals.&nbsp; Containers used for garbage and other oily, flammable or hazardous wastes shall be equipped with covers.</li>
<li>Material and equipment will be stored only in appropriate storage  locations.</li>
<li>Floors should be maintained clean and as dry as reasonably practicable.&nbsp; Liquid spills are to be cleaned up immediately.</li>
<li>Equipment is to be kept clean and in good working condition.</li>
<li>Individual work areas are to be kept clean to insure that work          activities may proceed in an orderly and efficient manner.</li>
<li>Tools, supplies, parts, and equipment will not be used in a manner that would be hazardous or adversely affect the work quality. Control should be used to insure that the work area is maintained in an acceptable manner.</li>
<li>Trenches, pits, or sumps are to be covered or barricaded at all           times.</li>
<li>Welding splatter and slag should be contained with the use of high temperature protective screens or shields. Welding splatter or slag           should be cleaned up before leaving the work site for an extended           period of time. The entire work site will be cleaned at the end of the work shift.</li>
<li>Compressed air shall not exceed 30 psi when used for cleaning purposes. Eye protection is required during these cleaning operations. The use of compressed air for cleaning an employee's body or clothing is discouraged.</li>
<li>Shelved items must be placed in an orderly manner and arranged so that the items cannot easily fall while nearby items are being retrieved.</li>
<li>Items will not be placed in front of shelves so that employees must climb or reach over the items stored in front of the shelves to retrieve items.</li>
<li>Storage of unnecessary combustibles such as cardboard boxes is discouraged.</li>
<li>Items stored shall remain 18" below the plane of the sprinkler heads, or 24" below the ceiling in areas without automatic sprinkler systems.</li>
<li>Every floor, working place, and passageway shall be kept free from protruding nails, splinters, loose boards, and unnecessary holes and openings.</li>
</ol> <br />
<p><strong> B. INSPECTIONS</strong><br /><br /> Work areas will be inspected for deficiencies in cleanliness and good physical appearance. Inspections should be performed at a frequency that will ensure the desired level of cleanliness and appearance are maintained. Supervisors should monitor these areas to insure that housekeeping is acceptable. In shared storage areas, shops, or offices, supervisors of the various employees should work closely together to insure that housekeeping is  maintained in an acceptable manner. Supervisors should develop an inspection checklist that is tailored to the individual shop or departmental area. All deficiencies noted during the inspection should be documented in sufficient detail to allow the use of the checklist as a cleanup guide. (See Housekeeping Checklist). Maintenance deficiencies that pertain to the university facilities should be submitted on a work order to the Physical Plant (extension 2500). During inspections, any safety related deficiencies that constitute hazardous conditions should be given priority attention. Hazardous conditions that constitute imminent danger shall be immediately reported to the departmental supervisor and to the Office of Safety and Fire Protection (extensions 2457 or 2481).<br /> Inspection guidelines:</p>
<ol>
<li>Housekeeping is being maintained as an integral part of every work operation.</li>
<li>Receptacles are available for waste and debris.</li>
<li>Cleaning and removal of waste, debris, and dust is being performed regularly.</li>
<li>A sufficient number of waste receptacles are available to make           their use convenient.</li>
<li>Stairways, aisles, corridors, and passageways are free from loose material and debris and are not used for storage.</li>
<li>Tools, cords, and other materials are not strewn about where they may cause tripping or other safety hazards.</li>
<li>Locker rooms, wash rooms, toilets, drinking fountains, and other           similar facilities are being constantly maintained in a sanitary           condition.</li>
<li>Deficiencies in physical appearance (such as a need for painting           and other appearance related maintenance items) should be noted during the inspections.</li>
<li>Deficiencies in the area of corrective maintenance such as leaking valves or fittings, excessive motor vibrations, etc., should be noted during the inspections.</li>
</ol> <br />
<p><strong>C. RESPONSIBILITIES</strong></p>
<p>1. The Office of Safety and Fire Protection shall:</p>
<ul>
<li>Insure that the requirements of this standard practice remain             current with the applicable regulatory directives.</li>
</ul>
<p>2. Supervisors shall:</p>
<ul>
<li>Insure that elements of this policy are being followed by conducting inspections, reviews, spot-checks, and other warranted follow-up action.</li>
<li>Plan for the necessary funding to insure good housekeeping standards are maintained.</li>
<li>Conduct or arrange for inspections in their area of responsibility.</li>
<li>Insure that each work area under their supervision is maintained at an acceptable level of appearance and cleanliness.</li>
<li>Initiate corrective action for deficient items noted during             inspections.</li>
<br /> 
</ul>
3. Personnel shall:<br /> 
<ul>
<li>Follow the requirements of this housekeeping policy.</li>
</ul>
<br /> Safety Office personnel are available to conduct departmental or       individual training relative to any of the listed safety topics upon       request.&nbsp; Please <a href="mailto:harmstone@byui.edu">contact the safety office</a> with your request or with any questions regarding information on the Safety Web Page.</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
