<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46760" Name="Machine Guarding" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Machine Guarding</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Machine Guarding</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[(Reference: 29 CFR 1910.211-219)       <strong> </strong>
<p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>
<p>There are as many potential hazards created by moving machine parts as         there are types of machines. Safeguards are essential for protecting         operators from needless and preventable injuries.</p>
<strong> </strong> <strong> </strong>
<p><strong>Scope and Application</strong></p>
<p align="left">The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA)         requires guarding for any machine where machine parts, functions, or         processes may cause injury. The need for machine guarding may be found         in machine shops in academic departments, maintenance shops, print         shops, and other areas where mechanical equipment is used.</p>
<strong> </strong> <strong> </strong>
<p><strong>Program Description</strong></p>
<p>Any machine part, function, or process which may cause injury must be         safeguarded. When the operation of a machine or accidental contact with         it can injure the operator or others in the vicinity, the hazards must         be either controlled or eliminated.</p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Where Mechanical Hazards Occur</span></p>
<p>Dangerous moving parts in three basic areas require safeguarding:</p>
<ul>
<li>The point of operation: that point where work is performed on the           material, such as cutting, shaping, boring, or forming of stock.</li>
<li>Power transmission apparatus: all components of the mechanical system         which transmit energy to the part of the machine performing the work.         These components include flywheels, pulleys, belts, connecting rods,         couplings, cams, spindles, chains, cranks, and gears.</li>
<li>Other moving parts: all parts of the machine which move while the         machine is working. These can include reciprocating, rotating, and         transverse moving parts, as well as feed mechanisms and auxiliary parts         of the machine.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Hazardous Mechanical Motions and Actions</span></p>
<p>A wide variety of mechanical motions and actions may present hazards         to the operator. These can include the movement of rotating members,         reciprocating arms, moving belts, meshing gears, cutting teeth, and any         parts that impact or shear. These different types of hazardous         mechanical motions and actions are basic in varying combinations to         nearly all machines, and recognizing them is the first step toward         protecting operators from the danger they present.</p>
<p>The basic types of hazardous mechanical motions and actions are:</p>
<strong>Motions</strong>
<p style="margin-left: 50px;">- rotating (including in-running nip points)<br /> - reciprocating<br /> - transversing</p>
<strong>Actions</strong>
<p style="margin-left: 50px;">- cutting<br /> - punching<br /> - bending</p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Requirements for Safeguards</span></p>
<p>Safeguards must meet these minimum general requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Prevent contact: The safeguard must prevent hands, arms, and any           other part of a operator's body from making contact with dangerous           moving parts. A good safeguarding system eliminates the possibility of           the operator or another worker placing parts of their bodies near           hazardous moving parts.</li>
<li>Secure: Operators should not be able to easily remove or tamper with         the safeguard, because a safeguard that can easily be made ineffective         is no safeguard at all. Guards and safety devices should be made of         durable material that will withstand the conditions of normal use. They         must be firmly secured to the machine.</li>
<li>Protect from falling objects: The safeguard should ensure that no         objects can fall into moving parts. A small tool which is dropped into a         cycling machine could easily become a projectile that could strike and         injure someone.</li>
<li>Create no new hazards: A safeguard defeats its own purpose if it         creates a hazard of its own such as a shear point, a jagged edge, or an         unfinished surface which can cause a laceration. The edges of guards,         for instance, should be rolled or bolted in such a way that they         eliminate sharp edges.</li>
<li>Create no interference: Any safeguard which impedes an operator from         performing the job quickly and comfortably might soon be overridden or         disregarded. Proper safeguarding can actually enhance efficiency since         it can relieve the operator's apprehensions about injury.</li>
<li>Allow safe lubrication: If possible, one should be able to lubricate         the machine without removing the safeguards. Locating oil reservoirs         outside the guard, with a line leading to the lubrication point, will         reduce the need for the operator or maintenance operator to enter the         hazardous area.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Protective Clothing and Personal Protective Equipment</span></p>
<p>Engineering controls that eliminate the hazard at the source and do         not rely on the operator's behavior for their effectiveness offer the         best and most reliable means of safeguarding. Therefore, engineering         controls are the first choice for eliminating machine hazards. But         whenever engineering controls are not available or are not fully capable         of protecting the operator (an extra measure of protection is         necessary), operators must wear protective clothing or personal         protective equipment.</p>
<p>If protective clothing and equipment is to provide adequate protection,       it must always be:</p>
<p style="margin-left: 50px;">- appropriate for the particular hazards<br /> - maintained in good condition<br /> - properly stored when not in use, to prevent damage or loss<br /> - kept clean, fully functional, and sanitary.</p>
<p>Protective clothing is, of course, available for different parts of the       body. Hard hats can protect the head from the impact of bumps and falling       objects when the operator is handling stock; caps and hair nets can help       keep the operator's hair from being caught in machinery. If machine       coolants could splash or particles could fly into the operator's eyes or       face, then face shields, safety goggles, glasses, or similar kinds of       protection might be necessary. Hearing protection may be needed when       operators operate noisy machines. To guard the trunk of the body from cuts       or impacts from heavy or rough-edged stock, there are certain protective       coveralls, jackets, vests, aprons, and full-body suits. Operators can       protect their hands and arms from the same kinds of injury with special       sleeves and gloves. Safety shoes and boots, or other acceptable foot       guards, can shield the feet against injury in case the operator needs to       handle heavy stock which might drop.</p>
<p>It is important to note that protective clothing and equipment can       create hazards. A protective glove which can become caught between       rotating parts, or a respirator face piece which hinders the wearer's       vision, for example, require alertness and continued attentiveness       whenever they are used.</p>
<p>Other parts of the operator's clothing may present additional safety       hazards. For example, loose-fitting shirts might possibly become entangled       in rotating spindles or other kinds of moving machinery. Jewelry, such as       bracelets and rings, can catch on machine parts or stock and lead to       serious injury by pulling a hand into the danger area.</p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Training</span></p>
<p>Even the most elaborate safeguarding system cannot offer effective         protection unless the operator knows how to use it and why. Specific and         detailed training is therefore a crucial part of any effort to provide         safeguarding against machine-related hazards. Thorough operator training         should involve instruction or hands-on training in the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>a description and identification of the hazards associated with           particular machines the safeguards themselves, how they provide           protection, and the hazards for which they are intended</li>
<li>how to use the safeguards and why</li>
<li>how and under what circumstances safeguards can be removed, and by         whom (in most cases, repair or maintenance personnel only)</li>
<li>what to do (e.g., contact the supervisor) if a safeguard is damaged,         missing, or unable to provide adequate protection.</li>
<li>This kind of safety training is necessary for new operators and         maintenance or setup personnel, when any new or altered safeguards are         put in service, or when operators are assigned to a new machine or         operation.</li>
<strong> </strong> 
</ul>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong>Roles and Responsibilities</strong></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Department</span></p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure machines are equipped with appropriate safeguards.</li>
<li>Provide personal protective equipment to operators, when necessary.</li>
<li>Provide machine specific training to operators.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Supervisors</span></p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure operators do not defeat machine safeguards.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Individual</span></p>
<ul>
<li>Operate machines with all safeguards in place.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Safety Office</span></p>
<ul>
<li>Provide assistance in machine safeguard development.</li>
<li>Assist in selection of personal protective equipment.</li>
<li>Assist in development of specific training, when needed.</li>
<li>Provide periodic audits of machine guarding.</li>
</ul>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong>For More Information</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Contact the university           safety office at extensions 2457 or 2481.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>A copy of OSHA's regulation, Machinery and Machine Guarding, 29 CFR           1910 Subpart O, is available through the university safety office.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
