<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x46761" Name="Personal Protective Equipment" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Personal Protective Equipment</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Personal Protective Equipment</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">true</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong><strong>Policy</strong></p>
<p>Personal protective equipment including those for eyes, face, head,         and extremities, protective clothing, respiratory devices, protective         shields and barriers shall be provided, utilized and maintained in a         sanitary and reliable condition whenever deemed necessary by reason of         hazards, processes or environment.</p>
<p><strong>Scope</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>This policy applies to all employees who by nature of their job         function have the potential to be exposed or come into contact with         chemical, physical, radiological or biological hazards which by this         exposure can cause illness, injury or impairment in the function of any         part of the body.</p>
<p><strong>Authority and Responsibility</strong></p>
<strong> </strong><em> </em>
<p><em>Immediate Supervisors </em>are responsible for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensuring personal protective equipment is available and providing             personal protective equipment as required or upon request to all             employees; and</li>
<li>Ensuring personal protective equipment is being used by each             affected employee during all job tasks which require such             protection.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Department Administrators </em>are responsible for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Assessing the workplace to determine if hazards are present, or             are likely to be present, which necessitate the use of personal             protective equipment;</li>
<li>Communicating selection decisions to each affected employee;</li>
<li>Selecting personal protective equipment that properly fits each             affected employee; and</li>
<li>Documenting aforementioned hazard assessment components</li>
</ul>
<em> </em>
<p><em>Employees</em> are responsible for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wearing personal protective equipment when deemed prudent or upon             direction of their immediate supervisor; and</li>
<li>Participating in training.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Considerations</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Personal protective equipment devices alone shall not be relied on to         provide protection against hazards, but shall be used in conjunction         with guards, engineering controls, administration controls and sound         manufacturing practices.</p>
<p>When selecting personal protective equipment, utilize the following         considerations as a basic directive.</p>
<ul>
<li>Application: What part of the body is being protected?</li>
<li>Chemical Resistance: Will material maintain its structural             integrity and protective qualities?</li>
<li>Strength: Is the material resistant to punctures, tears, and             abrasions?</li>
<li>Flexibility: Do gloves provide the necessary dexterity?</li>
<li>Thermal Limits: Does clothing maintain its mobility and protective             capacity in temperature extremes?</li>
<li>Cleanable: Can material be easily cleaned and reused?</li>
<li>Longevity: Will clothing resist aging?</li>
</ul>
<p>Contact the university Office of Safety and Fire Protection (2457 or         2481) or Stores (2325) for personal protective equipment product         recommendations.</p>
<p><strong>Hand Protection</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Hand protection should be worn when hands are exposed to hazards such         as those from skin absorption of harmful substances, severe cuts or         lacerations, severe abrasions, punctures, chemical burns, thermal burns         and harmful temperature extremes.</p>
<p>The type of hand protection used shall be based on the performance         characteristics of the hand protection relative to the task(s) to be         performed, conditions present, duration of use, and the hazards and         potential hazards identified.</p>
<p>With respect to selection of gloves for protection against chemical         hazards:</p>
<ul>
<li>The toxic properties of the chemical(s) must be determined; in             particular, the ability of the chemical to cause local effects on             the skin and/or to pass through the skin and cause systemic effects;</li>
<li>Generally, any "chemical resistant" glove can be used             for dry powders;</li>
<li>For mixtures and formulated products (unless specific test data             are available), a glove shall be selected on the basis of the             chemical component with the shortest breakthrough time, since it is             possible for solvents to carry active ingredients through polymeric             materials; and</li>
<li>Employees shall be able to remove the gloves in such a manner as             to prevent skin contamination.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Head Protection</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Head protection shall be worn in areas where there is a potential for         injury to the head from impact, flying or falling objects (e.g.,         working below other workers who are using tools and materials which         could fall through grates), or electrical shock and burns.</p>
<p>Helmets for protection against impact and penetration of falling         objects shall comply with the "American National Standard for         Personal Protection - Protective Headwear for Industrial Workers         Requirements" (ANSI) Z89.1. Helmets for protection against         electrical shock and burns shall comply with ANSI Z89.2-1971.</p>
<p><strong>Eye/Face Protection</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Suitable eye protection or face protection shall be worn when there         is the potential for exposure to the eyes or face from flying particles,         molten metal, liquid chemicals, acid or caustic liquids, chemical gases         or vapors or potentially injurious light radiation. Side protection is         required when there is a hazard potential from flying objects.         Detachable side protectors (e.g., clip-on or slide-on shields) meeting         the pertinent requirements are acceptable.</p>
<p>Eye protection shall be durable, comfortable and easy to clean.         Persons whose vision requires the use of corrective lenses and who by         nature of their job duties require eye protection shall wear goggles or         a full face shield that can be worn over the prescription lenses.</p>
<p>There are four general classes of eye and face protection: safety         glasses, face shields, goggles and welding helmets. The type of         protection required shall be determined by the type and degree of the         hazard and shall comply with ANSI Z87.1-1989 "American National         Standard Practice for Occupational and Educational Eye and Face         Protection".</p>
<p>Safety glasses shall be worn at all times in the following locations:</p>
<ul>
<li>Academic laboratories;</li>
<li>Physical Plant Shops (e.g., welding, carpentry, automotive);</li>
<li>All areas where airborne materials are present; and</li>
<li>Health Center when invasive patient related tasks are conducted.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Foot Protection</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Foot protection shall be worn when there is the potential for injury         to the feet from falling or rolling objects, objects piercing the sole         of the foot, electrical hazards, hot surfaces and slippery surfaces.</p>
<p>Foot protection shall comply with ANSI Z-1991 "American National         Standard for Personal Protection - Protective Footwear".</p>
<p><strong>Respirators</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Use of respirators shall be done in accordance with the Respiratory         Protection Program</p>
<p><strong>Body Protection</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Full body protection shall be worn when there is a potential for         contamination or exposure to other parts of the body (e.g., legs, arms,         back, chest) from heat, splashes from hot metals and liquids, impacts,         cuts, chemicals and radiation.</p>
<p>Body protection includes the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lab coats;</li>
<li>Boot covers;</li>
<li>Aprons;</li>
<li>Bouffant caps;</li>
<li>Tyvek suits; and</li>
<li>Coveralls.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Electrical Protective Devices</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Rubber insulating equipment should be used/worn to protect employees         from shocks/burns while working on "live" electrical systems.</p>
<p>Rubber insulating equipment shall comply with the following American         Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) standards:</p>
<ul>
<li>Specification for Rubber Insulating Gloves (D120-87);</li>
<li>Specification for Rubber Insulating Matting (ASTM D178-93 or             D178-88);</li>
<li>Specification for Rubber Insulating Blankets (ASTM D1048-93 or             D1048-88a);</li>
<li>Specification for Rubber Insulating Covers (ASTM D1049-93 or             D1049-88);</li>
<li>Specification for Rubber Insulating Line Hose (ASTM D1050-90); and</li>
<li>Specification for Rubber Insulating Sleeves (ASTM D1051-87).</li>
</ul>
<p>All electrical protective equipment shall be subjected to periodic         electrical tests conducted in accordance with appropriate voltages         identified by ASTM standards to reliably indicate whether the insulating         equipment can withstand the voltage involved. Insulating equipment         failing to pass inspections or electrical tests shall NOT be used by         employees.</p>
<p>Rubber insulating equipment test intervals shall occur as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rubber insulating line hoses shall be tested upon indication that             the insulating valve is suspect;</li>
<li>Rubber insulating covers shall be tested upon indication that the             insulating valve is suspect;</li>
<li>Rubber insulating blankets shall be tested before first issue and             every twelve months thereafter;</li>
<li>Rubber insulating gloves shall be tested before first issue and             every six months thereafter; and</li>
<li>Rubber insulating sleeves shall be tested before first issue and             every twelve months thereafter.</li>
</ul>
<em> </em>
<p><em>Note: </em>If the insulating equipment has been electrically tested         but not issued for service, it shall not be placed into service unless         it has been electrically tested within the previous twelve months.</p>
<p>All departments using rubber insulating equipment shall make the         appropriate arrangements for testing of such equipment.</p>
<p><strong>Maintenance Schedules</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>Personal protective equipment shall be inspected, cleaned and         maintained at regular intervals so that the personal protective         equipment can be discarded, changed and/or decontaminated as deemed         necessary. At a minimum, all personal protective equipment shall be         discarded when it has become contaminated, worn, torn or has other         integrity problems.</p>
<p>Personal protective equipment provides the requisite protection. It         is important to ensure that contaminated personal protective equipment         which cannot be decontaminated is disposed in a manner that protects         employees from exposure to hazards.</p>
<em> </em>
<p><em>Note: </em>Inspect personal protective equipment before each use for         tears, punctures, holes, cuts, cracks, embedded foreign objects and         texture changes (e.g., swelling, softening, hardening, becoming sticky         or inelastic).</p>
<p><strong>Training</strong></p>
<strong> </strong><em>
<p>Initial Training</p>
</em>
<p>Initial training shall be provided by the university Office of Safety         and Fire Protection or the appropriate department for each employee who         is required to use personal protective equipment. Each employee shall be         trained in at least the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>When personal protective equipment is necessary;</li>
<li>What personal protective equipment is necessary;</li>
<li>How to properly don, doff, adjust, and wear personal protective             equipment;</li>
<li>The limitations of the personal protective equipment; and</li>
<li>The proper care, maintenance, useful life and disposal of the             personal protective equipment.</li>
</ul>
<p>Each affected employee shall demonstrate an understanding of the         aforementioned training and the ability to use personal protective         equipment properly before being allowed to perform work requiring the         use of personal protective equipment.</p>
<em> </em>
<p><em>Retraining</em></p>
<p>When there is reason to believe that any affected employee who has         already been trained does not have the understanding and skill as         required above,&nbsp; the pertinent department shall make arrangements         with the university safety office and insure that each such employee is         adequately retrained.         Circumstances where retraining is required include, but are not limited         to, situations where:</p>
<ul>
<li>Changes in the workplace render previous training obsolete;</li>
<li>Changes in the types of personal protective equipment to be used             render previous training obsolete; or</li>
<li>Inadequacies in an affected employee's knowledge or use of             assigned personal protective equipment indicate that the employee             has not retained the requisite understanding or skill.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Recordkeeping</p>
</em>
<p>Department supervisors and/or the university Office of Safety and         Fire Protection shall verify that each affected employee has received         and understood the required training through written documentation         containing the name of each employee trained, the date(s) of training         and the subject of the certification.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
