<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x47657" Name="Semester at Badger Creek" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Recreation Management Semester at Badger Creek</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Semester at Badger Creek</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1>The Purpose</h1>
<p>Semester at Badger Creek is a partnership between the Health, Recreation, and Human Perfomance Department, and&nbsp;the Outdoor Learning Center.&nbsp; The program is designed to create deeply significant leadership, learning, and recreational experiences for students whose area of focus (including minors and clusters) is recreation management and therapy.</p>
<h2><br />Program Summary:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Unique Learning Experience: In-Class Instruction/Experiential Labs in the Field (16 Credits)
<ul>
<li>Facilities Management (X-Country Skiing, Sled Hill/tow rope, Ice-Skating, Ropes/Initiatives)</li>
<li>Risk Management - Ropes Course/Initiative Activities Facilitation (ACCT Level 1 Certification)</li>
<li>Program Management - Study and work with various types of programs and settings</li>
<li>Experiential Education - Work with University and community groups at Badger</li>
<li>Cross Country Skiing</li>
<li>Winter Camping</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Live on site at BYU-Idaho Outdoor Learning Center for the semester</li>
<li>Earn Pre-Internship hours</li>
<li>Part-time employment as part of semester 10-20 hours</li>
<li>Certification- ACCT Level 1 Certification (Ropes Courses/Initiatives Facilitator)</li>
</ul>
<h1><br />The Cost</h1>
<h2>Total Program Cost = $1,783 + tuition &amp; fees</h2>
<ul>
<li>Regular Tuition - $1825</li>
<li>Housing (Live on Site) - $600</li>
<li>Food (Pays for fully prepared home style meals) - $973 includes 273 meals @ $3.56 p/meal</li>
<li>Activity Fee - $45</li>
<li>Staff Coat - $120</li>
<li>Travel Fee - $45</li>
</ul>
<h2>When do I need to Pay?</h2>
<ul>
<li>Deposit towards Semester at Badger Creek Fees.&nbsp; $500 - Paid at Registration. Non-refundable</li>
<li>Remainder of Semester at Badger Creek Fees - $1,213 Due January 6, 2014</li>
<li>BYU-Idaho Tuition - Standard Semester Tuition Costs - See Academic Tuition Deadlines</li>
</ul>
<h4><br />Semster at Badger Creek Termination Policy:</h4>
<p>Those who withdraw from Semester at Badger Creek after it has started will be assessed a $500 termination fee, plus 2% per calendar day while enrolled in the program.&nbsp; Termination date will be established as the date written notification is recieved at badgercreek@byui.edu or the physical address: BYU-Idaho, Semester at Badger Creek Program, 103 ASB, Rexburg, ID 83460.&nbsp; Upon receipt of written refund, outstanding balances and/or damages will be determined and deducted from any refund.&nbsp; If the balance due is higher than the refund, the balance will be billed to the student or added to the student's BYU-Idaho account.&nbsp; Any money due to the student will be processed and mailed within 30 days of written notification.<br /><br />Tuition refunds will follow BYU-Idaho financial procedures and deadlines as outlined in the current BYU-Idaho Catalog, accessible at <a href="x42534.xml">www.byui.edu/catalog</a>.<br />Semester at Badger Creek Dismissal Policy:&nbsp; Students dismissed after the program begins will forfeit all fees.</p>
<h1><br />Example of Class/Work Schedule</h1>
<h4><a href="Documents/badger-creek/Tentative Schedule.pdf" title="Schedule" target="_blank"><br />For a Tentative Schedule Click Here</a></h4>
<h1><br /><br />Living on Site</h1>
<p><strong>BADGER CREEK ROOM &amp; BOARD: <br /></strong>The Semester at Badger Creek is housed at the BYU-I Badger Creek Outdoor Learning Center. This is a unique extension of campus and is a wonderful place to learn and enjoy.&nbsp; The setting is beautiful, especially in the winter.<br /><br />Your Semester at Badger Creek fees cover food, housing, and laundry facilities/supplies for the semester. Breakfast, lunch and dinner are served, and vending services are available for snacks.&nbsp; Badger Creek facilities are designed to be rustic. They have been modernized to accommodate extended stays without changing the rustic purpose:&nbsp; electric lighting and heating in the men's cabins, computers and internet connections in the classrooms, etc.&nbsp; Housing consists of bunk bed rooms above the lodge with limited storage and closet space. <br /><br /><strong>WHAT IS EXPECTED OF YOU:</strong>&nbsp; <br />You are expected to adhere to your BYU-Idaho commitments both at Badger Creek and on campus, including the Honor Code and Dress and Grooming Standards. &nbsp;Please review these at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/honorcodeoffice">http://www.byui.edu/honorcodeoffice</a>.&nbsp; <br />Living in close proximity to the same people can be a great blessing and a challenge.&nbsp; You are expected to treat each other with respect and dignity.&nbsp; Deciding now to serve and help your group and to follow your group coordinator will help make Semester at Badger Creek a great experience. The Semester at Badger Creek program is based on the theory of experiential education and includes meeting a variety of people.&nbsp; Please refrain from dating, pairing off, and engaging in public displays of affection. You are expected to do your part in keeping the common areas clean, and in meal preparation and cleanup.&nbsp; You will be assigned to a work committee.<br /><br /><strong>Receiving Mail and Packages:</strong>&nbsp; <br />You will be able to receive postal mail at Badger Creek using the following address:&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong><em>Your Name, BYU-Idaho Semester at Badger Creek Program, 1710 W 10,000 N, Tetonia, ID, 83452</em></strong>.&nbsp; Please remember to let friends and family know when you <span style="text-decoration: underline;">leave</span> Badger so that they can contact you at your campus address. Telephones at Badger Creek are in limited number and for local service only.&nbsp; Please plan to bring a cell phone for your long distance calls. Due to the remote location, however, you may have difficulty obtaining a clear signal in some areas.<br /><strong>&nbsp; </strong><br /><br /><strong>SUNDAY MEETINGS: </strong>&nbsp;<br />Semester at Badger Creek participants attend Young Single Adult meetings in Driggs, Idaho.&nbsp; Sacrament Meeting currently begins at 10:00am.<br /><br /><strong>&nbsp; </strong><br /><strong>TRANSPORTATION:</strong>&nbsp; <br />You are welcome to bring your own vehicle to Badger Creek.&nbsp; You need to be at <strong>Badger Creek Outdoor Learning Center no later than 12:00p.m., January <sup>6th</sup>, 2014. </strong><br /><br /><strong>&nbsp; </strong><br /><strong>HEALTH &amp; MEDICAL CARE:</strong>&nbsp;<br />We strongly recommend you visit with your physician prior to Semester at Badger Creek to insure you are healthy and able to participate in program activities. A Medical History Form and Assumption of Risk Form are included at the back of this information packet.&nbsp; Remember to be thorough and legible as the forms will provide information to the medical treatment staff and facility in case of illness or emergency, as well as permission for treatment.&nbsp; A parent's signature is required for students under age 18.&nbsp; <br /><br />Due to the remote nature of Badger Creek and program field trips, we recommend you bring two different sets of any prescriptions or inhalers, bee sting kits, Benadryl, dietary supplements, and so forth. &nbsp;Please be aware that wilderness expeditions are a distance from hospitals and doctors, and transportation to modern medical care is uncertain and may be delayed.</p>
<h4><a href="Documents/badger-creek/ITEMS TO BRING.pdf" title="List" target="_blank"><br />For a List of Items to bring click here</a></h4>
<p><br /><br /></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x47404" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x44785" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
