<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x47673" Name="Faculty Reserve" Layout="general_Policy.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty Reserve</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty Reserve</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120501T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong></strong>Currently, Faculty Reserve is located as a link on an online adjunct instructor's my.byui.edu portal.&nbsp; At this time, the Registration Office cannot remove this option from these instructors.&nbsp; Though accessible, online adjunct instructors should not use the Faculty Reserve function for their classes.&nbsp; This was decided in January 2010 and re-affirmed on May 1, 2012 in the Online Learning Directors meeting.&nbsp;&nbsp; If an instructor is identified as using the Faculty Reserve, the instructor's name, course, course section, and change in course capacity will be sent to the Online Instruction Director so it can be removed and corrected. Online Operations will be courtesy copied on the email so that they will know that one of their course capacities has been temporarily changed. <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Justification<br /></strong>Further justification is evidenced in exurbs email below.<br /><br />The original decision (Jan 2010) was that: <br />As a policy we need to prohibit individual instructors from reserving any seats for anyone, or trying to cut their load or adjust class constraints by holding back or shutting off enrollment. Reserving seats causes major issues in terms of other policies that have been implemented regarding the online management of seats and sections and in addition, some uses of faculty reserve could be contrary to university policy (aka... instructors closing off enrollment on the first day of class rather than at the end of the university-wide 1<sup>st</sup> week of class add/drop period). <br /><br />The decision was made to try and get the technical functionality removed, if possible, but after discussion with the registrar's office we found out that we are unable to remove this functionality for online instructors. <br /><br />If instructors have concerns about seat capacity they should consult with their CDM during pilot or with their TGL after pilot if they feel the capacity is inappropriate given our workload guidelines of 3-4 hrs/wk per credit. If instructors have other concerns regarding seat management they should express their concerns to their TGL who can then share that information with Online Instruction administrators for further review and discussion. <br /><br />Jan 2010 - Janine Gilbert &amp; Matt Sanders (Online Instruction), Peter Williams (Delivery/Operations), Nathan Relken (Services), Alan Young (Course Development) <br /><br />We have reconfirmed with the Registrar's office that we are still unable to remove this functionality so we may still have faculty members doing so, thus having negative implications on enrollment management procedures worked out between Instruction, Delivery/Operations &amp; Services. We ask that you not publicize this functionality and that you instruct faculty who are doing so (whom we can identify for you) to not do so in the future.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
