<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x47671" Name="Manually Drop Students from Online Courses" Layout="general_Policy.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Manually Drop Students from Online Courses</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Manually Drop Students from Online Courses</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120530T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a name="_Toc331666118"></a>Students Unable to Drop Themselves<br /></strong>If a student is unable to drop/withdrawal themselves from their class or classes, SRR can manually drop theses students. Students should be required to withdraw themselves unless circumstances don't allow them to do so. Unable to drop/withdraw does not mean unwilling to drop/withdraw. Unable can be, but is not limited to:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Physically unable due to illness or medication</li>
<li>No Internet access (mostly for International Pathway Students) Unable is not (for example):</li>
<li>The lack of time to withdraw themselves</li>
<li>The lack of knowledge to withdraw themselves</li>
<li>Telling the missionary couple and assuming it has been done &nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Students that have stopped attending and have less than 1 hour in I-Learn</strong>&nbsp;<br />Every semester there are a handful of students that stop attending class and do not withdraw themselves. Typically, later in the semester an instructor, the actual student, or someone in administration notifies the school that the students is no longer attending and should be removed from the class. Agreements have been made with Student Records and Registration (SRR) and the Bursar's Office to manually drop students without a petition if the student spent less than one hour in the online class and the OSC is notified before the last day to withdraw from a class or classes depending on the withdrawal type. If this is the case, the student will not receive a grade and they will receive a full refund.&nbsp; <br />
<ul>
<li>Students, administration, or instructors will notify the OSC of students that are no longer attending and that should be manually dropped.</li>
<li>The student's class activity will be looked at in I-Learn.</li>
</ul>
&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; o&nbsp;&nbsp; If the student has spent less than one hour in I-Learn, an email will be sent to SRR and the Bursar's Office letting them know.&nbsp;<br />&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; o&nbsp;&nbsp; If the student spent more than one hour in I-Learn, the student can choose to withdraw themselves (unless they are unable). If they are unhappy with the results of their withdrawal, they will need to petition both SRR and Bursar's Office to have their grade removed, withdraw date changed, or an adjustment made to their tuition reimbursement. <br />&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; o&nbsp;&nbsp; If the student spent more than one hour in I-Learn, the student can choose to remain in the class and receive a failing grade. This may seem ideal to some students for financial aid or deferment reasons. <br />
<ul>
<li>After SRR and the Bursar's Office has been notified, the will respond back to the OSC once the student has been withdrawn and tuition adjusted.</li>
<li>The OSC will follow up as needed.</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Note:</strong> The manual drop option is only scalable if the auto drop function is working. The auto drop function should remove many of the students that never attended. This would leave relatively few that need to be manually dropped based on non-attendance.<br /><br /><strong>Students that have stopped attending with more than one hour in the course</strong><br />Students that have more than one hour of recorded time in I-Learn are required to withdraw/drop themselves from the course.&nbsp; In many cases the Instructor or missionaries request to have a student be withdrawn/dropped simply because the student has stopped attending or is unresponsive. In these situations a student is still required to officially withdraw themselves. This is in accordance with Student Records and Registration Office's official policy. Some exceptions may make it necessary to have the school manually withdraw/drop a student. Some examples are: <br />
<ul>
<li>Unable to withdraw themselves due to medical circumstances.</li>
<li>International Pathway students not having Internet access. When possible these students should plan in advance to withdraw themselves before they are without Internet service. &nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Students that are unable to withdraw/drop themselves should contact the Online Support Center for assistance.</strong> <br /><br />If the student is unhappy with their grade or the amount of their tuition refund and the student has spent more than one hour in their online course, they will need to submit an <em>Academic Exceptions Petition</em> to the Student Records and Registration Office's and send an email to the Bursar's Office at <a href="mailto:bursar@byui.edu">bursar@byui.edu</a>.&nbsp; Those offices will make the decision on adjustments to grades and refunds.&nbsp;<br /><br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
