<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x47720" Name="New Course Proposal" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">New Course Proposal</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">New Course Proposal</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong><a href="Documents/foundations/New Course Proposals.docx">New Course Proposals and Development</a></strong><br /><br />Proposals for new courses may come from a variety of sources.&nbsp; They may originate from the faculty, both those currently and those not currently teaching Foundations courses.&nbsp; Deans, Department Chairs, and teaching teams might propose new courses, or a request to develop a new course may come from Academic Administration or the University President.&nbsp; &nbsp; Any idea for a new course should come in the form of a one-page description of the course and address the following questions: &nbsp;
<ul type="disc">
<li>How will the course fit into the current Foundations program? (See the BYUI course catalogue for current Foundations offerings.)</li>
<li>In what ways will the course be cross-disciplinary or interdisciplinary?</li>
<li>What departments and faculty might be interested in teaching the course?</li>
<li>What are the outcomes for the course and how will they be assessed?</li>
<li>What aspects of the course ensure sufficient academic rigor? How will the course build key academic skills, such as reading, writing, oral communication, analytical/problem solving, working on a team, quantitative reasoning, and technology?</li>
<li>How will the course and its instructors engage students, inspire them to delve deeply into the subject matter, and encourage the habits and passions of lifelong learning?</li>
</ul>
&nbsp; The proposal should be submitted to the appropriate Area Chair, who will review it with the Dean and Associate Dean of Foundations and give feedback. If this group feels the idea has merit, the Dean will review it with the Associate Academic Vice President for Curriculum (and possibly the Academic Vice President). At this point a course leader may be assigned to develop a formal course proposal.&nbsp; Released time is not granted for proposal development. &nbsp; A formal course proposal should follow these guidelines: Summary and Overview of the Proposal. This should show how the course meets the outcomes and practices of the BYU-Idaho Foundations program and the area in which the course will reside.
<ul type="disc">
<li>Syllabus and Course Architecture
<ul type="circle">
<li>Course description</li>
<li>Outcomes (no more than six)
<ul type="square">
<li>What do I want students to learn and be able to do?</li>
<li>What are the learning activities to help the student learn?</li>
<li>What will they do (how will I assess the learning) so I know they have learned?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Assessment Plan</li>
<li>Learning model incorporation and implementation</li>
<li>Major units and course activities</li>
<li>Curriculum Map that maps learning units to Outcomes and Assessments</li>
</ul>
&nbsp; When the course leader has prepared the proposal it will be presented to the Curriculum Council.&nbsp; Upon approval the Dean of Foundations will formally present the proposal to the Academic Vice President.&nbsp; University President approval may also be required. &nbsp; Upon approval from the Academic Vice President/University President the course leader can proceed with beta course development and pilot.&nbsp; Additional team members may be appointed at this time or a later date. Released time for the course leader and team members will be granted upon formal approval of course development. &nbsp; After a beta course has been piloted, the development team will meet with the University Curriculum Council to review the course before final approval as a regular offering in the Foundations curriculum. Two weeks before the review with the Foundations Council, the team will provide the Dean of Foundations with a short written document that addresses the following questions:
<ul type="disc">
<li>How integrated is the curriculum across the various sections of the course?</li>
<li>In what ways is the course cross- or interdisciplinary?</li>
<li>Is the course taught by a unified team that meets together regularly to discuss curriculum, instruction, pedagogy, assessment, course improvement, and other course issues?</li>
<li>What are the outcomes for the course? How are they assessed? How does the team use assessment data to improve the course? What has the team learned as a result of their assessment activity?</li>
<li>What aspects of the course ensure sufficient academic rigor? How does the course build key academic skills, such as reading, writing, oral communication, analytical/problem solving, teamwork/interpersonal, quantitative reasoning, and technology? Evidence should be provided from the course syllabus.</li>
<li>How do the course and its instructors engage students, inspire them to delve deeply into the subject matter, and encourage the habits and passions of lifelong learning? Evidence should be provided from examples of course lesson plans.</li>
<li>Do the enrollment patterns and student evaluations of the pilot section(s) indicate that there is sufficient student interest in the course to make it a regular part of the Foundations offerings? Evidence should be provided from student evaluations and section enrollment data.</li>
</ul>
&nbsp; The Dean of Foundations will provide the members of the Foundations Council and the University Curriculum Council with copies of the review document, and it will serve as the basis for conversation in the review meetings. &nbsp; If the course is approved it will be added to the catalogue. The Teaching Team continues to develop the course. The Course Lead usually receive one hour of load each semester for further course development, training of new team members, and inservicing the existing team. Team leads members can apply for leave to further develop the course as part of their regular Faculty Development Process. <a name="_GoBack"></a>&nbsp;]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17649" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
