<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<ContentSnippet ID="x48369" Name="itreorgbody" IsComponent="true"><ContentSnippet type="string" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">&lt;style&gt;
			#split&gt; img{
				float: right;
			}

			#row2{
				background-color: #326BA9;
				font-size: 1.5em;
				color: #FFFFFF;
			}
			#row2&gt; td{
				padding: 0.5em 0.5em 0.5em 0.5em;
				margin: 0 10px 0 10px;
			}
		&lt;/style&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Information Technology Organizational Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Effective Nov 2, 2012, operational and organizational changes were made to the Information Technology (I.T.) department. As BYU-Idaho continues on a steady upward course, I.T. will play and increasingly central role in the university's ability to serve students, employees and many other groups. The changes will allow I.T. to:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ol&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Operate more efficiently&lt;/b&gt; - contributing to our goal to decrease the cost to students&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Increase services&lt;/b&gt; - accommodating more individuals in more locations&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Better assist departments and offices to &lt;b&gt;improve the quality&lt;/b&gt; of their services&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;div id="split"&gt;
			&lt;img height="291" src="Images/helpdesk/itcircle.JPG" width="289" alt="I.T. Reorginization Structural Chart" /&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Each University Vice President has been given a dedicated team of I.T. employees who will work exclusively on their projects arising from their area. These portfolios of work will be reviewed and prioritized by each Vice President&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;A core group of I.T. employees will work on projects and initiatives which apply globaly to the university's employees and students.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;To assist you in understanding how you can begin utilizing these resources, I.T. will be holding a series of informational meetings. All meetings will be in the &lt;b&gt;MC Special Events Room.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;img alt="January 10th at 4pm, January 15th and 11am, and January 16th at 8am" height="83" src="Images/helpdesk/itstrip.JPG" width="529" /&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;For more information about the reorganization please view the Frequently Asked Questions below or view the &lt;a href="http://benjamin.byui.edu/reorg/reorg presentation.pdf" title="Click here to view more information about the I.T. Reorganization"&gt;Reorganization Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</ContentSnippet></ContentSnippet>
