<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x48375" Name="Lifting HCR" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Lifting High Credit Restriction</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Instructions on how to lift a high credit restriction.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<strong><br /> <em>Purpose of High Credit Restriction</em></strong><br /><br /> <em>The purpose of this restriction is three-fold: first, to help you create a graduation plan that will allow you to graduate in a timely manner and as efficiently as possible; second, to support the University's imperative to serve more students by allowing more students to attend BYU-Idaho; finally, it will help you honor your academic </em><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Presentations/Transcripts/Devotionals/2011_09_13_Eyring.htm"><em>stewardship</em></a><em> to use the Church's resources in the most effective and prudent way.</em><br /><br /><hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<h1><strong><br /> Process for Lifting a High Credit Restriction</strong></h1>
<strong>To lift your high credit restriction and a hold on registering, please complete a graduation plan as follows: &nbsp; </strong><br /><br /><ol start="1" type="1">
<li>Go to <a href="https://web.byui.edu/gradplan/">https://web.byui.edu/gradplan/</a> to plan your remaining classes. Due to the number of credits you have earned, you may only plan classes required to earn your degree. (Step-by-step instructions and other helpful tools are included below should you need assistance to complete your graduation plan.)</li>
<li>When you are finished completing your graduation plan, click "Submit for Approval."</li>
<li>Once you have submitted your plan, the Academic Discovery Center (ADC) for your major will review your plan. If changes are required, the ADC will contact you with instructions. If your plan is correct, it will be approved and the hold removed.</li>
</ol><strong>Graduation plans will be reviewed in the order they are received and processing time may take up to one week. Making needed changes and adjustments to your graduation plan will add to this time.&nbsp; <br /> <br /> </strong>If you need additional assistance, please contact the ADC responsible for your major.&nbsp; Visit <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academic-discovery-center/about-us/locations">http://www.byui.edu/academic-discovery-center/about-us/locations</a> for a list of ADC locations by college.<br /><br /><hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<h1><strong><br /> Instructions for Creating a Semester by Semester Graduation Plan </strong></h1>
<br /> <strong>Online Graduation Planning Tool: </strong>A simple planning tool that allows you to look at your Degree Audit and drag and drop classes into semesters. <br /><br />
<ul type="disc">
<li>Go to <a href="https://web.byui.edu/gradplan/">https://web.byui.edu/gradplan/</a> (you may have to download the SILVERLIGHT software if is not already installed on your computer).</li>
<li>Using the degree audit tool on the left side complete the following: review your degree requirements, drag and drop classes into the appropriate semesters, and plan all of your classes until graduation. BE SURE TO PLAN CLASSES ON SEMESTERS THEY WILL BE TAUGHT.<br /> (<strong>NOTE:</strong> sometimes the degree audit in the graduation plan tool is not accurate. To ensure accuracy of your major, minor, and/or clusters requirements as well as any prerequisites; always check your graduation plan with the <strong><em>official</em> </strong>online BYU-Idaho Catalog by your catalog year at: <a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog">http://www.byui.edu/catalog</a> (use the "Archive" link on the left to find your particular catalog year). &nbsp;</li>
<li>If a class is showing as INACTIVE or you cannot find a class you need to take, use the "Electives" tab at the top and search for the class by department.</li>
<li>Use the other sources listed below as needed to ensure that ALL your required courses are planned for the most optimal semester, including the sequencing of prerequisite requirements.</li>
<li>If desired, you can view a graduation plan <em>tutorial</em> on YOUTUBE at: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkl18usERfs&amp;feature=youtu.be">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkl18usERfs&amp;feature=youtu.be</a>.</li>
</ul>
<hr align="center" size="2" width="100%" />
<h1><strong><br /> Other Helpful Tools:</strong></h1>
<br /> <strong><em>BYU-Idaho Catalog:</em></strong> The catalog contains all university requirements for every degree with specific class descriptions, prerequisites, and semesters when classes are offered.<br /><br />
<ul type="disc">
<li>Go to <a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog">www.byui.edu/catalog</a></li>
<li>Select the latest catalog year for class planning or your specific catalog year for your degree requirements using the "Archive" link on the left</li>
<li>Scroll down to the "<strong>Academic Departments</strong>" heading (more than half way down)</li>
<li>Find your department/degree (i.e.; Mechanical Engineering, Physics, Architecture and Construction etc.)</li>
<li>Scroll down to find degree information and specific class descriptions for your major, minor, and/or clusters</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong><em>Your Degree Audit:</em></strong><em> </em>Your actual degree audit (outside of the graduation plan tool)&nbsp; is used to show the classes required for you to graduate with your current <em>declared </em>major and minor/clusters if required and declared. The degree audit is organized with your personal information at the top, followed by any upper division classes you have taken. It then shows all of the foundation requirements, followed by your major and minor/cluster requirements.<br /> &nbsp;<br /><br />
<ul type="disc">
<li>Log onto your <a href="https://my.byui.edu/ics"><em>my</em></a><a href="https://my.byui.edu/ics">BYUI</a> web page</li>
<li>Click on blue STUDENT tab at the top</li>
<li>Click on the gray tab on the left labeled DEGREE INFORMATION</li>
<li>Click on the blue hyperlink "View All Details"</li>
<li>Click on the blue "View PDF Degree Audit" hyperlink located at the bottom</li>
<li>This should open a new window with your personal degree audit</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong><em>Recommended Course Sequences</em></strong><em>:</em> The academic advising web page has recommended course sequences for most degrees. This will show you the recommended sequencing that will work without any course sequencing, prerequisite, or wrong track issues.<br /><br />
<ul type="disc">
<li>Go to <a href="http://www.byui.edu/academic-discovery-center/students/academic-advising-and-class-planning/class-planning/recommended-course-sequences">http://www.byui.edu/academic-discovery-center/students/academic-advising-and-class-planning/class-planning/recommended-course-sequences</a></li>
<li>This will take you to a list of all the academic colleges and departments</li>
<li>Click on the department that is over your major</li>
<li>Find your degree and catalog year; click on the blue catalog year hyperlink</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong><em>Department Web Page:</em></strong><em>&nbsp;</em> Each department has their own individual official web page that contains information for their majors and some helpful flow charts and sequencing information. <br /><br />
<ul type="disc">
<li>Go to <a href="http://www.byui.edu/directories/colleges-and-departments">www.byui.edu/directories/colleges-and-departments</a></li>
<li>Click on the department that is over your major</li>
<li>This will bring you to that department's web page where you can navigate to find specific information for that major including course offering schedules for certain classes that are not offered every single semester. BE SURE TO PLAN CLASSES ON SEMESTERS THEY WILL BE TAUGHT</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;<br /><br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
