<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x48817" Name="Third" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Third</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Third</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<!-- APARTMENT MANAGERS NAV BAR -->
<div><img src="Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/blank.png" width="63" /><a class="intLink" href="x8708.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/H.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/H-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/H.png" width="148" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44817.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/S.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/S-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/S.png" width="111" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44860.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/W.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/W-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/W.png" width="161" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44861.xml"><img src="Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/A-active.png" width="159" /></a><a class="intLink" href="x44863.xml"><img onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/M.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/M-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/apartmentmanagers/M.png" width="246" /></a></div>
<!-- END NAV BAR -->
<p></p>
<div style="width: 800px; hegith: 90px; margin: 0 auto;"><img src="http://www.byui.edu/Images/housing/Student%20Living/Apartment%20Managers/Welcome%20Meetings/studentLivingMeeting.png" /></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><strong><a href="x44881.xml"><img height="27" src="Images/housing/Student%20Living/back.png" width="79" /></a></strong></div>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Three:&nbsp; Large Group Gathering (essential for large complexes, but do not exceed 75 people) <br /></strong></p>
<p><em>Objective: Involve several students in discussing the importance of creating and strengthening a culture of love, shared responsibility, and mutual respect in each apartment and throughout the complex. Identify specific practices and extend specific invitations and commitments that will lead to such a culture.</em></p>
<p>Mode of Implementation:</p>
<ol>
<li>Prepare an agenda that increases students&rsquo; understanding of Student Living, engages them in a series of scenarios where the principles of Student Living can be naturally applied, and strengthens their commitment to building Zion in their apartments. Plan to meet for approximately 45 minutes.</li>
<li>Following a brief welcome/introduction, divide the large group into smaller groups and assign members of your staff or other trusted students to serve as group leaders. The group leaders must be trained prior to the Welcome Meeting so they fully understand their role with their respective group and what needs to be accomplished.</li>
<li>Show a Student Living video to introduce the principles of Student Living, invite the spirit, and set the stage for the subsequent group discussions. Make sure the groups are already divided and seated in their respective areas prior to showing the video. Student Living videos can be found on the Housing &amp; Student Living website (www.byui.edu/housing). Click on &ldquo;Student Living&rdquo; from the homepage.</li>
<li>Equip the group leaders with a few questions to ask their groups following the video to prompt a meaningful discussion. Examples of good questions can be found under the &ldquo;Small Group Gatherings&rdquo; section on the preceeding page. The group leaders should not dominate the discussion, but rather encourage participation from each member of the group and keep the discussion focused on the topic at hand.</li>
<li>Following the questions, the group leaders can pose certain scenarios that prompt additional discussion. The group leaders should be adept at connecting the principles of Student Living (love, shared responsibility, and mutual respect) to the group members&rsquo; responses to the scenarios. Some examples of real-life, practical scenarios are listed below. The manager and the group leaders should determine in adavance which scenarios they would like to present to the groups (either from the list below or others that would be beneficial to discuss). <br />Scenarios:
<ul>
<li>A roommate has invited a member of the opposite sex back to his/her room. How would you handle the situation?</li>
<li>You have a couple of roommates who do not participate in any apartment-related activities. They separate themselves from the group and spend time in their room(s). What would you do to build unity in your apartment?</li>
<li>A certain roommate has poor personal hygiene practices and seldom showers or performs any self-care. Sometimes the roommate&rsquo;s body odor is offensive to you and others in the apartment. How would you approach this roommate and what would you do to help?</li>
<li>One roommate is casual about keeping curfew and often comes in late. You&rsquo;ve tried to teach this roommate in a lighthearted, casual way but he/she has not changed his/her behavior. What do you do now?</li>
<li>On Sundays you&rsquo;ve noticed that a roommate or two violate dress and grooming standards for church meetings. For example, the skirt is shorter than it is on weekdays or the facial hair is more prominent on Sundays than on any other day of the week. What would you do?</li>
<li>You notice that a roommate has some edgy posters, DVDs, and reading material in his/her room. He/she is often up late on the computer and you suspect that he/she is involved in viewing pornography. What action would you take?</li>
<li>Your neighbors are planning a costume party that is reported to include a deejay, black lights, and &ldquo;crazy&rdquo; music. You&rsquo;ve been invited but feel that the party is not going to reflect BYU-Idaho standards for dress and behavior. What would you do?</li>
<li>You are aware of a roommate who is engaging in activities of self-harm. He/she has had a rough home life and you know that he/she is struggling emotionally, psychologically, and spiritually. How would you address this situation?</li>
<li>A friend is planning a co-ed camping trip next weekend. You are invited to attend. This is not a campus- or ward-sponsored event and you know that it compromises a university standard. What would you do?</li>
<li>An engaged roommate has his/her fianc&eacute;e over for several hours every day. They eat lunch and dinner together (often leaving a mess) and have taken up &ldquo;residency&rdquo; on the couch. There is seldom a time that the fianc&eacute;e is not present. You&rsquo;re beginning to feel uncomfortable in your own apartment. What would you do?</li>
<li>You have two roommates who seem to always be watching TV shows or movies that portray sexuality, intense violence, and/or use profanity including taking the Lord&rsquo;s name in vain. You&rsquo;re a bit scared to approach these roommates because, after all, they are adults and have both served full-time missions. What do you do?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>With 5-10 minutes left, ask all of the groups to direct their attention back to you. At this time you can ask a group or two to share their response(s) to a certain scenario, share some closing remarks that ties everything together, or do a combination of both.</li>
<li>Invite all students to make specific commitments that will foster a culture in which the principles of Student Living prevail throughout the complex.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>Note: You may or may not have time to do both #4 and #5 in a large group setting. Determine in advance what may be most beneficial and what you plan to accomplish in the small groups.</em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9764" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9287" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
