<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x50447" Name="FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently Asked Questions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently Asked Questions</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h2>The Tutoring Center</h2>
<h4>How can I become a tutor?</h4>
<p>To become a tutor, several requirements need to be met. First, all tutors are required to have a 3.2 overall GPA or higher. Second, all tutors must have received an A- or better in the course they wish to tutor. Third, all tutors must be recommended by the professor of the course they wish to tutor.</p>
<h4>How many hours can I work?</h4>
<p>Campus student employees are allowed to work up to 20 hours per week. The Tutoring Center requires all tutors to post a minimum of 10 hours per week, though tutors only work when students sign up for appointments.</p>
<h4>What are the hours tutors work?</h4>
<p>Tutors set their own schedules. Typically, appointments are set between 7 am and 7 pm. Tutors are free to post hours during the library hours of operation.</p>
<h4>What are tutors paid?</h4>
<p>The Tutoring Center starts new tutors 10 cents above the campus minimum for student employees. Tutors can receive periodic raises with the completion of start of the semester tasks and experience.</p>
<h4>How often can I visit a tutor?</h4>
<p>Students are allowed to visit a tutor for a specific course up to three times per week. Exceptions to visit a tutor more frequently than this are handled on a case by case basis.</p>
<h2>The Math Study Center</h2>
<h4>How much do I have to pay to get tutoring?</h4>
<p>Nothing. Labs, groups, and 1-on-1 tutors are free to all students who don't abuse the system.</p>
<h4>Why do we need to check in to use the math lab?</h4>
<p>We keep records of all of the visits to the math lab, so that we are able to staff the lab with enough tutors of the right subjects.</p>
<h4>What is the difference between using a 1-on-1 tutor and going into the math lab?</h4>
<p>The math lab is open for many hours for the entire week. You can just walk in, work on your homework and ask questions when you get stuck. The 1-on-1 tutoring is for students who need more specialized help or have been struggling with their class. With this option you have the benefit of having 1-on-1 attention and guidance, but you need to make an appointment.</p>
<h2>The Writing Center</h2>
<h4>How should I prepare for my visit?</h4>
<p>Come prepared with:</p>
<ul>
<li>Specific questions or concerns about the assignment.</li>
<li>Hard copy of the assignment.</li>
<li>Willingness to make changes.</li>
<li>Twenty to thirty minutes to spend in a session.</li>
<li>Enough time before assignment is due to make change.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Does my paper have to be for a class?</h4>
<p>No. The BYU-Idaho Writing Center works with resumes, cover letters, letters of introduction (for student teaching and graduate school applications) as well as creative works.</p>
<h4>Can you guarantee me an "A"?</h4>
<p>No. The Writing Center can work with students to help their assignment meet the guidelines, but the Tutors cannot guarantee an "A".</p>
<h4>What if a tutor gives me advice that I or my teacher disagree with?</h4>
<p>Writing tutors are your peers--fellow college students with experience in writing college papers. Because tutors are not familiar with the specifics of your assignment or your instructor's particular expectations, their comments should be understood only as suggestions. Always defer to the advice of your instructor and remember that the paper is yours; you must take responsibility for the suggested revisions you choose to incorporate in your final draft.</p>
<h4>How long are sessions?</h4>
<p>On average, sessions are around twenty minutes. This does not mean that for quick concerns students will be required to stay there for the full twenty minutes, or that students with many questions will be cut off after twenty minutes. International students on average have thirty to forty-five minute sessions, in order to address and concerns with the language itself.</p>
<h4>How much time before the due date should I come in?</h4>
<p>At least a few hours before class, but preferably at least a day or two in advance. This allows the student plenty of time to be able to correct or change any parts of their assignment that were worked on, as well as allowing enough time for the student to make any further changes or ask their teacher questions regarding the assignment.</p>
<h4>Can I request an online session if I'm on-campus?</h4>
<p>No. Since on-campus students are able to come in to the Writing Center in person whereas off-campus students are not, the online sessions are strictly for those who are off-campus.</p>
<h4>Where are you located?</h4>
<p>On the second floor of the McKay Library, near the Reading Center and Tutoring Center.</p>
<h4>Is the BYU-Idaho Writing Center part of the Tutoring Center?</h4>
<p>No. Although the Writing Center does Tutor, we are partly a drop-in service as well. This means that not all students need to make an appointment. At the Tutoring Center most subject areas require that the student makes an appointment first.</p>
<h4>Are all the employees at the BYU-Idaho Writing Center English majors?</h4>
<p>No. Some of the employees are, but others are Biology, Political Science, Health Administration, or Sociology majors. Being an English major is not required to work at the Writing Center.</p>
<h4>My teacher is requiring or giving extra credit for my visit. How will he or she know I have visited?</h4>
<p>We will stamp your draft or provide a kind of receipt, whichever you prefer. However, do not come with the attitude of "I'm just here to get my points." In order for us to provide evidence of your visit, you must visit at least 6 hours before the paper is due AND come with a draft copy (not the final copy you plan to turn in). If you come with your final copy, it will be obvious you have no intention of making changes, and therefore your visit is pointless.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x25860" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
