<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x50982" Name="Active Internship" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Active Internships</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Avtive Internships</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong> <strong>UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA</strong></strong><br /><br /> RANGE MONITORING INTERN<br /><br /> Duration - 3 months<br /><br /> Approximate hours per week - 40 to 60<br /><br /> Desired start date - September 15, 2014<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">DESCRIPTION:</span>&nbsp; Will be required to work in the office, outdoors and a variety of settings.&nbsp; Will also be required to travel to remote locations to collect data.&nbsp; Work days will vary with many days being more than 8 hours.&nbsp; Will assist with range monitoring data collection, data entry, data summarization, assist with workshop details, and assist in researching questions from public.&nbsp; Supervision of range monitoring data collection may occur after competence is established.&nbsp; The "Reading the Range" monitoring program is a collaborative grant funded monitoring program present on over 1 million acres, primarily in Gila County, Arizona.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">DESIRED MAJORS:</span>&nbsp; Animal Science, Plant Science, Biology, Ecology, Range, Wildlife and Fisheries<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">QUALIFICATION:</span>&nbsp; This position is physically taxing and the successful applicant should expect to spend long hours in the field.&nbsp; Some range monitoring sites are remote in location and must be reached by horseback, necessitating the ability to ride a horse.&nbsp; The ability to safely operate all-terrain vehicles and the ability to hike and climb in rugged terrain is also required.&nbsp; A valid driver's license with three years safe driving experience is required and a DMV check of a safe driving record will be performed.&nbsp; Some experience in identifying native range plants is desired, preferably by a plant identification college course and/or experience in the field.&nbsp; Computer literacy is required, including word processing and spreadsheet programs.&nbsp; Students in good academic standing with proof of enrollment at the university currently attending will be considered. &nbsp; The nature of this position also requires excellent communication skills with people of varying backgrounds from ranching to land management agency employees.&nbsp; The successful applicant will be expected to complete a student project as part of the internship. <br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">CONTACT INFORMATION:<br /> </span>Dr. Jim Sprinkle, PO Box 2844,&nbsp; Payson, Arizona&nbsp; 85547<br /><br /> sprinkle@ag.arizona.edu, (928) 474-4160<strong><br /><br /> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Y2 CONSULTANTS, INC.</strong><br /><br /> NATURAL RESOURCE TECHNICIAN<br /><br /> Y2 Consultants, inc. is an Environmental &amp; Engineering Consulting Firm located in Jackson, Wyoming.&nbsp; Y2's natural resource department focuses on providing rangeland inventory and monitoring services for private clients on public land. Y2 is currently hiring two (2) natural resource technicians to join our team for the 2014 field season. Positions are based out of the main office in Jackson, Wyoming but majority of field work is located in Nevada and other portions of western Wyoming.&nbsp; Ability to travel and have a flexible schedule is required for this position.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">DUTIES:</span>&nbsp; Field crews will work with an experienced crew lead, assisting in rangeland inventory surveys on public lands.&nbsp; Field work takes up about 85% of the position responsibilities.&nbsp; Inventory duties include ability to navigate to pre-determined field locations using a Garmin or Trimble GPS unit, completing data sheets to their entirety and utilizing basic plant ID skills.&nbsp; Familiarity with line-intercept, point-intercept, green-line, PFC, utilization, nested and pace frequency.&nbsp; Al technicians will be responsible for driving (all-terrain vehicles) and hiking to inventory sites.&nbsp; Work is in rugged and remote areas of Nevada and Wyoming.&nbsp; Office work consists of mainly data entry and weighing plant samples collected in the field.&nbsp; Technicians must be physically able to complete job.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">EDUCATION/EXPERIENCE:</span>&nbsp; Qualified applicants should have experience and/or education in rangeland management, natural resources, biological sciences, plant identification, soil science or general plant taxonomy and the ability to follow directions and safety protocols.&nbsp; Applicants must be experienced with 4WD vehicles and small trailers, GPS navigation, and have had a clean driving record for the past 3 years.&nbsp; Experience with ATVs and UTVs beneficial.&nbsp; Must be capable of hiking and camping for up to 8-9 nights.&nbsp; Must be able to squat/kneel for extended periods of time for data collection.&nbsp; Proficiency with Microsoft programs necessary. Experience with ArcGIS software desired but not required.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">SALARY:</span>&nbsp; $600/week, plus all expenses (food, lodging, gas, and company vehicle) covered during 10-day field stint.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">SCHEDULE:</span>&nbsp; Positions will start in May and continue through September, with a possibility to extend later into the season.&nbsp; A field schedule of 10-days on/4-days off will be followed.&nbsp; Work days are long and vary in length of 8-12 hrs/10 days when in the field.&nbsp; Applicant will need to use personal camping supplies during the 10-days.&nbsp; Crews will return to Jackson, Wyoming on day 10 of field stint.<br /><br /> Applicants should E-MAIL letter of interest, resume, and contact information for at least three references to <a href="mailto:jobs@y2consultants.com">jobs@y2consultants.com</a>.&nbsp; Please put "Natural Resource Technician" in the subject line. <br /><br /> Open until filled.<br /><br /> For more information, please visit our website: <a href="http://www.y2consultants.com">http://www.y2consultants.com</a><br /><br /><br /> <strong>THE CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER-DAY SAINTS</strong><br /><br /> Ensign Ranch &amp; Recreation Facility<br /><br /> Summer Internship Opportunity<br /><br /> Mid-May through Labor Day<br /><br /> Satisfy college internship requirements<br />Interact with youth and people with special needs<br />Work with missionaries; Prepare for a mission<br />Strengthen your testimony of the Gospel<br />Get work experience in many area: horses, cooking, campground maintenance, etc.<br /><br /> A stipend will be paid according to level of experience and availability<br /><br /> 509-656-2344 - Ask for Ensign Ranch Manager, Larry Hallows<br />3551 Hundley Road, Cle Elum, WA 98922<br /><a href="mailto:ensignranchcamp@ldsmail.net">ensignranchcamp@ldsmail.net</a><br /><br /><br /> <strong>THE CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER-DAY SAINTS</strong><br /><br /> Ensign Ranch and Recreation Facility<br />&nbsp; <br /> Summer Wrangler - Internship Opportunity<br /><br /> Work with horses and conduct trail rides<br />Satisfy college internship requirements<br />Interact with youth and people with special needs<br />Work with missionaries; Prepare for a mission<br />Strengthen your testimony of the Gospel<br />Get work experience in many areas<br /><br /> Safety-minded individuals with riding experience are needed from mid-May through Labor Day<br /><br /> Must be able to demonstrate horsemanship skills, and be willing to perform other general camp maintenance or janitorial work as needed.&nbsp; A stipend will be paid according to level of experience and availability.<br /><br /> 509-656-2344 - Ask for Ensign Ranch Manager, Larry Hallows<br />3551 Hundley Road, Cle Elum, WA 98922<br /><a href="mailto:ensignranchcamp@ldsmail.net">ensignranchcamp@ldsmail.net</a><br /><br />&nbsp; <br /> <strong>ROYALTON FARMS</strong><br /><br /><strong></strong>INTERNSHIP OPPORTUNITY<br /><br /> Agriculture and Food Science Department<br /><br />Opportunity to learn livestock production from Conception to Consumer<br /><br /> Wagyu Beef, Berkshire Pork, Passover Lambs<br /><br /> Farm-to-Table<br /><br /> Royalton Farms on Dairy Hill, Vermont<br /><br /> Contact Brother Powell <a href="mailto:powellke@byui.edu">powellke@byui.edu</a> for more information<br /><br /> <br clear="all" /> <strong>HELP HAITI</strong><br /><br /> Help us teacher others agricultural and environmental skills which they can use to improve their lives and build sustainable communities.<br /><br /> Reforestation, Community Agriculture<br /><br /> Summer 2014<br /><br /> Send resume to <a href="mailto:apico@sustain-haiti.org">apico@sustain-haiti.org</a><br /><br /> Learn more at <a href="http://www.sustain-haiti.org">www.sustain-haiti.org</a><br /> <br /><br /> <strong>ROCKIN' R RANCH</strong><br /><br /> Antimony, Utah<br /><br /> Internship<br /><br /> We are interested in inviting BYU-I students as interns to be a part of what we do.&nbsp; We operate a working cow ranch all year.&nbsp; We run approximately 500 mother cows.&nbsp; We also have a guest ranch open year round.&nbsp; The guest ranch part of the Rockin' R offers guided trail rides, hiking, tubing, and a wide range of other activities. The ranch also houses a program called Cowboy College that teaches young adults about the cowboy way of life to help them learn some fundamental such as responsibility and trust.&nbsp; We want to offer internships to BYU-I students because we know they share the strong values we appreciate in our workers both for the quality of work, and as examples.&nbsp; We want this intership to be available for students on all three tracks at BYU-I.<br /><br /> If you would like more information about the ranch and what we do, our website is <a href="http://www.rockinrranch.com">www.rockinrranch.com</a>.<br /><br /><br /> <strong>GARDINER ANGUS RANCH</strong></p>
<p>Internship<br /><br /> Gardiner Angus Ranch is seeking student interns from Land-Grant, agricultural universities who are interested in animal genetics, animal nutrition, animal health, reproductive management and/or marketing of purebred cattle.&nbsp; Applicants should be junior or senior undergraduate students with a background or major related to animal agriculture.<br /><br /> The goal of the internship program is to increase the knowledge and ability of undergraduate students in ranch management and marketing of purebred cattle and to enhance their potential to become leaders in the livestock industry.<br /><br /> Selection criteria include: 1) livestock industry background and experience; 2) academic performance and extracurricular activities; 3) career goals and leadership potential; and 4) work ethic and attitude.<br /><br /> A 10-week internship is available in the fall and in the spring (flexible timing based on college curriculum).&nbsp; Dates and activities associated with each internship period are outlined below:<br /><br /> <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">FALL:&nbsp; AUGUST - NOVEMBER</span></strong><br /><br /> Fall activities focus on completing the calving season, conducting the Fall Sale, gathering cow/calf pairs and heifers from summer pastures, processing calves, collection of embryos and beginning the AI breeding season.&nbsp; Interns would participate in calving watch, sale planning, gathering cattle from pastures on horseback, treating donors for superovulation and beginning the AI breeding program.&nbsp; The ranch breeds over 1,200 heads of registered females and transfers embryos to 1,300 recipient cows during the fall breeding season.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">INTERN DUTIES:</span>&nbsp; Interns will receive training and assist in the following: calves, record keeping, monitoring cows and calves for sickness, vaccination of calves, operating heavy equipment, feeding silage and hay, freeze branding, moving cattle on horseback, sorting and moving bulls for private treaty and production sales, conducting the Fall Sale, estrus synchronization and heat detention of cattle.<br /><br /> Interns will be provided with housing on the ranch, but will be responsible for their own meals.&nbsp; Each intern must provide proof of health insurance.&nbsp; The work schedule at GAR is typically 6 or 6-1/2 days per week.&nbsp; Work days often begin at 7 am and may not be complete until after 6 pm.&nbsp; Additional free time can be arranged with advance notice.&nbsp; In addition to educational opportunities on the ranch, interns will be presented with the opportunity to learn from veterinary professionals, feedlot operators, nutritional consultants, sale consultants and processing plant managers during the 10-week internship period.&nbsp; Each intern will receive a $2000 stipend upon successful completion of the 10-week internship.<br /><br /> <strong>APPLICATION INFORMATION</strong><br /><br /> Eligibility:<br /><br /> &middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Undergraduate Junior or Senior at land-grant or agricultural university<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Background or major related to animal agriculture<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Interest in animal genetics, animal nutrition, animal health, reproductive management and/or marketing of purebred cattle<br /><br /> Selection Criteria:<br /><br /> &middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Background and experience in the livestock industry<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Academic performance and extracurricular activities<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Career goals and leadership potential<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Work ethic and attitude<br /><br /> Application Materials:<br /><br /> &middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Completed Gardiner Angus Ranch Internship application (see website to download)<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Copy of college transcript (unofficial transcripts acceptable)<br />&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two letters of reference (see application for instructions to references)<br /><br />Application forms can be downloaded at:<br /><br /> <a href="http://www.gardinerangus.com">www.gardinerangus.com</a><br /><br /> Submit application materials:<br /><br /> Via U.S. Mail<br />Mark Gardiner<br />Gardiner Angus Ranch<br />2607 Country Road 13<br />Ashland, KS 67831<br /> Or<br />Via E-mail (preferred)<br /><a href="mailto:gar@ucom.net">gar@ucom.net</a><br /><br /> Application materials must be received by:<br /><br /> Spring Internship - October 15<sup>th</sup><br /><br /> Fall Internship - March 15<sup>th</sup> <br /><br /></p>
<p><strong>AGRI NORTHWEST</strong><br /><br /> INTERNSHIP PROGRAM<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">DESCRIPTION:</span>&nbsp; The Internship Program at AgriNorthwest is designed to evaluate college students as potential employees, while allowing college students the opportunity to gain work experience.&nbsp; Management will focus on recruiting students in their junior or senior year who have a desire and aptitude to work in Production agriculture.&nbsp; Interns will be recruited from various colleges and universities across the country.<br /><br /> Internships will usually last for three to four months, but occasionally may last longer.&nbsp; During this time interns will work on Pest Scouting.&nbsp; In this role you will report to an Area Director and collaborate with several of our Farm Unit Managers as you scout pests and report your findings to management.&nbsp; You will have a unique opportunity to learn from experts in the potato industry and help AgriNorthwest produce high quality, high yielding commodities and produce that will help us to fulfill our financial responsibility to our owner.&nbsp; As you complete your assignments you will have the chance to demonstrate your character and work qualities and, at the same time, we hope to earn your respect and trust.&nbsp; While fulltime positions are not guaranteed, our desire is for you to continually develop yourself to possibly become a future leader at AgReserves.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">COMPENSATION AND HOUSING:</span>&nbsp; In this position, the intern will have a starting wage of $10 per hour.&nbsp; In addition to the wage, the intern will receive a rent-free, furnished apartment in the Kennewick area.&nbsp; The furnishings at the apartment include: one queen size bed, microwave, stove, refrigerator, couch, coffee table, and dresser.&nbsp; We also provide all the kitchenware including dishes, silverware, pots, and pans.&nbsp; The Intern will be responsible to bring your own linens, towels, and entertainment equipment (televisions, computers, etc.).<br /><br /> The Intern will be responsible for commuting from Kennewick to the Plymouth/Eureka farm office each day where you will receive a farm truck to help you complete your daily assignments.&nbsp; The farm vehicle is only to be used for business purpose and should not be used for personal needs.<br /><br /> AgriNorthwest will also pay $150 each way to cover fuel costs from the Interns residence to Kennewick.<br /><br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">TO APPLY:<br /> </span>Send resume and cover letter to:<br /><br /> Roschel Bladow, Human Resources Manager<br /><br /> Email: <a href="mailto:Rbladow@agrinw.com">Rbladow@agrinw.com</a><br /><br /> Office: 509-734-5074 ext. 5250<br /><br /></p>
<div id="mylink" style="display: none;">
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">This textwill be show for five day. March 29 - April 2</span></p>
</div>
<p>
<script type="text/javascript">
var information =  document.getElementById("mylink");

var startday = 29; // user input for the start day
var endday = 2; // user input for the end day
var startmonth = 3;
var endmonth = 3;
var nextyear = 0; // use full date like 2013. this for if you what go next year like first of the month which is 1


var now = new Date();  // Today information
var day = now.getDate(); // get the today  like 22 if on that date of the month
var month = now.getMonth() + 1;  //get the month

var year = now.getFullYear();
	
if (startmonth == endmonth) // test the both month are same
{
    if (startmonth == month) // this test if you are in the less than and equal month you are on
	{
	    if (day >= startday && day <= endday)
		{
		  information.style.display = "block";
		}
		
    }
}

else if (nextyear > year )
{
	    if (startmonth <= month)
		{
		   information.style.display = "block";
	    }
}	    

else if (nextyear == year )
{
	    if (endmonth <= month)
		{
		    if (day <= endday)
			{
			  information.style.display = "block";
			}
	    }
}	   

else
{
    if (endmonth == month)
	{
	   if (day <= endday)
		{
		  information.style.display = "block";
		}
	}
	if (startmonth == month)
	{
	   if (day >= startday)
		{
		  information.style.display = "block";
		}
	}
	else if (startmonth <= month && endmonth >= month)
	{
	   information.style.display = "block";
	}
}
</script>
</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1833" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
