<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EmptyShell ID="x51040" Name="coverstory.htm" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">coverstory.htm</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">coverstory.htm</Abstract><ESContent type="string" label="Content" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">&lt;html&gt;

&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=windows-1252"&gt;
&lt;title&gt;A Conversation With President Kim B. Clark&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
&lt;!--
p.ctttxt
	{margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	text-align:justify;
	line-height:13.0pt;
	tab-stops:13.0pt 24.0pt 26.0pt;
	text-autospace:none;
	font-size:10.0pt;
	font-family:MinionPro-Regular;
	color:black; margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:0in}
 p.MsoNormal
	{mso-style-parent:"";
	margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	font-size:12.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:0in}
--&gt;
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="800" height="4677"&gt;
	&lt;!-- MSTableType="layout" --&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="bottom"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="DecArea" --&gt;
		&lt;p align="center"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="../../../Images/BYUI Upward/spring2006/conversationA.jpg" width="94" height="130"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="bottom" height="177"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentHead" --&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="5"&gt;A 
Conversation with President Kim B. Clark&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" colspan="2" height="17"&gt;
		&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" colspan="2" height="3648"&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="../../../Images/BYUI Upward/spring2006/conversationC.jpg" width="266" height="352" align="right" hspace="15" vspace="15"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
		At inaugural ceremonies on October 11, 2005, President Gordon B. 
		Hinckley charged Kim B. Clark, the fifteenth president of Brigham Young 
		University–Idaho, to elevate the institution to new heights of honor, 
		achievement, and recognition. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
		President Clark is now leading the university in a vigorous effort to 
		fulfill that charge, and the campus is busy with activity. To 
		familiarize readers with all that is happening at BYU–Idaho, Summit 
		Magazine sat down with President Clark for a one-on-one conversation.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: How 
		are you and your wife Sue adjusting to your new life in Rexburg?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark&lt;/i&gt;: We love Rexburg. We have been well received by the people 
		here. They have been very kind and open, warm and loving. And the 
		university is great. We love this university. The feeling on this campus 
		is unmatched, and it’s a blessing to come to campus every morning.
		&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: You 
		have now been at Brigham Young University–Idaho for several months and 
		have become well-acquainted with the work under way here. From your 
		perspective, how is the university doing? &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; I believe the university is making great progress. For me, 
		one of the really wonderful things about coming to BYU–Idaho was finding 
		a place that was well run. It was already moving forward in a good way. 
		It’s a tremendous blessing to be able to come in and focus on the 
		future. So, simply put, the school is in good shape. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: In 
		your inaugural response, you outlined three imperatives on which 
		BYU–Idaho must focus in order to fulfill its mission. Can you explain to 
		our readers what those imperatives are, why they are important, and how 
		the university will reach them?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; The first imperative is to raise substantially the quality of 
		every aspect of the student experience, whether it be academic, 
		religious, spiritual, social, or personal development. We want to 
		improve every aspect of that experience. The second imperative is to 
		reach more students. We want to make this wonderful experience available 
		to more students. And the third imperative is to lower the relative cost 
		of education. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The 
		imperatives are important because each one reinforces the others. It’s 
		often viewed in the world that of those three, you can pick two, but you 
		can’t have all three. However we are not bound by the traditions of men, 
		nor are we limited to our own understanding. Through the blessings of 
		heaven, we can have all three; and we are on track to do that. It means 
		we will need to be innovative and create new ways of learning and 
		teaching. We will need to find new ways of organizing our work. We will 
		need to find new ways of studying and learning. Doing all of these 
		things together, I believe, will allow us to achieve the imperatives.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
		Success will come as we implement a learning model here at BYU–Idaho and 
		as we take advantage of the technologies the Lord is making available to 
		us. It will come as we understand more about learning and as we come to 
		understand how to teach one another more effectively. The Lord will 
		bless us with the ability to take what He gives us and apply it.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: You 
		have also introduced six initiatives to the university which serve as a 
		sort of action plan for this phase of BYU–Idaho’s progress. Could you 
		outline those for our readers, and explain their importance?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="right"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="../../../Images/BYUI Upward/spring2006/ConversationB.jpg" width="229" height="312" align="left" hspace="15" vspace="15"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; The six initiatives are all directed at moving the university 
		forward on a steady, upward course. The first has been to take a new 
		look at the academic calendar and modify it to serve more students. By 
		creating three equal semesters, we organize the faculty’s work to make 
		better use of the summer and create a stronger experience during that 
		part of the year. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The 
		second deals specifically with the student experience. We are looking at 
		the whole experience the student has from the beginning until 
		graduation. We’ll ask ourselves how we can do this better. How do we do 
		it now? Are there ways to improve it? What should we do that we’re not 
		doing? How can we make this experience even more powerful and effective?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The 
		third is an initiative focused on online education. We will look at how 
		to develop our technical abilities in a way that will deepen the 
		learning experience on campus and extend the reach of the university off 
		campus. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The 
		fourth initiative is general education. Significant effort was put into 
		adding upper division courses when BYU–Idaho transitioned from a 
		two-year to a four-year school. Now we are going back and looking at our 
		general education program. I hope we will be able to create some 
		distinctive experiences for our students. Students need to learn how to 
		read and write and do the basic things you would expect in foundational 
		courses, but we hope there will be some elements unique to BYU–Idaho.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The 
		fifth initiative focuses on what we call the BYU–Idaho learning model. A 
		significant part of our ability to reach the three imperatives will be 
		in teaching and learning, in discovering new ways to do things. So we’re 
		working on creating what we hope will become an overarching framework 
		for learning that will reach across everything we do. It will allow us 
		to have sufficient continuity across courses and programs, so our 
		students will develop a capacity to learn beyond what they currently 
		have today. And in particular, we will implement learning by faith in a 
		very powerful and compelling way on campus. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The 
		last initiative focuses on the campus itself. It’s a 10- to 15-year look 
		down the road at what we need, where the campus is headed, and how we 
		can make it even more effective than it is today. We have a number of 
		projects under way in that area. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: Could 
		you tell us how these imperatives and initiatives were formulated? What 
		kind of direction did you receive?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; When I accepted President Gordon B. Hinckley’s invitation to 
		serve as president of BYU–Idaho, a series of experiences were set into 
		motion. Some were very personal as I was taught by the Lord what He 
		wanted to happen at this university. I had ideas, and I began talking to 
		people about them. I spoke with Elder David A. Bednar extensively during 
		the summer of last year and began to get a feel for where we were and 
		what the issues were. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; After 
		I came here, I began meeting with the vice presidents and others in the 
		community; and the three imperatives became very clear. Then we pulled 
		everyone in the senior leadership of the university together to look at 
		where the institution is going. We looked at what we need to work on 
		right now to move us to that next level, and the six initiatives 
		crystallized very quickly. It became very clear where we needed to go.
		&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: You 
		also receive a great deal of guidance from the Board of Trustees. Could 
		you describe for our readers the relationship that exists between the 
		Board and BYU–Idaho?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="../../../Images/BYUI Upward/spring2006/conversationD.jpg" width="268" height="178" align="right" hspace="15" vspace="15"&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; It’s an interesting relationship. The Board of Trustees is 
		passionate about education and deeply concerned about the direction, 
		focus, and progress of the university. They also have a great deal of 
		experience with the university and are very knowledgeable about it. They 
		care about it. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But 
		they also extend to us a significant degree of responsibility to move 
		the university forward in the way the Lord directs. It’s a combination 
		of intense and passionate engagement coupled with significant delegation 
		of responsibility. We have a clear understanding of the Board’s 
		policies, and we operate within the framework they establish. &lt;/font&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: You 
		have said you can see the Lord’s hand at work here at BYU–Idaho. How do 
		you see that guidance manifesting itself? What do you see happening on 
		campus that tells you the Lord is watching over us?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; We talk often on this campus about the idea that this is one 
		of the Lord’s universities. Some people may chalk that up to rhetoric; 
		because we’re part of the Lord’s church, it is obvious BYU–Idaho is one 
		of the Lord’s universities. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But 
		this is the Lord’s university in a very personal and specific way. I 
		think the most powerful manifestation is in the lives of the individuals 
		who work here. Virtually all whom I talk with have a story to tell about 
		how they arrived here, and those stories are quite interesting. There 
		are miracles at work as people are led to BYU–Idaho. I think that’s the 
		most compelling manifestation. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; There 
		are others. We often find situations in which we are at a bit of a dead 
		end, not knowing how to proceed on an issue. Then we’ll receive very 
		clear understanding and direction about what we should do. It comes like 
		the Spirit always comes—in whispers, impressions, and directions. It 
		often turns out that once we begin down a certain path, we discover the 
		way has already been prepared. There are opportunities available to us 
		we hadn’t anticipated. We see it in our discussion of the BYU–Idaho 
		learning model. We see it in our discussion of the academic calendar. We 
		see it in nearly everything we undertake. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: Why 
		do you think the Lord is so involved in what’s happening here? Why is He 
		so interested in this place?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; From the beginning of the Restoration, the Lord has made it 
		clear that education is a very important aspect of the kingdom—a very 
		important part in preparing the laborers in the kingdom. You have only 
		to go to the 88th section of the Doctrine and Covenants and read the 
		Lord’s words about preparing this generation of laborers for the work He 
		wants to give them. Education has been both practically and doctrinally 
		at the center of the preparation. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Now 
		after many decades of sacrifice and investment, we are blessed with 
		great universities in the kingdom. BYU–Idaho is one of them. It has a 
		distinctive and special mission to prepare what I call 
		“disciple-leaders.” It is the Lord’s plan to have such an institution 
		and to be able to lead and guide literally thousands of choice people to 
		come here. They are prepared to be disciple-leaders so they can go out 
		and be engaged in building the kingdom.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I 
		believe very strongly in Elder Bednar’s prophetic statements about this 
		university over the years and especially in his recent statement that 
		the founding of BYU–Idaho is one of the signal events of the 
		Restoration. It’s true. The Lord has in His plans a very important role 
		for this university to play. It revolves around the young people who 
		come here to go to school and what He has in mind for them.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: That 
		touches on another important idea you have discussed recently—our 
		mission to prepare the best quality graduates. Tell us more about that. 
		Who is a BYU–Idaho graduate? How should a graduate of this university be 
		different than those of other schools?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark:&lt;/i&gt; Our mission is to do two things. One is to prepare young 
		people to be disciples of the Savior. The other is to develop them as 
		leaders—first and foremost in their families so they will be great moms 
		and dads, great husbands and wives. We want them to be leaders in the 
		Church—faithful, active and committed, but also capable of taking on the 
		responsibilities the Lord gives them. We also want them to be leaders in 
		their communities, the world they live in, and in their work—wherever 
		they are.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;The kind of 
		leadership we have in mind is leadership with a small “l.” It’s 
		leadership that serves and inspires in every kind of organization at 
		every level. It’s the kind of leadership a bishop loves to have in his 
		Young Men program or in the nursery. It’s the kind of leadership someone 
		running a company wants in their team leaders and department heads. It’s 
		about building and developing &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;disciple-leaders. 
		It’s that combination that I think sets these young people apart. It’s 
		the combination of skill, ability, and training not only in the 
		classroom but in practical experiences where they really develop their 
		skills in leading and directing. And it happens in an environment where 
		they become disciples of the Savior. Many of our young people will go on 
		to become a significant influence because of what they learn here.
		&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; We 
		believe the university should be a living model of the high standards we 
		want to teach and develop in our students. Being at this university 
		should in itself be an education. It’s an organization guided by the 
		principles of the gospel, where the “Spirit of Ricks” prevails. These 
		students will have lived in a place that is a Zion-like community. They 
		will go out knowing what it feels like to build Zion because they’ve 
		lived in Zion here. They’ll take it with them. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" color="#454545"&gt;Summit Magazine: What 
		would you like the alumni and friends of BYU–Idaho to know and feel 
		about the university? What is their role in helping move this 
		institution forward?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;i&gt;President 
		Clark&lt;/i&gt;: I would like them to understand this really is the Lord’s 
		university. We work under the direction of the Lord and the prophet of 
		the Lord. And the course we are on is the course set by the Lord. &lt;/font&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
		Secondly, I hope they understand this is an enormously important and 
		exciting time in the life and the history of this university. This is a 
		relatively young university that has been built around the core of Ricks 
		College. I’d like them to understand BYU–Idaho did not leave Ricks 
		College behind. Ricks College is the core of BYU–Idaho. It has been 
		built around it and upon it. The “Spirit of Ricks” is alive on this 
		campus. I want them to know that and feel that in their hearts. &lt;/font&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I 
		hope they all have a desire to support the university in whatever way 
		the Lord directs—whether it be to support us financially, to serve as an 
		ambassador, to counsel with young people who come to them and ask what 
		it’s like to go to school here. I hope they become knowledgeable about 
		what we’re doing, committed to the Lord’s purposes here, and willing and 
		able to serve in whatever capacity the Lord directs.
		&lt;font color="#454545" size="1"&gt;SM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2" color="#454545"&gt;
		&lt;a href="contentshtm-x51038"&gt;
		Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td width="142"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td height="835" width="658"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;

&lt;/html&gt;</ESContent></EmptyShell>
