<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.101 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<NewsDetail ID="x51356" Name="Department Spotlight" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Department Spotlight Home and Family</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">An interview with Scott Gardner</subTitle><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Scott Gardner, chair of the Home and Family Department shares insights on the value of a the Marriage and Family Studies degree.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="241" Height="240" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" AlternateText="Scott Gardner">Admin_Offices/Online Learning/News room/Scott Gardner.png</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" List="Image" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="230" Height="230" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" AlternateText="Family">Admin_Offices/Online Learning/News room/Home and Family Side Pic.png</Image><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="230" Height="345" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" AlternateText="Family">Admin_Offices/Online Learning/News room/Family toned.jpg</Image><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="230" Height="169" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="10" Alignment="" AlternateText="Family">Admin_Offices/Online Learning/News room/PhillipandLiannaClark.jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20130328T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brandie Miguel</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Home and Family Department Chair, Scott Gardner, joined the team at Brigham Young University-Idaho five years ago determined to build a major out of what was, at that time, only a minor field of study. After a few years and a lot of hard work, Brother Gardner developed a program that made this bachelor's degree available to the students at BYU-Idaho. Shortly after the task was complete, he was approached about creating a course of study that would allow for the degree to be available online. Brother Gardner recounts the efforts required to build the online degree: "It's a difficult and timely process to create each course offered online, a couple of semesters at least for each course. But, as the technology catches up, we see the courses becoming better and better. In fact we are pretty much at a point where our online courses are as good as our face to face courses." <br /><br />When asked what Brother Gardner's motivating force was behind developing the program, he referred to the mandate found in the proclamation on the family, which states, "We call upon&nbsp;responsible citizens and officers of government everywhere to promote those measures designed to maintain and strengthen the family as the fundamental unit of society."&nbsp; Brother Gardner further clarifies this impelling cause: "The Marriage and Family Studies degree certainly does what the mandate states. If we can train more people to go out into the world to help others have strong families at that grass roots level- there is nothing better. Marriage and family is the Lord's work and glory. Being able to offer this degree online is a great blessing to many people. We see students through the Online Degree and Pathway programs being blessed throughout the world as they study about the most important work on earth [and] participate in this work that extends throughout eternity." &nbsp;</p>
<p>Purposefully naming the major "Marriage and Family Studies" at the same time as other universities remove marriage studies from their curriculum helps BYU-Idaho graduates to stand out as experts in their field. Brother Gardner found that other universities do not require even one class on marriage or parenting in their course work. "How can you be a family professional without having had those classes?" questioned Gardner. He goes on to say, "You can see how BYU-Idaho students are more prepared for two reasons. First, we...have a marriage and parenting focus. [Second,] we offer separate, more in-depth training than...other universities."</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho's Marriage and Family program pushes the students to use their knowledge in very practical and vital ways. During the major's course of study, students are required to participate in a practicum course and to fulfill an internship within the field. These experiences are unique, very structured, and heavily supervised, but prepare the student well for real-life success.</p>
<p>When asked what type of work Brother Gardner sees his students doing upon graduation, he pulled out a book on careers within the field of family science published by the National Council on Family Relations. It contained a long list of positions for which a marriage and family graduate with a bachelor's degree would be well prepared. Jobs listed cover a wide variety of entry-level positions within community, government, education, and non-profit agencies. &nbsp;The average starting pay for positions in this field is usually around $30,000 annually. Specific jobs might include work in an adoption agency, as a psycho-social rehabilitation worker, or a case manager for children in treatment centers or with mental or emotional health issues. Other interesting positions that Brother Gardner's students have acquired include advocacy, educating the Utah state legislature on family friendly laws, and creating relationship education programs for the Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA), and high schools.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>According to Brother Gardner, there are many career opportunities available to students with a bachelor's degree in marriage and family studies as long as graduates are willing to work hard and market themselves.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
