<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.101 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<NewsDetail ID="x51352" Name="Letizia Martinez" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Student Spotlight Letizia Martinez</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">A Shining Light</subTitle><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Chicago Pathway student Letizia Martinez talks about her experiences overcoming trials and finding hope in the Pathway program.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="201" Height="200" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" AlternateText="Letizia Martinez">Admin_Offices/Online Learning/News room/Letizia Martinez 3.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" List="Image" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="230" Height="341" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="" AlternateText="">Admin_Offices/Online Learning/News room/Letiza Martinaz Side Pic.png</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20130328T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Stephen Flanders</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>As a young girl, Letizia Kenoshann Martinez met several challenges along the already difficult road of childhood. Letizia lost her hearing at a young age and only knew Spanish at the time, so it was difficult to communicate. Her relationship with her parents was already rocky and this development only made it harder. Abuse, neglect, and abandonment were common in her childhood.<br /><br />After graduating from high school, the reality of life hit fast and hard. "I attempted several colleges, but I did not adjust at all and dropped out within weeks of starting."<br /><br />Letizia traveled the world over, spending time in Europe, Asia, and the Middle East. She then returned to Chicago and is currently enrolled in the Pathway program there. Letizia was hesitant at first, but her adoptive parents encouraged her to push herself to succeed. "I had zero faith in myself to attend consistently, do well in classes, or even complete one semester of Academic Start," Leticia says. Luckily she proved herself wrong and finished the semester with high marks in all of her classes. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p>According to Letizia, "The most significant experience was to actually complete a semester of college. It was an incredible, personal high for me to know that I am capable; I am worth the time and patience it required to invest in my own future. My self-esteem no longer needed validation from others; instead I looked within myself and to Heavenly Father." &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Letizia would like to pursue a bachelor's degree in the fields of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics. She has learned that life is what you make it, and she is determined to continue conquering the shadow that she sometimes feels around her. "I intend to bring honor, integrity, and ethical awareness to my thinking and behavior no matter where I am or what I am doing, redefining my character into something both God and I can be proud of," she says. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Letizia's advice to other Pathway students is, "Treat the Pathway experience like a lifeline to your dreams. This education is not about rote memorization and passing quizzes. You miss out on so many spiritual blessings that can be found in the classroom, your daily life, and in your spiritual growth. Be an active learner." &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho's Learning Model has also helped Letizia to learn more about herself, about others around her, and about the things that she is studying. The Learning Model has helped her to focus during class and to truly concentrate on what is being taught. The model has also encouraged friendships to be built within her Pathway group.</p>
<p>Letizia has several other goals that she intends to accomplish. She explains her inspiration and determination, "My biggest aspiration that has carried me through my toughest moments in life is my desire to be like the moon. &nbsp;I had a vivid dream as a pre-teen and dreamt that I was the moon and the stars around me were all the lives I positively touched with my unknown talent and potential. I interpreted that as I live in a world where abuse, neglect, and abandonment were gray areas and hard to prove or shed light upon. No matter how dark it gets, I hope the glow of my light will reach others near and far and inspire them to change their circumstances too."</p>
<p>It is safe to say that she has overcome the shadow that once followed her. Letizia created a list of ways to get involved and succeed in the Pathway program, which has aided student growth in the Chicago Pathway site. This location currently has a fully functional student council, and Letizia would like to see a flurry of activities be developed, "I have no doubt that if everyone pulled together and stated what they would like to see or do to have a great college experience that it would be a hit."</p>
<p>Letizia Kenoshann Martinez will surely continue to shine throughout her life and at her Pathway site in Chicago.&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
