<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x52318" Name="12-17-12 Center Stage Winter 2013" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Center Stage announces winter performing arts series</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho in Rexburg has announced its lineup of events for Winter Semester 2013.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="150" Height="150" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">Internal_Use/newsroom/CenterStageWinter12(thumb).jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="230" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="197" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">Internal_Use/newsroom/CenterStageWinter12(article).jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20121217T19:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Don Sparhawk</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho in Rexburg has announced its lineup of events for the Winter Semester.&nbsp;The season opens Jan. 18 with a performance in the Hart Auditorium by Vocal Point, a popular a cappella group from BYU in Provo, Utah, that competed on NBC's "The Sing Off" in 2011.&nbsp;<br /><br />"ZooZoo," a theatrical show by Imago Theatre of Portland, Ore., will feature a fun night of entertainment with many unique animals, including polar bears, anteaters, frogs, rabbits, hippos and penguins on Jan. 25 and 26 in the Kirkham Auditorium.&nbsp;Headlining this year's Barbershop Music Festival on Feb. 2 in the Barrus Concert Hall will be Vocal Spectrum, winners of the 2006 Barbershop International Quartet competition. Well-known trombonist Delfeayo Marsalis will headline this year's Winter Jazz Fest in the Kirkham Auditorium on Feb. 8 and 9. <br /><br />The ninth annual John Philip Sousa Night on Feb. 15 will feature world-famous euphonium player Brian Bowman and the BYU-Idaho Symphony Band in the Barrus Concert Hall. The Turtle Island Quartet and fiddler Michael Doucet will team up on Feb. 23 in the Kirkham Auditorium to explore the many faces of Cajun music. Christopher Houlihan, who is widely acknowledged as one of the brightest stars in the new generation of American organists, will play the Ruffatti organ March 1 in the Barrus Concert Hall.&nbsp;<br /><br />The BYU Singers from Provo and BYU-Idaho Collegiate Singers from Rexburg will perform together on both March 8 and 9 in the Barrus Concert Hall.&nbsp;BYU Ballroom Dance Company, the first Americans ever to win the prestigious British Formation Championships, will perform March 22 in the Kirkham Auditorium. <br /><br />A free brochure listing all performing arts events at BYU-Idaho is available at the Kimball Ticket Office and the Rexburg Chamber of Commerce, or by calling 496-3100. Detailed information can also be found on the Center Stage website at www.byui.edu/centerstage. Season tickets also may be ordered through the ticket office by calling 496-3170.&nbsp;Here is more detailed information about each event: <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Vocal Point</strong><strong></strong> <br /><strong>Friday, January 18 <br />7:30 p.m., Hart Auditorium <br />6 p.m., Preshow dinner, Manwaring Center</strong> <br /><br />They have percussion without drums. They have a rhythm section without a bass. The only instruments on stage belong to the nine voices of the a cappella group Vocal Point. Hailing from BYU in Provo, Utah, Vocal Point gives stunning, high-energy performances that have won them the International Championship of Collegiate A Cappella and a faithful following throughout the world. Last fall the group competed on NBC's <em>The Sing-Off</em>. After several weeks of competing, Vocal Point was eliminated from the competition, but not before becoming one the top five final groups. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale December 26. $6 for BYU-Idaho students, $12 for general public. No children under four. Classroom dress. Preshow dinner is $15 extra.</em> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /><br /><strong>ZooZoo</strong> <strong>By Imago Theatre<em></em></strong> <br /><strong>Friday &amp; Saturday, January 25-26 </strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m., Kirkham Auditorium</strong> <br /><br />Imago Theatre, best known for FROGZ and internationally acclaimed for its special brand of vaudeville, comedy, acrobatics and illusions, is proud to announce its latest hit ZooZoo, which combines mime, dance, music and special effects. Featured creatures include polar bears, bug eyes, anteaters, frogs, rabbits, hippos and penguins. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale January 7. $6 for BYU-Idaho students, $12 for general public. No children under four. Classroom dress.</em> <em>&nbsp;</em> <br /><br /><strong>Barbershop Music Festival</strong> <strong>Featuring International Champions</strong> <strong>Vocal Spectrum <br /></strong> <strong>Saturday, February 2 </strong><br /><strong>6 &amp; 8:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong> <br /><br />Vocal Spectrum, winner of the 2006 Barbershop International Quartet Championship, will headline this year's BYU-Idaho Barbershop Music Festival. Barbershop singing continues its popularity at BYU-Idaho and the Barrus Concert Hall has been attracting large crowds to its event for several years. Besides Vocal Spectrum, you will hear student quartets, the BYU-Idaho Men's Choir and Women's Choir, and the Carousel Chorus. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale January 7. $5 for BYU-Idaho students, $10 for general public. No children under six. Classroom dress. </em><strong></strong> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> <br /><br /><strong>Winter Jazz Fest</strong> <strong>Featuring Delfeayo Marsalis</strong> <strong>and BYU-Idaho Sound Alliance</strong> <br /><strong>Friday &amp; Saturday, Feb. 8-9 </strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m., Kirkham Auditorium</strong> <br /><br />Trombonist Delfeayo Marsalis will headline this year's Winter Jazz Fest featuring the BYU-Idaho Sound Alliance jazz band. Delfeayo is one of the top trombonists, composers and producers in jazz today. In January 2011, Delfeayo and the Marsalis family (father Ellis and brothers Branford, Wynton and Jason) earned the nation's highest jazz honor - a National Endowment for the Arts Jazz Masters Award. More information about the Winter Jazz Fest, clinics, workshops, and performances will be made available as the event draws near. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale January 14. $6 for BYU-Idaho students, $12 for general public. Classroom dress.</em> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> <br /><br /><strong>John Philip Sousa Night</strong> <strong>with Brian Bowman and</strong> <strong>the BYU-Idaho Symphony Band<br /> Friday, February 15</strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong> <br /><br />The 9th annual Sousa Concert will feature the BYU-Idaho Symphony Band along with world renowned euphonium player Brian Bowman. The well-known performer and recording artist has played euphonium in both the U.S. Navy and U.S. Air Force bands, and even performed the first euphonium recital at Carnegie Hall. The concert will follow the standard Sousa programming, including an overture, sacred tunes, popular and show music, patriotic selections, and of course, rousing marches. <br /><br /><em></em> <em>Tickets go on sale January 22. $3 for BYU-Idaho students, $6 for general public. No children under six. Classroom dress.</em> &nbsp; <br /><br /><strong>Turtle Island Quartet &amp;</strong> <strong>Cajun Fiddler Michael Doucet</strong> <br /><strong>Saturday, February 23 </strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m., Kirkham Auditorium</strong> <br /><br />The 1949 Pulitzer prize winning film score of&nbsp;<em>Louisiana Story</em> provides the inspiration for Grammy award-winning artists Michael Doucet on fiddle and the Turtle Island Quartet to delve into the many faces of Cajun music and beyond. Afro Cuban rhythm, the modern jazz harmonic language, traditional and classical styles from France, and even South Indian tabla grooves all find their place at the table, a sumptuous meal with spice, sweetness and unbridled joy. Doucet is leader of the famed ensemble BeauSoleil, which specializes in Cajun music. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale January 28. $6 for BYU-Idaho students, $12 for general public. No children under six. Event dress.</em> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> <br /><br /><strong>Christopher Houlihan</strong> <strong>playing Ruffatti Organ</strong> <br /><strong>Friday, March 1 </strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong> <br /><br />The young musician Christopher Houlihan is widely acknowledged as one of the brightest stars in the new generation of American organists. Christopher did his graduate degree work at The Juilliard School in New York where he studied with the Grammy Award winning organist Paul Jacobs. He is Artist-in-Residence at St. Ignatius of Antioch (Episcopal) in New York. During the summer of 2012, he performed the six organ symphonies of Louis Vierne in marathon sessions in six major north American cities - New York, Chicago, Denver, Dallas, Los Angeles and Montreal. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale February 4. $6 for BYU-Idaho students, $12 for general public. No children under six. Event dress.</em> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> <br /><br /><strong>BYU Singers and BYU-Idaho Collegiate Singers</strong> <br /><strong>Friday &amp; Saturday, March 8-9 </strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m. Friday; 3 p.m. Saturday, Barrus Concert Hall</strong> <br /><br />Two great university choirs will join together for two concerts in the Barrus Concert Hall. The Friday night and Saturday afternoon concerts will feature the BYU Singers from Provo and the BYU-Idaho Collegiate Singers from Rexburg in a choral exchange between the two schools. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale February 11. $5 for BYU-Idaho students, $10 for general public. No children under six. Event dress.</em> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> <br /><br /><strong>BYU Ballroom Dance Company</strong> <br /><strong>Friday, March 22 </strong><br /><strong>7:30 p.m., Kirkham Auditorium </strong><br /><strong>6 p.m., Preshow dinner, Manwaring Center</strong> <br /><br />The BYU Ballroom Dance Company from Provo is coming to BYU-Idaho for a one-night performance in the Kirkham Auditorium. The first Americans ever to win the prestigious British Formation Championships, a feat they have repeated an unprecedented ten times, the dancers have also competed in the World Formation Championships and have consistently earned top honors in the United States National Formation Championships. The company tours with its variety showcase of Latin and international dance styles, including waltz, samba, foxtrot and hustle. <br /><br /><em>Tickets go on sale February 25. $6 for BYU-Idaho students, $12 for general public. No children under six. Event dress. Preshow dinner at 6 p.m. for $16 extra.</em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17620" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
