<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x52328" Name="09-05-12 Center Stage Fall Series" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho Center Stage announces fall performing arts series</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho in Rexburg has announced its fall lineup.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="150" Height="150" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">Internal_Use/newsroom/2012/Canadian Brass news thumb.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="230" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="233" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">Internal_Use/newsroom/2012/Canadian Brass news photo[9](0).jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120905T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Don Sparhawk</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho in Rexburg has announced its fall lineup, including a performance by the Mormon Tabernacle Choir and Orchestra at Temple Square and a Christmas concert by the Canadian Brass.</p>
<p>The season opens Sept. 14 and 15 with Comedy Night, featuring standup comedians Ryan Hamilton, Bengt Washburn and Spencer King.&nbsp;The Tabernacle Choir and Orchestra at Temple Square will perform a concert in the BYU-Idaho Center on Sept. 21.&nbsp;Pianist Alpin Hong will perform Sept. 28, followed by the 17-piece string orchestra A Far Cry from Boston on Oct. 3 and the men's singing group Cantus from Minnesota will perform Oct. 12.</p>
<p>"Ukelele Hero" Jake Shimabukuro will perform in the Hart Auditorium on Oct. 19 following by Stayin' Alive, a Bee Gees tribute band on Nov. 2.&nbsp;The Parisii Quartet from Paris, France, will present a classical string quartet concert on Nov. 9.&nbsp;The season will end on Dec. 1 with "A BYU-Idaho Christmas" concert featuring the university choirs and orchestra with special guests Canadian Brass.</p>
<p>A free brochure listing all performing arts events at BYU-Idaho is available at the Kimball Ticket Office and the Rexburg Chamber of Commerce, or by calling 496-3100. Detailed information can also be found on the Center Stage website at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/centerstage">www.byui.edu/centerstage</a>.&nbsp;Season tickets also may be ordered through the ticket office by calling 496-3170.</p>
<p>Here is more detailed information about each event:</p>
<p><strong>Comedy Night</strong></p>
<p><strong>Featuring Ryan Hamilton, Spencer King and Bengt Washburn</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday and Saturday, Sept. 14-15</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m., Kirkham Auditorium</strong></p>
<p>Comedy Night will feature the return to campus of standup comedians Ryan Hamilton and Spencer King, along with a first-time appearance by Bengt Washburn. Ryan, who grew up in nearby Ashton and attended BYU-Idaho, now lives in New York City where he keeps people laughing with his stories of Idaho. Both Spencer and Bengt are popular comedians who make their home in Utah.</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale August 27. Cost is $12 for general public, $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under four. Classroom dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>Mormon Tabernacle Choir and Orchestra at Temple Square</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday, September 217:30 p.m., BYU-Idaho Center</strong></p>
<p><strong>Pre-show dinner at 6:00 p.m., Manwaring Center</strong></p>
<p>In its first performance in the BYU-Idaho Center, the Mormon Tabernacle Choir and Orchestra at Temple Square will perform a full evening of favorite music. As one of the oldest and largest choirs in the world, the choir has performed before U.S. presidents, sold millions of records, won scores of awards, and enthralled audiences in dozens of countries. Ronald Reagan, president of the United States from 1981 to 1989, dubbed the Mormon Tabernacle Choir "America's Choir" in 1981 when the choir sang at his inauguration.</p>
<p><em>Tickets are now on sale. Cost is $12 for general public, $6 for BYU-Idaho students. Preshow dinner is $15 extra. No children under six. Event dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>Alpin Hong</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday, September 28</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong></p>
<p>Whirlwind American tours and performances across the globe have earned pianist Alpin Hong the reputation as a modern-day Pied Piper. His combination of stunning technique, emotional range, and rare humor continues to bring audiences young and old to their feet. Rooted in extensive classical training from Juilliard and a background in skateboarding, snowboarding, martial arts, and video games, Mr. Hong is a creative force unmatched in his youthful vivacity and boundless energy.</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale September 4. Cost is $12 for general public; $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under six. Event dress.</em></p>
<p><strong> A Far Cry</strong></p>
<p><strong>Wednesday, October 3</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong></p>
<p>A Far Cry stands at the forefront of an exciting new generation in classical music. According to the New York Times, the self-conducted orchestra "brims with personality or, better, personalities, many and varied." A Far Cry was founded in 2007 by a tightly-knit collective of 17 young professional musicians - the Criers - and since the beginning has fostered those personalities, developing an innovative structure of rotating leadership both on stage and behind the scenes. The Criers are proud to call Boston home, and maintain strong roots in the city rehearsing at their storefront music center in Jamaica Plain.</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale September 10. Cost is $12 for general public, $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under six. Event dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>Cantus</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday, October 12</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong></p>
<p>Acclaimed as "the premier men's vocal ensemble in the United States" (Fanfare), Cantus is committed to inspiring audiences with music performed at the highest level.Rehearsing and performing without a conductor or music director, the nine members of Cantus are renowned for adventurous programming spanning many periods and genres. Cantus shares its impeccable singing, engaging stage personality, and heartfelt interpretations with audiences across the country as they tour and at home in Minneapolis and St. Paul, Minnesota.</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale September 17. Cost is $12 for general public, $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under six. Event dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>Jake Shimabukuro "Ukulele hero" (Rolling Stone)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday, October 19</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m. Hart Auditorium</strong></p>
<p>It's been a defining year for "ukulele hero" (Rolling Stone) Jake Shimabukuro. He's performed on "Jimmy Kimmel Live!," "Rolling Stone Live," "A Prairie Home Companion" and CNN's "The Next List." On October 2, Jake's most ambitious record to date, entitled More Ukulele, may catapult his career even further. It's rare for a young musician to earn comparisons to the likes of Jimi Hendrix and Miles Davis. It's even harder to find an artist who has entirely redefined an instrument by his early thirties. But Jake Shimabukuro &nbsp;has already accomplished these feats, and more, in a little over a decade of playing and recording music...on the ukulele.</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale September 24. Cost is $12 for general public, and $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under four. Classroom dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>Stayin' Alive </strong></p>
<p><strong>A Bee Gees Tribute Band</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday, November 2</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m. Hart Auditorium</strong></p>
<p>The Bee Gees have been captivating audiences for more than five decades with their unique vocal sound. Stayin' Alive creates a realistic sense of hearing and experiencing the brothers' Gibb live in concert. The tribute band offers to their audiences the songs and sights of a full Bee Gee's playlist, singing blockbusters such as "Night Fever," "Jive Talking," "How Deep is Your Love?," "You Should Be Dancing," "Nights on Broadway," and "Stayin' Alive."</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale October 8. Cost is $12 for general public, and $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under four. Classroom dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>Parisii Quartet</strong></p>
<p><strong>Friday, November 9</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m., Barrus Concert Hall</strong></p>
<p>Formed in 1984 by four prize-winning graduates of the Conservatoire National Superieur de Paris, the Parisii Quartet won early acclaim with its triumphs at three major international competitions: Banff (1986), Munich (1987), and Evian (1987). Invitations followed from the major concert halls and festivals of Europe, and the Parisii has since toured regularly throughout Europe and the United Kingdom. The French quartet is noted for its performances of distinctive and unusual repertoire of the l8th, l9th and 20th centuries. While at BYU-Idaho, they will be conducting a residency with music students.</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale October 15. Cost is $12 for general public, $6 for BYU-Idaho students. No children under 6. Event dress.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><strong>A BYU-Idaho Christmas&nbsp;with special guests&nbsp;Canadian Brass</strong></p>
<p><strong>Saturday, December 1</strong></p>
<p><strong>7:30 p.m., BYU-Idaho Center</strong></p>
<p><strong>6:00 p.m., Pre-show dinner in Manwaring Center</strong></p>
<p>The legendary Canadian Brass will be the featured musical guests at the university's second Christmas program in the new 15,000-seat BYU-Idaho Center. Canadian Brass will join BYU-Idaho choirs and orchestra, and other students from the College of Performing and Visual Arts. With an international reputation as one of the most popular brass ensembles today, Canadian Brass has truly earned the distinction of "the world's most famous brass group."</p>
<p><em>Tickets go on sale October 29. Cost is $12 for general public, $6 for BYU-Idaho students. Pre-show dinner is $15 extra. No children under six. Event dress.</em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17620" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
