<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x52565" Name="04-05-10 Spring Performing Arts Series" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Center Stage announces spring performing arts lineup</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at BYU-Idaho announces its spring lineup.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20100405T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Writer: Don Sparhawk</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho has announced its spring lineup-and they're ones you're not going to want to miss.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	April 23:	A Dvorak Finale! <br />(Features the Idaho Falls Symphony and cellist Steven Honigberg)<br />Marking the final performance of Maestro George Adams, the Idaho Falls Symphony will perform Symphony No. 7 by Antonin Dvorak. Celebrating its 60th season, this volunteer orchestra has brought the finest in symphonic music to Idaho Falls and the eastern Idaho area.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	April 30:	Ryan Shupe &amp; the RubberBand<br />Ryan Shupe &amp; the RubberBand is always a favorite. This American music group is based in Utah and popular for its unique style of bluegrass. Ryan started playing violin at the age of 5 and since then has picked up the guitar and mandolin. Popular songs in recent years have included "Dream Big," "Banjo Boy," and "Even Superman."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	May 7 &amp; 8:	Comedy Improv Night<br />You have to see this show to believe it-improvised music, comedy scenes, the works! The show features Kirby Heyborne (The RM, The Best Two Years), Corbin Allred (Saints and Soldiers, Christmas Mission), Lincoln Hoppe (Singles Ward, The RM), and Kelly Lohman.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	May 14:	BYU Young Ambassadors<br />Brigham Young University's Young Ambassadors will present the musical production, The New Music Makers. The show celebrates popular music and dance from the 1960s up to the present day, and features familiar tunes that will no doubt have the audience tapping their toes and humming along.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><br />&bull;	May 21 &amp; 22:	The Work: A Nashville Tribute to the Missionaries<br />The Nashville Tribute Band will perform vocal and instrumental music from its newest album about Latter-day Saint missionaries. They also will perform popular selections from two other popular albums: Joseph: A Nashville Tribute to the Prophet and Trek: A Nashville Tribute to the Pioneers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	July 1:		Patriots and Pioneers: A BYU-Idaho Heritage Collection<br />For the first time, the BYU-Idaho Department of Music presents a major Independence Day concert to celebrate our national heritage! Join the BYU-Idaho Symphony Band, more than 250 choral singers, and tenor Stanford Olsen for a new holiday tradition that is sure to become a family favorite for years to come.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	July 29:	Heartbound (Education Week Concert)<br />For years you've enjoyed Heartbound classes at BYU-Idaho Education Week. Now come and hear them sing some of your favorite popular songs. They'll have you tapping your toes, laughing, and having a good time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	July 30:	Marvin Goldstein &int;(Education Week Concert)<br />Hear pianist Marvin Goldstein as he performs Broadway showtunes; love songs; and patriotic, religious and international music with some of his special friends.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A free brochure listing all performing arts events at BYU-Idaho is available at the BYU-Idaho Ticket Office, the BYU-Idaho Alumni Center on Main Street in Rexburg, the Rexburg Chamber of Commerce, or by calling 496-1150. Season tickets may also be ordered at www.byui.edu/tickets or at the BYU-Idaho Ticket Office. For high resolution images, please contact us.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
