<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x52520" Name="08-26-10 Fall Performing Arts" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Center Stage announces fall performing arts lineup</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at BYU-Idaho has announced its fall lineup, including Jon Schmidt, Natalie McMaster, and Collin Raye.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20100826T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Writer: Don Sparhawk</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Center Stage Performing Arts Series at Brigham Young University-Idaho has announced its fall lineup, including Jon Schmidt, Natalie McMaster, and Collin Raye.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Sept. 10-11:	Jon Schmidt (with cellist Steven Sharp Nelson)<br />Described as a new American classic, Jon Schmidt's virtuosity and performance will both astonish you and make you smile. He has created a hybrid of music that is equal parts classical, contemporary, and rock and roll. His performances showcase the unique blend that is Jon Schmidt as he transitions from the dramatic and reflective into his show stopping, pyrotechnic-laced back flip.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Sept. 17:	ABBA-Mania<br />ABBA-Mania takes you back to the disco era of one of the greatest pop bands in history, ABBA. The concert features nine musicians and singers who perform 21 of ABBA's hits, with costume changes, choreography, a live band, back-up singers, and big studio sound.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Sept. 24:	Quartetto Gelato<br />Quartetto Gelato not only thrills its audiences with its instrument mastery of violin, cello and accordion, but also offers the bonus of a brilliant operatic tenor. Few quartets have risen to great artistic and critical heights, yet Quartetto Gelato will dazzle and enchant with their classical masterpieces, sizzling tangos, Latin rhythms, and Gypsy and folk music.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Sept. 28:	Saxophobia<br />Saxophobia offers a rare glimpse at some of the most unusual saxophones ever made. Accompanied by piano, bass, and drums, sax player Rob Verdi pays tribute to some of the great legends who popularized the instrument. Today, more than 150 years after its birth, the saxophone continues to be loved and embraced, and is a vital voice in many styles of music.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Oct. 8:		Eric Bibb<br />Already enjoying success in Europe, Grammy-nominee Eric Bibb is becoming a familiar face and voice in the United States. Nominated for nine Blues Music Awards and winner of the Best Newcomer title in the British Blues Awards, Eric has been appropriately described as "discreetly awesome" and "a total original." As his popularity escalates, earlier comparisons to legendary greats Ry Cooder and Taj Mahal are being replaced by quotes that speak to Bibb's ability to "use standard blues ingredients to cook up something all his own."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Oct. 16:	Natalie McMaster and Donnell Leahy<br />Natalie MacMaster and Donnell Leahy are two of the world's most celebrated fiddlers. They also happen to be married. Together Natalie and Donnell are a whirlwind of fiddle-driven music, dance, and song. The foot-tapping rave-ups, heart-wrenching ballads, and world-class step dancing of this collaboration leave onlookers breathless from the moment it hits the stage. Audiences now have the chance to hear the fruits of this renowned musical matrimony during an unforgettable evening of Celtic music.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;	Nov. 5:	Collin Raye<br />One of the true hit-makers of the 1990s, country singer Collin Raye still continues to crank out soulful, heartfelt material with the honesty and richness that is signature to his vocals. Between 1991 and 2007, Collin charted 30 singles on the U.S. country charts. Four of his singles have reached No. 1 on the Billboard country music charts: "Love, Me," "In This Life," "My Kind of Girl," and "I Can Still Feel You." He has recorded a total of 11 studio albums.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><br />A free brochure listing all performing arts events is available at the BYU-Idaho Ticket Office, the BYU-Idaho Alumni Center on Main Street in Rexburg, the Rexburg Chamber of Commerce, or by calling 496-1150. Detailed information may also be found at www.byui.edu/centerstage. Season tickets may also be ordered at www.byui.edu/tickets or at the BYU-Idaho Ticket Office. For high resolution images, please contact us.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x10257" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
