<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x52907" Name="By Study and by Faith" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">By Study and By Faith</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">As a private, religious university, BYU-Idaho’s constant development is deeply connected to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<img alt="By Study and by faith" height="296" src="Images/Admin_Offices/university_communications/About_byui/about_byu_idaho/Main image.jpg" width="650" />
<p style="margin: 20px 0 0 0;">At Brigham Young University-Idaho, students are taking charge of their education. Classrooms are busy as students lead presentations, build leadership skills, and prepare for competitive careers. Everyone is a learner and a teacher. BYU-Idaho President Kim B. Clark said students at BYU-Idaho are being "educated, developed and prepared in a far more effective way than has ever been done before."</p>
<p>In this student-centered atmosphere, the quality of every student's experience is a key priority. Faculty and administration work progressively to ensure each student is adequately prepared to contribute in the workforce, family, and community.</p>
<div style="color: #3384bb; border-top: 1px dashed #9B9C9B; border-bottom: 1px dashed #9B9C9B; padding: 20px 0; font-size: 18px; width: 100%; margin: 15px 0;">
<div style="width: 410px; margin: 0 0 0 20px; font-style: italic;">"Reviewing previous learning promotes better retention and deeper understanding. Students prove their learning not only through quizzes and exams, but though regular opportunities to apply their skills in real-world settings."</div>
</div>
<p>Ambitious and talented students travel from all 50 states and more than 60 countries to study on this campus. And with close to 15,000 students filling its halls, BYU-Idaho is a bustling center of academic activity.</p>
<p>As a private, religious university, BYU-Idaho&rsquo;s constant development is deeply connected to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. Students&rsquo; life-changing learning is fostered by faith in the Lord Jesus Christ, commitment to the restored gospel, and continuous effort to build a learning community.</p>
<h3 style="color: #3384bb; font-style: italic; font-size: 16px; margin: 20px 0 5px 0;">The Learning Model</h3>
<p>At BYU-Idaho, students and faculty lead the education process together. The standardized model developed to guide students and teachers to a higher level of learning is called the Learning Model. It builds on the understanding that all learners and teachers are at different levels in their individual progress. The Learning Model guides students along three steps toward a deeper learning experience: 1) Prepare, 2) Teach One Another and 3) Ponder/Prove.</p>
<p>Prepare: Before coming to class, students study the assigned reading and complete required homework. Preparing through online discussions and pre-class study groups is also fundamental. However, true learning comes as students live worthy of the Holy Ghost&rsquo;s influence through daily prayer, scripture study, and obedience.</p>
<p>Teach One Another: President Clark teaches that the most powerful way to learn is to teach. As students teach, they articulate, polish, clarify, and correct their own understanding. Instructors create and supervise experiences in which students learn with and from each other. Such experiences prepare students for lifelong learning, leadership, and discipleship.</p>
<p>Ponder/Prove: Students are encouraged to internalize their learning through a process of reflection and application. Reviewing previous learning promotes better retention and deeper understanding. Students prove their learning not only through quizzes and exams, but though regular opportunities to apply their skills in real-world settings.</p>
<h3 style="color: #3384bb; font-style: italic; font-size: 16px; margin: 20px 0 5px 0;">Foundations</h3>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Foundations program, a complete redesign of traditional general education, is another unique component of BYU-Idaho. The goal of the program is to raise the quality of every student&rsquo;s experience by providing a stronger foundation that future learning can build upon.</p>
<p>Foundations courses are divided into five areas: Eternal Truths, Academic Fundamentals, Science, Cultural Awareness, and Connections. The interdisciplinary courses work hand-in-hand with the BYU-Idaho Learning Model and together provide a more focused education. Through Foundations, students are more thoroughly immersed in specific aspects of the subject matter.</p>
<h3 style="color: #3384bb; font-style: italic; font-size: 16px; margin: 20px 0 5px 0;">Internships</h3>
<p>BYU-Idaho is one of the largest intern-providing institutions in the nation. Each semester, BYU-Idaho students cover the globe as they work with approved internship providers to gain practical experience. Statistics show that nearly 50 percent of students receive a job offer at the completion of their internship. These hands-on opportunities enable students to receive valuable work experience with qualified professionals. Once students see how a company operates and what is required to succeed in their field, they gain a practical view of their career choice.</p>
<p>While BYU-Idaho interns gain an invaluable education through internships, they aren&rsquo;t the only ones benefitting. Many employers desire BYU-Idaho students because of their strong work ethic, clean-cut appearance, innovation, and creativity. Internship providers are also eager to work with BYU-Idaho students because they are available year-round.</p>
<h3 style="color: #3384bb; font-style: italic; font-size: 16px; margin: 20px 0 5px 0;">Three-track system</h3>
<p>The creative &ldquo;three-track system&rdquo; is another distinctive element of BYU-Idaho. Each school year is divided into three equal semesters (fall, spring, and winter) of 14 weeks each. When a student is admitted to the university, he or she is assigned to a specific academic &ldquo;track&rdquo;: fall/winter, winter/spring, or spring/fall.</p>
<p>What makes this system so different is that springtime here (traditionally summertime at other schools) is a full semester. Enrollment is consistent across all three tracks, and students are afforded the same academic opportunities no matter what assignment they receive. This calendaring system allows many thousands more students to attend the university each year.</p>
<h3 style="color: #3384bb; font-style: italic; font-size: 16px; margin: 20px 0 5px 0;">Online Learning</h3>
<p>BYU-Idaho is working to make a quality education available to more students at a lower cost. One way the university makes this possible is through Web-based classes in the Online Learning program. Specially designed to resemble campus classrooms, with rich discussions and personal interactions, Online Learning provides students much more flexibility.</p>
<p>Online courses follow the same semester calendar as on-campus classes. These require the normal time commitment of traditional classes, but students manage their participation around their daily schedule.</p>
<p>Quality is not sacrificed through online courses, as they are Learning Model based. Knowing how to learn and communicate with others online will become a big part of students&rsquo; lives and careers through their BYU-Idaho experience.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x86" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
