<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x53201" Name="About Us" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">About Us</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A history of the Automotive Program.  Mission Statement. Description of classes taught and desired student outcomes.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: large; color: #3584c2;">Automotive Technology Program</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium; color: #3584c2;">Mission Statement</span></p>
</div>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">"The purposes of the Automotive Technology Program at BYU-Idaho are to prepare its graduates to be competitive in the automotive field, enabling them to be good providers for their families and to offer the automotive world skilled, honest, and hardworking indivduals who possess and display moral character and ethics at work, home, and in their communities."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium; color: #3584c2;">Department of Automotive Technology</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The Automotive Program is housed in the Mark Austin Engineering and Technology building, one of the finest facilities for automotive repair education available. It includes four laboratories, each furnished with quality testing, diagnostic, and repair equipment.</span><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><br />The BYU-Idaho Automotive Department prepares students to enter one of the largest and far-reaching service industries that affects virtually every household. The opportunities in this field have never been better, both in the corporate world and in the retail service industry, as the complexity of the automobile removes many operations and procedures from the abilities of the do-it-yourself technician.<br />This results in a high demand for well trained, honest, progressive individuals, whether it be in the automotive service, technical repair, teaching or business fields. Students may enter this program during winter, spring, or fall semesters but they must be on the winter/spring or fall/winter track.<br />Students may earn an Associate of Applied Science Degree in Automotive Technology in a period of two school years with an internship in the summer between. Upon completion of the associate degree, students are qualified to enter the workforce as entry level service technicians with a strong technical background and some good hands-on experience. The program reinforces diagnostic skills by working on customer vehicles.</span><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"> </span><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><br />Many students, as they complete their Associate degree, decide to continue on with Bachelor's degree program in Automotive Technology Management. They can complete this in two additional years. Students receive a good business background in addition to their technical automotive skills. <br />Students graduating from this program are qualified to work in management programs for the automotive manufacturing and service industries. Many of our graduates work for Ford, General Motors, Honda, Toyota, Hyundai, and others. Others work in dealerships or automotive specialty shops. </span><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><br />By the time a student serves their internship, they should have their own tools. Students are encouraged to bring tools with them, or they may purchase tools at a discount through the program. For those planning to serve missions, we have a few basic rental tool sets available, then tools can purchased following the mission. <br />For information concerning required classes for either the two year program or the four-year technology management program, see the advising tab on the left side of this page.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Welcome to an exciting, challenging, and rewarding field of study!<br /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium; color: #808080;"><br /></span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x8175" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
