<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x53824" Name="Degrees &amp; Majors" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Degrees</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">This contains information for the BYU-Idaho Bachelor of Science Computer Engineering degree, the Bachelor of Science Computer Science degree, and the Bachelor of Science Electrical Engineering degree.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img height="246" src="Images/Colleges_and_Departments/Physical Sciences and Engineering/Computer Science and Electrical Engineering/AUS_Banner.jpg" width="710" /><br />
<p>The curricula in the BYU-Idaho Department of Computer Science and Electrical Engineering are designed to provide a broad background in the theory and practice of computer software, computer hardware, and electrical systems.</p>
<p>An advisory committee, which consists of individuals employed in the industry who have experience pertinent to the programs within the department, has been developed to help keep our programs current. The members of this committee study the programs and give insight regarding the content of courses and possible new courses that will benefit our students.</p>
<h1>Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering</h1>
<p>Computer Engineers design computer systems, both hardware and software, to create new technology and meet new social needs. The degree focuses on technologies that are required in computing machines such as in robotics, and on providing students with laboratory experiences to explore and apply these technologies. The core courses are in areas of logic design, electronics, software engineering, computer architectures, microprocessors, real-time embedded systems, controls, communications, and computing networks. The Computer Engineering (BS) program at Brigham Young University-Idaho is accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology (EAC/ABET) [granted in 2007, effective as of October 1, 2004]. Visit www.abet.org for more information about this accreditation.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><em>As a computer engineer, imagine creating the next super computer, the next revolutionary MP3/video player, or even the next control system for the latest Air Force fighter jet. The Computer Engineering program at BYU-Idaho balances scientific and engineering theory with technical laboratory experiences in order to develop practical knowledge and skills that working computer engineers need. The curriculum is balanced to make you adept at designing and developing both computer hardware and computer software. In addition, throughout your computer engineering education, you will gain in-depth knowledge and skills in the design and development of many different types of computer systems: from small MP3 players to large parallel computer systems. Graduates are prepared for high paying employment as computer engineers or to continue their education at graduate school.</em></p>
<h1>Bachelor of Science in Computer Science</h1>
<p>The Computer Science major provides a solid background in Computer Science by providing experience in algorithm development, procedural and object-oriented design and programming, software engineering practices, data structures, computer organization, and theoretical foundations.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><em>As a computer scientist, imagine creating the next search engine, the next social web site, or even the next "must have" video game. The Computer Science program at BYU-Idaho offers a solid background in computer science by providing experiences in algorithm development, procedural and object-oriented design and programming, software engineering practices, computer security, web engineering, technical communication, and the theoretical foundations of computing. Graduates are prepared for high paying employment as software engineers or to continue their education at graduate school. </em></p>
<h1>Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering</h1>
<p>Electrical engineering focuses on the study of electrical and electronic systems. Electrical engineers have many potential job functions but most design, develop, and test products that are powered by or produce electricity. There are many potential products that an electrical engineer may work on. A few include medical equipment (e.g., Magnetic Resonance Imaging - MRI), communication equipment (e.g., cellular phones), computers, motion controllers, and airline navigation systems. Often overlapping with computer engineering, a degree in electrical engineering can open up the door to a technical career in almost any industry.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><em>As an electrical engineer, imagine creating the next generation of consumer electronic devices, the next generation of robotics, or the next electronic medical device that saves lives. The Electrical Engineering program at BYU-Idaho prepares you to use electricity and electronics in novel ways to help solve some of the world's greatest scientific challenges. The program balances scientific and engineering theory with technical laboratory experiences in order to develop practical knowledge and skills that working electrical engineers need. Graduates are prepared for high paying employment as electrical engineers or to continue their education at graduate school.</em></p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>To qualify for graduation, students must achieve at least a C- grade in all major required classes.</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://byui.box.com/shared/static/762809b5767581b05d01.pdf"></a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x27783" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
