<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EmployeeInfo ID="x53897" Name="Reed Nielsen" Layout="general_employee.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Reed Nielsen BYU Idaho Faculty Rexburg Idaho Department of Design and Construction</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PersonalInfo" label="Personal Info" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><FirstName type="string" label="First Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Reed</FirstName><LastName type="string" label="Last Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Nielsen</LastName><DeptOffice type="string" label="Department or Office" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Design &amp; Construction Mngmnt</DeptOffice><JobTitle type="string" label="Job Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Faculty</JobTitle></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PersonalInfo" label="Contact Info" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><Office type="string" label="Office" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">129 AUS</Office><Zip type="string" label="Zip" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">83460+1030</Zip><Phone type="string" label="Phone" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">208-496-7584</Phone><Email type="string" label="Email" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">nielsenr@byui.edu</Email><xPower Type="Link" Link="external" Name="Homepage" label="Homepage" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" URL="http://emp.byui.edu/nielsenr&#xA;" LinkText="" Target=""/><xPower Type="Link" Link="" Name="Download" label="Download" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="CoreInfo" label="Core Info" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="List" List="EducationItem" Name="EducationItems" label="Education History" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true"><EducationItem readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true">BS - Arizona State University 1975</EducationItem><EducationItem readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true">MS - Arizona State University 2003</EducationItem><EducationItem readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true">PhD studies - Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Virginia Tech) 2005 Registered Professional Engineer (California)</EducationItem></xPower><xPower Type="List" List="InterestItem" Name="InterestItems" label="Areas of Interest" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true"><InterestItem readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true">Project and Company Mangement</InterestItem><InterestItem readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true">Project Controls ( Cost and Schedule )</InterestItem><InterestItem readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true">Field Engineering</InterestItem></xPower><xPower Type="List" List="xpowerlink_CurrentCourseItem" Name="CurrentCourseItems" label="Current Courses Taught" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Link" Link="external" Name="CurrentCourseItem" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Expanded="true" URL=""/></xPower><xPower Type="List" List="xpowerlink_OtherCourseItem" Name="OtherCourseItems" label="Other Courses Taught" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Link" Link="" Name="OtherCourseItem" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" LinkText="" Target="" Expanded="true" URL=""/></xPower></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="OptionalInfo" label="Optional Info Items" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" List="xpowergroupstart_OptionalInfo" LinkText="" Target="" Link="" Expanded="true"><OptionalItemsName1 label="Optional Item Title 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Publications</OptionalItemsName1><OptionalItemsText1 type="dhtml" label="Optional Item Text 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>A Construction View of the Intermountain Power Project, co-authored with Gary T. Rose, Proceedings: 1989 Fossil Power Plant Construction Conference</p>
<p>Construction Technologies in Japan, Chapter 5 - Construction Field Operations and Automated Equipment, R.L. Tucker, Chairman, National Science Foundation sponsored JTEC Panel Report, June 1991</p>
<p>The Use of Simulation Software for a Power Plant Construction Project, co-authored with Arthur Stover, Civil Engineering Practice, Journal of the Boston Society of Civil Engineers Section /ASCE - Spring/Summer 1993, Volume 8, Number 1</p>]]></OptionalItemsText1><OptionalItemsName2 label="Optional Item Title 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Teaching Experience</OptionalItemsName2><OptionalItemsText2 type="dhtml" label="Optional Item Text 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[Prior to coming to BYU-Idaho, I taught courses at both Arizona State University and<br />Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (Virginia Tech.) A brief summary of<br />the classes I was responsible for at those institutions follows.<br />While taking courses required for a PhD from Virginia Tech located in Blacksburg,<br />Virginia, I was responsible for two freshmen level courses. The focus of courses, BC<br />1214 - Introduction to Building Construction I (taught in the spring of 2004 and 2005)<br />and BC 1224 - Introduction to Building Construction II (taught in the fall of 2004), were<br />to introduce students to the basic building blocks of construction in terms of vocabulary,<br />materials, techniques and tools (both physical and management.)<br />I also taught two construction courses, while completing the requirements for a Masters<br />of Science in Construction at Arizona State University.<br />I was twice responsible for the capstone course (CON 455) of the Del E. Webb School of<br />Construction for students of senior standing. The course summarized and brought<br />together the subject matter that had been taught in their previous three years of<br />instruction. There were from 35 to 45 students in each class taught.<br />My goal in teaching the class was to help the students understand how their classroom<br />experiences had a practical application. The course work revolved around understanding<br />project management principles and applying them to the construction industry. Group<br />work and in-class discussion and "role play" experiences were used to teach principles of<br />responsibility and communication and to help the students develop the skills necessary to<br />work together in a group or team effort to accomplish a specific goal.<br />Several practicing construction professionals from home building, risk management and<br />industrial construction segments of the industry gave presentations to the class to expand<br />their understanding of the industry. The students were required to summarize and<br />comment on each of the presentations to help develop their listening and critical analysis<br />skills.<br />The final assignment in the class was a group project (of up to 4 students each) where the<br />various groups were given a real world project and required to prepare a project<br />execution plan. These plans were approximately 15 pages in length and provided an<br />outline of safety and quality plans that addressed the project's specific needs and<br />challenges, a site layout, management and staffing plans and elementary schedule and<br />equipment requirements. Each group gave a formal presentation of their respective<br />execution plans and answered questions from other class members and the instructor.<br />This simulated the type of presentation they would ultimately be required to give to<br />prospective clients and evaluation teams.<br />During the fall semester of 2002 I was responsible for teaching Construction Methods,<br />Materials and Equipment (CON 242). There were 40 + students in the class.<br />Primarily taken during the sophomore year, this course introduced the students to basic<br />construction terminology while presenting the materials and equipment that are used in<br />construction and the methods by which these materials and equipment are used to<br />construct buildings, homes and industrial facilities.<br />The course objective was for the students to obtain a basic understanding of the materials<br />and equipment used in building construction and the various methods used in their<br />installation and for the student to become more familiar with construction terminology.<br />This included gaining an understanding of the Construction Specifications Institute's 16<br />division Masterformat standard. Class discussions, outside reading, group and individual<br />projects and presentations, in addition to homework, were designed to support the class<br />objective.<br />]]></OptionalItemsText2><OptionalItemsName3 label="Optional Item Title 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Industrial Experience - Summary:</OptionalItemsName3><OptionalItemsText3 type="dhtml" label="Optional Item Text 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Twenty-six (26) years experience in project, construction and contract management of power<br />plant, refinery, telecommunications projects and research and development with various Bechtel<br />entities.<br />I held positions of Field Engineer, Contract Engineer, Contract Manager, Project Superintendent,<br />Manager of Bechtel's Construction Technology Group of Bechtel's Research and Development<br />Organization, Field Construction Manager, Project Manager, Director of Operations and<br />President of a Brazilian Joint Venture Telecommunications company. While manager of<br />Construction Technology I made presentations at Stanford University, Arizona State University,<br />University of Texas - Austin and Purdue University (among others) and represented Bechtel as<br />Task Force Member of the CII (Construction Industry Institute at University of Texas at Austin)<br />and CIFE (Center for Integrated Facility Engineering at Stanford University). I also was a<br />member of a NSF funded group which studied the status of the Japanese construction industry in<br />the early 1990's. Please see the publications outlined below.<br />I returned to Arizona State University in August 2001 to earn a Masters degree in Construction<br />to prepare myself to teach at the university level.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong>PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS:</strong></em><br />Registered Civil Engineer, California, License C-32002<br />Current reviewer of professional papers submitted to various ASCE publications.</p>
<p><br /><em><strong>PUBLICATIONS:</strong></em></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">A Construction View of the Intermountain Power Project</span>, co-authored with Gary T. Rose,&nbsp;Proceedings: 1989 Fossil Power Plant Construction Conference</p>
<p><em><strong>&nbsp;</strong></em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Construction Technologies In Japan, Chapter 5 - Construction Field Operations and Automated Equipment</span>, R. L. Tucker, Chairman, National Science Foundation sponsored JTEC Panel Report, June, 1991</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">The Use of Simulation Software for a Power Plant Construction Project</span>, co-authored with Arthur Stover, Civil Engineering Practice, Journal of the Boston Society of Civil Engineers Section/ASCE - Spring/Summer 1993, Volume 8 Number 1</p>
<p>Thesis entitled "<em>THE IMPACT OF TRAINED CONSTRUCTION PROFESSIONALS ON</em><br /><em>PROJECT PERFORMANCE</em>". &nbsp;The hypothesis, that training positively affects project success,<br />is being tested through the evaluation of recent construction projects using bivariate and<br />multivariate statistical evaluation techniques.</p>
<p><br /><em><strong>LANGUAGE CAPABILITIES:</strong></em><br />Read, write and speak fluent Portuguese</p>
<p><br /><em><strong>EXPERIENCE DETAIL:</strong></em><br />I retired from Bechtel Telecommunications. My last assignment (through May 4, 2001) was as<br />Bechtel Construction Manager of the Western Integrated Networks Project (WIN). I was<br />responsible for the construction effort in Dallas, Texas and Sacramento, California. For a fourmonth<br />interval I was also the Acting Sacramento Market Manager. During this time we<br />developed and implemented the processes (engineering, procurement, construction, safety,<br />project controls, contracts administration, document control, etc.) that will be used on all future<br />WIN fiber optic city builds throughout the Western United States.<br />From May 1998 to July 2000 I served as the Operations Director of a joint venture company,<br />Bechtel M&eacute;todo Telcom, Ltda. (BMT) located in S&atilde;o Paulo, Brazil. BMT is a limited<br />partnership formed between M&eacute;todo (a Brazilian construction engineering firm) and Bechtel.<br />BMT provides construction and construction management services to the Brazilian<br />Telecommunication Industry. My responsibilities included all field operations (design;<br />procurement; construction, contract and project management and the company's on-going<br />management training program) and providing support to Business Development and Marketing<br />in the areas of presentations and bid preparation. For the final 10 months of my assignment I<br />also served as the President of the company. While President, in addition to the operations<br />responsibilities, I was responsible for coordinating and interfacing with both Joint Venture<br />partners and for providing direction and approval to all company operations including marketing,<br />engineering, human resources and finance and accounting.<br />I was assigned to Bechtel's Sprint PCS cellular telephone project from December 1995 until May<br />1998. Over a two year period the design, procurement and construction of over 2800 cellular<br />phone sites was accomplished throughout the United States of America. In my first area of<br />responsibility on this project I was the Field Construction Manager responsible for the Seattle,<br />Washington market. I relocated to the Pleasanton Regional office in July 1996 as the Western<br />Region Construction Manager and in October 1996 was promoted to Western Regional<br />Operations Manager. In this capacity, I was responsible for the management of over 170 Bechtel<br />employees, 52 architect engineering firms and 97 construction firms in eight different cities in<br />the western United States and for direct interface with management of both Lucent Technologies<br />and Sprint PCS. In November 1997, I became the CM Project Manager and was responsible for<br />the entire project, consisting of 17 major metropolitan areas in the United States.<br />From December 1993 until December 1995, I was assigned to the Shell Oil Company Clean<br />Fuels Project at Martinez, California. For the first four months I was the construction interface<br />representative at R. M. Parson's Glendale, California, office. In April 1994, I moved to the job<br />site and became Area Superintendent for all off-site construction - union and non-union<br />subcontract and direct hire work, valued at over $400 million. In this assignment I had<br />responsibility for cost, schedule, quality and safety. At peak, approximately 700 craft were<br />involved in offsite construction of interconnecting pipe and electrical, pipe racks, flare and flare<br />compressors and a 100MW gas-fired co-generation power plant.<br />Early inn 1993, I became the Project Manager for start-up coordination and verification at the<br />Carbon II Power Plant (Piedras Negras, Mexico). During this time I also directed preparation of<br />proposals for power plant construction and provided construction input to Bechtel Civil and<br />Petroleum proposals prepared in Bechtel's Norwalk, California office.<br />From July 1991 until February 1993, I was the Site Manager (Senior On-Site Bechtel employee)<br />for construction of an 83 MW (net) circulating fluidized bed boiler electric generating facility<br />located near Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. The project included coal handling, crushing, cooling<br />water and ash handling systems. It was completed ahead of the 25 1/2-month design,<br />construction and start-up schedule. In this capacity, I was responsible for all site construction<br />activities and support functions (Finance and Accounting, Procurement, Field Engineering,<br />Safety, Project Controls), site client interface and local public relations.<br />The previous two years I was the Manager of Bechtel's Construction Technologies group located<br />in the San Francisco corporate office. In this capacity I was involved in the development of<br />processes, hardware and systems for improvement of the Bechtel construction effort. Working<br />closely with Bechtel's Engineering Technologies group, I coordinated the effort to monitor,<br />evaluate and disseminate domestic and international developments for construction technologies.<br />During this assignment I was a member of a National Science Foundation investigative team<br />which visited and reported on construction technology development and its use in Japan. I also<br />served as Bechtel's representative on the Construction Industry Institute's Automation Task<br />Force.<br />Prior to being assigned to corporate headquarters in San Francisco, I was the project<br />superintendent at the Basic American Foods co-generation plant (120 MW net) located in King<br />City, California. In this role I was in charge of all direct hire construction work, including<br />quality, safety, cost and scheduling and labor relations and provided guidance to craft<br />superintendents regarding methods, sequencing, work planning and execution.<br />I was assigned to the Bechtel Construction Management team at the Intermountain Power Project<br />from August 1982 until August 1988. Serving almost four years as the Field Contracts Manager,<br />I had responsibility for the commercial administration of sixty-three contracts. Major contracts<br />included the installation of two 800 MW (net) General Electric turbines, coal handling and<br />crushing facilities, Babcock and Wilcox boilers (6.1 million pounds / hour) and ash handling<br />facilities. Over 8 million cubic yards of excavation and backfill was performed, 500,000 cubic<br />yards of concrete placed, 72,000 tons of structural steel erected and 13,000,000 feet of wire and<br />cable installed and 615,000 linear feet of pipe hung on this project. The project included over 9<br />miles of twin 48 inch diameter pre-cast concrete intake pipe, over 450 acres of reservoir and<br />effluent ponds and associated ash slurry pipe, and coal handling equipment including conveyor<br />belt systems capable of handling up to 6,000 tons per hour of coal. In January of 1987, I was<br />promoted to Field Construction Manager, where I was responsible for dealing with site<br />contractors and project owner and operator during the completion phase of the project. I<br />completed the assignment at IPP as the Assistant Site Construction Manager of an integrated<br />project team that consisted of personnel from the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power<br />(LADWP), Black and Veatch and Bechtel Construction. In this capacity I reported to the Site<br />Manager (an employee of LADWP), directed the electrical and mechanical activities of this<br />multi-company integrated organization and was responsible for all commercial administration<br />and civil design at the facility.<br />From January 1976 until August 1982 I held various responsibilities at the San Onofre Nuclear<br />Generating Station, Units 2 and 3, at San Clemente, California. Initially I was responsible for the<br />planning, implementation and final inspection of concrete placements over a seven-month<br />period. I was then given the responsibility of directing the field design, engineering and<br />inspection of the two unit's containment exterior walls and domes, in addition to the fuel<br />handling building. For almost two years I served as the Senior Field Engineer supervising the<br />work of all civil construction field engineers and assisting the civil craft superintendents. This<br />included assisting in the preparation for and placement of major Nuclear Steam Supply System<br />equipment including reactor vessels, steam generators and associated coolant pumps and all<br />associated grouting. For eighteen months I was the assistant civil superintendent monitoring and<br />directing civil crafts (over 500 individuals) and coordinating work with other disciplines and<br />superintendents. I then was the contract superintendent responsible for all thermal insulation and<br />then electrical superintendent for Unit 3 containment structure. My assignment at San Onofre<br />completed as the Discipline Contracts Superintendent, where I was responsible for field<br />operations of all site contractors, during the successful start-up phase of Unit 2 and into the<br />beginning of the start-up of Unit 3.<br />I started with Bechtel at the Cholla Power Plant (Units 2, 3 and 4) as a field contracts engineer.<br />During this six-month assignment I monitored work performance and contract compliance of<br />heating, ventilating and air conditioning, elevator roofing, pile driving and chimney<br />subcontractors and related activities.<br />Before beginning college I served a mission for the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints<br />in Brazil and worked on various road construction projects in and around Salt Lake City, Utah.</p>]]></OptionalItemsText3><OptionalItemsName4 label="Optional Item Title 4" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></OptionalItemsName4><OptionalItemsText4 type="dhtml" label="Optional Item Text 4" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[]]></OptionalItemsText4><OptionalItemsName5 label="Optional Item Title 5" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></OptionalItemsName5><OptionalItemsText5 type="dhtml" label="Optional Item Text 5" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[]]></OptionalItemsText5><OptionalItemsName6 label="Optional Item Title 6" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></OptionalItemsName6><OptionalItemsText6 type="dhtml" label="Optional Item Text 6" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[]]></OptionalItemsText6></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1893" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></EmployeeInfo>
