<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x53948" Name="Policies" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Policies</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Policies</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<h3>Dance - Studio Area Dress Codes</h3>
<hr />
<p><img alt="Ballet Class" height="376" src="Images/dance/Ballet Class.jpg" width="649" /></p>
<p>Students are required to understand and comply with the University dress code  as stated in the catalog for all activities on campus. The spirit of the <a href="Documents/dance/Spiritual%20Environment.pdf" title="BYUI Honor Code">Honor  Code</a> encourages neatness, cleanliness, and modesty. In your dance class you are  allowed to wear clothes that facilitate the movement required. Please wear  comfortable clothes that will not restrict movement and are not too bulky or  heavy. <strong>It is NOT</strong> <strong>permissible to wear classroom  dancewear outside of the dance area</strong>. It is also required for students  to have the appropriate footwear. Any questions regarding appropriate shoes  should be directed to the instructor.</p>
<p>For specifics regarding each dance class see below:</p>
<h4>Clogging</h4>
<p>If you wear shorts/capris they may range anywhere from below the knee to the  ankle in length. Clogging shoes are required.</p>
<h4>Contemporary/Jazz</h4>
<p><strong>Women:</strong> Proper and modest dance attire: tank, cap, or long  sleeved leotard, sports bra, and black dance pants that go below the knee. NO  soccer shirts. NO cut offs or shorts of any kind.</p>
<p><strong>Men:</strong> Proper and modest dance attire: tight t-shirt,  compression shorts, and black dance pants that go below the knee. NO soccer  shirts. NO cut offs or shorts of any kind.</p>
<h4>Ballroom</h4>
<p>Women will wear a skirt or dress pants. Men will wear dress pants or Latin  pants. Ballroom shoes are required.</p>
<h4>Ballet</h4>
<p><strong>Women:</strong> Pink canvas - split sole ballet shoes, round neck  short sleeved or tank leotard in black, pink tights with the opening for footed  and or footless wearing. Ladies must carefully consider their support bras so  that the best possible line can be presented for esthetic concerns during  classes.  Dancers may cover up with any manner of sweatpants and tops or jazz  pants and or knitwear legwarmers and sweater tops in any color of choice.  We  just need to be down to the leotard and tights layer so as to properly see the  architecture of ballet as you perfect your practice.</p>
<p><strong>Men:</strong> White canvas - split sole ballet shoes,  white tee  shirt worn out ok, black mens tights, black men's dance belt. The dance belt  will provide you with proper carriage and esthetic body lines while in class and  on stage.  Your basketball athletic supporter is not firm enough and not does it  give you handsome body lines.  Dancers may cover up with any manner of  sweatpants and tops or jazz pants and or knitwear legwarmers and sweater tops in  any color of choice.  We just need to be down to the leotard and tights layer so  as to properly see the architecture of ballet as you perfect your practice.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x8168" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
