<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x53936" Name="Degrees" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Degrees</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Degrees</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<div id="content" style="z-index: 1; position: relative; padding: 10px 25px 25px; margin: 0px; width: 530px; top: -10px; left: -10px;">
<h1>Dance - Major, Minor, &amp; Cluster</h1>
<hr />
<p><img alt="Couple Swing Dancing" height="389" src="Images/dance/101116_DanceAlliance050.jpg" width="648" /><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">The Department of Theatre and Dance has a first-year open enrollment policy for all students to attempt the Dance BA degree. Students may initially declare a dance major at the time of application to the University. However <span style="text-decoration: underline;">all</span> declared dance majors whether new, continuing, or transfer students are considered as "Prospective Dance Majors" until they are formally accepted by the Department into the Dance BA program.<span style="color: #ff0000;"> Formal acceptance will be made <span style="text-decoration: underline;">after</span> the successful completion of a proficiency audition.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;"><span style="color: #ff0000;">Students are encouraged to audition during their Freshman year, preferrably during their first semester. (Note: This is a change in policy as of Winter 2012 Semester.) </span><br /></span></p>
<ul></ul>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Written applications should be submitted no later than one week prior to auditions. Both the number of sections and available faculty assignments and resources limit the number of majors accepted annually. Students will be notified of their status a few weeks after the audition. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Students who have declared themselves majors but have not auditioned and&nbsp; been accepted will need to change their major to something other than Dance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Students who have not completed the change of major by the first day of the next semester will have their major changed automatically to General Studies (399). Only those students accepted as Dance Majors may enroll in many upper level dance classes that require major status for registration. Students who are not accepted for a Dance Major may use the accomplished classes toward requirements for a Dance Minor or Cluster.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Each semester all students enrolled in the dance major must complete a jury examination to determine the final grade and advancement within the degree. The juried performance consists of a demonstration of modern/contemporary dance technique acquired in class. Students must successfully pass all juries as required in order to advance. In addition to technical movement and achievement, advancement is also dependent on department involvement and demonstrated personal responsibility.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">The following rubrics will be used for the juries:</span></p>
<p><a href="Documents/theatre-dance/Dance/Major Rubric 1st year(0).pdf"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">First Year Rubric</span></a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/theatre-dance/Dance/Major Rubric 2nd 3rd year(0).pdf"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Second/Third Year Rubric</span></a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/theatre-dance/Dance/Major Rubric 3rd 4th year(0).pdf"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Third/Fourth Year Rubric</span></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">&nbsp;</span>Effective Fall Semester 2012:</h3>
<p>Dance Majors will be required to maintain an Academic Portfolio. This portfolio will be kept in a file in the Dance Office and be given to you, the Dance Major, when you graduate. You will begin compiling items for your portfolio based on where you currently are in your academic course of study. For example, if you are a senior, you will only be required to include items from your senior year. On the other hand, incoming freshmen will begin compiling the items for their portfolio when they audition for and are accepted as a Dance Major.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Porfolios will include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jury reviews from your Technique Classes. (Rubrics that will be used are posted above.) You should be enrolled in a Technique Class (DA 240, DA 340, DA 440 or DA 443) every semester you are a Dance Major. Dance Majors will be required to perform a solo and participate in an interview. Students in DA 240 will need to prepare a 60 second solo, DA 340 students will need to prepare a 90 second solo, and DA 440 and DA 443 students will be required to prepare a 3 minute solo.</li>
<li>Concert reviews. You will be required to attend all Dance Concerts in semesters you are enrolled. Suggested Concert Synopsis Questions are posted at byui.edu/dance/resources.</li>
<li>Philosophy and Research Papers. This includes papers from DA 350, DA 356, DA 402, DA 442, DA 495 and DA 496. It also includes your Capstone proposal and review.</li>
<li>Choreography/Performance Reviews from your peers and choreographers. The Choreographer Review Rubric is posted at byui.edu/dance/resources. We hope this will give you feedback and inspire more responsibility.</li>
<li>Dance Community Student Participation Reviews. This includes your participation in Dance Alliance, Collegiate Dancers, Choreography Showcase, Senior Capstone numbers, etc. A Student Participation Rubrid is posted at byui.edu/dance/resources. We want you to be out, involved and working. This is part of becoming an artist.</li>
</ul>
The Dance Faculty feel that the Juries and Academic Portfolio will provide a better way to track your progression, help you focus more on the process, and get the most from your experience as a Dance Major.</div>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<h3><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Audition Information</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Winter Semester Dance Major Proficiency Auditions will be held <strong>May 11, 2013.</strong> An information meeting for all interested in auditioning will be May 2, 2013, at 2:00 p.m. in the MC Little Theatre (MC 372).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">For additional information and an audition schedule, click<a href="Documents/dance/Audition%20for%20Dance%20Major.pdf"> </a><a href="Documents/dance/Audition for Dance Major(0).pdf">here</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Before auditioning, you <strong>must</strong> fill out and submit a <a href="Documents/dance/Dance Major Audition Application(3).pdf">Dance Major Application</a> <strong>one week prior to the audition date. The deadline for submitting applications this semester is Monday, May 6, 2013 at 9:00 a.m. </strong>Please submit applications to Kathy Whitworth, the Dance Faculty Office Assistant.<strong><br /></strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">The following Rubric will be used for the Major Auditions:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="Documents/theatre-dance/Dance/Major Rubric Audition(0).pdf">Dance Major Audition Rubric</a><strong><br /></strong></span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Scholarship Information</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;"><strong>Dance Scholarships are available to students who have auditioned and been accepted as Dance Majors and are taking at least 14 credits.</strong> Interested students, who meet this criteria,&nbsp; may turn in the <a href="Documents/dance/dance scholarship application(0).pdf">scholarship application</a> to the Dance Office at MC 214 before each semester's deadline.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<table border="0" style="width: 465px; height: 118px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="background-color: #eaeaea;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Semester</span></td>
<td style="background-color: #eaeaea;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Deadline</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;"> </span>Winter 2013</td>
<td><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;"> </span>23 October 2012</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Spring 2013<br /></span></td>
<td><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">19 February 2013<br /></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Fall 2013<br /></span></td>
<td><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">4 June 2013<br /></span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br />
<h3><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">Minor &amp; Cluster</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; color: #333333;">For additional information reguarding the Dance Major, Minor, or Cluster please see <a href="Documents/dance/DanceCatalog.pdf">the catalog</a>.</span></p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x8168" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
