<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x54074" Name="Creative Writing" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Creative Writing</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Creative Writing</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Creative Writing</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<strong>Creative Writing at Brigham Young University-Idaho</strong>
<p>The BYU-Idaho English department offers three creative writing courses-English 218, 318R, and 418R. (The "R" indicates that the course is repeatable for credit.) In these courses, students write poetry, fiction, and/or creative non-fiction. Occasionally, courses are offered in writing dramas, screenplays, and children's and young adult literature. Instruction in BYU-I creative writing courses typically focuses on literary writing and the reading of literary texts. Creative writing students are regularly expected to share their work in one-on-one conferences with teachers, as well as in classroom peer groups.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Courses</strong></p>
<p><em>English to 218: Introduction to Creative Writing</em> is an exploratory course in which students write in a variety of genres, such as poetry, fiction, and creative nonfiction.</p>
<p><em>English 318R: Advanced Creative Writing</em> is a genre-specific course. Each semester courses are offered in poetry, fiction, or creative nonfiction, as well as occasional courses in the writing of plays, screenplays, young adult lit., and children's lit.</p>
<p><em>English 418R: Creative Writing and Publishing</em> is a course in which students choose their genre and regularly workshop writings in peer groups. In addition, students in English 418 edit and publish <em>Outlet: The BYU-Idaho Student Literature and Art Journal</em>. In English 418, students learn about publishing creative writing as they become familiar with contemporary literary journals and publishers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>English Department Faculty Reading</strong></p>
<p>Each semester BYU-I English faculty participate in the Faculty Reading, an event in which they read their own original works to an audience of students, faculty, and the community. Through the Faculty Reading, students see their own teachers model the mantra that "writers write."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Student Writing Retreat</strong></p>
<p>Each semester, English majors apply to participate in the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/english/english-department-information/creative-writing/student-writing-retreat">Student Writing Retreat</a>, an off-campus writing workshop led by English Department faculty. Held in the shadows of the Teton Mountains, this retreat allows selected students to work alongside faculty in an intense three-day writing experience. Student expenses for the retreat are paid by the English Department.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong>Literary Readings</strong>
<p>Each semester the BYU-I English Department &nbsp;invites one or more published writers to the BYU-Idaho campus. Visiting writers give readings and attend classes to speak with students about writing and publishing. Past visiting writers have included Pulitzer Prize-winning poet Stephen Dunn, novelist Lynn Stegner, and BYU<a name="_GoBack"></a> poet Lance Larsen.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Value of Creative Writing</strong></p>
<p>Only a few writers make a living writing novels, poetry, essays, or plays. Most published novelists and poets have other jobs that pay the bills. Fortunately, creative writing courses offer rewards far more certain than the chancy promise of royalty checks. In creative writing courses, students explore and develop their creativity, improve their writing, enjoy the play of language, and learn a good deal about humanity. As with the development of any valuable skill, the benefits come from the balance of work and play, passion and discovery. Students who want to learn about language, literature, and life will find much to gain from the creative writing courses at BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Get Published Online</strong></p>
<strong><strong> </strong></strong>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<table border="0" style="width: 450px; height: 365px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Dear Idaho Writers:</p>
<p>Fiction Weekly seeks stories for its upcoming issues. Since launching in early July, Fiction Weekly has published one new and noteworthy story per week. Our contributors include established, emerging, and previously unpublished authors, and they've enabled us to provided our readers with a steady stream of high caliber stories. As we prepare for the new year, our hope is that you'll visit the site, subscribe, submit, and spread the word to your colleagues, students, friends, and fellow writers.</p>
<p>Best regards,</p>
<p>Jason Reynolds</p>
<p>Call for Submissions</p>
<p>Fiction Weekly is dedicated to offering readers the best in new fiction 52 times a year. At the same time, we offer writers the opportunity to have their work showcased on the site for one week and featured on the homepage for three months. Unlike other journals, we accept submissions via email, read year round, and respond to every submission within 30 days. For further information, please visit us online:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.fictionweekly.com/" target="_self">www.fictionweekly.com</a></p>
<p>When people ask what you've been reading, we want to be the answer.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x1905" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
