<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x54186" Name="Registration, Insurance, Medical Info" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Registration, Insurance, Medical Info</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Registration, Insurance, M</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Info</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><img height="234" src="Images/english/colossolhead.jpg" width="350" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Course Registration</strong></p>
<p>Experience has shown that students are more likely to benefit from a   tour if they pursue academic credit. Therefore, students must enroll in   at least one course.</p>
<p>Students may register for tour courses through its directors. During   winter semester, directors will issue add cards which students will   complete accordingly. The directors will then submit them to the   Registrar's Office. The base cost of the tour does not include tuition,   which is $110 per credit hour. A three-credit course, for example, is   $330. There is no fee in conjunction with the FA 100 requirement.   Tuition payments are handled by the Cashier's Office (124 Administration   Building, BYU-Idaho, Rexburg, ID 83460-4184).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><a name="Insurance" title="Insurance" target="_parent"></a> Insurance</strong></p>
<p>Because BYU-Idaho is not responsible for any illness, injury, loss,   theft, or damage that may occur on the tour, participants must have   their own insurance. Participants and/or their parents should carefully   consider the following:</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>1. Medical Insurance.</strong> Students enrolled in BYU-Idaho   courses already have medical insurance, * VIA EITHER THE BYU-IDAHO   STUDENT HEALTH INSURANCE PLAN OR ANOTHER PRIVATE INSURANCE plan. For an   $18 premium, students may extend the BYU-Idaho Student Health Insurance   Plan through the first summer term. In this case, Peggy Gibson   (208-294-1921), who handles student insurance arrangements at BYU-Idaho,   changes students' insurance program status from on-campus to   off-campus. Students are then covered under the BYU-Idaho Student Health   Insurance Plan while on the tour. Non-student participants and  students  not enrolled in the BYU-Idaho Student Health Insurance Plan  may, of  course, continue coverage under their existing policies.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>2. Flight Insurance (if applicable).</strong> Participants   enrolled as students have coverage under the University's blanket travel   insurance policy. Additionally, tour participants automatically  receive  air travel insurance from the travel agency--free of charge. In  any  case, participants may purchase flight insurance directly from the   airline company. Tour directors will purchase airline tickets in  January  or February. They will then notify participants as soon as  airline  tickets have been secured, after which participants (and/or  their  parents) may contact the airline company or a travel agent about   purchasing additional insurance. Insurance may also be purchased at the   airport at the time of departure. Costs vary, but flight insurance may   be purchased for about $12 for approximately $200,000 of coverage.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>3. Travel Insurance.</strong> Travel insurance can protect   travelers from such risks as trip delay, cancellation, and/or   interruption; baggage delay, loss, damage, and/or theft; emergency   medical and dental treatment; etc. Students may, for example, check with   their parents to see what options are available from their insurance   companies. Participants may also purchase additional travel insurance   from a private insurance company. Information concerning travel   insurance plans may be obtained from the directors of the individual   tours.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><a name="Medical Information" title="Medical Information" target="_parent"></a> Medical Information</strong></p>
<p>All participants (and, if under age 21, a parent or legal guardian)   must sign a liability waiver. No special immunizations are required for   these tours. However, participants should bring adequate quantities of   prescription medication and any other necessary medical items. Please   inform tour directors, in writing, of any potentially serious health   conditions--whether physical, mental, or emotional. Participants should   be in a sufficient state of health to engage fully in a rigorous travel   schedule. Because some activities are strenuous, tour directors  reserve  the right to screen applicants or limit activities based on  medical  considerations.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><a name="Standards of Conduct" title="Standards of Conduct" target="_parent"></a> Standards of Conduct</strong></p>
<p>BYU-IDAHO travel study programs do no discriminate on the basis of   race, creed, sex, or ethnic or national origin. Participants need not be   LDS; however, all participants are required to maintain the standards   of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. This includes the   BYU-IDAHO Code of Honor, implying high standards of honor, integrity,   morality, graciousness and the application of Christian ideals.   Abstinence from alcohol, tobacco, tea, coffee, and illegal drugs is   required. The University's dress and grooming standards will also be in   effect during the tour. Standards are detailed in both the BYU-IDAHO   student handbook and catalog. Students who violate BYU-IDAHO standards   may be sent home at their own expense. For safety and other reasons,   participants must also be cooperative in following all tour leader's   instructions.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><a name="Tour Cancellations" title="Tour Cancellations" target="_parent"></a> Tour Cancellations</strong></p>
<p>Note, there will be a fee for any cancellations; the remaining amount   of money that a student has paid may be refundable. Cancellations and   requests for refunds must be submitted in writing. Any additional   deposit money not already spent on the individual student at the time of   cancellation will also be refunded within 30 days. Every effort,   however, will be made to hold losses to a minimum for those who need to   withdraw.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x1905" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
