<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x54215" Name="Outcomes" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Outcomes</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Outcomes</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><a href="Documents/foundations/II. Outcomes.doc"><strong>PART II: POLICIES AND PROCEDURES</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/foundations/II. Outcomes.doc"><strong>OUTCOMES AND ASSESSMENT</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/foundations/II. Outcomes.doc"><strong>PART ONE: OUTCOMES</strong></a></p>
<p>All Foundations courses share common outcomes and practices. These outcomes are assessed both during the creation process of new courses and as a part of ongoing review of current courses. In addition, they should be assessed in surveys administered to the students at the time of matriculation and again at graduation.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p>Having a defined set of academic and learning outcomes is vital for every academic institution.  They guide our efforts in providing the best educational opportunity possible.  They also are a vital tool in measuring our progress and success in providing that education.  As they are measured they provide evidence to outside agencies that outcomes have been identified and focus is given to achieving those outcomes.  All Foundations courses define and assess outcomes at five levels: 1) Institutional; 2) Academic; 3) Foundations; 4) Area (Eternal Truths, Academic Fundamentals, Science, Cultural Awareness, and Connections); and 5) Course.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Outcomes are defined in a hierarchy; outcomes at the institutional level define its purpose and mission.  Academic outcomes support the institutional objectives.  Foundations, Area, and Course Objectives each, in turn, support academic goals.  This concept is illustrated in the graphic below:</p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><strong><img height="461" src="Images/foundations/hierarchy.png" width="804" /></strong></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<strong><br clear="all" /> </strong>
<p><strong>BYU-Idaho Institutional Outcomes</strong></p>
<p>Intended outcomes for BYU-Idaho students are defined in the university's mission statement:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Build testimonies of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ and      encourage living its principles</li>
<li>Provide a quality education for students of diverse interests and      abilities</li>
<li>Prepare students for lifelong learning, for employment, and for      their roles as citizens and parents</li>
<li>Maintain a wholesome academic, cultural, social, and spiritual      environment</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Student Development Outcomes</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>To Know - </strong>Learning Deeply and Broadly</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Learn how to learn.</li>
<li>Learn deeply and broadly in      Foundations.</li>
<li>Cultivate focused learning      in a major.</li>
<li>Seek opportunities to apply      and expand your learning.</li>
<li>Elevate your learning from      remembering information to understanding principles; apply your      understanding by acting for righteous purposes in real-world settings.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>To Do - </strong>Developing Core Academic Skills</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Practice reading to extract      and make meaning from written language.</li>
<li>Improve your ability to      express ideas in appropriate styles of speech</li>
</ul>
<p>·         and writing.</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Sharpen your ability to use      quantitative skills to analyze arguments and</li>
<li>make decisions.</li>
<li>Train yourself to act in      ways that contribute to team success.</li>
<li>Learn to create, locate,      and evaluate information.</li>
<li>Think critically, make wise      decisions, and solve problems creatively.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>To Become - </strong>Becoming a Disciple-Leader</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Seek faith in and a      testimony of Jesus Christ and His restored gospel.</li>
<li>Cultivate personal peace      through obedience and honor.</li>
<li>Develop the capacity to      influence others for good.</li>
<li>Heighten your learning and      teaching skills.</li>
<li>Refine your power to      innovate and improve.</li>
<li>As your learning and skills      increase your capacity as a disciple-leader, act in faith to apply for      righteous purposes the lessons you learn at BYU-Idaho.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Foundations Outcomes</strong></p>
<p>Student outcomes for the Foundations program are as follows:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Each student will engage      in a variety of theories, perspectives and viewpoints relevant to the      subject matter.</li>
<li>Each student will      encounter, absorb, process, formulate, use, share and lead others through      skills and information central to the course of study, thereby      experiencing multiple levels of engagement.</li>
<li>Each student will apply      foundational principles of learning and develop key academic skills in      communication (both oral and written), analytical/problem solving,      teamwork/interpersonal, quantitative reasoning, and technology.</li>
<li>Each student will connect      with a field of study, and develop the passions and practices of lifelong      learning.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Faculty outcomes for the Foundations program are as follows:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Faculty will study and implement the principles      and processes of the BYU-Idaho Learning Model.</li>
<li>Faculty will have the opportunity of working with      colleagues across disciplines, colleges, and departments.</li>
<li>Faculty will create significant learning and      teaching experiences by working in teaching teams and participating in a      culture of classroom observation.</li>
<li>Faculty will have significant opportunities for      personal and professional development as a result of the      cross-disciplinary nature of Foundations.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>All Foundations courses share the following common practices:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>In contrast to      more traditional survey courses, BYU-Idaho's Foundations courses will      provide a more focused approach, allowing students to investigate and      engage deeper into detailed aspects of the subject matter.</li>
<li>All courses are      cross disciplinary.</li>
<li>All courses are      designed to fully implement the BYU-Idaho Learning Model.</li>
<li>All courses are      taught by teams who collaborate in the development and delivery of course      material. </li>
<li>All sections of      a course share a common syllabus, outcomes, and assessment measures. </li>
<li>Teaching teams      meet often to discuss curriculum and teaching techniques.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Area Outcomes</strong></p>
<p>Students take courses from five Foundations Areas: Eternal Truths; Academic Fundamentals; Science; Cultural Awareness; and Connections, the capstone course. Following are outcomes for each Area:</p>
<p><em>Eternal Truths</em></p>
<p>·         Students' testimonies will deepen and strengthen as they learn to rely on the scriptures as the primary source of gospel instruction.</p>
<p>·         Acting, rather than being acted upon, students will apply gospel principles in their lives, "at all times, and in all places."</p>
<p>·         Students will demonstrate greater personal integrity and obedience, living moral and ethical lives as disciples of Jesus Christ.</p>
<p><em>Academic Fundamentals</em></p>
<p>·         Students will develop the vital skills of critical reading, thinking, and analysis, and verbal and written communications, through fundamental and advanced course work.</p>
<p>·         Students will develop mathematical competency and understanding of collegiate-level expressions and equations, demonstrating the ability to apply mathematical concepts and logic.</p>
<p><em>Science</em></p>
<p>·         Students will understand science in both general and specific contexts, learning to appreciate, understand, and evaluate a variety of scientific points of view.</p>
<p>·         Students will learn methods of studying and comprehending the scientific aspects of current events and their consequences.</p>
<p>·         Building on introductory instruction, students will develop in-depth knowledge of challenging contemporary scientific issues.</p>
<p><em>Cultural Awareness</em></p>
<p>·         Students will develop an understanding of the history and founding principles of the American experience, including constitutional, economic, and political issues.</p>
<p>·         Students will demonstrate an awareness, understanding, and appreciation of world civilizations and their religion, art, literature, music, culture, and perspectives.</p>
<p>·         Students will deepen their understanding of the human condition and develop greater empathy for their fellowman.<em> </em></p>
<p>·         Students will study current events, developing a comprehension of their significance in the context of history and humanity.</p>
<p><em>Connections</em></p>
<p>·         In this capstone experience, students will further develop the skills of critical thinking and problem solving.</p>
<p>·         Students will learn how to develop personal positions and make judgments on challenging moral and ethical issues, giving expression to those positions in both verbal and written form.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Individual Foundations courses should have common outcomes, syllabi, and assessment practices. They also should fulfill Area, Foundations, Academic, and Institutional outcomes. Some courses will be taken by all BYU-Idaho students, while others will be chosen according to personal preference and interest.  Some courses are designed to be permanent fixtures of the academic program at BYU-Idaho. Others will be offered for three to five years and then phased out as other topics courses are developed. Courses in the latter category include Humanities, Science, and International Foundations. See the BYU-Idaho course catalog for more information about specific courses.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Course Outcomes</strong></p>
<p>Courses that have multiple options to fill a single requirement, such as Humanities, International, and 200-level Science Foundations) have common course-level outcomes.</p>
<p><em>Science</em></p>
<p>·         Students will demonstrate knowledge of subject-specific scientific principles.</p>
<p>·         Students will be able to understand and evaluate a variety of scientific points of view from both the physical and life sciences.</p>
<p>·         Students will be able to test scientific hypotheses by collecting, analyzing, and interpreting data.</p>
<p>·         Students will be able to scrutinize current science news and discoveries through the application of critical scientific thinking.</p>
<p><em>FDCA 101</em></p>
<p>·         Students will be able to describe a variety of styles, forms, and genres in the arts and letters, placing various artworks in cultural and historical context.</p>
<p>·         Students will attend live performances, shows, and readings.</p>
<p>·         Students will use basic cognitive tools to make value assessments about quality in the arts.</p>
<p>·         Students will cultivate and train the affective side of their nature, study works with deep emotional and intellectual content, and have detailed, intimate experiences with a few major works.</p>
<p>·         Students will explore intellectually the ideas expressed in an artwork, and articulate an affective reaction to it in informed cognitive terms.</p>
<p>·         Students will engage in the creative process or interpretive performance.</p>
<p>·         Students will make connections-with other art works, with Gospel principles, with life events, and with other intellectual endeavors.</p>
<p><em>FDCA 20X</em></p>
<p>·         Students will increase their awareness of time, place, people, and culture, especially outside Western civilization.</p>
<p>·         Students will personalize the current lives of individuals in a place or places defined by the course.</p>
<p>·         Students will analyze institutional, cultural, and personal bias.</p>
<p>·         Students will demonstrate the ability to contextualize current problems (i.e. political, historical, cultural).</p>
<p>·         Students will read complex texts, write informed and well-constructed prose, and think critically about complex topics.</p>
<p>·         Students will formulate and defend conclusions and opinions orally and in writing.</p>
<p>·         Students will explain how the course has changed their thinking.</p>
<p>·         Students will deepen their ability to reflect on their learning and practice and demonstrate progress towards gaining greater competence as a learner.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17649" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
