<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x54370" Name="Health Science Internship Information" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Health Science Internship Information</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Health Science Internship Information</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>What is an Internship?</strong>
<p>The purpose of an internship is to obtain practical and valuable work experience that will enable you to be better prepared to get a job after graduation or see what workers do in that industry.</p>
<strong>Health Science Internship Requirements</strong>
<p>1. Should be directly related to any area of Health Science<br />2. Must last at least 10 weeks<br />3. Must be at least 10 hours a week<br />4. Internships at Madison Memorial require 20 hours a week. <br /><em>(We recommend that the student get as many hours as possible in order to receive the maximum experience. Some students have 500 internship hours. Many companies require 40 hours a week for an internship.)</em></p>
<strong>Health Science Internship Credits</strong>
<p>1. Students may choose between one (1) to three (3) credits for their internship.<br />2. 100 hours is required for each credit. <br /><em>(If you only desire one (1) credit, you can work as many hours as you want above 100 and still just count it as one (1) credit.)</em></p>
<strong>When Should You Do Your Internship?</strong>
<p>1. The internship should be done during your junior or senior years. <br />2. We recommend that you do your internship during your off track so that you have more time available to concentrate on getting experience in your field. However, there are exceptions for students that do their internships during their on tracks.</p>
<strong>How Do You Get Started?</strong>
<p>Although we wish we had a magical list of available internships, we do not. It is the student's responsibility to line up his or her own internship experiences.</p>
<p>Before you start looking for an internship, think of what type of job or graduate school you want to do after you graduate. Search the community for an opportunity in that area. There are a lot of internships available in the Rexburg area; we recommend that you look in other communities such as where you call home (if not Rexburg) or where you might want to live after graduation.</p>
<p>Look for companies or governmental agencies that specialize in the field that interests you. You can contact them directly or sometimes they already have an internship program set up in which case you contact their director of internship. The Internship website has a list of previous internship providers and sometimes contact information. Career Navigator may even have a few available internship opportunities.</p>
<p>Networking is a great way to find an internship. Discuss your intership desires with family and friends. Many times they may know someone that could use an intern.</p>
<p>Applying for an internship is almost like applying for any other job - as long as the hiring manager knows you are applying for an internship rather than a job. You should plan on having a great resume'. Be prepared to be interviewed by the company.</p>
<p>Many companies have internship programs in place and have you apply for positions on their corporate website. When searching their job postings, be sure to include "internship" in your search criteria. When a company has a dedicated internship program, be careful that you don't miss deadlines!</p>
<p>Be sure that you do not apply for a full-time permanent position without disclosing that you are seeking a temporary internship position.</p>
<strong>After You Have Found An Internship</strong>
<p>1. Go to the Career Navigator on the Internship site 2. Fill out an "Initial Internship Approval" form and print out three (3) copies <br />3. Visit with your department coordinator and have them sign your form - Current coordinators are: Tyler Watson and Jim Hopla<br />4. Bring the signed form to the Internship Office to begin registration process <br />5. The Internship Office will inform you of any additional steps or documentation <br />6. Once the Internship Office approves the internship, they will register you in the class</p>
<p>Each Experience provider must sign a "Master Agreement." If they have hosted a BYU-I intern before, then they should have one on file. You may ask the Internship Office whether they have one or not. If they have not had a BYU-I student intern before or do not have a Master Agreement form on file, the Experience Provider must go to the Career Navigator to fill one out.</p>
<strong>Are There Any Other Requirements?</strong>
<p>Yes! Each department coordinator has developed a course syllabus for internships. You will always have some sort of academic requirement such as daily journal entries, a weekly check-in, monthly reports, etc. Part of your grade will depend on the assignments you complete. Contact your coordinator in order to get a syllabus.</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><!--071613 xpowercomponent_Optional to xPower--></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x1837" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
