<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x54333" Name="Major Information" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Major Information</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Major Information</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div style="font-family: Times New Roman;">
<p><strong>Health Science Emphasis in Public Health (750-39)</strong><br />The Public Health major includes a core set of health and related classes common for all students and three different emphasis areas to choose from: Public Health, Occupational Safety and Health and Community and Worksite Wellness. This major prepares students to work in the public health sector in promoting, protecting and preserving the health of a population and the government actions to accomplish these tasks. The program prepares students to take the Certiﬁed Health Education Specialist (CHES) examination offered through the National Committee on Health Education Credentialing, Inc.</p>
<p><strong>Health Science Community and Worksite Wellness Emphasis (750-101)</strong><br />This major prepares students theoretically and experimentally for health related career opportunities. These include community health educator, health promotion specialist, worksite wellness specialist, health counseling, wellness coaching, resort wellness, ﬁtness center, lifestyle training specialist, etc. This emphasis is also a great option for students interested in pursuing graduate programs in Physical Therapy and Occupational Therapy. Some students may also be eligible to take the CHES exam.</p>
<p><strong>Health Science Occupational Safety and Health Emphasis (750-102)</strong><br />Students are trained in the practice of anticipation, recognition, evaluation and control of safety and health hazards found in the work environment. They will be prepared to enter business, and industry as safety, industrial hygiene and environmental professionals. Students are also prepared for graduate programs in industrial hygiene and safety.</p>
<p><strong>Healthcare Administration (752) </strong><br />The Healthcare Administration major prepares students to directly enter the workforce as administrator/managers of healthcare facilities such as medical group practice, urgent care center, long-term care facilities, department-level positions in hospitals, ambulatory surgery centers, skilled nursing facilities, health insurance companies, etc. This degree is also a solid path for those seeking to pursue a master's degree in healthcare administration or business management. Program Director is <a href="x35561.xml">Dennis Tolman</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Medical Assisting Program (361)</strong><br />The Associate Degree of Applied Science in Medical Assisting prepares students to be employed in an ambulatory medical facility, i.e. a doctor's ofﬁce, outpatient clinic, or same-day surgical center. A Medical Assistant is cross-trained and multi-skilled to perform both administrative (front ofﬁ ce) and clinical (back ofﬁ ce and lab) procedures to support the physician/employer in providing excellent patient care. This program prepares students to take the National Certiﬁed Medical Assistant exam offered by the American Association of Medical Assistants (AAMA).<br /><br />To enter the program the student should ﬁrst complete BIO 264 with a C or higher and HS 280 with a B- or higher. The student should apply to the program by attending one of three orientation meetings. The entry courses are offered during all three semesters so students on every track can apply. At the end of the program (with all MA courses completed) the student will complete a 200 hour, unpaid externship at an ambulatory medical facility. The purpose is to practice and perfect the skills learned in class. The externship may be done off track and out-of-state upon approval of the school's Internship Ofﬁce and the Program Director, <a href="x35521.xml">Paula Criman</a></p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><!--071613 xpowercomponent_Optional to xPower--></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x1837" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
