<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.101 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x54310" Name="Internships" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">International Studies Internships</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">International Studies Internships</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p align="center"><strong>Internship Possibilities</strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;">The following list is meant to give you some idea of the types of possibilities that exist. Most students find internships that do not come from this list, but use this list as a starting point for possibilities. Once you have someidea of the type of internship you would like to pursue, see Bro. Jerry Hansen, Ricks 262T, for preliminary approval, as well as course requirements, and insurance requirements.</p>
<p>You can fulfill the internship requirement in one of two ways: International Studies 398R or International Studies 399R. To get credit for either 398R or 399R, students must fulfill course requirements.</p>
<p>International Studies 398R is a regular internship. You must work at list 210 hours during the semester. You can work abroad or in the states, but the internship must be internationally based. This means that, while it would be great to intern for a U.S. Senator, the internship would not work for your requirement, unless that Senator could guarantee that your assignment would mostly entail working on international issues. On the other hand, you could work in Rexburg, if the business you worked for used you, the vast majority of the time, in responsibilities associated with foreign countries. Some jobs that we do not accept are foreign language call center jobs or working with tourists at a resort, theme park, or as a bus driver.</p>
<p>International Studies 399R is the International Study Experience (ISE). The ISE includes the BYUI language study programs in China and Chile. It could also include the BYU Provo study abroad programs. BYU Provo programs which run for only seven weeks, can still be accepted if you live in country with a family native to that country (a French speaking family in Paris; a German speaking family in Vienna, etc.). Students can also select a foreign university to attend that does not have a formal agreement with BYUI, but must receive approval and acquire insurance through HTH Worldwide.&nbsp; Information on this insurance can be found at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/financial-services/risk-management/insurance/hth-international-medical-insurance">http://www.byui.edu/financial-services/risk-management/insurance/hth-international-medical-insurance</a>.</p>
<p><strong>General Help</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.goabroad.com/">www.goabroad.com/</a> </span></p>
<p>This site costs money if you use them to find an internship. But it is great site to get ideas on types of internships that are offered in different academic disciplines as found in different countries.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.culturalvistas.org/">http://www.culturalvistas.org/</a>&nbsp; General Internships both domestic and international in many fields. You would need to do some looking on this site. Go to Programs and you will find some really interesting international opportunities.</p>
<p><strong>Internships with NGO's, IGO's, or businesses</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.vesalius.edu/">www.vesalius.edu</a></p>
<p>Vesalius College, offers courses in many fields in English. There are French courses, home stays with French (or Dutch) speaking families, and internships in business, communication, and international studies. Vesalius has a list of internships that they will find for you, if you sign up for their internship course.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.hrwf.org/">www.hrwf.org</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Human Rights Without Frontiers. A Human Rights NGO. See Bro. Hansen if you are interested (typically you will need a 3.5 GPA and strong writing skills to apply for this internship).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.eias.org/">www.eias.org</a></p>
<p>European Institute for Asian Studies is a leading Think Tank based in Brussels and Luxembourg, the twin capitals of the European Union, focusing on EU-Asia relations.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.clscholarship.org/">www.clscholarship.org/</a> </span></p>
<p>Critical Language Scholarship: fully-funded summer language institutes for U.S. university students and is sponsored by the U.S. Department of State.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.iss.europa.eu/about-us/opportunities/detail/article/internships-period-january-july-2012/">http://www.iss.europa.eu/about-us/opportunities/detail/article/internships-period-january-july-2012/</a></p>
<p>European Union's think tank for strategic and security issues</p>
<p><a href="http://www.state.gov/vsfs/">http://www.state.gov/vsfs/</a></p>
<p>The Virtual Student Foreign Service projects may be research based, contributing to reports on issues such as human rights, economics or the environment. They may also be more technology oriented, such as working on web pages, or helping produce electronic journals. Selected students are expected to work virtually on an average of 5-10 hours per week on VSFS eInternship projects. Students apply in the summer and if selected, begin the eInternship that fall lasting through spring. Most work and projects are internet-based and some have language requirements.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.eurunion.org/eu/Delegation/Washington-Delegation-Internships.html">http://www.eurunion.org/eu/Delegation/Washington-Delegation-Internships.html</a></p>
<p>The Delegation of the European Union in Washington offers a unique opportunity for dynamic individuals to engage in the work of one of the EU's largest and most active diplomatic missions. By interning with the EU Delegation, students and recent graduates develop a comprehensive understanding of the transatlantic relationship.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cbyx.info/">http://www.cbyx.info/</a></p>
<p>The Congress-Bundestag Youth Exchange (CBYX) is a full-year work-study fellowship program which provides 75 young Americans with an understanding of everyday life, education, and professional training in Germany. The program begins in July and includes two months of intensive German language training&nbsp;(no prior German language knowledge required), four months of classroom instruction at a German university or college of applied sciences, and a five-month internship in each participant's career field. Expenses paid: Full-year scholarship including round-trip transatlantic flight, university tuition, language training, living stipend, and program-related travel costs in Germany; Two-months German language training in Germany; Four months of study at a German university or university of applied sciences; Five-month internship in a German-speaking work environment; Accommodation in a German home or student residence; Orientation, midyear, and final evaluation seminars; In-country support throughout the program; Health and accident insurance. Candidates for CBYX must meet the following eligibility requirements: U.S. citizen or permanent resident; 18-24 years old at the beginning of the program; Minimum of high school diploma or equivalent; Completed general coursework in target internship field at a community college, college, or university; Completed some relevant work experience (short-term, volunteer, or internship) in target internship field; Previous knowledge of the German language is preferred, but is not required; Ideal candidates have clear career goals, good communication skills, and exhibit flexibility and diplomacy</p>
<p><a href="http://www.europolitics.info/">http://www.europolitics.info/</a></p>
<p>A well-respected daily paper centered on the events, policies, and activities of the EU. Interns here would be doing journalism. A Communications student with European expertise would work well here, but a Political Scientist or International Studies major cold also benefit from the experience. Students would do the work that the journalists did not have time to do. They might be asked to keep their own dossier on a certain topic. They would take notes at conferences and press conferences. They would call sources such as industries in order to get reactions and confirm sources. They may write a few articles.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.becketfund.org/">http://www.becketfund.org/</a></p>
<p>The Becket Fund for Religious Liberty is a non-profit, public-interest law firm dedicated to protecting the free expression of all religious traditions. The Becket Fund has a 17-year history of defending religious liberty for people of all faiths. Its attorneys are recognized as experts in the field of church-state law. The Becket Fund for Religious Liberty, 3000 K St. NW, Suite 220, Washington, D.C. 20007, Phone: 202.955.0095, Fax: 202.955.0090</p>
<p><a href="http://www.scottishrefugeecouncil.org.uk/">http://www.scottishrefugeecouncil.org.uk/</a></p>
<p>Scottish Refugee Council works with refugees and asylum seekers across Scotland from our Central Glasgow headquarters and satellite offices in Springburn and Edinburgh.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.iphronline.org/index.html">http://www.iphronline.org/index.html</a></p>
<p><strong>International Partnership for Human Rights (IPHR)</strong>&nbsp;is a Brussels-based non-profit non-governmental organization, which is committed to promoting human rights worldwide. It aims at empowering local civil society groups and assisting them in making their concerns heard at the international level. It also aims at advancing the rights of vulnerable groups, such as women, children, migrants and minorities.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.daad.org/">https://www.daad.org</a> &nbsp;</p>
<p>The Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst (DAAD) is a private, publicly funded, self-governing organization of higher education institutions in Germany. DAAD promotes international academic relations and cooperation by offering mobility programs primarily for students and faculty, but also for administrators and others in the higher education realm. German Academic Exchange Service, 871 United Nations Plaza, New York, New York 10017, 212-758-3223 Fax: 212-755-5780</p>
<p><a href="https://app.e2ma.net/app/view:CampaignPublic/id:30540.12973295968/rid:647b264a7fcf49d363ecdae007833af5">https://app.e2ma.net/app/view:CampaignPublic/id:30540.12973295968/rid:647b264a7fcf49d363ecdae007833af5</a></p>
<p>The National Council on U.S.-Arab Relations' Washington, DC Summer Internship Program offers undergraduate and graduate students a ten-week professional, academic, and career opportunity internship in the nation's capital. The program features a demanding mix of professional involvement, intellectual challenge, career exploration, and cultural encounters designed to provide interns with a rich and varied experience during their time in Washington. <em>Professional workplace experience:</em> Interns are placed with one of over a dozen Near East and Arab world-related organizations in Washington, D.C., where they are expected to work 35-40 hours/week under the direct supervision of their host organizations.</p>
<p>American Presence Post is a very small diplomatic facility of the United States government located abroad. It is usually staffed by a single Foreign Service Officer who carries the title of Consul. They accept interns. There are currently posts in Medan, Indonesia; Busan, South Korea; and the following cities in France: Bordeaux, Lille, Lyon, Rennes, and Toulouse. The easiest way to find information is to google "American Presence Post."</p>
<p><strong>Teaching English</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.frenchculture.org/">www.frenchculture.org</a><a href="http://www.frenchculture.org/">/</a></span></p>
<p>On website look under education, then higher education. The French government will pay students ($1000/month) to teach English for a 7 month period. You must have taken up to at least French 201, or have ability equivalent to that level.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.chinahorizons.org/">www.chinahorizons.org</a></p>
<p>Teach English in China. Cost including airfare is about $1000.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ilp.org/">www.ilp.org</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Teach English in Russia, China, Mexico, Ukraine, or Thailand.</p>
<p><strong>Humanitarian</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.help-international.org/">www.help-international.org/</a> </span></p>
<p>Humanitarian</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.eliabroad.org/">www.eliabroad.org/</a> </span></p>
<p>Humanitarian, also includes Study Abroad possibilities.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.orphanagesupport.org/">http://www.orphanagesupport.org/</a></p>
<p>Orphanage Support Services Organization (OSSO) is a nonprofit charitable organization that provides volunteer opportunities to serve in orphanages in Ecuador in over 10 orphanages</p>
<p><a href="http://www.casa-nica.com/">http://www.casa-nica.com/</a></p>
<p>Casa-Nica is a NGO located in Masaya, Nicaragua, known as the "cultural basin" of Nicaragua that works with the Nicaraguan people in a diverse array of project fields such as education, agriculture, sustainability, technology, and animal care.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.selfreliantagriculture.org/">www.selfreliantagriculture.org/</a></p>
<p><em>The Institute for Self-Reliant Agriculture</em> (SRA) is a continuation of the small-scale agriculture model which was created and demonstrated in many developing nations over the past several decades, by the Ezra Taft Benson Agriculture and Food Institute at Brigham Young University. SRA is currently implementing the small-scale agricultural model in Ibarra, Ecuador and Piura, Peru. SRA has invitations from the governments of Bolivia, Congo, Uganda, Kenya, Guatemala, and Ghana for future projects as funds become more available.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ucdv.org/">www.ucdv.org</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Organization:&nbsp; Union of Community Development Volunteers (UCDV)</p>
<p>In-situ Program Director and Contact: Mutebi Eddie, Mailing Address: P.O. Box 35792 Kampala, Uganda. Physical Address: Block 26, Plot 842, Professor Apolo Nsibambi Road, Kampala, Uganda</p>
<p>Brief: The Union of Community Development Volunteers-Uganda (UCDV) is a perfect fit for BYU-Idaho students seeking international experience and internship opportunities in fields of education, public health, international studies, nursing, and many others.&nbsp; UCDV has been in operation since 2004 and has partnered with the LDS church since 2006.&nbsp; The organization's priorities are in clean water projects and sanitation, with secondary portions of work going to tree planting in urban areas in an effort to improve air quality; and HIV/AIDS awareness.&nbsp; Water/sanitation in both physical projects (wells, latrines) and sanitation/hygiene education comprise 60% of the work.&nbsp; The remaining portion is tree replanting, teaching vocational life skills, and HIV/AIDS awareness programs. The office is located in Mengo, a nice part of Kampala, just a few blocks from the LDS branch.&nbsp; LDS Humanitarian Missionaries have been closely involved in UCDV projects since 2006.&nbsp; Program Director Mutebi Eddie is an active member of the church and attends Mengo Branch.&nbsp; Living conditions:&nbsp; Kampala is a teeming metropolis of three million with a rapidly growing LDS community.&nbsp; Safe living conditions are readily available.&nbsp; Interns could live in any part of the city, but should look for American standards living conditions and should expect to pay $200 per person/ per month for safe and comfortable furnished housing not including the cost of food.&nbsp; Airfare from Salt Lake City to Entebbe, Uganda ranges from $1600 to $2000 depending on season. <a href="mailto:info@ucdv.org">info@ucdv.org</a>&nbsp; <a href="mailto:ucdvolunteersug@gmail.com">ucdvolunteersug@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.crossculturalsolutions.org/">http://www.crossculturalsolutions.org</a></p>
<p>Cross-Cultural Solutions is a nonprofit working to address critical global issues by providing meaningful and sustainable volunteer services to international communities, and contributing responsibly to local economies.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/">http://www.volunteerhq.org/</a></p>
<p>International Volunteer HQ (IVHQ) provides safe, quality and extremely affordable volunteering programs abroad in developing countries all over the world. Each year we place over 4000 people into our programs abroad and have a wide range of volunteer travel opportunities in <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#kenya">Kenya</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#kenya-maasai">Kenya - Maasai</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#tanzania">Tanzania</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#ghana">Ghana</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#uganda">Uganda</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#southafrica">South Africa</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#india">India</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#nepal">Nepal,</a> <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#vietnam">Vietnam</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#cambodia">Cambodia</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#guatemala">Guatemala</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#ecuador">Ecuador</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#costarica">Costa Rica</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#thailand">Thailand</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#china">China</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#brazil">Brazil</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#colombia">Colombia</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#perucusco">Peru - Cusco</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#peru">Peru - Lima</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#morocco">Morocco</a>, <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#srilanka">Sri Lanka</a> and <a href="http://www.volunteerhq.org/programs.html#mexico">Mexico</a>.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>International Study Experiences </strong></p>
<p>For China or Chile see the BYUI language department in the Smith Building.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.isep.org/students/Programs/isep_exchange.asp">http://www.isep.org/students/Programs/isep_exchange.asp</a></p>
<p>A site that arranges student exchanges.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gotoeurope.org/">www.gotoeurope.org</a></p>
<p>Participants will spend the semester visiting over 10 countries throughout Europe, while studying history and Russian at&nbsp;National Technical University of Ukraine and working as inerns and volunteers in&nbsp; Kiev, the capital of Ukraine.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1904" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
