<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x54408" Name="Physical Therapist Assistant" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physical Therapist Assistant</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physical Therapy Assistant</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">THE BYU-IDAHO PHYSICAL THERAPIST ASSISTANT PROGRAM IS CURRENTLY BEING DEVELOPED&nbsp;</h1>
<p><strong><br />**These web pages are being posted to help our student body understand our future plans and process for delivering the PTA program and admitting students. Plans and policy may change, especially in the early stages of this development, so please check back often or contact us to become aware of updates**.<br /><br /> <strong>Graduation from a physical therapist assistant education program accredited by the </strong><strong>Commission on Accreditation in Physical Therapy Education (CAPTE), 1111 North Fairfax </strong><strong>Street, Alexandria, VA&nbsp; 22314; phone; 703-706-3245; accreditation@apta.org is necessary </strong><strong>for eligibility to sit for the licensure examination, which is required in all states.</strong><br /><br /> <strong>Brigham Young University - Idaho is seeking accreditation of a new physical therapist assistant education program from CAPTE.&nbsp; The program will submit an Application for Candidacy, which is the&nbsp;formal application required in the pre-accreditation stage.&nbsp; Submission of this document does not&nbsp;assure that the program will be granted Candidate for Accreditation status.&nbsp; Achievement of&nbsp; Candidate for Accreditation status is required prior to implementation of the </strong><strong>professional/technical training phase of the program; therefore, no students may be enrolled in </strong><strong>professional/technical training courses until Candidate for Accreditation status has been achieved.&nbsp; Further, though achievement of Candidate for Accreditation status signifies satisfactory progress toward accreditation, it does not assure that the program will be granted accreditation. </strong><br /> <br />Therefore, it is <span style="text-decoration: underline;">VERY IMPORTANT</span> that students understand the following...&nbsp;<br /></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="background-color: yellow;">**Even though the faculty and administrators are committed to achieving the goal of full accreditation by the time our first class graduates, there is no guarantee that this will happen. &nbsp;It is possible that students could finish our PTA program training, but be unable to sit for the national licensure exam.**</span></strong> <br /><br /><strong>The BYU-Idaho PTA program is working towards the following milestones. &nbsp;<br /></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>It is expected that the BYUI-Idaho Physical Therapist Assistant program will achieve status as a formal "Candidate" for accreditation in the summer of 2013. &nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong>The program will accept applications for the first cohort of students until Fall Semester 2014. &nbsp;Deadlines and procedures for completing this application are posted under the menu item "<a href="x47836.xml">How to Apply</a>"&nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong>Students who apply and are accepted to the first cohort for this program are scheduled to begin formal training in Fall Semester 2014. &nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong><strong>The BYUI-Idaho PTA program will continue to work on accreditation requirements with the goal to achieve full accreditation by the end of Fall 2015. &nbsp;Assuming that all goes according to plan, students enrolled in the first cohort will be able to sit for the national licensure exam soon after graduating at the end of Fall Semester 2015.</strong></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong></strong><strong>In the event that the above milestones are not achieved as planned, students who complete PTA course work will still be able to count their PTA course credits towards a variety of bachelors degrees on campus. Advising for this option is available to students.<br /><br />Students take a risk when they apply for this first cohort, therefore, we encourage you to think carefully about your academic plans, goals and needs. &nbsp;Feel free to contact us. We can advise you and answer questions and concerns that you may have.&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1837" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
