<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x55097" Name="Family Celebrations Help Build Unity " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Family Celebrations Help Build Unity and Teach Values </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20061101T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Steve Dennis </Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Family Celebrations Help Build Unity and Teach Values</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Steve Dennis</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, November 2006)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Celebrations have always been a part of family and community life.   Although most of our celebrations and holidays have gradually changed  since their historical beginnings, their purpose has not.  As always,  the pageantry, ritual, and symbolism of celebrations help us to unite,  motivate, and educate.  For parents, this makes them ideal tools for  building family strengths and teaching children values.  Research  continues to find that families who celebrate together are healthier and  better able to meet the challenges of modern day living.  So what does  this mean for parents? Let's take a closer look.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong> Celebrations help us unite.</strong></em> Whether it's  the presentation of Olympic gold, a backyard birthday barbecue, or  handing out diplomas at a high school graduation, celebrations unite us.   They allow us to share in the success.  They bind us to our friends,  families, and communities.  As human beings we have a deep need to  belong or be a part of something larger than ourselves.  We come  together as couples, friends, classmates, colleagues, teams, communities  and families.  As members of these social groups, we adopt the rules  and values of the groups that promote cooperation and connect us  together.  Research has found that individuals and families who are not  well connected to their communities and one another are at greater risk  for depression, suicide, delinquency and criminal behavior.  On the  other hand, youth who feel a part of their communities are more likely  to abide by the community's laws and standards for behavior.  Similarly,  children who feel connected to their families are more likely to live  by the rules of the family.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Recently, a panel of family scholars gathered to discuss the strengths  and challenges of modern families.  One of the problems that was  identified was  widespread feelings of disconnectedness among many  American families.  They noted that the rapid pace and change of modern  life has left many stressed, depressed, and isolated.  Some experts have  suggested that traditions, rituals and celebrations are one key to  bringing continuity to our lives and connecting us to our past and  present.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong> Celebrations help us motivate</strong></em>.   Celebrations not only allow us to take pride in past achievements, but  they also rally confidence for the future. For example, celebrating the  promotion of a family member sends a message that the person is  deserving, worthy, and supported in his or her efforts-all of which  motivate the person to even greater achievements. Similarly, holidays  such as Thanksgiving or Independence Day can encourage us to be grateful  for our blessings or fight to maintain our freedoms.  It was during the  gloomy hours of World War II when England was at the brink of defeat,  that Sir Winston Churchhill rallied his countrymen by reminding them of  their strengths and by celebrating their accomplishments.  And nearly  sixty years later, England still celebrates Churchhill's rallying cry, <em>"We  shall fight on the beaches. We shall fight on the landing grounds. We  shall fight in the fields, and in the streets, we shall fight in the  hills.  We shall never surrender!"</em> Perhaps as parents, we should rally our families and move forward in united purpose.</p>
<p><br /> <em><strong> Celebrations help us educate.</strong></em> One of the  goals of our public education system is to develop citizenship and  patriotism in our youth.  How is it done?   It's done by sharing  patriotic stories, covering our hearts at flag ceremonies, reciting the  pledge of allegiance, and sharing the meaning behind symbols of freedom  such as the soaring eagle or the torch of Lady Liberty.  Yet, symbols  and ceremonies are nothing until they are enriched with meaning.  A flag  is only colorful fabric until one knows the stories behind it and the  values it represents.  Then it becomes a tool that helps us cherish and  pass on the memories and values of our forefathers.  Who isn't stirred  by our flag blowing in the wind when they recall the final words of  Sir  Patrick Henry,  <em>"Give me liberty or give me death!" </em>Or the  words of our anthem, the Star-Spangled Banner, as penned by Francis  Scott Key as he anxiously awaited dawn's early light so he could see if  the flag was still flying over Fort McHenry.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just as these National symbols and celebrations instill in us and in  future generations messages of courage, freedom and perseverance, so  too, family celebrations and rituals teach lessons of character and  values. Celebrating a marriage anniversary teaches children of love,  cooperation, and commitment.  It also remind us of the vows taken during  the wedding and inspires renewal.  In every celebration, there is a  lesson.  By enriching our holidays with stories, symbols and rituals and  looking for opportunities to celebrate the accomplishments of each  other, we can unite and inspire our families.<br /> <br /> <br /> Steve Dennis is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
