<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x55070" Name="Community" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Community</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Community</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x40450" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 20px;"><strong>The Afterschool Partnership</strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 20px;">&nbsp;The afterschool program will serve interested children and families in the comminity and&nbsp;will also serve as a practicum and internship placement site for Child Development majors at BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 20px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 20px;">Also many of the majors are designed to interact with the community. Some examples of this are:</p>
<p style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 20px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Professional Preschool Education Program (PPE)</strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>The BYU-Idaho Professional Preschool Education Program (PPE) leads to an Associate in Applied Science Degree. It offers students the opportunity for in-depth study and experience in teaching young children in the "R Children" preschool located on BYU-Idaho's campus. The "R Children" preschool is committed to providing a safe and nurturing environment while promoting the physical, social, emotional, and intellectual development of young children. The PPE degree is intended to be a "terminal degree" (one that provides professional preparation to enter the work-force). Students who seek to graduate in PPE should realize that the program is not intended to be transferrable to four-year colleges, or to be the foundation for a teaching certificate in early childhood education. The program is designed to help graduates become teachers in or directors of developmentally appropriate child care centers or preschools in home and commercial settings, or to be qualified teacher's aides in nursery schools, kindergartens, and special education/inclusion classes.<strong> </strong></p>
<p style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 20px;"><strong>Child Development Overview</strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>The Bachelor of Science Degree in Child Development offers an overview of scholarship and research in the study of children. The core courses in this degree are intended to focus on knowledge about children in their environments, such as home, school, and community. Emphasis is given to the application of scholarly knowledge with the goal of helping children and their families develop and thrive regardless of circumstances of birth or environment. Practicum and internships are built into the core curriculum to give practical knowledge and hands-on experience in working with children and families, as well as agencies that serve children and families.</p>
<p>Students pursuing this degree have many career options, but the degree is primarily designed for those who desire to work with children and their families in community or government agencies. Students should consult with their advisor about possible academic and career options such as: <br /> (1) A focus on agencies or organizations that serve young children and their families.<br /> (2) A focus on agencies or organizations that serve adolescents and their families.<br /> (3) A focus on a scholarly understanding of children and families.<br /> (4) Preparation for&nbsp;graduate study&nbsp;in the field of child development or early childhood education.</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1847" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
