<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x55049" Name="Degrees" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Degress Offered</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Degress</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Preschool Education (AAS)</strong></h2>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Professional Preschool Education Program (PPE) leads to an Associate in Applied Science Degree. It offers students the opportunity for in-depth study and experience in teaching young children in the "R Children" preschool located on BYU-Idaho's campus. The "R Children" preschool is committed to providing a safe and nurturing environment while promoting the physical, social, emotional, and intellectual development of young children. The PPE degree is intended to be a "terminal degree" (one that provides professional preparation to enter the work-force). Students who seek to graduate in PPE should realize that the program is not intended to be transferrable to four-year colleges, or to be the foundation for a teaching certificate in early childhood education. The program is well designed to help graduates become teachers in or directors of developmentally appropriate child care centers or preschools in home and commercial settings or to be qualified teacher's aides in nursery schools, kindergartens, and special education/inclusion classes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog/2011-2012/Home%20and%20Family.pdf"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Link to registration</span></a><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Family &amp; Consumer Sciences Education (BS) </strong></h2>
<p>The Degree of Family and Consumer Sciences Education is a composite major that provides a holistic approach to the study of home and family in preparation to teach. Upon graduation students are secondary education certified to teach FACS in the state of Idaho with an endorsement in Professional Technical education.&nbsp; Students can also work as home economists in business, or continue on to graduate studies to prepare for work as a cooperative extension agent.</p>
<p>Students participate in the BYU-Idaho Family and Consumer&nbsp;Association which highlights FCCLA, service, professional, and social development. A Family and Consumer Education major provides the opportunity to apply professional skills to home, family, church, and community as well as prepare for a career in education, extension, or business.</p>
<p><strong>Family and consumer sciences educators (students) will be able to:</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Engage in classroom activities, home experiences, extracurricular activities, and professional association events, simulated&nbsp;laboratory experiences - particularly in foods, child development, management, nutrition, home decor, clothing, and textiles.</li>
<li>Conduct field trips, obtain guest speakers, and assign individual projects.</li>
<li>Select and prepare learning aids for classroom use (i.e., textbooks, computer-aided instruction using media, and study guides).<strong> </strong></li>
<li>Ensure that learning activities from professional technical youth organizations are integrated into classroom instruction.</li>
<li>Prepare lesson plans and teaching activities based on state standards.</li>
<li>Advise students in academic and career goals.</li>
<li>Collaborate with teachers, parents, and community</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The program teaches courses designed to:</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li><strong>Teach</strong> doctrine, principles, theory, and skills to help maintain and strengthen the home as the most effective institution in society for impacting the well being of the family unit.</li>
<li><strong>Provide </strong>a well balanced education for students focusing on the importance of home and family. Classes include: family relations, money management, clothing construction and apparel, textiles, interior design, child development, foods and nutrition, home and family management, and with a secondary education component.</li>
<li><strong>Prepare</strong> students for careers in secondary education, graduate school, and professions relating to home and family education, children, and families.</li>
<li><strong>Strengthen</strong> students' testimonies in the gospel of Jesus Christ.</li>
</ul>
<ul></ul>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog/2011-2012/Home%20and%20Family.pdf"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Link to registration</span></a></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><strong>Child Development (BS)</strong></h2>
<p>The Bachelor of Science Degree in Child Development offers an overview of scholarship and research in the study of children. The core courses in this degree are intended to focus on knowledge about children in their environments, such as home, school, and community. Emphasis is given to the application of scholarly knowledge with the goal of helping children and their families to develop. Practicum and internships are built into the core curriculum to give practical knowledge and hands-on experience in working with children, families, and agencies that serve children and families.<br /> Students pursuing this degree have many career options, but the degree is primarily designed for those who desire to work with children and their families in community or government agencies. Students should consult with their advisor about possible academic and career options such as</p>
<ul>
<li>A focus on agencies or organizations that serve young children and their families.</li>
<li>A focus on agencies or organizations that serve adolescents and their families.</li>
<li>A focus on a scholarly understanding of children and families.</li>
<li>Preparation for <span style="text-decoration: underline;">graduate study</span> in the field of child development or early childhood education.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog/2011-2012/Home%20and%20Family.pdf"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Link to registration</span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Marriage and Family Studies (BS)</h2>
<p>The Bachelor of Science Degree in Marriage and Family Studies prepares students to understand the dynamics of healthy and strong families and to work in a wide range of human service professions, especially those servicing children and families. The major has a strong applied focus, with students completing a practicum where they develop and implement a family life education program and by completing an internship. The Department of Labor listed the job outlook within the social and human services as growing faster than average, however many of these jobs are entry-level positions. Those seeking a career within this discipline are advised to obtain at least a Master's degree.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog/2011-2012/Home%20and%20Family.pdf">Link to registration</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more info see the catalog</p>
<p><a class="extLink" href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/catalog/2012-2013/Home%20and%20Family.pdf" title="Home and Family catalog pdf">Home and Family Catalog PDF</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1847" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
