<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x55088" Name="Dad...Are You There?" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dad...Are You There?</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090108T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Owen Anderson</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Dad...Are You There?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Owen Anderson</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, June 2009)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The United States is one of the few countries in the world that has an  official day on which fathers are honored by their children. On the  third Sunday in June, fathers all across the United States are given  presents, treated to dinner or otherwise made to feel special. As we  celebrate Father's Day we should reflect upon a sad fact: It is becoming  common to meet young people who either do not know their dads, or who  have a minimal relationship with their fathers. Although most children  have come face-to-face with their father at some point; sadly, most have  little regular contact with the man, or have any faith that he loves or  cares about them. In fact, when fatherless young people write about  their lives, they tell heartbreaking stories about feeling like  "throw-away people." A regular theme of their stories is that they feel  safer in a foster care home or juvenile detention center than on the  outside, partly because they have no father to hold together the family.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When we begin to view the extent of the problem, the numbers are  alarming. The nation's out-of-wedlock (no father involvement likely)  birth rate is 38%, with the rate among poor teens almost three times as  high as the rate among those from non-poor families. Among Caucasian  children, 28% are now born to a single mother; among Hispanic children  it is 50%, and the rate reaches a frightening 71% for African American  children. Among the rest of America&rsquo;s children nearly a quarter of  Caucasian children (22%) do not have any adult male in their homes;  nearly a third (31%) of Hispanic children and over half of African  American children (56%) have no adult male figure in the home. Maybe  most important of all is that having a dad at home is almost a certain  pathway out of poverty; because about 40% of single-mother families are  in poverty. Taken together, this represents a dramatic shift in American  life. In the early 1960s, only 2.3% of white children and 24% of  African American children were born to a single mom.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A father&rsquo;s non-involvement in family life can be seen early. In  kindergarten, children living with single parents are more likely to  trail children with two parents when it comes to health, cognitive  skills, and their emotional maturity. Having a dad is an advantage&nbsp; and  is generally viewed as a passageway to middle-class status, which in  turn, increases the likelihood of getting a college education. The odds  increase for a child's success with the mental and financial stability  rooted in having two parents. Having two parents means there is a  greater likelihood that someone will read to a child as a preschooler,  support him through school, and prevent him from dropping out, as well  as teaching him how to compete, win and lose, and get up to try again,  in academics, athletics, and the arts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Most people can agree that having an involved father has obvious  benefits to children. In addition, we can probably agree that fathers  are important because they help to teach children values and lessons in  solving the problems they may face. Fathers also serve as role models in  their children's lives that affect how well they relate to peers and  adults outside the home. Before you say what about mothers?&rdquo;&mdash; tell  yourself that it's not a question of who is more important: mothers or  fathers. The point is that having both parents involved in rearing their  child has some obvious, and some maybe not-so-obvious, benefits for the  child, the family, and for father&rsquo;s themselves.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When we talk about the benefits of being an involved father, we most  often focus on the benefits that children receive from such a  relationship. Being an involved father means being actively involved in  nearly every aspect of your child's life, from play and responsibility  for childcare to making oneself available to his child on the child&rsquo;s  timetable. The benefits of having a father involved in raising his  children are pretty clear. For instance, did you know that research has  shown that children whose fathers are involved in rearing them score  higher on cognitive tests than those with relatively uninvolved fathers.  In fact, fathers who are involved in their children's schools and  academic achievement, regardless of their own educational level, are  increasing the chances their child will graduate from high school,  perhaps go to vocational school, or even to college. In addition, a  father's involvement in children's school activities protects at-risk  children from failing or dropping out; as a matter of fact, the research  shows that fathers who are more involved with their children tend to  raise children who experience more success in their career. Career  success can lead to greater income and greater financial stability. <br /> <br /> In the social arena, father involvement is related to lower rates of  teen violence, delinquency, and other problems with the law. On the  other hand, a father&rsquo;s involvement is associated with positive child  characteristics such as empathy, self-esteem, self-control,  psychological well-being, social competence, and life skills. Also,  children who grow up in homes with involved fathers are more likely to  take an active and positive role in raising their own families. It is  thought that having an involved father provides a role model for  positive parenting, healthy caregiving, and a commitment to the family. <br /> <br /> When fathers choose to be involved in family life, benefits come in the  form of loving and nurturing relationships among family members. Did you  know that involved fathering is related to better communication between  fathers and family members; a greater sense of commitment to the  family; and less troubling conflict with teenage children. Being  involved in caring, not only for the child, but for the family can bring  greater harmony and fewer arguments. The family tends to enjoy their  time together more. <br /> <br /> Finally, being an involved father brings benefits to dads themselves.  When fathers build strong relationships with their children and others  in the family, they receive support and caring in return. Research has  shown that healthy family relationships provide the strongest and most  important support network a person can have, whether that person is a  child or an adult. Being involved in their family members&rsquo; lives helps  fathers:&nbsp; to enjoy a secure attachment relationship with their children,  to cope well with stressful situations and everyday hassles, and to  feel as if they can depend on others more. Additionally, fathers  involved in family life feel more comfortable in their occupation and  feel that they can do their job well; they feel confident they have a  lot to offer others in terms of their job skills, parenting skills, and  social relationships. <br /> <br /> The benefits listed above are really only a few of the research findings  from studies of families with involved and uninvolved fathers. Many of  the benefits may seem obvious, or perhaps not. If you look at your own  involvement in your family, you might discover that you have been  enjoying some of the benefits without really noticing them. Generally,  being an involved parent requires hard work and setting priorities, but  it&rsquo;s worth it. <br /> <br /> Dads, as you celebrate Father's Day, proudly accept those pats on the  back and the high fives, but don't forget to pause and reflect on the  important work you are doing within the walls of your own home. You will  come to appreciate that the long term intellectual, social, and  emotional benefits for your children and you are profound. Now, can I  make a final request? Dads, at the end of this Father&rsquo;s Day and the end  of each day, stop and express thanks for the opportunity to be a father.  As you reflect on those things you have given to your family (including  time, energy, and talents) reflect also on the benefits you are getting  in return. Then, in appreciation, you will likely join with me in  saying, &ldquo;I love being a dad!&rdquo; <br /> <br /></p>
<p><br /> Owen Anderson is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
