<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x55163" Name="Semester in Chile" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Semester in Chile</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Semester in Chile</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Description</strong></h1>
<p>Located in beautiful Vi&ntilde;a del Mar, the Universidad de Vi&ntilde;a del Mar provides a great setting for a Spanish immersion experience for near-beginners and near-natives as well.&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">The BYU-Idaho Semester in Chile offers students a program of Spanish language and culture plus an opportunity to choose from Humanities, International Business, and International Studies courses that focus on Latin American issues and which are taught in English. &nbsp;These courses have been pre-approved for use in BYU-I degree programs.</span></p>
<p>Additional information can be found at the Universidad de Vi&ntilde;a del Mar's web site <a href="http://www.uvm.cl/dri/estudia.shtml" title="UVM" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h1><strong><strong>Dates</strong></strong></h1>
<p>August 2, 2013 to December 7,&nbsp; 2013</p>
<h1><strong><strong>Program Cost</strong></strong></h1>
<h2>Set Costs&nbsp;</h2>
<p>$1,785 BYU-Idaho tuition</p>
<p>$4,750 UVM program fees&nbsp;<br /><strong></strong></p>
<h2>Variable Costs&nbsp;</h2>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">$1,500 - $2,000 Airfare$160 Reciprocity tax (If you been in Chile in the past 10 years and if you have the receipt, you won't have to pay this.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">$500 Personal expenses</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">$100 Some of the activities scheduled by the Direcci&oacute;n de Relaciones Internaciones&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>Payment Schedule</h2>
<p>May 27, 5:00 PM - $300 (non-refundable)</p>
<p>June 17, 5:00 &nbsp;PM - $2,225</p>
<p>July 15, 5:00 &nbsp;PM&nbsp;- $2,225</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"><strong style="color: #056cb6; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 17.27pt; line-height: 1em;">Available Courses</strong>&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>UVM Spanish Program Courses</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Espa&ntilde;ol comunicacional y Cultura chilena</strong> = Spanish 201</li>
<li><strong>Estrategias comunicacionales: Gram&aacute;tica y composici&oacute;n</strong> = Spanish 321</li>
<li><strong>Ortofon&iacute;a</strong> = Spanish 325</li>
<li><strong>Temas Contempor&aacute;neos de Am&eacute;rica Latina</strong> = Spanish 350, Spanish 490R&nbsp;</li>
<li><strong>Literatura Latinoamericana</strong> = Spanish 451&nbsp;</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"><strong>Culturas en Contacto (Ingl&eacute;s-Espa&ntilde;ol)</strong> = Spanish 490</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"><strong>NEW - Chilean Socio-Political History in the 20th Century</strong>&nbsp;= Spanish 350, Spanish 490R<br />A course focused on the socio-political evolution of Chile, from the civil war to the military dictatorship, taking into account the great revolutions in Chile, as well as considering the Mexican and Cuban revolutions, two of the most important revolutions in Latin America, in order to understand how revolutionary ideas began to circulate in Chile in the early twentieth century and how these revolutions began with people from the humblest walks of life to become large social movements.</span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">NEW</strong><strong>&nbsp;- Socioeconomic Evolution of Latin America</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span>&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">= Spanish 350, Spanish 490R, International Studies 350&nbsp;This course will provide students with an explanation of how Latin America, over more than five hundred years ago, accidentally became a part of a complex historical project of European origin known as modernization. The class will analyze the fundamental misconceptions associated with the emancipation process of Latin America, as well as learn to recognize the cultural, social, and economic consequences of the conquest on the original peoples of Latin America. Tying in with what they learn from the first portion of the class, students will study what impacts the current economic growth of Chile, Colombia, and Brazil is having on their societies.</span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">NEW - Current Events in Latin America</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">= Spanish 350, Spanish 490R, International Studies 350 &nbsp;In this class, students will analyze Latin America's integration in the economic, political, linguistic, cultural, and religious plans, understanding that Latin America, along with Asia, before the economic fall of the First World, has great potential for growth and development in the coming decades.&nbsp; At the end of this course students will understand the importance of the&nbsp; "Bolivarian Dream" as a mythical story that spans the historical encounters and clashes among Latin American countries. Students will also be able to recognize and analyze the impact of the Cold War on the integration process of Latin America. Finally, students will learn about the main economic and political principals of Latin America (OEA, UNASUR, MERCOSUR, ALADI, ALBA-TCP, CAN among others).</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong><strong>UVM&nbsp;COURSES IN ENGLISH 2013</strong></strong></h2>
<p><strong>BUSINESS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strategies of International Marketing</strong>&nbsp;= BYU-I Business 380 &nbsp;Objectives:&nbsp;This course will help students develop the knowledge and skills to successfully understand and execute marketing strategies that are relevant to the current global market environment.&nbsp;Basic economic skills will be useful to the course, but not necessary. There will be a focus on group work, case studies and a final marketing project.</li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Negotiation Strategies in Latin America</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;= BYU-I Business 380, International Studies 350 &nbsp;Objectives:&nbsp;1. Understanding the general business context in Latin America.2. Understanding the communicational style in Latin America, and the application of it to the negotiation process.3. Understanding the process development, from basic individual psychology to crisis management.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">SOCIAL SCIENCES</span></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Indigenous People in Chile</strong>&nbsp; = Spanish 350, Spanish 490R &nbsp;The Mapuche are the largest indigenous people in Chile and particularly significant in terms of Chile's culture and identity. However, our indigenous roots have been systematically denied by the country's dominant elites since the inception of Chile as a Nation State. Furthermore, Chilean society at large has remained either oblivious, ignorant or distant of their indigenous ancestry, considering the Mapuche, and everything related to them, as something of the past or, at the best, marginal. In fact, since the emergence of the Chilean Nation-State at the beginning of the XIX century, the elites have adopted and transmitted a Eurocentric view of themselves and of society as a whole and, therefore, also adopting a racist attitude and praxis which has had dire consequences for the country's indigenous peoples.&nbsp;It is within this general framework that this course seeks to analyze and understand the historical relationship between the State and the Mapuche from an interdisciplinary perspective. Thus, the course examines theories and concepts which will help the student to comprehend the current Mapuche movement and the State's reaction to the latter's visibilization and actions which challenge the present nature of a uninational State.</li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Gender and Minority Studies in Chile and Latin America</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp; = Spanish 490R &nbsp;Course Objectives:&nbsp;1. To know the different concepts and definitions of Gender in the context of Latin-American Feminism 2. Recognize the psychological, anthropological, social and political dimensions of Gender&nbsp;3. Analyze the relationship between Gender, Power and Social Inequality, in Latin America &nbsp;4. &nbsp;To know the Chilean experience in Gender-related research 5. &nbsp;To know the studies and theories of sexual minorities from a Gender perspective, in Latin America.</span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Social Inequality, Exclusion and Democracy</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;= Spanish 490R &nbsp;Course Objectives: 1. To know the different concepts and definitions of Democracy, their elements and actors.&nbsp;2. To know and recognize the different Types of Modern Democracy. &nbsp;3. To know and recognize the effects on the Modern Democracy: Civil Society, Pluralism, Political Participation and Representation. &nbsp;&nbsp;4. To know the Modern Democracy challenge: the political and social Inequality and Exclusion. &nbsp;5. To know and analyze the present elements that affects the Modern Democracy: Multiculturalism and the new citizenship exercise with the use of new technology.</span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Latin America Regional Scenario in the XX century</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;= Spanish 490R Course Objectives: &nbsp;1. Define and explain the concepts of political power, totalitarianism, ideology, dictatorship, democracy and national interest, to apply them to the Latin American reality.2. &nbsp;Identify the socio cultural elements that shape the Latin American Identities in order to explain the evolution and outcome of political and economic models applied in the region during the twentieth century.3. Explain the historical differences and similarities among the Latin American countries in order to develop a vision different from the usual stereotypes.4. Explain the major political, economic and social events of the twentieth Century Latin America (Cuban Revolution, dictatorships and dirty war, International openness, etc.)</span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Human Rights in Latin America&nbsp;</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">= Spanish 490R &nbsp;General Objectives:&middot; To provide the students with a critical overview of the various aspects that drew Chile towards a situation of political, social, economic crisis that generated coup d'etat (11 September 1973) and a long military dictatorship&middot; To provide the students with theoretical knowledge regarding how the national institutions in Chile were destroyed in order to establish a policy of denial of human rights&bull; To be able to analyze different tools, most of them apparently legal, that permitted the perpetration of human rights as well as the impunity of the wrongdoers&bull; To be able to analyze, one by one, the specific landmarks of transitional justice utilized to reestablish truth, justice, and democracySpecific Objectives:&bull; To be able to analyze if a solid democracy has been reestablished in Chile&bull; To be able to analyze if the Chilean society considers that it has really advanced from the moment the dictatorship ended and if there continue to be barriers that prevent this country to obtain its full democracy</span></li>
<li><strong style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Poverty Reduction and Sustainable Development</strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;= Spanish 490R &nbsp;The poorest are the ones hardest hit with environmental issues as they often depend directly on natural resources for their daily needs and livelihoods. Far from being anti-development, environmental policies aimed towards achieving sustainable development can actually be used to protect the health and livelihoods of poor people, and increase their political and economic power.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">HUMANITIES AND LIBERAL ARTS</span></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Latin America History of Ideas</strong>&nbsp;= Spanish 490R &nbsp;General Objective:&nbsp;To provide the student with a general and critical overview of central identity problems in the Latin American history of ideas. &nbsp;Specific Objective:&nbsp;To provide a relevant didactic link between personal experiences in Chilean society and the theoretical content of the central identity problems.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
<li><strong>Globalization of Art and its Marketing</strong>&nbsp;= Spanish 490R</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<h1><strong style="font-size: 17.27pt; line-height: 1em;">Application Requirements</strong></h1>
<p><strong>Application Deadline:</strong> May 13, 2013</p>
<ol>
<li>Complete the <a href="https://byui.qualtrics.com/SE/?SID=SV_3JKv31wadkqdjw1" target="_blank">application form</a>.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Meet with Bro. Hunsaker to make sure course work in Chile will move you toward graduation</li>
<li>Submit this application to Brother Hunsaker.&nbsp; It must be in his hands by 5:00 PM, May 13, 2013.</li>
<li>Bro. Hunsaker will inform you whether or not you have been accepted to the program through e-mail by May 20, 2013.&nbsp; He will then advise the BYU-Idaho Accounting Department, which will charge your account for the full amount of the program fee, $4,750.</li>
<li>You must make at least a $300 deposit payment against this amount in order to hold your slot. If you have not made the deposit payment by 5:00 PM, May 27, 2013, your application will not be considered. Take or mail the $300 deposit to the BYU-Idaho cashier's office.&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Be sure to tell them it is a payment on the Semester in Chile program</strong>. &nbsp;An additional $2,225 payment is due by June 17 and the remaining $2,225 must be paid in full by July 15, 2013. &nbsp;You may pay the complete amount at any time.</li>
<li>BYU-Idaho tuition is due according to the normal schedule.</li>
<li>Complete and submit the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/Colleges_and_Departments/Language_and_Letters/Foreign%20Languages/form_cl%20(1).doc">UVM application</a>.</li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"></span>Prerequisites</h2>
<p>Students must have successfully completed (C or better) one semester of university-level Spanish and have sophomore standing by the end of Spring Semester 2013.</p>
<h2>Additional Requirements</h2>
<p>Additional student Commitment&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/Colleges_and_Departments/Language_and_Letters/Foreign%20Languages/STUDENT%20COMMITMENT.pdf">form</a>&nbsp;for students under 18 or financially dependent upon parents or guardians.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #056cb6; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 17.27pt; line-height: 1em;">Contact</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;"><span style="line-height: normal;"><strong>Director:</strong> Steve Hunsaker</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;"><span style="line-height: normal;"><strong>Office:</strong> Smith 458</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;"><span style="line-height: normal;"><strong>Phone:</strong>&nbsp;(208) 496- 1170</span></span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: normal; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt;"><strong>Email:</strong> hunsakers@byui.edu</span><strong style="line-height: normal; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt;">&nbsp;</strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x48779" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
