<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x55135" Name="Requirements &amp; Application" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Requirements &amp; Application</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Requirements of Tour/ Application</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>It is important to read and understand the following information before applying to the program.</em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Admission Requirements</strong></span></p>
<p>A prerequisite of: Art 101, a&nbsp;Humanities Foundations Course, or World Foundations&nbsp;101, is required before departure to ensure that participants are sufficiently prepared for the Europe experience.&nbsp; Students participating in travel-study programs must enroll as full-time students taking 5-9 credit hours selecting from a Humanities-based curriculum.&nbsp; Courses cannot be audited.&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Travel study programs will not accept applications from students on probation&nbsp;for either academic or Honor Code violations.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Standards</strong></span></p>
<p align="justify">As a matter of personal commitment, faculty and students of Brigham Young University-Idaho seek to demonstrate in daily living on and off-campus those moral virtues encompassed in the gospel of Jesus Christ, and will:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be honest</li>
<li>Live a chaste and virtuous life</li>
<li>Obey the law and all campus policies</li>
<li>Use clean language</li>
<li>Respect others</li>
<li>Abstain from alcoholic beverages, tobacco, tea, coffee and substance abuse</li>
<li>Participate regularly in church services</li>
<li>Observe&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/Catalog/2008-2009/Dress%20and%20Grooming%20Standards.pdf" target="_self">Dress and Grooming Standards</a></li>
<li>Encourage others in their commitment to comply with the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/Catalog/2008-2009/Honor%20Code.pdf" target="_self">Honor Code</a> "at all times... and in all places" (Mosiah 18:9).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Anyone who violates these standards at any time during the program will be sent home at personal expense</strong>.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Insurance - Travel and Health</strong></span></p>
<p>By university policy, participants in BYU-Idaho travel programs will automatically be enrolled with&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/RiskManagement/HTH%20Travel/BYUIdahoPamphlet.pdf" target="_self">HTH&nbsp;Worldwide Insurance Services, Inc</a>.&nbsp;for coverage against accidents or sickness when out of the United States at a charge of approximately&nbsp;$30.&nbsp;&nbsp;Use the HTH link to&nbsp;see a policy.&nbsp;&nbsp;There is however no compensation for the loss, damage or theft of luggage and/or personal belongings.</p>
<p>Regular Health insurance for coverage within the United Staesis is also required for class registration.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Health</strong></span></p>
<p>Participants should consider whether they are physically and emotionally capable of engaging in a rigorous travel schedule.&nbsp;We advise participants to have a physical check-up before registering for the program.&nbsp; Brigham Young University cannot be responsible for any illness that would occur on the tour. Persons with heart disease, high blood pressure, or other physical impairments that could hinder them from normal participation&nbsp;in group travel&nbsp;<em>must contact the tour director prior to submitting an application.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Students With Disabilities</strong></span></p>
<p>While the university is committed to providing a working and learning atmosphere that reasonably accommodates qualified persons with disabilities, our itinerary is strenuous and travel conditions in Europe are beyond our control. Often these circumstances do not accommodate individuals with severe physical limitations.&nbsp;&nbsp; If you have a disability that could hinder successful participation in this program,&nbsp;<em>please contact the program director before applying.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Cost</strong></span></p>
<p>The travel portion of the program is $3700. This includes round-trip airfare from Salt Lake City, all hotels, breakfasts and dinners, major museum entrance fees, all ground transportation, and tickets to<em> </em>a play and a concert/opera. Additional<strong> </strong>costs include:<strong> </strong> tuition, insurance, room and board during the on-campus instruction, passports, transportation to and from Salt Lake City, and personal spending money.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Payment</strong></span></p>
<p>Upon acceptance to the program, the travel portion of the tour&nbsp;may be paid in full&nbsp;or according to the payment&nbsp;plan as found under&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/TravelPrograms/Humanities_European_Tour_files/cost8.htm" target="_parent">Cost<strong>.</strong></a></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Cancellations</strong></span></p>
<p>Cancellation fees can cost the tour upwards of thousands of dollars. Please plan carefully&nbsp;<em>before </em>committing to participate in a travel-study program.&nbsp; If you choose not to participate once you have been accepted into the European Study program, you must notify the Department of Humanities and Philosophy in Taylor 240 i<strong>n writing</strong>.&nbsp;&nbsp;There will be no refund of the $300 deposit for cancellations. Expenses incurred above the $300 will also be charged to the student's account and will remain due and payable to the university.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Financial Aid and Scholarships</strong></span></p>
<p>The same financial aid programs available to students on-campus are available to travel-study participants. Application should be made through BYU-Idaho Financial Aid, Kimball 100, (208) 496-1600. Scholarships are administered at the same location and phone number.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Passports</strong></span></p>
<p>Students will need passports for travel.&nbsp;&nbsp;Your passport number will be requested&nbsp;in January in order to&nbsp;finalize the airline tickets.&nbsp; Apply early this process&nbsp;may take&nbsp;several months.<strong> </strong> An official site for a passport application is&nbsp;<a href="http://travel.state.gov/passport/passport_1738.html" target="_parent">travel.state.gov/passport/passport_1738.html</a></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Baggage</strong></span></p>
<p>Due to space constraints, participants will be limited to one small carry-on bag 42" total&nbsp;(height plus width plus depth) and one suitcase 59" total per person.&nbsp;&nbsp;The weight restrictions are limited to 15 pounds and 40 pounds&nbsp;to meet the flight requirements in Europe.&nbsp; Please pack so that you can carry everything yourself (there won't be any porters!).</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Changes in Travel-Study Program</strong></span></p>
<p>Brigham Young University-Idaho travel-study programs reserve the right to make changes or substitutions in this offer as a result of increases in fares, hotels, currency rates, or other unforeseen eventualities prior to departure.&nbsp; We reserve the right to cancel the tour if deemed necessary for circumstances beyond our control such as strikes, riots, wars, acts of God, etc.&nbsp; In such case, Brigham Young University-Idaho travel-study programs or its agents have no responsibility beyond refunding all deposits and moneys paid.&nbsp; Such refunds will be made within 30 days.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Application Process</strong></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Fill out the application form with all signatures. Please list your BYU-I e-mail address as that is the main means of communication.</li>
<li>Write a 300-word letter of intent explaining your interest&nbsp;in the European Humanities travel-study program and why you should be considered for admission .</li>
<li>Submit the following to the Humanities Department, TAY 240, Rexburg ID 83460-1525 or FAX to (208) 496-5279 before October 26th:&nbsp;<strong>A completed and signed application form, t</strong><strong>he Assumption of Risk and Release agreement, and t</strong><strong>he Letter of Intent.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Notification letters will be sent to applicants&nbsp;November 1<sup>st</sup> by means of their BYU-I e-mail address and in written form.&nbsp; Students that are accepted and those invited to be on the waiting list must respond to the invitation as directed. Vacancies resulting from engagements, illness, or economic downturns occur annually and are filled with students on the waiting list.</p>
<p><strong>By November 10<sup>th</sup></strong> students accepted to the program must notify the Humanities Department in writing (e-mail) of their commitment to join the travel-study program and pay a $300 nonrefundable deposit at the Cashier's office. We will assume that applicants who do not meet this deadline no longer desire to participate in the program and their space will be awarded to someone on the waiting list.</p>
<p>*Application does not automatically guarantee admission to the program. Only about 46 participants can be accommodated in each program. Admission is granted according to the relevance of the tour to students' academic objectives (including Major, Minor and Cluster), program diversity, academic standing, and other program needs.</p>
<p>Click <a href="Documents/Colleges_and_Departments/Language_and_Letters/Humanities/application2013.pdf" title="Tour Application">here</a> to download an Application.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1902" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
