<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x55117" Name="Teenagers Friends and Parents " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Teenagers Friends and Parents </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20070701T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Kelly McCoy</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Teenagers Friends and Parents</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By J. Kelly McCoy</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, July 2007)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I confess. I like to watch Saturday morning cartoons with my children. A  couple of years ago I caught the tail-end of "Pepper Ann," the animated  adventures of a typical 13-year-old girl. As the cartoon concludes,  Pepper Ann and her mother are sharing the hope that they will always be  able to express to one another the special feelings they have for each  other. Suddenly, Pepper Ann's face takes on an anxious look as she adds,  "As long as you never act that way in front of my friends or within a  one-mile radius of my school."</p>
<p><br /> Watching this animated interaction between a mother and daughter  reminded me why the teenage years can be such a confusing time for  parents regarding their place in their teenagers' lives. At one moment,  teenagers seem to seek the same nurturing behavior from parents that  they experienced when they were children, in the next moment, they are  acting as if they would rather die than be seen with their parents by  anyone their own age.</p>
<p><br /> Although teens do want and need greater autonomy as they get older,  granting teenagers increasing autonomy does not necessarily mean parents  cannot still be involved in teenagers' lives. From my research during  the past several years, it is clear that although friends do become  increasingly important during the teenage years, parents can continue to  be a part of their teenagers' lives--even that part which is occupied  by friends.</p>
<p><br /> What becomes problematic for many teenagers is not whether parents are  involved in their friendships, but rather how parents are involved in  teens' friendships. For example, the extent that parents respect and  value their teenagers' choices in selecting friends, provide their  adolescents with appropriate autonomy regarding their friendships, and  genuinely enjoy the friends their teens have selected.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>During childhood, parents are a necessary part of their children's  friendships. Parents of younger children provide them opportunities to  meet new friends, transportation to be with friends, advice about how to  be a good friend, and set rules about the who, what and where of their  children's friendship interactions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>During adolescence, young people become much more independent in their  ability to accomplish many of these tasks. Although teenagers become  much more independent in their ability to select and interact with  friends, they generally appear to like their parents taking an interest  in their friendships and have better friendships when parents are  involved. What is important, however, is whether parents' involvement is  changing in conjunction with the adolescents own development. Teens  generally don't respond well to parents continuing to control their  friendships in the same way the parents did when the teens were younger.  Teens also don't respond well to parents' attempts to be just "one of  the gang."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Parents' involvement in teens' friendships works best when the parents'  relationship with their teens and the teens' friends is transformed from  the more managing style appropriate to childhood toward a relationship  that is more collegial, where parents are genuinely interested in the  ideas and opinions of their teens and their teens' friends, and enjoy  having their teens' friends around.<br /> This does not mean that parents will automatically like every friend  their teens select, and parents should be honest in sharing those  concerns. But before placing a negative judgment on their teens' choice  of friends, parents should first demonstrate respect for their teens'  ability to make wise choices and attempt to understand, from their  teenager's perspective, those qualities that make a particular friend  desirable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As parents respond positively to the friends their teenagers have  selected, teens are more positive about their parents being involved in  those relationships, and as parents are more involved, teens report  greater satisfaction with the friends they have selected.<br /> <br /> J. Kelly McCoy is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
