<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x55110" Name="The People We Too Often Take For Granted " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The People We Too Often Take For Granted </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20070901T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">J. Kelly McCoy</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The People We Too Often Take For Granted</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By J. Kelly McCoy</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, September 2007)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This past year, new opportunities in life required that I live alone for  three months and away from most of my family for five months. From this  experience, I gained insight about many  aspects in my life, but three  in particular: the need to have a common purpose during trying times,  the importance of being physically together as a family, and the value  of relationships we too often take for granted. Last year, I was offered  the opportunity to come teach at BYU-Idaho, but had a daughter who very  much wanted to finish her senior year in high school in Provo with her  friends from the last eleven years. My wife and I determined together  that the best way to help all of our children bring better closure to  their school experiences in Provo would be for me to move to Rexburg  ahead of everyone else and live alone until our children(s school year  had ended. As a result, beginning last January I had the opportunity to  live alone for the longest time since my wife and I had been married 26  years ago. Although this lasted only a few months, it felt like an  eternity. <br /> <br /> One of our family(s biggest challenges during this period of separation  was the need to remain emotionally together in purpose even though we  were physically far apart. When living together my wife and I often talk  and make decisions together about our relationship, about our children,  and about the daily events of life. Although my wife and I often spoke  on the phone during my time away, I still felt like a bystander in my  own family(s day-to-day living. We still shared the same broader goals,  but I often found myself becoming overly focused on my life here in  Rexburg and my wife becoming overly focused on her life with the  children in Provo. It was easy to become less connected, less  intertwined in one another(s lives. It was frightening to me to see how  easily the daily demands of life could cause us to drift apart on so  many levels in our marital relationship.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This brought about a better understanding of another aspect of the  connectedness within our family relationship. I was surprised how  important physical presence is to my sense of being an effective parent.  This challenge was most evident in my relationship with my 12 year old  son, and my and my wife(s ability to parent him during this time. One of  the most frustrating experiences I had during my time away from my  family was to watch my son sometimes struggle, become moody, and even  act out while I was 300 miles away with only a phone to keep me  involved. Because I was physically absent from my son and daughters, I  felt very limited in my ability to work with my wife to support and  guide our children. These challenges made me much more aware of the  great difficulties that exist for divorced parents when a mother and  father attempt to continue being effective, responsive parents to their  children after a divorce has occurred.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The last lesson learned was the sense of incompleteness that occurs when  we come to define much of who we are through the relationships we share  with the other members of our family. Through my many friendships with  those who have long been single, I know that it is not necessary to have  other people to establish a sense of personal completeness. But once we  come to define who we are through our relationships with the others in  our immediate family, it is an odd experience to suddenly not have those  other individuals be a part of our daily existence and be constant  contributors to our personal sense of self.<br /> <br /> Although difficult, our family did pass through this time of separation  quite successfully, and, as a result of the lessons learned, I have come  to appreciate my wife and children and my relationship with each of  them much more. I recognize, however, that my time apart was a minor  inconvenience compared to many others who are separated from their  families by greater distance and for much longer periods of time. In  particular, I feel for the many servicemen and women who must currently  be away from their families defending a way of life that they believe is  worth fighting for. I suppose that the main lesson I have learned is  that when we must be away from our families for extended periods of time  (and even when we are not away) it is important that we cling to and  cherish the relationships that are shared therein, and recognize the  valuable benefits that come from our family connections.<br /> <br /></p>
<p><br /> <br /> <br /> <br /> J. Kelly McCoy is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
