<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x55102" Name="Heart of Fathering " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Heart of Fathering </Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20080601T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Steve Dennis </Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The Heart of Fathering</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">By Steve Dennis</p>
<h6>(LDS Life, June 2008)</h6>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The idea for a special day to honor fathers began in Spokane, Washington  in 1909 as Sonora Smart Dodd was listening to a Mother's Day sermon.  Having been raised by her father, after her mother died, Sonora wanted  to acknowledge his selfless sacrifice and courage. Sonora's father was  born in June, so she chose to hold the first Father's Day celebration in  1910. The observance of Father's Day grew and in1972, President Richard  Nixon established a permanent national observance of Father's Day to be  held on the third Sunday of June. <br /> <br /> Nearly a century later, fatherhood has become both something to  celebrate and a significant social concern. Today more than perhaps at  any other time in history there are many absent fathers.&nbsp; Nearly one  third of children in United States are born to an unwed mother where  often there is little commitment or involvement on the part of the  father. Research has shown that fatherless children are more likely to  drop out of high school, run away from home, abuse alcohol and other  drugs, become pregnant as teens, and engage in delinquency and crime.&nbsp;  Furthermore, the rates of poverty are significantly higher for  single-parent families-- most of which are headed by mothers.<br /> <br /> While there are more absent fathers than ever before, there are also  many nurturing and involved fathers. The rise in dual earner families  and the loosening of gender roles have made fathering a hands-on  activity that requires more than economic support and distant  parenting.&nbsp; Protecting, feeding, playing, reading, comforting, bathing,  clothing, correcting, empathizing, teaching, loving and supporting may  all be part of family life for the involved dad.&nbsp;&nbsp; In fact, some may  wonder if gender roles have become so blurred or similar that the  distinct contributions of mothers and fathers have been diminished. In  some settings, even the terms "mother" and "father" have fallen into  disfavor because they are said to perpetuate gender discrimination.  "Parent" is often the preferred term.&nbsp; Still,<em> The Family: A Proclamation to the World </em>makes  it clear that "gender is an essential characteristic of individual,  premortal, mortal, and eternal identify and purpose."&nbsp; It further  states, "By divine design, fathers are to preside over their families in  love and righteousness and are responsible to provide the necessities  of life and protection for their families.&nbsp; Mothers are primarily  responsible for the nurture of their children.&nbsp; And these sacred  responsibilities, fathers and mothers are obliged to help one another as  equal partners."<br /> <br /> While some of the gender differences between males and females are  certainly cultural constructions others are divine and part of God's  great plan. Children benefit from the complementary roles of mothers and  fathers. Each makes unique contributions. Research indicates fathers  contribute significantly to a child's school achievement, identity  formation, self-esteem, and development of appropriate limits and  boundaries. Of course, for a variety of reasons, a father or mother may  not be present.&nbsp; In such circumstances, we simply do our best to  surround our children with positive and caring role models and trust in  the Lord.<br /> <br /> Being a father is both a joyful and solemn responsibility that extends  into eternity. It requires sacrifice and service.&nbsp; It results in  heartache and happiness. But with an open heart and practice we can  improve.&nbsp; Here are seven ways to be a better dad.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Nurture the relationship with your wife.</strong>&nbsp; It will  have payoffs for your children.&nbsp; The apostle Paul wrote, "husbands, love  your wives, even as Christ also loved the church" (Ephesians 5:25).&nbsp;  Research indicates that fathers who feel good about the relationship  with their wife are more involved with their children. During times of  martial stress, fathers tend to withdraw from their children.</li>
<li><strong>Protect your children.&nbsp;</strong> Children need protection  from physical hazards and natural disasters, and more.&nbsp; Moral dangers  abound on the Internet, television and throughout our society. Parents  must be vigilant. Start by keeping your computer and television out of  private spaces such as bedrooms.&nbsp; Like Captain Moroni, we must protect  ours homes from the enemies of the family.&nbsp; His preparation included,  "heaps of earth"&nbsp; "high timbers", and "watch towers".&nbsp;&nbsp; In an electronic  age, our preparations and watchfulness will be different, but must be  every bit as diligent. </li>
<li><strong>Provide for your children.</strong> This includes economic  sustenance, but also much more. Provide emotional support. Provide  opportunities for growth and learning. Provide occasions of excitement  and energy, but also times of peace and solace.&nbsp; Give liberally of your  time.&nbsp; Elder Neal A. Maxwell has said, "The vital transfer of spiritual  power and responsibility to the rising generation seldom occurs when  fathers are too busy for such blessings..." (Ensign, 1985,8).</li>
<li><strong>Be intentional in the creation of family routines and traditions.</strong>&nbsp;  Routines and traditions develop unity, create expectations, and convey  values. The stability and predictability they provide help children  internalize values, develop self-confidence, and behave appropriately.  Family Home Evening, scripture study, daily prayer, bedtime routines,  reading together, playing together, vacations, dinnertime discussions,  family councils, family walks or bike rides, gardening and on and on can  all become regular routines or treasured traditions. </li>
<li><strong>Preside with love and compassion</strong>. As the spiritual  leader in the home, call your family together for prayer, initiate  family scripture reading, personal interviews, or family councils. Be  anxiously engaged in the governance of your home and family, but never  domineering. Preside in council and full partnership with your wife and  create ample opportunities for choice among all family members.&nbsp;  Providing children with choices helps them develop personal  responsibility and commitment.&nbsp; Coercion or forceful approaches may  result in compliance, but rarely cultivate the change of heart necessary  for children internalize behavior and develop a love of truth and  respect for parents.&nbsp;&nbsp; </li>
<li><strong>Participate actively in the breadth and depth of parenting.</strong> Play with your children, but do more. Learn about the development of  children in general and your child in particular.&nbsp; Brigham Young advised  parents to "study their [children's] dispositions and their  temperaments, and deal with them accordingly" (JD 19:221). Prepare  yourself and take part in the full range of parenting responsibilities.&nbsp;  Elder M. Russell Ballard counseled, "On a day-to-day basis, fathers can  and should help with the essential nurturing and bonding associated  with feeding, playing, storytelling, loving, and all the rest of the  activities that make up family life." (BYU Devotional, 19 August 2003)</li>
<li><strong>Teach and discipline with encouragement and tenderness.</strong>&nbsp;  Fathering is more than entertaining or having fun with our children.  Elder Dallin H. Oaks warned, "I believe many of us are overnourished on  the entertainment junk food and undernourished on the bread of life."  (Ensign, May 2001, 82).&nbsp; Fathers must actively teach children life  skills, gospel principles, and secular knowledge.&nbsp; Enos recorded of his  father that, "he was a just man-for he taught me in his language, and  also in the nurture and admonition of the Lord." He obviously respected  the words of his father for he further wrote "I went to hunt beasts in  the forests; and the words which I had often heard my father speak  concerning eternal life, and the joy of the saints, sunk deep into my  heart." (See Enos 1:1-3).&nbsp; Likewise, Lehi set high expectations and  encouraged his sons even when they murmured against him.&nbsp; To Lamam he  said, "O that thou mightest be like unto this river, continually running  into the fountain of all righteousness!"&nbsp; And to Lemuel he encouraged,  "be like unto this valley, firm and steadfast, and immovable in keeping  the commandments of the Lord!" (See 1 Nephi 2: 9-10).&nbsp; Though our  efforts may not be immediate, teaching with tenderness and love is never  in vain.</li>
</ol>
<p><br /> Fathers, view your awesome responsibility with a long term lens.&nbsp; In a  very real sense we are not only parenting our children, but we are  setting the foundation for generations to come.&nbsp; Each of our lives have  been shaped by individuals long deceased. So too are we establishing the  patterns of living that will influence our grandchildren and  great-grandchildren to come. President Gordon B. Hinckley reminded us,  "All that you have of body and mind will be transmitted through you to  the generations yet to come, and it is so important, so everlastingly  important, my brothers and sisters, that you do not become a weak link  in that chain of your generations." (Regional conference, Oahu, Hawaii,  23 January 2000.)&nbsp; May the hearts of the fathers be turned to their  children so in time the hearts of the children may be turned to God.<br /> <br /></p>
<p><br /> Steve Dennis is a member of the faculty in the Department of Home and Family at Brigham Young University - Idaho</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x207" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
