<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x55273" Name="FDMAT108" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mathematics Department</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Foundation Math 108</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>FDMAT 108/108T - Math for the Real World</strong></p>
<p><strong>Within the framework of the BYU-Idaho Learning Model, FDMAT 108 will enable student to develop quantitative reasoning skills that will benefit them in their subsequent courses and daily lives.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Objectives and Outcomes</strong></p>
<p><strong>Develop the Necessary Arithmetic and basic algebraic skills to succeed in daily life.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Properly apply unit conversion in their problem solving techniques.</li>
<li>calculate appropriate absolute and relative changes in finding percentages.</li>
<li>View percentages in terms of fractions, changes,  and comparison.</li>
<li>Apply the of versus more than rule with percentages.</li>
<li>Demonstrate the difference between percentage and percentage point.</li>
<li>Solve simple one and two-step equations.</li>
<li>Algebraically solve for the different variables structured whiting an applied formula.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Analyze and critique real-world issues and arguments involving probability and statistics.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Discuss coherently the potential for abuse and misuse of statistics and be able to critique, at their level of ability, the validity of statistical studies found in professional journals.</li>
<li>Describe the abuse of statistical graphs often found in the media</li>
<li>Describe the role of randomness, placebos, single and double-blinded studies, control vs. experimental groups and other key concepts found in inferential statistics.</li>
<li>Point out the difference between correlation and causation</li>
<li>Describe the difference between weak and strong correlation and between positive and negative correlation.</li>
<li>Calculate and interpret the mean, median, mode, range, and standard deviation of a data set</li>
<li>Calculate and interpret the five-number summary, z-scores, percentile, and outliers of data.</li>
<li>Construct histograms, box plots, pie charts, scatter plots and demonstrate pros, and coins.</li>
<li>Form a basic assessment of the role of hyp0otheses, margin of error, and statistical inference.</li>
<li>Calculate the margin of error for proportional data and construct a 95% confidence interval.</li>
<li>Show rudimentary understanding of the roles hypotheses, margin of error, and statistical significance play in research.</li>
<li>Identify normal , uniform, positive, and negatively-skewed distributions.</li>
<li>Appropriately apply the 68-95-99.7 Rule to both data and population contests.</li>
<li>Gain facility with the complement, And, Or, and At Least Once Rules from basic probability.</li>
<li>Describe and interpret the notion of the Law of Large Numbers and expected value with real applications.</li>
<li>Discuss risk and the role it plays in our society and the decisions we make.</li>
<li>Discuss, in a cogent manner, the mathematical, social, and moral issues that arise in lottery and other gambling activities including the gambler's fallacy.</li>
<li>Show how to count arrangements using repetition, factorials, permutations, and combinations.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Explore the use of mathematical models in describing and making predictions about real-world phenomena.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Discuss the role of mathematical formulae, graphs, and numeric tables in modeling real-world issues such as finance, populations, probabilities, etc.</li>
<li>Describe the specific differences between linear and exponential growth.</li>
<li>Construct exponential models to accommodate forecasting future values of a variety of phenomena.</li>
<li>Apply the Rule of 70 to calculate doubling time and half-life periods for modeling.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Understand the dangers of debt, the power of compound interest, and the advantages and disadvantages of various financial choices.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Construct a reasonable budget based on income, savings, and expenses and demonstrate the importance of taking control of one's personal finances.</li>
<li>Demonstrate the power of compound interest and the role it plays in investments.</li>
<li>Describe the difference between annual percentage rate and annual percentage yield.</li>
<li>Calculate both the annual return and total return as a percentage on an investment.</li>
<li>Calculate the future value of both lump sum and annuity investments as well as solving for present value ad time.</li>
<li>Demonstrate the competence with the mathematics of installment loans by constructing amortization schedules using a spreadsheet.</li>
<li>Discuss the pros and cons of paying extra principal on a long-term loan.</li>
<li>Gain facility in describing the relationship between principal and interest in the context of both debt and investment.</li>
<li>Discuss the key elements of liquidity, risk, and return and their relationship to investing.</li>
<li>Carefully explain the mathematics and dangers of consumer credit and hot to plan properly for living within one's means.</li>
<li>Describe the marginal income tax brackets of our nation's tax code and how calculations are made based upon deductions and exemptions.</li>
<li>Calculate the FICA tax on wages, its history and impact on our retirement system.</li>
<li>Describe the difference between a tax credit and a tax deduction using specific examples.</li>
<li>Demonstrate an understanding of the difference between our national debt and deficit and the ramifications for the future.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Learn to competently evaluate logical arguments and resolve real-life problems that require quantitative reasoning.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Identify propositions, negations, conditionals, converses, inverses, and contra positives.</li>
<li>Distinguish between deductive and inductive arguments.</li>
<li>Assess the validity and soundness of arguments.</li>
<li>Apply George Poly's four-step problem-solving guidelines to quantitatively-based problems.</li>
<li>Gain facility in the selection of appropriate tools such as the calculator and spreadsheet in solving of quantitative real-world problems.</li>
</ul>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1883" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
