<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x55272" Name="Course Offerings" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Course Offerings</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mathematics Department</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p><strong>FDMAT108 Mathematical Tools for the Real World   (3:3:0) </strong><br />This class prepares students to understand, analyze, and solve real-life problems that<br />require quantitative reasoning. Topics include the meaning of probabilities, how to<br />read, critique, and apply statistical information found in news reports, public policy<br />debates, consumer reports, and other daily life and professional situations; the use of<br />mathematical models in describing, understanding, and making predictions about real<br />world phenomena; and the mathematics of loans and investments. Other topics may be<br />included as time permits. All topics will be illustrated by examples and applications from<br />current events, daily life, business, and natural phenomena.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>FDMAT108T Math for the Real World Test Out Option  (1:0:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: One of the following courses: FDMAT110; FDMAT112; FDMAT221; FDMAT222;<br />FDMAT223; FDMAT224; MATH 109; MATH 113, MATH 215<br />This pass/fail online-based course allows students who have already had a Foundations<br />mathematics course, to explore the contemporary topics of finance math, linear and<br />exponential modeling, probability, and statistical reasoning. It will satisfy the BYU-Idaho<br />Foundations quantitative reasoning requirement and contains the most vital topics of<br />the traditional 3.0-credit FDMAT 108. Completion of the course includes passing both<br />a financial mathematics exam and statistical reasoning exam along with a financial<br />life-planning spreadsheet project. Students may take FDMAT 108T one time only. Failure<br />of FDMAT 108T would require the students to take the traditional 3.0 credit FDMAT 108<br />course to complete the foundations quantitative reasoning requirement.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>FDMAT110 College Algebra   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Elementary analysis of functions having discrete or connected domains. Methods of<br />solving equations. Systems of equations and matrices. Strong connections to real world<br />applications of functions and matrices will be made. Students who will be going on to take<br />Calculus are strongly encouraged to take Math 109 instead of FDMAT 110.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>FDMAT112 Calculus 1   (4:4:1) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 109 or (FDMAT 110 and MATH 111)<br />Limits, continuity, derivatives, integrals, and transcendental functions. Properties and<br />applications of the above.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>FDMAT221 Business Statistics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: Completion of 15 credits<br />Graphical representations of data; measures of center and spread; elementary probability;<br />sampling distributions; correlation and regression; statistical inference involving means,<br />proportions, and contingency tables.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>FDMAT222 Biostatistics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: Completion of 15 credits<br />Graphical representations of data; measures of center and spread; elementary probability;<br />sampling distributions; correlation and regression; statistical inference involving means,<br />proportions, and contingency tables; odds ratio and relative risk.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>FDMAT223 Social Science Statistics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: Completion of 15 credits<br />Graphical representations of data; measures of center and spread; elementary probability;<br />sampling distributions; correlation and regression; statistical inference involving means,<br />proportions, and contingency tables.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
</div>
<div><br />
<p><br /><strong>MATH 100A Arithmetic   (1:0:3) </strong><br />A study of arithmetic and applications using arithmetic. This course is only for those<br />needing a review of elementary school arithmetic including signed numbers, fractions,<br />decimals, and percents.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 100B Beginning Algebra   (2:0:3) </strong><br />The arithmetic of integers and rational numbers as well as an introduction to algebra. This<br />course is recommended for those needing basic algebra before taking progressively higher<br />math courses.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 101 Intermediate Algebra   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Fundamental operations of algebra, properties of exponents, solving linear, fractional,<br />radical and quadratic equations, graphing linear and quadratic functions. Math 101 may<br />not be taken for credit if FDMAT 110 has been completed with a grade of "B" or higher.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 109 Precalculus   (5:5:0) </strong><br />Combination of College Algebra and Trigonometry. Intended to prepare students for<br />Calculus or other math and science courses. Elementary analysis of functions having<br />discrete or connected domains. Methods of solving equations. Systems of equations and<br />matrices. Triangle relationships, graphs of periodic functions, trigonometric identities,<br />inverse trigonometric functions, and applications of trigonometry.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 111 Trigonometry   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Trigonometric functions, triangle relationships, graphs, identities, inverse trigonometric<br />functions, complex numbers, and applications. Applications of trigonometry will be<br />emphasized throughout the course.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 113 Calculus 2   (3:3:1) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112 or MATH 112<br />Techniques of integration, infinite sequences and series, polar coordinates, and<br />parametric curves.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 114 Calculus II for Education Majors   (4:4:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112 or MATH 112<br />Techniques of integration, infinite sequences and series, polar coordinates, parametric<br />curves, introduction to multi-variable and vector calculus.<br />(Fall, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 119 Calculus for Business and Life Sciences   (4:4:1) </strong><br />Prerequisites: One of the following courses: FDMAT110; MATH 110; MATH 109; FDMAT109<br />A one-semester terminal course of single and multi-variable calculus designed primarily<br />for students in biology, agriculture, and business. Topics include derivatives, integrals, and<br />Applications.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 190 Tutoring Mathematics   (1:1:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112 or MATH 112<br />This course gives math education majors a mid-level practicum experience working with the secondary level students.  We hope that participants will discover whether or not they really want to pursue a secondary education degree.  During this practicum experience, participants will tutor juior high school students, discuss and use "best" practices in tutoring and improve their presentation skills by completing a theater workshop.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 205 Fundamentals of Number Theory   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT108 or FDMAT108T<br />This course is for Secondary Education Mathematics Majors and Minors and Elementary<br />Education majors. Systems of numeration, operations on whole numbers, integers and<br />rational numbers, the real number system, and other topics from number theory are<br />included.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 206 Elementary Geometry   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT108 or FDMAT108T<br />This course is for Secondary Education Mathematics majors and minors and Elementary<br />Education majors. Concepts of geometry in two and three dimensions.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)<br /><br /><strong>MATH 214 Multivariate/Vector Calculus   (3:3:1) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 113<br />Techniques of integration, infinite sequences and series, polar coordinates, parametric<br />curves, introduction to multi-variable and vector calculus. Math 214 and Math 215 cannot<br />both be taken for credit.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 215 Multivariable Calculus   (4:4:1) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112<br />Polar coordinates, parametric curves, vectors, vector geometry, vector-valued<br />functions, partial derivatives, gradient, optimization, multiple integration, vector fields, and<br />operations on scalar and vector fields. Emphasis on methods and applications. Math 215<br />and Math 214 cannot both be taken for credit.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 241 Linear Algebra 1   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112<br />Introduces and explores some of the major concepts of matrix analysis through solving<br />significant real world problems.<br />(Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 242 Linear Algebra 2   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 241<br />Introduces and explores some of the major concepts of vector spaces and linear<br />transformations through solving significant real world problems.<br />(Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 271 Elementary Differential Equation   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 114 or MATH 113<br />Introduces and explores some of the major concepts of differential equations and<br />dynamical systems through solving significant real world problems.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 281 Introduction to Applied Mathematics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112; MATH 119<br />Mathematical modeling concepts applied to areas such as biology, physics, chemistry,<br />game theory, and economics. May include guest lecture, field trips, and interdisciplinary<br />projects.<br />(Fall, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 301 Introduction to Analysis   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 113<br />Achieving maturity in mathematical communication. Topics include introduction to<br />mathematical proof, analysis of proof, set theory, mathematical induction, logical<br />reasoning, elementary number theory, and properties of relations and functions.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 316 Differential Equations with Linear Algebra   (4:4:1) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 214 or MATH 215<br />Matrices, determinants, eigen values and eigenvectors, first and second order ordinary<br />differential equations, power series and Fourier series methods, Laplace transforms,<br />systems of linear ordinary differential equations. Emphasis on methods and applications.<br />Math 316 and Math 371 cannot both be taken for credit.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<strong>MATH 323 Intermediate Statistics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Graphical representation of data, principles of experimental design, confidence intervals, hypothesis testing, contingency tables, nonparametric tests, ANOVA, multiple comparisons, multiple regression, regression diagnostics, subset selection procedures, and some nonlinear regression models.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)
<p><br /><strong>MATH 325 Intermediate Statistical Methods   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT 222 or FDMAT 223</p>
<p>Various nonparametic procedures, ANOVA and ANCOVA with two or more factors, multiple linear regression, modules to develop various skill sets: a)  principles of experimental design, six-sigma, and quality control, b)  odds ratio/relative risk, chi-square , and logistic regression analyses, c) basic time series and forecasting models.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>MATH 326 Experimental Design   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT 222 or FDMAT 223</p>
<p>Designed to explore various experimental designs, to analyze data from these designs, and to consider optimal experimental designs.  Students will design and conduct major specific projects.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>MATH 327 Introduction to Bayesian Statistics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112; MATH 119; FDMAT 222 or FDMAT 223</p>
<p>Introduction to Bayesian Statistics, Topics include:  the scientific method, conditional probability, Bayes' Theroem, multiple integrals, probability distributions, prior/posterior distributions, hypothesis testing, credible intervals, conjugate distributions (beta-binaomial, Poisson-gamma, normal-normal), MCMC methods (i.e. Gibbs sampling), and comparison to frequentitst methodologies.<br />(Fall, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 340 Discrete Mathematics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Co-requisites: Must be taken concurrently with Math 340L<br />Topics from graph theory, combinatorics, logic, and mathematical induction. Training in<br />how to communicate clearly and carefully about mathematical concepts. To be taken<br />concurrently with Math 340L.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 340L Technical Writing Lab   (1:0:2) </strong><br />Co-requisites: Must be taken concurrently with Math 340<br />Training in how to create and edit technical documents and how to typeset mathematics<br />and mathematical figures using a computer. To be taken concurrently with Math 340.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 341 Linear Algebra   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT112<br />Systems of linear equations, matrices, determinants, eigenvalues and eigenvectors,<br />vectors, vector spaces, linear transformations, and applications.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 350 Geometry   (3:0:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 340<br />Axiomatic treatment of finite geometries, transformation geometry, Euclidean and<br />non-Euclidean geometries with emphasis on the historical significance of the Parallel<br />Postulate.<br />(Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 411 Numerical Analysis   (3:0:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: CS 124 and (MATH 316 or MATH 341); MATH 301 strongly suggested<br />Basic error analysis, complexity of algorithms, roots, interpolation, least squares<br />approximation, curve fitting, numerical differentiation and integration, and systems of<br />linear equations.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 412 Scientific Computing   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 411 and (MATH 214 or MATH 215)<br />Methods of solving complex problems using numerical analysis and computer simulation.<br />A variety of computing tools will be employed to study significant problems of current<br />interest. Topics may include graph theory, cryptography, random number generation,<br />queuing theory, discrete optimization, parameter fitting, finite element analysis, numerical<br />PDE methods, etc.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><strong>MATH 423 Probability and Statistics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: FDMAT 221; Math 214; Math 119; Math 214; Math 241<br />Methods of solving complex problems using numerical analysis and computer simulation.<br />A variety of computing tools will be employed to study significant problems of current<br />interest. Topics may include graph theory, cryptography, random number generation,<br />queuing theory, discrete optimization, parameter fitting, finite element analysis, numerical<br />PDE methods, etc.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><strong>MATH 425 Applied Linear Regression   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Designed to expolore fundamentals of regression, theory of regression models, residual and residual analysis, multiple regression, remediation, transformations and ANOVA.  Students will use SPSS for statistical analyses.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 440 Modern Algebra   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 340 or MATH 240 or MATH 301<br />This course is for secondary education majors and minors. Number theory, division<br />algorithm, primes, GCD, LCM, proof, rings, integral domains, fields, polynomials,<br />Fundamental Theorem of Algebra, groups, isomorphisms, and how these topics apply to<br />the secondary school mathematics curriculum.<br />(Fall,Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 441 Abstract Algebra 1   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 301 and MATH 341<br />Introduction to groups, rings, fields, vector spaces, and applications.<br />(Fall)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 442 Abstract Algebra 2   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 441<br />Additional exposure to groups, rings, fields, vector spaces, and applications.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 450 History of Mathematics   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 350 and MATH 440<br />Intended for those students majoring in Mathematics Education. Presents an overview of<br />the development of mathematics and its interaction with society.<br />(Fall)<br /><br /><strong>MATH 461 Real Analysis 1   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: (MATH 214 or MATH 215) and (MATH 316 or MATH 341)<br />Rigorous treatment of the calculus. Limits, continuity, differentiation, integration, and<br />metric properties of Euclidean spaces.<br />(Fall)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 462 Real Analysis 2   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 461<br />Analysis in the context of metric spaces. Applications involving such tools as<br />approximation, Fourier analysis, and multivariate optimization.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 463 Complex Analysis   (3:0:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 214 or MATH 215<br />Arithmetic, algebra and calculus operations and concepts applied to complex numbers<br />and functions of a single complex variable.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 472 Introduction to Partial Differential Equations   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 316</p>
<p>Solving linear homogeneous and nonhomogeneous second-order partial differential<br />equations with homogeneous and nonhomogeneous boundary conditions by separation of<br />variables. Sturm-Liouville theory. Applications of partial differential equations to diffusion,<br />wave, and other phenomena. Fourier series and their applications to solving partial<br />differential equations. Solving first-order partial differential equations using the method of<br />characteristics. Introduction to the finite-element and finite-difference methods.<br />(Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 490 Secondary Education Mathematics Teaching Methods   (2:2:0) </strong><br />Prerequisites: MATH 302; MATH 350; MATH 440; MATH 450<br />Math 490 must be taken the semester before student teaching. This course is designed to<br />help preservice secondary mathematics teachers apply research-based teaching strategies<br />that lead students to discover, create, appreciate, and utilize mathematics. Students<br />will have many opportunities to teach, prepare lesson plans, learn how to organize and<br />manage classrooms, and gain a knowledge of state and professional standards for<br />secondary mathematics teachers.<br />(Fall, Winter)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 495R Topics in Mathematics   (3:3:0) </strong><br />Prerequisite: Consent of instructor<br />The content of this class will be determined by the department and the instructor, based<br />on student need and interest. Possible subjects are Number Theory, Topology, Stochastic<br />Processes, and Actuarial Science.<br />(Fall)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 498R Internship   (1-3:0:0) </strong><br />Prerequisite: Consent of instructor<br />Practical experience working in a math intensive industry.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p><br /><strong>MATH 499R Senior Project in Mathematics   (1-3:0:0) </strong><br />Prerequisite: Consent of instructor<br />Content tailored to individual needs and interests of the students. Investigation and/or<br />application of mathematical principles under the guidance of a faculty member.<br />(Fall, Winter, Spring)</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<br />
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1883" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
