<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x55232" Name="ALEKS" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ALEKS</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ALEKS</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong>Math Refresher Course<br /><br />What three things do you do to complete ALEKS?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>Take an initial assessment to generate your personalized pie chart</li>
<li>Click your personalized pie chart to study concepts you need to master</li>
<li>Attain a mastery of 120/142 as listed above your personalized pie chart</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong>How long will it take to complete ALEKS after the initial assessment?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>Plan to spend 30 to 60 minutes a day working in ALEKS</li>
<li>Most students spend 3 to 15 total hours working in ALEKS</li>
<li>You have SIX weeks to complete ALEKS</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong>How much does the ALEKS program cost?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>Your initial account and SIX weeks in ALEKS are free</li>
<li>Each additional account and six weeks will cost $25</li>
<li>Each additional six weeks requires reassessment</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong>What if I decide not to complete ALEKS?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>Sign up for Math 100B and spend more than 32 hours in class</li>
<li>Attain a "B" grade or higher</li>
<li>Do NOT attain a "B-" or lower</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong>What IMPORTANT things should I remember?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>ALEKS is an assessment</li>
<li>ALEKS is NOT a pass or fail test, you do NOT need to study for it</li>
<li>ALEKS will teach you what you need to learn</li>
<li>After your assessment, click the pie chart to earn points</li>
<li>As you learn the concept you will earn points</li>
<li>Typically three correct answers per concept earns one point</li>
<li>You CAN achieve a score of 120 BEFORE you need to retest</li>
<li>Your first account is free, additional accounts cost $25 each</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong>How do I start the ALEKS program?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>Write down your course code, MQMUR-R3XT3</li>
<li>Find your 9-digit I# (BYU-Idaho student number)</li>
<li>Visit <a href="http://www.aleks.com"><strong>www.aleks.com</strong></a> and create your account</li>
</ul>
<br /> <strong>What if I have a computer or other problem loading the ALEKS program?</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li>Call ALEKS customer support at <strong>714-619-7090</strong></li>
</ul>
<br />&nbsp;<br />Additional helpful information follows to help you complete the ALEKS program.<br /><br /><strong>Where You Will Take the Refresher Course and Complete the Preparation Program</strong>
<p>This course has been purchased for you by the University to help you succeed.&nbsp; There is no additional cost to you.&nbsp; Once you have created an account and taken the assessment, you have <strong>six weeks </strong>to work to improve your skills. Do not create another account. If you forget your password, contact ALEKS customer support. The univerisity will only pay for one account for your initial six weeks. <strong>Any additional accounts will be charged at $25 each to your student account.</strong></p>
<p>When you reach the ALEKS homepage, click on NEW USER under the login box, and enter this course code,&nbsp;<strong><strong>MQMUR-R3XT3</strong></strong>.</p>
<p>When ALEKS asks for your student ID, enter your 9-digit I#.&nbsp; You will be directed through a short tutorial that shows you how to enter the mathematical answers.&nbsp; After you have completed that tutorial, you are ready to take the Initial Assessment.&nbsp; While this is an assessment of your abilities, you do not study prior to taking the assessment.&nbsp; You don't pass or fail it.&nbsp; It is an assessment that determines what you know and what you need to learn.&nbsp;&nbsp; Once the program has determined what you need to learn, it will teach you the skills you need.</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>This initial assessment is to be taken online at <a href="http://www.aleks.com/">www.aleks.com</a> from any location you choose. If you have trouble downloading the program, contact <strong>ALEKS customer support at 714-619-7090</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>How You Will Take the Initial Assessment</strong></p>
<p>You should answer the questions as best you can.&nbsp; After you have completed the Initial Assessment, you will have the opportunity to improve your score.&nbsp; It is important that your score be an accurate representation of<strong> your</strong> skills.</p>
<p>The Initial Assessment is to be taken under the following conditions:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should set aside one to one and a half hours to take the test without distractions.&nbsp; There is no time limit for the test, but it needs to be taken at one sitting.</li>
<li>You may<strong> not</strong> use notes, books, the Internet, other people or tools to help you answer the questions.</li>
<li>You may not use a calculator unless indicated in the problem.&nbsp; A calculator is available in the program if one is allowed on the problem.</li>
<li>You may use a pencil and paper to write notes and calculations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What Your Score Means</strong></p>
<p>If you score at least 120, you are eligilble to register for FDMAT 108.</p>
<p>If you score less than 120, you have six weeks to increase your score to 120.</p>
<p>If you do not increase your score to 120 by the end of six weeks, you may choose to pay $25 and continue your studies within the ALEKS program.&nbsp; Or you may decide to enroll in Math 100B.&nbsp; If you decide to enroll in Math 100B, you must achieve a "B" or higher.</p>
<strong>&nbsp;</strong>You have<strong> six weeks</strong>from the time you took the Initial Assessment to raise your score.&nbsp; Following the Initial Assessment, ALEKS generates a color-coded pie chart to display what you do and don't know.&nbsp; Plan to spend 30-40 minutes each day working to improve your score.
<p>The ALEKS program then helps you learn the concepts you are having difficulty with.&nbsp; If you have no idea how to work through a problem, click the "Show Me" button.&nbsp; As you work to master the problems in each pie slice, you will periodically be given pop quizzes to see if you remember what you've learned.&nbsp; If you've forgotten certain topics, you'll have to master them again.&nbsp; This is to help you learn the topics and achieve long-term success in classes requiring math.</p>
<p>To familiarize yourself with ALEKS, please read the instuctions below.</p>
<p><img height="394" src="https://byui.box.net/shared/static/rxhd7b63echk2isnxjfu.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="529" />When you reach the ALEKS homepage, click on New User under login box, and enter this course code, <strong><strong>MQMUR-R3XT3</strong></strong>.</p>
<p><img height="358" src="https://byui.box.net/shared/static/28zmix0p31hy47vcfqcx.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="525" />When it asks for your student id, enter your 9-digit I#. You will be directed through a short tutorial that shows you how to enter mathematical answers. After you have completed that tutorial, you are ready to take the placement test, called the Initial Assessment. <img height="385" src="https://byui.box.net/shared/static/vbmoke0omybo58zufeov.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="514" /> You should answer the questions as best you can, without help. <strong>Once you have created an account, do NOT go back into ALEKS using the NEW USER button and the class code above. This will create another account and you will be charged $25 for it.</strong> Just use your log-in name and password. Based on your score on the Initial Assessment, you will have an idea which math course you are prepared for here at BYUI.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>How You Will Take the Placement Test</h4>
<p>The Initial Assessment is to be taken under the following conditions:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should set aside an hour to an hour and a half to take the test without distractions. There is no time limit for the test, but it needs to be taken at one sitting.</li>
<li>You may <strong>not</strong> use notes, books, the Internet, friends, parents, teachers, or any other tools to help you get the answers.</li>
<li>You may <strong>not</strong> use a calculator unless indicated in the problem. An electronic calculator is available on the web page if the question indicates a calculator is OK.</li>
<li>You may use a pencil and paper to write notes and calculations. It is very important that you do your best, but be truthful about what you don&rsquo;t know.</li>
</ul>
<br />
<h4>What You Can Do to Raise Your Score</h4>
<p>You have 6 weeks from the time you took the initial assessment to raise your score before school starts. After school starts you have until the second day of class to raise you score enough to get into FDMAT 108. Following the Initial Assessment, ALEKS generates a color-keyed pie chart to display what you do and don't know. <img src="https://byui.box.net/shared/static/zi5gu3igos4if1g0m3ka.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="95%" />To practice problems in ALEKS click on any slice of your pie chart and you will see a list of problems you can work on. <img src="https://byui.box.net/shared/static/c9jr69kmcttklpr69isl.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="95%" />Click on any problem and as you master those problems your score will increase.</p>
As you work to master the problems in each pie slice, you will periodically be given pop quizzes to see if you remember what you&rsquo;ve learned. If you&rsquo;ve forgotten certain topics, you&rsquo;ll have to master them again. This is to help you really learn the topics for the long term so that you can be successful in subsequent courses that rely on this material.
<p>If you want to raise your score on the Initial Assessment, you should work in ALEKS everyday for at least 30-45 minutes.If you have not made sufficient progress in ALEKS to register for FDMAT 108 before the six weeks is up, you may purchase another licence for ALEKS ($25) or you may register for Math 100B.&nbsp; Be aware that once the Math 100B classes are full, they are full and no more will be added.</p>
<p>Ideally, you should take the initial assessment about 6 weeks before you can register for classes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Contacts</h4>
We are looking forward to working with you as you pursue your college education and hope you will use the many supports available to students at BYU-Idaho. In addition to the Career and Academic Advising Center, there is the Academic Support Center in the library where you can get a tutor for any class or attend walk-in Math and English labs. We are genuinely interested in your success. Come and see us!
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="width: 250px; float: left;">
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 15px;">Department of Mathematics<br />Brigham Young University &ndash; Idaho<br />208-496-7520</p>
</div>
<div style="width: 250px; float: left;">
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 15px;">Career and Academic Advising Center<br />Brigham Young University &ndash; Idaho<br />208-496-9800</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1883" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
