<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x55874" Name="CE CR 1"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">[N-327] Advanced Physical Assessment</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong>Clinical Requirements</strong><br /> All clinicals must be completed with a nurse practitioner, physician  assistant or a physician. Hospitals are not recommended locations for  this clinical experience. Clinics and/or doctor's offices are preferred.  The student can do 3-6 hours of clinical work per week. This is to allow  sufficient time for study and preparation for clinical. Physical  assessment of many patients will be completed, but the documentation of  two patients for each system is required to be submitted in journal  entries. <br />Clinicals for 327 include the following: Completion of a health  history on an individual of student's choice. See Brain Honey for  instructions. Cultural assessment on individual of student's choice. See  Brain Honey for instructions. Completion of 48 hours working with a NP,  PA or a physician learning the physical exam. Student is to be actively  involved doing exams on patients under supervision of preceptor.  Student can complete only 4-6 hours per week with a preceptor. Time must  be spent completing two open book exams each week and reviewing two  videos prior to the clinical experience. Completion of 52 hours producing  written documentation of clinical journal, patient charting, and other  supporting materials. <br /> <strong>Number of Hours </strong><br />Credit hours: 4, 3 hours theory/week<br /> Total theory hours are calculated on a 1 credit hour: 1 theory hour  ratio and are based on a 16-week semester compressed into 14 weeks.<br /> 1x3 = 3 hours/week x 16 = <strong>48 hours/semester required for clinical</strong>. <br /> Total clinical/lab hours per semester are calculated on a 1 credit hour:  3 clinical hours ratio and are based on a 16-week semester compressed  into 14 weeks. Faculty may choose to plan individual experiences to  equal the total number of hours as needed related to optimal  experiences, testing, holidays, etc.]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
