<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x55988" Name="Pat Huish Award" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Teacher and student win design awards</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Patrick Huish, a Design and Construction Management teacher, is the recipient of the National Association of Home Builders Outstanding Educator Award, and Valene Edwards, a senior studying interior design, placed second in the Charette Design Competition.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="150" Height="150" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">physical-sciences-engineering/HuishAward.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="790" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="514" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">101116_BYU-IdahoCenter_09a.jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120229T19:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Jason Lyons</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><img height="150" src="Images/physical-sciences-engineering/HuishAward.jpg" width="150" /></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho’s Design and Construction Management Department has  recently received recognition for two successes, both by faculty and a  student.</p>
<p>Design and Construction Management Department teacher Patrick Huish  was recently awarded the Outstanding Educator Award at the National  Association of Home Builders (NAHB) in Orlando, Fla.</p>
<p>The Outstanding Educator Award is meant to give recognition for the accomplishments of teachers in construction education.</p>
<p>“When [they] announced some of the things the winner was involved in,  I then realized he was talking about me. I was very … surprised,” Huish  said.</p>
<p>Nominees are judged in five categories: teaching responsibilities;  voluntary activities with students; participation in local NAHB  activities; professional research, publications and presentations; and  construction experience.</p>
<p>Huish said he has spent a lot of time coaching teams that have placed  very well in NAHB Student Competitions. He has also served on the NAHB  Student Advisory Board.</p>
<p>“I am grateful to my fellow faculty who felt I was worthy of such a recognition and recommended me for it,” Huish said.</p>
<p>Valene Edwards, a senior studying interior design, placed second in  the Charette Design Competition, winning $4,000. The competition  included 31 different schools and 398 other entries. It consisted of  designing a layout for a kitchen, specific to the requests of a client.</p>
<p>“The day before the completion, I like to review the codes and  guidelines I have learned as well as look at kitchens for inspiration,”  Edwards said. “I feel as though looking at good design really helps  ideas come quickly during the competition.”</p>
<p>Contestants are given three hours to draft plans that include a  design concept, dimensions, specifications and a perspective of the  kitchen.</p>
<p>“The hardest part of the competition is managing your time. You  really have to think quickly and make fast decisions,” Edwards said.</p>
<p>The Charette Design Competition is a national program that connects dozens of schools throughout the nation.</p>
<p>Each school holds their own competition during the fall when entries  are judged and the top three entries from every school receive a $50  scholarship.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x8169" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
