<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<CustomPageWithReturn ID="x56132" Name="Behavioral Health Center" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Behavioral Health Center Internship</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Detail and application for Behavioral Health Center Internship</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="LeftNavGroup" label="Left Nav Return" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><ParentName type="string" label="Parent Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></ParentName><xPower Type="Link" Link="x10260" Name="Link" label="Link" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" LinkText="" Target="" Expanded="false"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><strong> </strong></div>
<h4 align="center" style="text-align: justify;">The internship for BHC is a great opportunity for students who are perusing a  career in clinical or counseling psychology.  The following is an outline of the  current job description and obligation for BYU-I students interested in this  internship.
<p style="text-align: left;"><br />The Behavioral Health Center is a free-standing psychiatric hospital that is  part of Eastern Idaho Regional Medical Center with:</p>
</h4>
<ul>
<li>76 beds on four different units - Adult Special Care, Daybreak, Child/Adolescent Unit, and Teton Peaks Residential</li>
<li>Adult Special Care Unit:  Adults (18y/o through geriatrics) with an acute psychiatric illness that deems them 1) a danger to themselves or others, or 2) gravely disabled.  Many of these patients are committed involuntarily to the facility.  Average length of stay is 5-10 days.</li>
<li>Daybreak Unit:  Adult patients with a psychiatric illness that are capable of insight and able to participate actively in their own treatment.  Patients are involved in Cognitive-Behavioral therapies.  Most of these patients are voluntary.  Average length of stay is 5-10 days.</li>
<li>Child/Adolescent Acute Care Unit:  Children and Adolescents, aged 3-18, that are at risk for 1) harm to themselves or others, or 2) gravely disabled.  These patients have a primary psychiatric diagnosis but also often have conduct disorders, legal issues, and substance abuse problems.  Average length of stay is 5-10 days.</li>
<li>Teton Peaks Residential Treatment:  Adolescents with primary psychiatric illnesses placed for long-term treatment (6 months to 18 months) who are also often dealing with severe substance abuse, family dysfunction, legal issues and behavior problems.</li>
<li>We treat a broad range of thought and mood disorders.</li>
<li>Students will have the opportunity to observe and participate with patients in group psychotherapy, individual psychotherapy, case management, recreation therapy, occupational therapy, psychological testing, and other various assessments.</li>
<li>They will meet with a clinician once a week to discuss/process their experiences.</li>
<li>All students are required to provide evidence of previous immunizations, TB screening, and sign a confidentiality agreement. </li>
<li>Participation on the Teton Peaks Residential Unit will require a background check and fingerprinting at the students expense.</li>
<li>Students must have a basic understanding of various mental illnesses, be willing and comfortable interacting with individuals who are suffering with severe mental illnesses, and maintain clear boundaries. </li>
</ul>
<h2 align="center">
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Prerequisites: </strong></span></p>
</h2>
<p>- Transportation <br />- Passing grade in Psych 342 Abnormal Psychology <br />- Completion of the internship application <br />- Completion of the Confidentiality and Security Agreement <br />- Completion of the Student Health Questionnaire <br />- Completion of the Educational Experience Checklist <br />- A recent TB (PPD) test <br />- An interview with Dr. Richard Cluff</p>
<p>Requirements:  This internship will require a minimal commitment of 2 credit hours which equate to 100 hours of service.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2 align="center" style="text-align: left;">BHC Internship Application
<p> </p>
<p>Name: ____________________________                 Major:  ____________________________</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Year in school:    Freshman _____   Sophomore _____  Junior  ______  Senior  ______</p>
<p> </p>
<p>GPA: _____    Phone Number: ________________________  Email:  ______________________</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Do you have personal transportation: Yes ______   No ________</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If no, what arrangements have you made to guarantee your ability to meet your  internship obligations?  ______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Available Blocks of time if selected as an  intern:_______________________________________</p>
<p>Have you completed the Abnormal Psychology Course:    Yes_________    No_________</p>
<p>Coursework related to this placement:  _______________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Previous positions of responsibility/leadership:   _______________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Other information that may be useful to us in making a determination of your  "fit" with this</p>
<p>Internship opportunity/placement:  __________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>______________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Upon completion make an appointment to meet with Dr. Cluff for a brief  interview and bring this application.</p>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:cluffr@byui.edu">cluffr@byui.edu</a></p>
<p> </p>
</h2>
<h3 align="center" style="text-align: left;">EASTERN IDAHO REGIONAL MEDICAL CENTER- IDAHO FALLS, IDAHO<strong><em> </em></strong></h3>
<h3 align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong><em>Educational Experience Checklist for Observation  Students</em></strong></h3>
<h3 align="center" style="text-align: left;">
<p><strong><em>The following checklist must be completed <span style="text-decoration: underline;">prior</span> to the  first clinical experience at EIRMC. </em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>A completed checklist must be submitted <span style="text-decoration: underline;">yearly</span> for all  on-site faculty and students. All signed and completed checklists are to be  returned to the EIRMC Education Department.</em></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>STUDENT NAME______________________________________________</strong></p>
<p><strong>FACULTY NAME______________________________________________  EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION___________________________________  PROGRAM________________________ DATE_____________________</strong></p>
<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p><strong>I agree that I have complied with all provisions in the EIRMC Student  /Faculty Policy (HR Policy 900.39).  These include:</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>1.   ______      Student Health Questionnaire</p>
<p>2.   ______      Signed copy of "Confidentiality &amp; Security Agreement"</p>
<p>3.   ______      Review of "Student Orientation Booklet"</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>All of the above documents and supporting verification are to be  retained and kept on file by the educational institution for each student.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________Date:  _______________</strong></p>
<p><em>Student Signature</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________Date:  _______________</strong></p>
<p><em>Faculty Signature</em></p>
</h3>
<h3 align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>Confidentiality and Security Agreement</strong>
<p>I understand that the facility or business entity (the "Company") in which or  for whom I work, volunteer or provide services, or with whom the entity  (<em>e.g</em>., physician practice) for which I work has a relationship  (contractual or otherwise) involving the exchange of health information (the  "Company"), has a legal and ethical responsibility to safeguard the privacy of  all patients and to protect the confidentiality of their patients' health  information.  Additionally, the Company must assure the confidentiality of its  human resources, payroll, fiscal, research, internal reporting, strategic  planning, communications, computer systems and management information  (collectively, with patient identifiable health information, "Confidential  Information").</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">1. I will not disclose or discuss any Confidential Information with others,  including friends or family, who do not have a need to know it. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">2. I will not in any way divulge, copy, release, sell, loan, alter, or  destroy any Confidential Information except as properly authorized. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">3. I will not discuss Confidential Information where others can overhear the  conversation. It is not acceptable to discuss Confidential Information even if  the patient's name is not used. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">4. I will not make any unauthorized transmissions, inquiries, modifications,  or purgings of Confidential Information. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">5. I agree that my obligations under this Agreement will continue after  termination of my employment, expiration of my contract, or my relationship  ceases with the Company. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">6. Upon termination, I will immediately return any documents or media  containing Confidential Information to the Company. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">7. I understand that I have no right to any ownership interest in any  information accessed or created by me during my relationship with the Company. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">8. I will act in the best interest of the Company and in accordance with its  Code of Conduct at all times during my relationship with the Company. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">9. I understand that violation of this Agreement may result in disciplinary  action, up to and including termination of employment, suspension and loss of  privileges, and/or termination of authorization to work within the Company, in  accordance with the Company's policies. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">10. I will only access or use systems or devices I am officially authorized  to access, and will not demonstrate the operation or function of systems or  devices to unauthorized individuals. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">11. I understand that I should have no expectation of privacy when using  Company information systems. The Company may log, access, review, and otherwise  utilize information stored on or passing through its systems, including e-mail,  in order to manage systems and enforce security. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: small;">12. I will practice good workstation security measures such as locking up  diskettes when not in use, using screen savers with activated passwords  appropriately, and position screens away from public view. </span></li>
</td>
<td valign="top">
<ul>
<li>13. I will practice secure electronic communications by transmitting  Confidential Information only to authorized entities, in accordance with  approved security standards. </li>
<li>14. I will: </li>
<li>a. Use only my officially assigned User-ID and password (and/or token (e.g.,  SecurID card)). </li>
<li>b. Use only approved licensed software. </li>
<li>c. Use a device with virus protection software. </li>
<li>15. I will never: </li>
<li>a. Share/disclose user-IDs, passwords or tokens. </li>
<li>b. Use tools or techniques to break/exploit security measures. </li>
<li>c. Connect to unauthorized networks through the systems or devices. </li>
<li>16. I will notify my manager, Local Security Coordinator (LSC), or  appropriate Information Services person if my password has been seen, disclosed,  or otherwise compromised, and will report activity that violates this agreement,  privacy and security policies, or any other incident that could have any adverse  impact on Confidential Information. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The following statements apply to physicians using Company systems  containing patient identifiable health information (e.g.  CPCS/Meditech):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>17. I will only access software systems to review patient records when I  have that patient's consent to do so. By accessing a patient's record, I am  affirmatively representing to the Company at the time of each access that I have  the requisite patient consent to do so, and the Company may rely on that  representation in granting such access to me. </li>
<li>18. I will insure that only appropriate personnel in my office will access  the Company software systems and Confidential Information and I will annually  train such personnel on issues related to patient confidentiality and access. </li>
<li>19. I will accept full responsibility for the actions of my employees who  may access the Company software systems and Confidential Information. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<p>Signing this document, I acknowledge that I have read this Agreement and I  agree to comply with all the terms and conditions stated above.</p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="408">
<p>Employee/Consultant/Vendor/Office Staff/Physician Signature</p>
</td>
<td valign="top" width="150">
<p>Facility Name and COID</p>
</td>
<td valign="top" width="121">
<p>Date</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="408">
<p>Employee/Consultant/Vendor/Office Staff/Physician Printed Name</p>
</td>
<td valign="top" width="150">
<p>Business Entity Name</p>
</td>
<td valign="top" width="121">
<p> </p>
<br /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Nov. 1, 2001                                                                                                                                                                           Attachment to IS.SEC.005</p>
<p> </p>
</h3>
<h2 align="center" style="text-align: left;">EASTERN IDAHO REGIONAL MEDICAL CENTER
<p> </p>
<p><strong>I.  STUDENT/ FACULTY ON-SITE HEALTH QUESTIONNAIRE</strong></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p><strong>NAME: ___________________________________ BIRTHDATE:  ____________</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>ADDRESS:  ______________________________________________________</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________PHONE:  ____________________</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION:  ______________________________________</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><em> Please answer the following questions and attach appropriate  documentation.</em></strong></p>
<p align="center"> </p>
<p><strong>1.         Have you ever had Chicken Pox (Varicella)?    Yes ____    No ____</strong></p>
<p><strong> If "NO": Attach a copy of Varicella titre results  <span style="text-decoration: underline;">or</span> proof of Varicella    Vaccination.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>2.         Were you born <span style="text-decoration: underline;">in <em>or</em> after</span> 1957?    Yes  ____  No ____</strong></p>
<p><strong> If "YES": Attach a copy of proof of <span style="text-decoration: underline;">two</span> Measles,  Mumps, and             Rubella </strong></p>
<p><strong> (MMR) Vaccinations <span style="text-decoration: underline;">or</span> attach a copy of results of  Rubella <span style="text-decoration: underline;">and</span> Rubeola </strong></p>
<p><strong> titres.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>3.         Have you ever had a positive reaction to a TB (PPD) skin  test? </strong></p>
<p><strong> Yes ____  No ____</strong></p>
<p><strong> If "YES": Attach copy of results of chest x-ray taken  within the last 12 </strong></p>
<p><strong> months.</strong></p>
<p><strong> If "NO": Attach copy of results of recent TB Skin Test  (PPD).</strong></p>
<p><strong> <em>AN ANNUAL TB SKIN TEST IS REQUIRED.</em></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong> SIGNED: ________________________________ DATE:  _________________</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Completed questionnaire and appropriate supporting documentation to  be retained and kept on file at the educational institution for each student. </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<span style="font-size: xx-small;">Copyright©   2011 BYU-Idaho</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">All Rights Reserved.</span></h2>
<div style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1848" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></CustomPageWithReturn>
