<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<CustomPageWithReturn ID="x56149" Name="Graduate School Opportunities" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Graduate School Opportunities</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Graduate School Opportunities</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="LeftNavGroup" label="Left Nav Return" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><ParentName type="string" label="Parent Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></ParentName><xPower Type="Link" Link="x42783" Name="Link" label="Link" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" LinkText="Graduate School Opportunities" Target="" Expanded="false" URL=""/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="100%">
<p>10/2012<br />Below is information for Juniors and Seniors who might be considering attending graduate school in Clinical or Counseling Psychology in the next couple of years.&nbsp; Our program here at Radford University provides excellent clinical and research training at the masters level and we are hoping to recruit some of your best students. Attached is a brief description of our program. I encourage students who are interested in learning more about our program to check out our website and then to contact me if they have additional questions.&nbsp; <br />Web address: <a href="http://www.radford.edu/content/chbs/home/psychology/programs/clinical.html">http://www.radford.edu/content/chbs/home/psychology/programs/clinical.html</a></p>
<p>We look forward to having more students from your school apply!<br />Sincerely,</p>
<p>Ann Elliott, Ph.D. (<a href="mailto:aelliott@radford.edu">aelliott@radford.edu</a>) 540-831-5790<br />Coordinator of the Clinical-Counseling Psychology Program<br />Radford University</p>
<p align="center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Interested in Graduate School in Clinical-Counseling Psychology?<br />Consider Radford University</span></strong></p>
<p>The goal of our two-year, full-time, Clinical-Counseling Master's Degree Psychology program is to prepare competent professionals by providing a strong theoretical and applied foundation for those wishing to work in the field of mental health counseling or for those wishing to pursue additional graduate or professional training in counseling or in clinical psychology.</p>
<p>The program provides students with training in the content areas of: normal and abnormal development, the assessment and counseling of individuals experiencing mental health issues, statistical and research methodology, and the ethical practice of mental health counseling.</p>
<p>Students complete two semesters of applied research training during the first year in the program and two semesters of internship training and supervision in a clinical setting during the second year.</p>
<p>For more information about our program, please check out our website: <a href="http://www.radford.edu/content/chbs/home/psychology/programs/clinical.html">http://www.radford.edu/content/chbs/home/psychology/programs/clinical.html</a></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: justify;">4/2012<br /><strong>Attention Psychology Students - Important Notice!<br />Gonzaga Universityis extending their deadline<br />For the next two weeks they will be accepting applications from interested BYU-I graduates<br /></strong>Contact:<br /> Lisa Bennett at Bennette@gonzaga.edu<br />Gonzaga University &bull; 502 East Boone Avenue &bull; Spokane, WA 99258-0102&bull; (800) 986.9585<strong><strong> </strong></strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>************************</p>
<p>12/2009<br />We are currently accepting applications for:&nbsp; <br /><strong>Masters of Arts degree in Family Therapy at the <a href="http://www.uhcl.edu/" target="_blank">University of Houston-Clear Lake</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>About Our Program </strong><br />The Family Therapy program at UHCL has been accredited by the <a href="http://www.aamft.org/cgi-shl/twserver.exe?run:COALIST" target="_blank"><strong>American Association of Marriage &amp; Family  Therapy</strong></a> (AAMFT) since 1983 making it one of the most established  programs in the United States. Our unique program offers students the  opportunity to become well-trained clinicians through our 61 credit hour degree  track which includes an <a href="http://www.uhclfamilytherapy.org/" target="_blank"><strong>on-campus clinical practicum</strong></a> (2 semesters)  and off-campus internship (2 semesters). We have over 20 internship placements  throughout the Houston metro area that provide students with excellent  experience opportunities.</p>
<p><strong>About UHCL</strong><br />Our <a href="http://www.uhcl.edu/" target="_blank"><strong>campus</strong></a> is located within a 524-acre wildlife and nature preserve offering students a  unique, tranquil environment. Students are also 30 minutes away from  downtown Houston (4th largest city in the U.S.) and 30 minutes from Galveston  beaches providing students with plenty to experience outside of the classroom.</p>
<p><strong>Our Faculty</strong><br />The<a href="http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/HSH/HOME/PROGRAMS/FT/TAB327670" target="_blank"><strong> faculty</strong></a> of the UHCL family therapy program  are active clinicians, supervisors, and researchers. They provide clinical  expertise in Emotionally Focused Therapy for couples, Latino families, gender  issues, and systemic work with families. In addition, active research groups are  available for students interested in presenting at national/regional conferences  and publishing in professional journals. Current projects include the following  topics: outcome-based research on EFT, Latino couples, international family  therapy trends, systems theory and creativity, and systems theory applied to  business settings.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Assistance</strong><br />We know that many students need financial assistance for their education.  UHCL offers the <a href="http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/FAO/Scholarships/Dollars_for_Scholars" target="_blank"><strong>Dollars for Scholars</strong></a> program for incoming  students that <strong><em>waives out-of-state tuition for students</em></strong> that qualify. In addition, the family therapy program offers competitive  scholarships annually to family therapy students. <a href="http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/FAO" target="_blank"><strong>The  Financial Aid Office</strong></a> can help with providing students with  low-interest loans and additional aid. In general, Texas offers a low  cost-of-living with affordable housing and low-cost tuition compared to other  metropolitan areas in the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>Admissions Process</strong><br />Admission to the Professional Psychology Programs at UHCL is competitive.  <strong><em>You must submit the program application materials between December  10 and January 25</em></strong> for admission to the program for the following  summer/fall.  Applications require students to submit an application with  letters of reference, official transcripts, and official GRE scores.</p>
<p>Download the <a href="http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/HSH/PORTLETS/Professional%20Psychology%20Documents/Prof%20Psyc%20Brochure.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>Professional Psychology Brochure</strong></a> for a  detailed description of the program, prerequisites, curriculum and application  process. Follow the application process as described in the Brochure, for which  you will need to complete the forms provided below:<br /><a href="http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/HSH/PORTLETS/Professional%20Psychology%20Documents/Application.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>Professional Psychology Application  Form</strong></a><br /><a href="http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/HSH/PORTLETS/Professional%20Psychology%20Documents/Recommendation.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>Recommendations Form</strong></a></p>
<p>We feel that the family therapy program offers a supportive environment to  students that want to receive high quality training. Our graduating students are  known for their excellent clinical skills. In addition, students seeking PhD  studies following the program are well-prepared and are accepted to some of the  top programs in the U.S.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="100%">
<p align="center" style="text-align: justify;">For further program information, feel free to contact us:</p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: justify;"><strong> </strong></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Dr. Brent Bradley (Program Director)<br />Phone: (281) 283-3396<br />Email: </strong><a href="mailto:bradleyb@uhcl.edu" target="_blank"><strong>bradleyb@uhcl.edu</strong></a><strong><br /></strong><a href="http://www.uhclfamilytherapy.org/" target="_blank"><strong>www.uhclfamilytherapy.org</strong></a></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: justify;">We look forward to hearing from you!</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1848" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></CustomPageWithReturn>
