<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56293" Name="Overview" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mission and Objectives of BYU Idaho Social Work Program</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mission and Objectives of Brigham Young University Idaho Social Work Program</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>The Social Work program at Brigham Young University - Idaho prepares students for generalist social work practice with individuals, groups, families and communities. The social work program at BYU-I has a mission that is appropriate to social work education as defined in the Educational Policy Section 1.1, Purposes of Social Work Education of the Council on Social Work Education. The BYU-I social work program mission is consistent with baccalaureate level training and preparing students for generalist practice and is consistent with the BYU-I institutional mission. The Baccalaurate Social Work Program at Brigham Young University - Idaho is accredited by the Council on Social Work Education.</p>
</div>
<p>The mission of the Brigham Young University - Idaho Social Work program is to support the overall mission of BYU-Idaho, and the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. To help students to learn to be disciple centered leaders; to exhibit faith in Jesus Christ as a principle of power and action, to act for themselves and accept responsibilities for learning and teaching, to exhibit integrity, understand the importance of human relationships, the dignity and worth of individuals and to love serve and teach one another. To help students develop social work knowledge, values and skills to be competent and effective communicators and professional social workers for generalist social work practice and Christian service with individuals, groups, families, communities and society.</p>
<p>To help students of diverse interests and abilities to use and integrate social work historically grounded purposes, philosophy, knowledge, values, supervision, consultation, scientific inquiry, and skills of the profession in order to develop competence, promote human and community well-being and for leadership in the evaluation and development of social policy, social service delivery systems, professional social work employment and for their roles as citizens and parents. To become aware of global perspectives, person and environmental factors, diversity, poverty, human right issues, to strive to eliminate poverty, understand economic and social justice, and prepare graduates to work within the context of their client's specific cultures. To strive to promote Christian heritage, understand how political, economic, social, cultural demographic and global contexts relate to person-environment transactions, to use new knowledge, scientific inquiry, technology, as appropriate, and to try to enhance the quality of life for all persons.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho social Work program has goals that are derived from its mission statement.</p>
<p>The specific program goals can be found in the <a href="Documents/sociology-social-work/studentmanual.2010%20%281%29.pdf">Student Manual</a>(PDF)</p>
<div>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<br />
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x41749" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
