<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56316" Name="Course Offerings " Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Course Offerings</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Course Offerings</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: left;"><img height="261" src="Images/new_image_structure/homepage interactive images/main-home-graduation.jpg" width="648" /></h3>
<hr />
<h3>Course Offerings for Education Majors 	
<hr />
</h3>
<script src="http://quickconnectfamily.org/blog_support/blogsupport.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 109 Introduction to Education &nbsp;(2:1:2)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">With the knowledge that everyone is a teacher, this course is designed to answer the question: What kind of teacher will I be? Through an overview of university programs (ECSE, ElEd, and SecEd), structures of schools, learning and teaching, the teaching profession, great minds in education, and potential field experiences, student will be prepared to make an informed career decision. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 200 History/Philosophy of Education &nbsp;(2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">Elementary Education and Early Childhood/Special Education Majors
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course provides future teachers with knowledge of the historical events, philosophies, and theories that have helped build American education; fosters in them an understanding of their own personal teaching philosophy; and encouraged them to develop the wisdom to follow the Savior as they strive to become master teachers.</div>
Secondary Education Majors
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: 24 completed university credit hours</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is a cornerstone of secondary teacher preparation at BYU-I intended to be a threshold experience for students. Its purpose is to develop, in each of us, firm educational roots through understanding historical events, theories and philosophy of education, broadened perspectives, and enlightened discernment. We will be encouraged to increase wisdom to follow the Savior as we strive to become master teachers. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 206 Education Technologies &nbsp;(1:1:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is an overview of electronic presentations, spreadsheets, concept maps, graphics, charts, graphs, social media, SMART boards, desktop publishing and ethics. Students will produce samples education related products. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 210 Introduction to Online Teaching &nbsp;(3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course serves as an introduction to the online teaching endorsement. Students will be oriented to the requirements and competencies necessary for receiving the online teaching endorsement from the state of Idaho. The development of online education and the philosophies and practices of the field of online learning will be explored. Students will take a competency and concept assessment that will serve as a diagnostic tool to develop their future learning path. The class meets twice a week synchronously through our Adobe-connect classroom. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 241 Elementary Early Field Experience &nbsp;(3:2:3)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is designed as an introductory practicum experience in the public schools. Students will have the opportunity to teach one-on-one, in small groups, and in whole class settings. Once a week students will attend an on-campus seminar to discuss practicum experience and to receive instruction. Students will be introduced to basic lesson planning, classroom management, teaching strategies, and professionalism. This course is a benchmark for continuation in education programs. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 242 Motivation and Management &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; ElEd Majors should take concurrently with ED 241</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is intended for all education majors, those with education clusters, and those wanting to improve the management of children in an ecclesiastical or home setting. It is designed to provide models of discipline practices where agency and respect are fostered and to help bridge the gap between theory and practice through exploration of management and motivation theories, practices, and teaching strategies. Strategies learned help in the creation and building of cooperative and inclusive classroom environments where all students are invited to actively participate. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 259 Integrated Science &nbsp; (4:3:3)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; FDSCI 101</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">The main objective of this course is to gain a solid foundation of content in biology, physical science, and earth and space science so pre-service teachers can be confident in teaching these concepts in elementary school classrooms. Students will gain confidence in basic concepts and principles of science and hands-on applications in teaching elementary school level science inquiry 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 304 Educational Psychology &nbsp;(3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">ElEd Majors and SecEd Majors are to enroll in their respective assigned classes.</div>
Elementary Education and Early Childhood/Special Education Majors
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is an intensive exploration of educational theories of learning and their impact on teaching methods and classroom practice. This course focuses on the three learning domains and their impact on brain research in memory and understanding</div>
Secondary Education Majors
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; 36 credits</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is an exploration of teaching and learning through educational theories of development, cognition, and understanding and the impact of this information on teaching methods and classroom practice. This course includes specific focus on the affective and cognitive domains and the impact of brain research in memory and understanding 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 312 Culture and Diversity &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students will analyze historic and present-day relationships between the American educational system and cultural dynamics. They will identify prejudices and discriminatory practices in society and their causes and in" uence on education today. Students will be introduced to sheltered instruction. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 313 Culture and Diversity Practicum &nbsp; (1:0:2)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This one credit additon to the ED 312 course is designed to give students experience in applying principles of cultural relativism. The course will consider individual and circumstantial responsiveness to the differences that exist in language, race, ethnicity, gender, class, age, ability, and religion. In addition to these variables a close investigation and analysis of language acquisition and development will be considered in light of helping teachers be more responsive to learning and development of the child with diverse backgrounds. This practicum will give the student opportunity to assess present levels of culturally and/or linguistically diverse students. After the assessment determine learning needs and work with a child or group of ESL children two times a week for about an hour for 12 weeks to increase ability in language and learning. The practicum student is required to do on-going formative assessment and design instruction that meets individual needs. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 341 Elementary Art Methods &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Total Course Fees: $15.00 			<br /> Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course provides K-12 pre-service teachers instructional experience in the visual arts. Emphasis is placed on the elements and principles of design, integration of the visual arts throughout the curriculum and instructional strategies aligned with the National Art Standards 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 342 Elementary Music Methods &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course for K-12 pre-service teachers establishes a classroom environment for musical development. Emphasis will be on the nine National Standards for school music programs, including: appropriate songs, activities, resources, instructional strategies and integration of music throughout the curriculum. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 343 Elementary PE Methods &nbsp; (2:1:2)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is designed to provide pre-service K-12 teachers with the curricular knowledge, pedagogical skills, practical application, and integration skills for teaching physical education in the schools. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 344 Idaho Comprehensive Literacy #1 &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course teaches linguistic and language structure basics related to early reaching skills. Pre-service teachers will learn strategies to differentiate instruction and assess early skills of phonological awareness, concepts of print, the alphabetic principle, phonics, syllables and morphology. Students must complete the state literacy exam upon completion of this course. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 345 Idaho Comprehensive Literacy #2 &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 241; ED 344</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">In this course, pre-service teachers learn strategies to teach and assess reading skills of fluency, expanded vocabulary, comprehension and writing. Students must complete the state literacy exam upon completion of this course. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 346 Literacy Practicum &nbsp; (1:0:2)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 345 or concurrent enrollment</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This is a supervised practicum experience in the public schools during which pre-service teachers apply the knowledge of reading instruction and assessment learned in ED 344 and ED 345. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 361 Secondary Education Principles of Teaching &nbsp; (3:2:3)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; ED 304</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course provides pre-service secondary education students opportunities workng in public school classrooms. A minimum 40-hour practicum includes observation and instruction experiences. Curriculum design, lesson planning, classroom management, instructional strategies, and assessment will be taught and implemented. Integration of multiple secondary education content areas is encouraged. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 402 Linguistic Assessment and Strategies &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SPED 310; ED 200</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Introduction to the assessment and evaluation of culturally and linguistically diverse students. This class reviews and deepens the student&rsquo;s understanding of language structure, bilingual development, bilingual assessment and bilingual education/intervention. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 409R Independent Readings and Projects &nbsp; (1-4:0:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is designed as an independent study program, with content and objectives determined by the student and a faculty member. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 420R Online Endorsement Supervision &nbsp; (1-3:0:3)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 210</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course serves a supervisory purpose as individuals seeking the online teaching endorsement complete their individual learning plans which were developed in ED 210, the introductory course. The student chooses between 1-3 credits and meets accordingly with faculty 1-3 times a week for consultation in mastering endorsement competencies and preparing for the culminating experience of the course which is to student teach in a online course 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 424 ECSE Assessment and Evaluation &nbsp; (4:3:2)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Total Course Fees: $30.00 			<br /> Prerequisites: ED 344; FDMAT108; ED 345; SPED 310</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students are introduced to and required to apply test and measurement theory, including the selection, administration and interpretation of assessment tools. The class includes assessment strategies spanning the continuum from informal to formal. Child progress monitoring and program evaluation are also included. Students use assessment data in mock MDT and IEP meetings to make decisions about children. Concepts are applied via video case studies and direct assessment of children. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 425 Strategies for ECSE &nbsp; (4:4:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Total Course Fees: $15.00 			<br /> Prerequisites: ED 424</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">To understand and apply approaches and theory of intervention strategies, classroom management, child guidance, and direct teaching procedures, with young children with and without special needs. The students will learn to use theories of direct instruction and collaboration and team interventions. The students focus on a case study format of assessing present levels, implementing IFSP/IEP process, implementing strategies to meet goals, and monitoring child responsiveness and overall progress. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 427 ECSE Senior Practicum &nbsp; (4:2:6)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 442; SPED 310; ED 443; ED 444</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students will receive practical, hands-on experience in classroom management, curriculum design, and collaboration while working in a public or private kindergarten classroom. Hours include time in public schools with a weekly seminar. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 441 Language Arts Methods &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: FDENG 101; FDENG 201; ED 241; ED 345</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is designed to introduce pre-service teachers to a vase array of instructional strategies appropriate for teaching grammar, punctuation, spelling, vocabulary, handwriting and forms of communication to students in grades K-8. Students will preassess their own skills and complete a self-directed study program. Students will learn to design lessons in the four methods of instruction aligned to the National Core Standards, teach mini-lessons in the six language arts areas, develop resources for teaching language arts and develop skills in integration of the language arts in other content areas. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 442 Elementary Math Methods &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 241; ED 200; MATH 205</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course provides K-8 pre-service teachers with instructional strategies in mathematics aligned with the National Council for Teachers of Mathematics (NCTM). 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 443 Elementary Science Methods &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; ED 241; ED 259</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course provides K-8 pre-service teachers with inquiry-based instructional strategies aligned to the National Science Education Standards. The Big Ideas of Science, the skills and attributes of scienti" c inquiry will be emphasized. Students will create lessons plans in all four instructional methods, create and teach science activities, and increase their skills in identifying and correcting common science misconceptions. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 444 Elementary Social Studies Methods &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; ED 241; FDAMF 101; HIST 201 or HIST 202</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course provides K-8 pre-service teachers with instructional strategies aligned with the framework of the National Council for the Social Studies and National Standards. The ten themes and major concepts of social studies will be emphasized. Students will create a social studies unit including elements of the instructional cycle as well as actively participate in increasing their skills in curriculum planning. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 448 Assessment and Evaluation in Education &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Concurrent Courses: ED 449</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course assists the K-8 pre-service teacher in developing and applying skills of constructing assessment devices as well as administering and analyzing test results with the ability to communicate student achievement in various settings. Student will learn to conduct a parent/teacher conference and develop skills in communicating assessment results. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 449 Elementary Senior Practicum &nbsp; (6:2:12)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 241, ED 346, pass all state literacy exams. 			<br /> Concurrent Courses: ED 448</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course combines educational theory and practicum experience in a K-8 classroom. The Idaho Standards for Teacher Certi" cation are emphasized and assed in order to prepare students for a successful student teaching experience. Students prepare lesson plans, teach lessons in the classroom, experience classroom management, interact with students and faculty, discuss educational theory, reflect on their teaching and receive formal teaching evaluations throughout the course. The course includes two days of practicum experience in a classroom as well as a weekly seminar. This is a benchmark course in the elementary education program. Student must complete both the academic and practicum experience satisfactorily in order to move to student teaching. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 461 Reading in the Content Area &nbsp; (3:2:3)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; ED 304; ED 361</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This senior level course is designed to immediately precede the student teaching semester. It is recommended that students take this course in conjunction with their content and general secondary methods courses. Students are taught assessment first planning and develop the abililty to facilitate learning through fostering general and content specific literacy skills. Prospective teachers will continue development of general teaching abilities with a focus on selection and creation of learner appropriate curriculum materials. Practical application of the skills of this and all previous courses are facilitated by 25-30 hours per semester of lab experience in local secondary schools. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 492 Student Teaching &nbsp; (10:0:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Total Course Fees: $90.00</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Student Teaching is the culminating experience, the capstone of the academic and professional training of a pre-service teacher. A twelve week practicum is completed in the public school classroom. A weekly seminar will serve as the forum in which student teachers can address challenges and concerns while sharing experiences, expertise, and successes. There are a vast number of education students that BYU-Idaho is trying to service. Because of this, be aware of the following: 1. There is a STRONG probability that your student-teaching placement will be a distant site. (Las Vegas, South Salt Lake and Davis County, Mesa, Boise) 2. Distant-site placements are limited to certain locations that have been organized for BYU-Idaho students. These sites have been researched and contacts made in order to help BYU-Idaho students gain a student-teaching experience. 3. There will be a disruption in your regular routine in order to participate in your studentteaching experience. You may need to move to a new area and re-establish your home. This may require you purchasing new items that you deem necessary. Also be aware that there may be additional expenses in transportation, housing, food, and utilities involved in your distant-site placement. 4. If you are in a campus-based placement, there will most likely be significant commuting for many of you. 5. There will be some unanticipated program expenses that develop through the program such as Praxis PLT, fingerprinting, and/or background checks. These are expenses that are not BYU-Idaho based, but mandated by school districts or the state. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ED 494 Student Teaching Seminar &nbsp; (2:0:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is ony available to students who are currently student teaching. It is a seminar-based class where student teachers have the opportunity to gather in person and through I-Learn discussion boards to more deeply explore issues related to the teaching profession and to read about, ponder and discuss ways to become better teachers. Six online modules and a few local seminars will be held at each of the student teaching sites (currently South Salt Lake, Davis County, Las Vegas, Mesa, and Southeast Idaho) over the course of the semester. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>ECD 350 Early Childhood Development: Toddler Core Principles &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisite: CHILD 150; CHILD 210 or ED 200; CHILD 300 			<br /> Concurrent: ECD 350L</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students will learn how to use assessment, collaboration, and developmental knowledge to prepare and create developmentally appropriate activities for toddlers both with and without special needs through play, with an emphasis in the areas of music, movement, books/literacy, art, make believe, fine and gross motor, sensory and blocks. Documenting toddler development and collaborating with families and professionals in the field of early childhood will be emphasized. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> ECD 350L Early Childhood Development: Toddler Lab &nbsp; (2:0:7) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Concurrent: ECD 350 			<br /> Prior application required</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students will receive practical, hands-on experience working with toddlers both with and without special needs and their families in a campus lab setting with a home visit component. In the lab, child focused planning will be determined by family collaboration, assessment, family identified goals and outcomes, and child interest. Students will develop activity plans, perform assessments, monitor progress, and document growth based on these elements. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> ECD 360 Early Childhood Development: Preschool Core Principles &nbsp; (3:3:0) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: CHILD 150; CHILD 210 or ED 200; CHILD 310 			<br /> Concurrent: ECD 360L</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students will learn how to use assessment, collaboration, and developmental knowledge to prepare and create developmentally appropriate lessons for preschool children both with and without special needs through developmentally appropriate practices, preschool curriculum development and implementation, child guidance, observation and assessment, and collaboration with parents and others in the early childhood community. The students will be expected to apply knowledge gained in this class in the preschool practicum class. This course is a co-requisite to ECD 360L: Preschool Lab. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> ECD 360L Early Childhood Development: Preschool Lab &nbsp; (3:0:12) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Concurrent: ECD 360 			<br /> Prior application required</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Students will receive practical, hands-on experience working with preschool-aged children both with and without special needs and their families in a campus lab setting with a home visit component. In the lab, child-focused planning will be determined by family collaboration, assessment, family identified goals and outcomes and/or Individualized Education Program (IEP) identified goals and outcomes, and child interest. This course will provide opportunities for application of core principles including developmentally appropriate practices, preschool curriculum development and implementation, child guidance, observation and assessment, and collaboration with parents and others. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;">
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div><strong>SPED 221 Issues in Special Education &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">A seminar class dealing with current issues in the field of special education. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 300 Assistive Technology &nbsp;(2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">An introduction to assistive technology devices and services utilized when working with students with disabilities in a public education environment. The legal basis for assistive technology will be the foundational structure for exploring the use of assistive technology for assessment; the use of assistive technology for access; the use of assistive technology to support academic learning; and the use of assistive technology as an augmentative communication tool. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 310 Exceptional Students: P-Grade 6 &nbsp;(3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200 or CHILD 150; CHILD 210</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course will emphasize the types and developmental patterns of specific exceptionalities (including giftedness, and poverty), addressing risk factors, etiology, characteristics, and classification of common disabilities. Focus will also be on legal issues, parent/student rights, responsibilities of teachers, both general education and special education, quality teaching for ALL students, including intervention strategies, accommodations, and the use of community resources to meet children&rsquo;s individual needs. Child maltreatment, including legal requirements, is introduced. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 360 Exceptional Students: Grade 6-12 &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200, ED 304 			<br /> Concurrent Courses: ED 461</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">This course is an introduction to Special Education for Secondary Education Majors. Course content includes history, laws, assessment and descriptions of common exceptionalities encountered in secondary school classrooms. Special emphasis is given to resources, classroom management and appropriate teaching practices. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED 380 Legal Issues, Policies and Procedures &nbsp; (3:3:0) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisite: SpEd 310</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">An in-depth examination of special education law, including the policies and procedures implemented in public education. IDEA, Section 504 and ADA will be compared and applied to the school setting. The six basic principles of IDEA and their implementation in special education services will be studied along with the legal requirements of disciplinary procedures for students with disabilities. Students will learn their role in ensuring that legal rights and responsibilities of students with disabilities, their parents and teachers are protected. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 381 Evidence-Based Practices &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisite: SpEd 310</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">An introduction to evidence-based practices as related to the field of special education. Types of educational research will be examined along with legal policies and criteria for identifying evidence-based practices. Students will be exposed to current evidence-based practices such as Response to Intervention and Positive Behavioral Interventions and Supports and their implementation in the educational environment. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED 391 Teaching Reading/Language Arts to Students with Disabilities &nbsp; (3:2:1) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SpEd 310; ED 345; ED 424 			<br /> Concurrent Courses: ED 345; ED 424 			<br /> Co-Requisite: ED 441</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Prospective special education teachers will explore methods, strategies, and accommodations for teaching reading and language arts within the context of special education. Cognitive, social and learning characteristics of students with reading difficulties will be identified. Students will have the opportunity to administer informal and formal reading assessments, interpret assessment data, and plan curriculum based on assessment outcomes. This course will be offered in a hybrid format. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED 392 Teaching Math to Students with Disabilities &nbsp; (3:2:1) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SPED 310; ED 424</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Prospective special education teachers will explore methods, strategies, and accommodations for teaching students with emotional and behavioral disorders. Cognitive, social and learning characteristics of students with emotional and behavioral disorders will be identified. Students will have the opportunity to administer informal and formal social and behavioral assessments, interpret assessment data, and plan curriculum based on assessment outcomes. Positive Behavioral Interventions and Supports as well as Behavioral Intervention Plans will also be developed using assessment outcomes. This course will be offered in a hybrid format. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED&nbsp;393 Social and Behavioral Strategies for Students with Disabilities&nbsp;(3:2:1) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SpEd 310; ED 345; ED 424 			<br /> Concurrent Courses: ED 345; ED 424</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Prospective special education teachers will explore methods, strategies, and accommodations for teaching students with emotional and behavioral disorders.  Cognitive, social and learning characteristics of students with emotional and behavioral disorders will be identified. Students will have the opportunity to administer informal and formal social and behavioral assessments, interpret assessment data, and plan curriculum based on assessment outcomes. Positive Behavioral Interventions and Supports as well as Behavioral Intervention Plans will also be Developed using assessment outcomes.  This course will be offered in a hybrid format. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED 400 Practicum &ndash; Elementary Education &nbsp; (4:2:6) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SpEd 391; SpEd 392; SpEd 393 			<br /> Concurrent Courses: SpEd 391; SpEd 392; SpEd 393</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Prospective special education teachers will receive practical, first-hand experience working with a special education teacher in an elementary school setting grades K-8. Opportunities for engaging in both formal and informal assessment activities, designing individualized curriculum, accommodating the general education curriculum, monitoring student progress, and collaborating with other professionals and families will be embedded within the practicum experience. A weekly two-hour seminar will serve as the forum in which students can address challenges and concerns while sharing experiences, expertise and successes. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter)</div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 421 Family and Community Relationships &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: ED 200; ECD 350; ECD 350L</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Perspective on providing family-focused services, with emphasis on families who have a child with special needs (birth through adulthood). Important issues to be discussed will be on empowering parents, strengthening family and professional partnerships, and interagency collaboration. Students will also develop a family service plan and have practical experience researching, accessing and linking families and community resources 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 422 Emotional and Behavioral Disorders &nbsp; (2:0:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SPED 310 OR SPED 360</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Introduction to behavior management: an elective course providing students with an in-depth look at emotional and behavioral disorders, their impact on development and learning, and appropriate home, classroom, and community interventions. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 423 Autism Spectrum Disorders &nbsp; (2:2:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SPED 310 OR SPED 360</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Designed as an elective course for students desiring a more in-depth knowledge and understanding of autism spectrum disorders. Topics include the history, diagnostic criteria, current research and theories, family impact, and researched-based strategies/interventions for working with individuals with autism. 			<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 441 Students with Severe Disabilities &nbsp; (3:3:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SpEd 380; SpEd 381; ED 424
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Prospective special education teachers will be introduced to the medical, cognitive, motor and communication needs of students with severe disabilities. The requirements and procedures for alternative assessment will be taught and implemented. Emphasis will be placed on designing curriculum including technology for students with severe disabilities. Legal and ethical considerations for providing educational services for students with severe disabilities will be explored. 				<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED 442 Curriculum and Instruction for Secondary Students &nbsp; (3:3:0) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SpEd 391, SpEd 392, SpEd 393 				<br /> Concurrent Courses: SpEd 391, SpEd 392, SpEd 393 				<br /> Co-requisite Course: SpEd 460</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Federal and state policies and procedures regulating services for secondary students with disabilities will be reviewed. Students will be introduced to the physical, cognitive and behavioral characteristics of adolescents. Common teaching models for secondary education will be explored along with instructional methods for teaching core content to secondary students with disabilities. Students will become acquainted with postsecondary options and transition services for students with disabilities. 				<br /> (Fall, Winter, Spring)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong> SPED 460 Practicum &ndash; Secondary Education &nbsp; (4:2:6) </strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Prerequisites: SpEd 391, SpEd 392, SpEd 393 				<br /> Concurrent Courses: SpEd 391, SpEd 392, SpEd 393 				<br /> Co-requisite Course: SpEd 442</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Prospective special education teachers will receive practical, first-hand experience working with a special education teacher in a secondary school setting grades 6-12. Opportunities for engaging in both formal and informal assessment activities, designing individualized curriculum, accommodating the general education curriculum, monitoring student progress, and collaborating with other professionals and families will be embedded within the practicum experience. A weekly two-hour seminar will serve as the forum in which students can address challenges and concerns while sharing experiences, expertise and successes. 				<br /> (Fall, Winter)</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />
<div>
<div class="somethingToClick" style="cursor: pointer;"><strong>SPED 492 Student Teaching Special Education &nbsp; (10:0:0)</strong> <span>&nbsp;</span> <span class="arrowDisplay" style="color: red; font-size: smaller;">&darr;</span></div>
<div class="contentDisplay" id="contentDisplayStuff" style="display: none;">
<div style="padding-left: 10px;">Total Course Fees: $90.00 				<br /> Prerequisites: All coursework must be completed, required exams passed (ie TCA), a background clearance from the assigned state, and all Praxis II exams must be passed.</div>
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">Student teaching is the culminating experience and capstone of the academic and professional training of a pre-service teacher. This practical experience lasts a minimum of thirteen weeks and is completed in a public school classroom. A weekly seminar will serve as the forum in which student teachers can address challenges and concerns while sharing experiences, expertise, and successes. The seminar is accompanied by preparatory experiences, including reading and writing assignments, reflection, and collaboration with others. Students are required to build a portfolio that they present and defend before a panel of faculty near the end of student teaching. Students who apply are recommended by faculty, and are selected and given the opportunity to be placed in partner schools and internships.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1851" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
