<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56899" Name="Silver Crest ES" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Silver Crest ES</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Silver Crest</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3><img alt="picture of school" height="250" src="Images/education-human-dev/Field Services_New/elem_silvercrest_bldg.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; border: 0pt none;" width="313" /></h3>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Silver Crest Elementary School</strong></h2>
<hr />
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Jordan School District, Riverton, Utah (South Salt Lake area)</h4>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Principal: Jill Durrant</h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://silvercrestelem.wikispaces.com/Silver%20Crest%20Elementary" target="_self">Silver Crest school's website</a></p>
<h5><strong>About Silver Crest Elementary</strong> 
<hr />
</h5>
<p>Silver Crest Elementary is located in the rapidly growing city of  Herriman. Our students come to us from Riverton City as well as from  Herriman. The Silver Crest faculty is dedicated to giving students a  well-rounded education with a good foundation in basic skills and ample  opportunities for social and emotional development. Our focus is on  student learning and achievement in the areas of literacy, numeracy, and  on creating and maintaining a positive school atmosphere. <strong> </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<h5><strong>General Information </strong> 
<hr />
</h5>
<ul>
<li>Silver Crest Elementary serves 735 students from K-6 on a modified three track year-round calendar (A, B, &amp; D Tracks). </li>
<li>The school day begins at 8:55 a.m. and ends at 3:50 p.m. except on  Fridays, when school dismisses at 1:50 p.m. to allow teachers time for  planning. </li>
<li>The modern, attractive, two-story building, which opened in August  of 2009, features large spacious classrooms, which are equipped with  audio enhancement and digital projection systems. Students have easy  access to a centrally located media center and a state of the art  computer lab. In addition, students have access to two mobile computer  labs.</li>
<li>The teacher/pupil ratio is 1:23 in 1st, 2nd, and 3rd grades, and 1:27 in 4th, 5th, and 6th grades. Actual class sizes may vary.</li>
<li>Bus service is provided for students who live 1.5 miles or more from the school</li>
<li>A nutritious hot lunch is prepared and served daily. The cost of  school lunch is $1.75. Free and reduced price lunches are available to  qualifying students. Students who wish to only purchase milk may do so  for $.25 a carton.<br />School Highlights</li>
<li>Silver Crest has a dedicated faculty of well-trained teachers who  work together in Professional Learning Communities to provide excellent  education opportunities for students in each learning center. Our staff  currently has 35 certificated teachers. This number includes specialists  in Speech/Language, Psychology, Literacy, and Special Education. In  addition, 30 classified employees serve in numerous other positions  throughout the school.</li>
<li>All certificated staff hold current teaching certificates with  several teachers having earned advanced degrees and educational  endorsements beyond the regular teaching certificates.</li>
<li>All staff members are formally evaluated on a regular basis for the  purpose of improving performance. Teachers continually participate in  professional development courses to improve instructional skills. </li>
<li>The curriculum meets or exceeds all district and state requirements.  Teachers use the Balanced Literacy framework to teach reading and  writing. Math is taught using a combination of Investigations and Scott  Foresman/Addison Wesley curriculum.</li>
<li>Technology is an important aspect of the school curriculum. Our  up-to-date computer lab, along with two mobile computer labs, enables  students (K-6) to learn and practice keyboarding skills, word processing  programs, safe Internet skills, and to work with software in all  curriculum areas. </li>
<li>Silver Crest students are expected to attend school regularly and to dress in clean, appropriate clothing. </li>
<li>Students at Silver Crest Elementary are taught responsible  citizenship as teachers set reasonable limits, reinforce positive  behavior, and employ programs to build student self-esteem.</li>
<li>Our student council and student safety patrol gives student leaders  an opportunity to gain valuable leadership and communication skills as  they work together to build school pride and to serve others.</li>
<li>An active PTA and School Community Council assist with activities and regularly give input on important school issues. </li>
<li>Visitors are and volunteers are welcomed and encouraged at Silver  Crest. Volunteers support the educational process through their work  within the classroom. It is our goal to have every family at Silver  Crest give of their time and service in the quest to educate the youth  of today and the leaders of tomorrow. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h5><strong>Did you know? </strong> 
<hr />
</h5>
<p>Silver Crest has been awarded an art grant to support our Art  Grandma. What is an Art Grandma, you ask? Well let us introduce her!<br /><br />Denise  Ludlow comes to Silver Crest 3 days a week and goes into our classes to  teach the kids different forms of art. Last year she paid for all of  the supplies herself because she has always loved art and feels that  kids need art.<br /><br />If you asked our Art Grandma why she chose to come  to Silver Crest she would say that her first reason is because she has  grandchildren that attend Silver Crest, but if you ask her now she would  tell you it is because of the wonderful teacher, staff and students  that we have here. She now has over 800 grandkids that attend Silver  Crest.<br /><br />Her philosophy is that anyone can succeed at art no matter  what their age is or what they think their talent level is. This year  she would like to do 11 original projects that include real water  colors, acrylics, abstract art, pointillism and color blending. All of  her projects can be done in an hour and can be done by anyone in the  school from the kindergartners to the 6th graders.<br /><br />Our Art  Grandma says that it is her privilege to work with the students and  teachers at Silver Crest and she wants to do anything she can to support  the great things that happen within the wall of our school. She also  want to thank everyone for supporting her dream!</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
