<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56898" Name="Midas Creek ES" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Midas Creek ES</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Midas Creek ES</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1><img border="0" height="261" src="http://schools.jordandistrict.org/midascreek/images/Building.jpg" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="545" /></h1>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Midas Creek Elementary School</strong></h4>
<strong> 
<hr />
</strong>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Jordan School District, Salt Lake City, Utah</h4>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Principal: Kevin Pullan</h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://schools.jordandistrict.org/midascreek/index.html" target="_self">Midas Creek </a><a href="http://schools.jordandistrict.org/midascreek/index.html" target="_self">website</a></p>
<h5><strong>Mission Statement      
<hr />
</strong></h5>
<p>Faculty and staff at Midas Creek Elementary value childhood,  compromise, effort, fairness, family, happiness, humor, kindness,  learning, organization, parents, policy, professionalism, progress,  quality, safety, and stewardship.</p>
<h5><strong>About Midas Creek        
<hr />
</strong></h5>
<p>Midas Creek Elementary is located in northwest Riverton City on the  west side of the Salt Lake Valley. The school's mission is twofold, to  maximize every child’s capacity as a learner, and to maintain a kind,  happy, positive, and nurturing environment for children. To help assure  each child’s success, Midas Creek Elementary has four areas of focus:  Literacy &amp; Numeracy, Differentiated Instruction, Gifted Education,  and Arts Integration.</p>
<p><img height="200" src="http://www.jordandistrict.org/wp-content/uploads/elem_midascreek_logo.png" style="border: 8px solid white; float: right;" width="200" />Faculty and staff at Midas Creek Elementary value childhood,  compromise, effort, fairness, family, happiness, humor, kindness,  learning, organization, parents, policy, professionalism, progress,  quality, safety, and stewardship.<br />Midas Creek parents are encouraged  to be involved in school. Teachers communicate regularly with parents  through home contacts and parent/teacher conferences.</p>
<ul>
<li>Midas Creek Elementary serves 1050 students on a year-round  schedule. Students are divided into four attendance tracks. Typically,  each track is in school for 45 days followed by 15 days of vacation. The  school takes a common vacation in July.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Midas Creek Elementary was completed in July 2007. The library/media  center is located in the middle of each classroom cluster. Classrooms  are arranged to encourage interaction among teachers and can be  reassigned by grade as the student population fluctuates.</li>
<li>The school day begins at 9:00 a.m. and ends at 3:55 p.m., except on  Fridays when school is dismissed at 1:55 p.m. to allow teachers time for  planning and making track changes.</li>
<li>The teacher/pupil ratio is 1 to 23 in first, second, and third  grade. The ratio is 1 to 16 in fourth, fifth, and sixth grade. The  actual class sizes vary. </li>
<li>The Midas Creek staff is well qualified. Teachers hail from many  different states with a variety of backgrounds and specialty training.</li>
<li>Teachers work in collaborative teams in order to give students access to the best talents of each teacher.</li>
<li>The curriculum follows state and District guidelines and meets or exceeds all elementary requirements.</li>
<li>Midas Creek students are expected to follow a Code of Conduct for  Responsible Citizens which spells out expectations for behavior.</li>
<li>Resource teachers give special help to students who are behind in math or reading.</li>
<li>A guidance specialist is available to provide group or individual  counseling. Speech therapy is also provided for students as necessary.</li>
<li>Midas Creek students have the opportunity to use computers as part of their regular curriculum.</li>
<li>The school benefits from a supportive, cooperative parent group. PTA  officers and parent volunteers provide hours of service to the school  each week.</li>
<li>Well-balanced meals are provided daily through the school's hot  lunch program at a price of $1.50 per lunch. Reduced rate or free  lunches are available to students in need.</li>
<li>Bus service is provided for students who live 1-1/2 miles or more  from school. About 25 percent of Midas Creek students ride the bus each  day.</li>
<li>Midas Creek Elementary is striving to meet the needs of accelerated  students. Problem solving and higher level thinking skills are  introduced in every classroom, and teachers modify instruction as needed  to meet the needs of each student.</li>
<li>Midas Creek is using Utah State Trust Lands grant funds to improve reading skills.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="http://schools.jordandistrict.org/midascreek/index.html" target="_self"><br /></a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
