<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56866" Name="Partner Schools" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Idea of Partner Schools</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Idea of Partner Schools</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div style="font-family: arial;">
<p><img height="260" src="Images/New image stucture/homepage interactive images/main-home-meetwithteacher.jpg" width="650" /></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho is producing higher and higher quality  teacher candidates and has established a reputation for producing among  the best prepared students regionally.&nbsp; Consequently, windows of  opportunity have availed themselves to us to consider placements  differently than we have in the past.&nbsp; Earlier attempts to do this were  not possible.&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">As you are aware, student teaching placements have  been accomplished in past semesters by gathering the names of students  by area where they wanted to be placed, and then sending those lists off  to the school districts those areas: Local, Boise, Las Vegas, Mesa, and  Salt Lake.&nbsp; Our ability to control the quality of that placement  diminished to nearly nothing at the point that those names moved from  our hands to theirs.&nbsp; Further, with rare exception, the only person in  the district that genuinely sought to assure certain quality outcomes  was the cooperating teacher and in some cases, even they have not been  committed to any specific outcomes.&nbsp; Thus, our office has and continues  to investigate other approaches to student teaching that would assure a  higher quality experience for every student.&nbsp; The idea of partner  schools came of that desire.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Further, we believe that our students can be a  great resource to schools when schools can come to depend on the  resource and plan around it.&nbsp; They can reduce student teacher ratios,  share ideas they have with their cooperating teachers based on best  practices they learned on campus, ask questions that cause reflection on  current practice, be involved in extracurricular activities, etc.&nbsp; We  hope that you can be a resource to them.&nbsp; Further, the partnership is  focused on collaboration and sharing between our faculty and their  faculty.&nbsp; We hope they will tell us how to produce a better product.&nbsp; We  hope to share research and experiences that could improve their  practice.&nbsp; The dialogue will make us both better.&nbsp; In the end, the  greatest benefactor will be the children in the schools we all serve.</p>
<h4 class="MsoNormal">Advantages for us and our students:    
<hr />
</h4>
<p class="MsoNormal">While each partner school has varying levels of  collaboration and advantages to us, each meets some basic parameters:&nbsp;  Partner schools are those schools where we have commitments from the  administrators to place at least one small cohort (3 to 5) of students  each and every semester, and increasing the continuity collaboration  between their staff, our clinical faculty, and our campus faculty.&nbsp; Each  partner school was selected by us or by district administration because  the school leader and most or all of the staff are committed to improve  their practice, to innovate, and to provide the highest quality  experience to their students and ours.&nbsp; This translates into many  advantages for us and our students:</p>
<ul style="margin-top: 0in;" type="disc">
<li class="MsoNormal">By the first week of April each year, students  will know their placement for Fall, Winter, and Spring and can begin to  interact with and prepare for their assigned classrooms.</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">Given that these partner schools will be aligned to BYU-Idaho alone, we will have greater interaction between their staff and:      
<ul style="margin-top: 0in;" type="circle">
<li class="MsoNormal">our clinical faculty (several times each week) &ndash; where trust can be built and collaboration will be fostered</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">our full-time faculty &ndash; as we will have  opportunities to visit and interact with their staff at least once a  semester and hopefully more by email, video conferencing, etc.</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">our students &ndash; hopefully we can increase the  interactions our students can have with real classrooms while they are  learning in our classes.&nbsp; The schools are open to it.&nbsp; What and how much  occurs will be up to you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">The opportunity to learn in an innovative, progressive environment, </li>
<li class="MsoNormal">Working with other student teachers from BYU-I in  the same school where they can collaborate with each other each day and  weekly in their cohort seminars.</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">Participating in the interview process (possibly improving employment opportunities),</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">In some cases, additional training or  collaboration opportunities will be provided (e.g., SIOP, REACH, Covey,  Center for Educational Excellence),</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">More regular contact and collaboration between site faculty and our campus faculty,</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">Clinical faculty selected who match the culture and climate of the school where they supervise,</li>
<li class="MsoNormal">Cooperating teachers who were matched to the student&rsquo;s demographic information and desires.</li>
</ul>
<p class="MsoNormal">&nbsp;</p>
<h4 class="MsoNormal">Advantages for the district and what we commit to:    
<hr />
</h4>
<p class="MsoNormal">Partner schools benefit because principals will  interview and select which students come to their schools and only  students who are well prepared will be allowed to interview.&nbsp; Students  can be selected to match the culture and climate of the school, to  fulfill current or anticipate needs of the school (employment), and to  address other concerns the school might have.&nbsp; The school will be able  to plan on the arrival and resource that these students provide.&nbsp; The  school will benefit from the infusion of energy and training on current  best practices that our students will bring.&nbsp; The school will influence  what and how we teach and we will influence what and how they teach.&nbsp;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">The idea for partner schools was not mine but  yours.&nbsp; I have discussed the need to such an experience with many of you  over the last six years I have been on the faculty.&nbsp; We have hoped for a  lab school and ways to increase the quality of our field experiences.&nbsp; I  am only implementing what we have talked about over that time.&nbsp; As I  have moved forward with these ideas, I have consulted with some of you  more than others.&nbsp; I believe the doors that have opened to make this  possible did not open by luck or good fortune, but by divine providence  and intervention.</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="text-indent: -0.25in;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; School districts become partners with us in producing future employees  that are better prepared and specifically prepared to the teach students  within the climate and culture of that district.</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="text-indent: -0.25in;">&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; School districts will have the opportunity to change what is taught on  our campus through regular dialogue about the areas of deficiencies our  students have.</p>
<p>Because our students become a dependable resource to the schools, the schools can use them in ways that they have not been</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
