<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x56868" Name="Fremont HS" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fremont HS</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fremont HS</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><strong><img height="227" src="Images/education-human-dev/Field%20Services_New/School%20Picture.jpg" width="681" /></strong></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><strong>Fremont High School</strong><br /><br /> Dr. Rod Belnap, Principal<br /><br /> fremont.wsd.net<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><hr /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">School Mission Statement</span><br /><br /> We educate and inspire. Prepare to learn. Prepare for life! Since 1994, our vision and mission has defined Fremont High School.&nbsp; We have steadily grown with strong leadership, excellent community partnerships and links to local universities and colleges, and have built a strong and effective learning community.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><br /><hr /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Principal's Message</span><br /><br /> &nbsp;Martin Luther King Jr. once said, "The function of education is to teach one to think intensively to think critically.&nbsp; Intelligence plus character - that is the goal of true education."&nbsp;&nbsp; Here at Fremont High School our learning focus is through the use of technology, mathematics, and literacy.&nbsp; These goals are designed to prepare our students for a better future and catapult them to brighter prospects.&nbsp;It is important for each of us, in the pursuit of our goals, to remember that intelligence, however, is not enough.&nbsp; We encourage students to dedicate themselves to helping society, to making things better for others.&nbsp; It is in that spirit that we will find great satisfaction in whatever we pursue as our educational passion.&nbsp; Each of our students has an incredible opportunity here at Fremont to "find their passion."&nbsp; Whether it is in career and technical education, writing, mathematics, agriculture, art, music, or a health related field (among others)... pursuing that passion makes them want to do more and &nbsp;learn more.&nbsp; The teachers and staff here at Fremont have our students' future in mind and want to help them achieve their goals through a belief in themselves that we help to foster. &nbsp;We want our students to know that they can accomplish anything they set their mind to through hard work and discipline as they learn to think critically and collaborate with others.&nbsp; Fremont is a special place where students can learn and discover. &nbsp;Here at Fremont, the future is bright!</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><hr /><span style="text-decoration: underline;">About</span><br /><br /> &nbsp;Fremont High School is located in Plain City, Utah.&nbsp; We have approximately 1800 students attending Fremont.&nbsp; Our staff at Fremont consists of a principal, three assistant principals, five counselors, 82 teachers, seven secretaries, 16 aides, five full time custodians, a CTE coordinator, one law enforcement officer, one computer technology specialist and one media specialist.&nbsp; Fremont offers 11 AP courses and multiple concurrent enrollment courses, including a bridge to health science track (BHST) as well as CNA courses for those aspiring to the medical field. All of these programs are designed to focus on student interests and strengths to help them prepare for college and career.&nbsp; We take educational best practice that is grounded in solid research and use it to develop an engaging learning environment.<br /> &nbsp;<br /><br /> We have a great study body at Fremont.&nbsp; We serve diverse student groups and provide them with many opportunities to excel.&nbsp; The classrooms here at Fremont are "student-centered" classes focusing on the needs of our students.&nbsp; We truly believe that EVERY student can learn and that learning is the fundamental purpose of our school!<br />&nbsp;<br /><br /> We recognize that technology is only going to become more vital in the future, the Fremont High community is dedicated to teaching and learning the latest technology, including LCD projectors, document cameras, smart boards, e-readers, tablets, and clickers, as well as social media and networking.&nbsp; Our teachers are encouraged to learn and explore new technology for student learning while using technology with their instruction. Our Bring Your Own Device policy encourages teachers and students to use their electronic devices as learning devices.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><br /><hr />&nbsp;<br />We are looking for enthusiastic student teachers ready to learn and teach... teachers that show their "zest" for teaching and kids. We have already had the opportunity to see the benefits from this co-teaching model in our building.&nbsp; We are excited for this opportunity and look forward to working with BYU-Idaho students that can help us build on the beliefs, goals, and commitments of Fremont High.&nbsp; We value a collaborative culture, so your commitment to collaboration will help to enhance the learning environment here at Fremont.<br />&nbsp;<br /><br /> Our collaborative school community helps new teachers feel comfortable with the staff and students.&nbsp; We can help to facilitate our students finding their "passion..." the thing will love to pursue in the future.&nbsp; With the support system here at Fremont High School, student teachers will leave our school with experiences that will help them step in to any classroom.<br /><br /></div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x26131" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
