<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56891" Name="Reagan ES" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Reagan ES</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Reagan ES</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Ronald Reagan Elementary School" height="310" src="Images/education-human-dev/Field Services_New/Reagan elem.(0).jpg" width="649" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Ronald Reagan Elementary School</strong></h2>
<hr />
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Nampa School District</h4>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Principal:<a href="x26162.xml"> Gregg Russell</a></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www1.nsd131.org/mainsite/schools/rgn/default.aspx">Click here to visit the schools website</a></p>
<h5><strong>Our Story</strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>The Ronald Reagan Elementary story began in 2002 as one of three new elementary schools added to accommodate growth in the Nampa School District. We serve students in the eastern part of Nampa and our school district.</p>
<p>Ronald Reagan is a welcoming, caring place where students in grades K-5 master the essential skills in preparation for a lifetime of learning. Our students also learn the building blocks of science, social studies, citizenship, and health complemented by art, music, and physical education in a comprehensive curriculum</p>
<h5><br /><strong>Our Students</strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>Our students come from a variety of backgrounds and experiences. We use these backgrounds and experiences to fuel our students learning.</p>
<table border="0" style="width: 422px; height: 195px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="background-color: #d5d5d6;">
<td><strong>Reagan ES<br /></strong></td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>District</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>565</td>
<td>Total Enrollment</td>
<td>15002</td>
</tr>
<tr style="background-color: #e1e1e1;">
<td>4.89%</td>
<td>English Language Learners</td>
<td>10.47%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>50.55%</td>
<td>Free/Reduced Lunch</td>
<td>59.31%</td>
</tr>
<tr style="background-color: #e1e1e1;">
<td>12.2%</td>
<td>Special Education Participants</td>
<td>7.95%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>0.00%</td>
<td>Migrant</td>
<td>0.00%</td>
</tr>
<tr style="background-color: #e1e1e1;">
<td>80.10%</td>
<td>Whites</td>
<td>62.97%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>15.01%</td>
<td>Hispanics</td>
<td>30.84%</td>
</tr>
<tr style="background-color: #e1e1e1;">
<td>4.89%</td>
<td>Other</td>
<td>6.19%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><img height="468" src="Images/education-human-dev/Field Services_New/Reagan elem2.jpg" width="621" /></p>
<h5><strong>What You Will Experience</strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>If you choose to spend a semester with our school, you will be immersed in many proven practices that increase student achievement. It is our goal that you will come willing to learn and leave with valuable frameworks that will enrich your teaching career. Here is an example of some of our successful practices.</p>
<h5><strong>Professional Learning Communities</strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>Our school's PLCs are learning focused, collaborative, action oriented, geared toward best practice, committed to improvement, and results oriented. Our teachers meet monthly as teams for several hours to assess student data and plan instruction. Our PLCs are based upon Richard Dufour's Four Critical Questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is it we want students to learn?</li>
<li>How will we know if each student has learned it?</li>
<li>What do we do if students haven't learned it?</li>
<li>How do we enrich the material for students who have learned it?</li>
</ul>
<h5>Other items you will be exposed to include:</h5>
<ul>
<li>Essential Content based on Endurance, Leverage, and Readiness</li>
<li>Common Formative Assessments</li>
<li>Data Tracking</li>
<li>Student Feedback &amp; Motivation</li>
</ul>
<h5><br /><strong>Three Critical Commitments</strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>Our school is highly involved in three critical interventions designed to increase student achievement. Each of these commitments are intertwined into our daily activities. They simply are "what we do".</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. Provide student feedback based on learning goals and common formative assessments<br />2. Ensure effective teaching using a common instructional model<br />3. Build student background knowledge</p>
<h4>Staff Focus</h4>
<p>Each month our staff "goes to class" to learn about best practices. Our staff meeting time is not based around the day to day operations of our school; instead, it is a prime learning time where we study books and learn from one another. In our school, learning never stops.</p>
<h4>Frameworks</h4>
<p>Our school prides itself around being intentional and purposeful in everything we do. To do this, we use frameworks to guide our thinking. You will be exposed to many different frameworks that will enrich your career and practice, hone your ability to think critically about instructional design, and enhance your understanding about effective instructional models-how and when to use them strategically to get results.</p>
<h4>McRel Plans</h4>
<p>Our school incorporates school wide plans for various student populations. Each of these plans are based on student data and are developed with staff input. These plans then help guide our teacher's instruction and create a school wide focus for improvement.</p>
<h3><br />Recommended Readings</h3>
<p>Each of these books will help enrich your experience at our school. These are highly recommended if you consider applying to our school.</p>
<ul>
<li>Learning By Doing: A Handbook for Professional Learning Communities at Work by Richard DuFour - PLC's are a common word in education today. We pride our selves in working hard to incorporate the key components of a PLC.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>How The Brain Learns by David Sousa - This is a fabulous resource on how the human brain learns. This book is the basis for our common framework of instruction.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Building Background Knowledge for Academic Achievement by Robert Marzano - A valuable resource to develop a framework on how to increase student background knowledge.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Classroom Instruction that Works by Robert Marzano- Another valuable book designed to create a framework of instruction.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Getting Serious About School Reform: Three Critical Commitments by Robert Marzano - An excellent resource to learn about proven interventions that increase student achievement.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Reagan Elementary, Nampa School District, BOISE Area</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
