<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56971" Name="By-Laws" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">By-Laws for Education Council</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">By-Laws for Education Council</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Article I Official Name &amp; Membership</strong><br /><em>Section 1:</em> The name of the Society  shall be Brigham Young University-Idaho Education Society, hereinafter  referred to as the Education Society.</p>
<p><em>Section 2:</em> Membership in the Education Society will be determined according to the following requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>o An accepted student of Brigham Young University-Idaho. </li>
<li>o A declared Education Major or of some major affiliated with Education. &nbsp; </li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Article II Purposes &amp; Goals <br /></strong></p>
<p><em>Section 1 </em>On<em>e</em> monthly activity (no more than four  in a semester) will be planned to promote networking and professional  development within the Teacher Education Department.</p>
<p><strong>Article III Elections</strong></p>
<p><em>Section 1:</em> Elections for officers will be conducted during the first meeting of the new semester. &nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Section 2:</em> Students off-track are able to participate but not as council members.</p>
<p><em>Section 3:</em>&nbsp; All positions will be for one semester except the vice president /president elect position.</p>
<p><em>Section 4:</em> An application with a &nbsp;faculty recommendation &nbsp;is required.</p>
<p><em>Section 5</em>:&nbsp; Positions available during the election, that  will be voted on during the meeting are as follows:&nbsp; Vice President/  President-Elect, Secretary/Treasurer and Publicity Coordinator.</p>
<p><em>Section 6:</em> Representatives (Secondary, Elementary, and Early Childhood/Special Ed.) will be appointed by the presidency &amp; advisors.</p>
<p><strong>Article IV Officers &amp; Duties</strong></p>
<p><em>Section 1:</em> The President is to head up and run the Education  Society under the direction of the advisor, department head, and  College Dean of Education. They will report to the advisor about Society  events. They oversee the Vice President and Secretary/Treasurer in  assisting in the needs of the Education Society. He/she will supervise  the committees.&nbsp;&nbsp; He/she will conduct or delegate to the Vice President  the responsibility to conduct council meetings.&nbsp; A meeting agenda will  be sent to the advisor a day before the meeting.</p>
<p><em>Section 2:</em> The Vice President/ President Elect is to work  with the other presidency members in running the Education Society under  the direction of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College  Dean of Education. The V.P. will prepare to preside over the next  semester.</p>
<p><em>Section 3: </em>The Secretary/Treasurer is to work with the other  presidency members in running the Education Society under the direction  of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean of  Education. Meeting minutes, accounting of funds provided by the  University and a semester budget will be recorded by the Secretary/  Treasurer.</p>
<p><em>Section 4:</em> The Publicity Coordinator is to work with the  other presidency members in running the Education Society under the  direction of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean  of Education.&nbsp; Emails to be sent out for activities will be created and  sent to the advisors for review.&nbsp; The advisors will be responsible for  distributing the emails.&nbsp;&nbsp; Posters and other publicity will be part of  the job (school requirements will be followed).</p>
<p><em>Section 5</em> Representatives (Secondary, Elementary, and Early  Childhood/Special) will work with the other presidency members in  running the Education Society under the direction of the President,  Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean of Education.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article V &nbsp;Council Members and Responsibilities (Financial rules, meetings and governing policies)</strong></p>
<p><em>Section 1:</em> The council will meet twice a month and report on  their job and responsibilities and inform council members of  occurrences in their committees.</p>
<ul>
<li>o The presidency and the advisor will assign the specific meeting time and place. </li>
<li>o Meeting times (1st &amp; 3<sup>rd</sup> Thursdays @2:00) and location will be announced to concerned parties at least one week in advance. </li>
<li>o All council/presidency meetings must have at least one advisor present</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Section 2 </em>One monthly activity will be planned to promote networking and professional development within the Teacher Education Department.<em>: </em>&nbsp;The Council will plan and execute the activities while staying within the budget.<em> <br /></em></p>
<p><em>Section 3 </em>Committees may be formed as needed.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1851" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
