<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x56911" Name="TESOL (Any major)" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">TESOL (Any major)</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">TESOL</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3><img alt="Students" height="261" src="Images/new_image_structure/homepage interactive images/main-home-classdiscussion.jpg" style="border: 5px solid white;" width="648" /></h3>
<h3>TESOL 497: TESOL Teaching Practicum</h3>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Michael Paul Ph.D.</p>
<h5><strong>Introduction</strong>&nbsp;</h5>
<hr />
<p>Many districts, including all the  districts in California, are now requiring an ESL or related endorsement  to teach in their districts.&nbsp; While not required in other districts,  students applying to them would have a significant advantage over other  applicants by having the endorsement. It is strongly recommended  especially for ELED majors.</p>
<p>The TESOL Practicum is associated with the TESOL minor (or TESOL  endorsement for ECSE or ELED) and is the culminating experience of the  20 credit program.&nbsp; It leads to the English as a New Language (ENL)  endorsement in Idaho or a similar endorsement in other states* to teach  children who are learning English as a second language while learning  their other curriculum.&nbsp; It can be taken as a stand-alone course offered  in the Upper Snake River Valley (Madison County and surrounding areas)  or attached to student teaching completed in other areas (Nampa, Las  Vegas, Mesa, or Salt Lake).</p>
<p><em>* Requirements differ by state.&nbsp; You are advised to know those  requirements and take additional courses or experiences to be prepared  for the requirements of the state in which you intend to be certified.</em></p>
<p><em><br /></em></p>
<strong>Timing</strong> 
<hr />
<p>TESOL 497 should be completed in conjunction  with student teaching. You will be placed in a school with a high  number of English Language Learners and work with a qualified and  experienced ESL teacher.</p>
<p><em><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Students must have completed all  minor required classes and have passed the English to Speakers of Other  Languages (0631) Praxis exam.</em></p>
<p><em><br /></em></p>
<h5><strong>Description </strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>This course fulfills a requirement of  the State of Idaho that all people certified in TESOL have some TESOL  teaching experience before the graduate. Students will be assigned to a  public school where they will work with students whose first language is  not English.&nbsp; In most cases, the typical TESOL Teaching Practicum will  involve teaching those students English or assisting them in  successfully completing other school subjects.&nbsp; The BYU-Idaho student,  working with school officials, will work out a schedule where he or she  will work with non-native speakers of English for a minimum of sixteen  hours during the semester.&nbsp; The sixteen required hours will not include  prep time in creating lessons and other teaching preparations.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong>Topics </strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>Guided instruction of non-native speakers of  English.&nbsp; Topics of instruction will be English vocabulary, syntax,  morphology, phonetics &amp; phonology.&nbsp; Students may also assist  non-native speakers of English with other school subjects.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong>Objectives</strong></h5>
<hr />
<p>The TESOL 497 student will gain  experience teaching and interacting with non-native speakers of English  in a public school setting.&nbsp; He or she will gain an understanding of the  needs and challenges of such students and how best to meet them.&nbsp; He or  she will also become familiar with the culture and environment of the  public schools.&nbsp; The experience will be invaluable as the TESOL 497  student embarks on a career in public education where so many students  need services in this area.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong>Links </strong></h5>
<hr />
<strong> </strong> 
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/ForeignLanguage/TESOLedminor.htm" target="_self">BYU-Idaho TESOL Education Minor/Endorsement Information</a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sde.idaho.gov/site/teacher_certification/" target="_self">Idaho: State Department of Education: Teacher Certification</a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sde.idaho.gov/site/teacher_certification/subject_area.htm#15" target="_self">Idaho: State Department of Education: ENL Endorsement</a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.ets.org/s/praxis/pdf/0361.pdf" target="_self">Praxis Exam: English to Speakers of Other Languages (0631)</a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.ets.org/praxis/prepare/materials/0361" target="_self">Praxis Preparation</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For&nbsp;additional information about the TESOL Minor, Endorsement, or TESOL 497 please contact:</p>
<p>Michael Paul</p>
<p>Office: 471 Smith</p>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:paulm@byui.edu" target="_self">paulm@byui.edu</a></p>
<p>Phone: (208) 496-4315</p>
<p><strong>For&nbsp;additional information about practicums, student teaching, and internships please go <a href="http://www.byui.edu/FieldServices/contacts.htm" target="_self"><em>click here</em>.</a></strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19230" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
