<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x57076" Name="Student Letters" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Student Letters</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Student Letters</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Jane from New York</p>
<p>Dear Future student,</p>
<p>Brigham Young University Idaho is a great place to further your education. This University offers each of its students an opportunity to achieve a higher education but it also supplies each student with an environment where they can not only feel the spirit but also learn by the spirit.</p>
<p>As you are on your journey to getting a college education there are three important tools you need in order to accomplish your goal of graduating from college. The most important tool you need to succeed in college is to make a plan. Set up goals that you would like to accomplish before you leave school. First start off with small, realistic achievable goals then as you complete these goals start branching out and make challenging goals that will help you meet the requirements you need to finish college. A tool to help accomplish both small and large goals would be to make a semester calendar to keep track of all your classes, assignments, test and other important meetings you might have for the semester. Then make a weekly schedule that you can keep with you to keep you up to date. The semester calendar could be considered a large goal and the weekly schedule can be like your smaller goals that you can check off each week.</p>
<p>The second important tool you need to help you succeed in college is time management make sure you are setting up enough to time to get all your assignments done on time. Try your best not to procrastinate do not put off any homework or studying time, prioritize and make sure you are taking the time to get all your work done before they are due. But also set aside a time for you to relax and meditate or do whatever it is you need to do to make sure you are getting enough sleep and keeping yourself healthy.</p>
<p>The last tool you need that will help you become a successful student is always going to the Lord with all your concerns and trying your best at everything you do. Make sure you always utilize all the schools academic tutoring centers on campus and always contact your instructor and keep them up to date on how you are doing in all your classes. One last thing to keep in mind is to make sure your GPA is always above a 2.0 to avoid getting on academic probation or suspension these things will hold you back and be a stumbling block in your academic life. Be sure to do your best and allow the Lord to take care of the rest</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tia from Idaho</p>
<p>As you enter into the life of a college student you will recognize that standards and education will increase significantly. You may either panic or take the advice the Lord has given us in The Doctrine and Covenants, Section 6 verse 36, "Look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear not."</p>
<p>Brigham Young University-Idaho has Academic Standards so that we can achieve all that our Father in Heaven has in store for us. Therefore, there are three topics I would like to address to you at this time that will help you discover what it is that Heavenly Father sees in you. First, you can learn to not fear class work by adjusting your schedule so that you may leave enough time to focus on each class. You may do this by understanding which sacrifices are more important and recognizing the things in your life that will not lead to a successful education. Managing time is of great worth to you emotional, physically, and spiritually.</p>
<p>Second, never doubt that you are capable in achieving success in your education. There are plenty of resources to provide help to students. Free tutoring and workshops that can help you learn skills that will support you with an increase of knowledge. Asking for help is showing you are humble and have a desire to grow. We are all born into this world with different talents and abilities. It is okay to ask for help and then remember to use your talents to help others increase their knowledge as well.</p>
<p>Third, as we look to the Lord and prayerfully seek the correct career path through prayer and fasting. You will know that you are following the right advice. So in times of hardship during your education period, which there will be many, remember it is the Lord who has directed you. We know the Lord would never lead any of us astray, but he will let us be stretched so that we can grow and become more like him.</p>
<p>Brothers and Sisters education is part of our Heavenly Father's great plan, remember him always and you will be comforted and you will understand what it is you must do to achieve all that he has in store for you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Madison from Oregon</p>
<p>Hey there!</p>
<p>I am just finishing up my Junior year at BYU-Idaho and I wanted to share with you a few of the things I have learned.  Hopefully these things will help you be successful as well.</p>
<p>First, while it is important to take a full course load and make the most of your time here&hellip; do not overload yourself.  It is best if you take enough courses to stay busy, but you do not want to fail any either.  Make sure you leave enough time to study and prepare.  It will be tempting to fill your time with social activities.  I agree that this is a fun time in life, but don&rsquo;t forget you are here for an education and you need to put it first.</p>
<p>Second, do not procrastinate.  This has taken me multiple semesters to learn the hard way.  It makes your life much more stressful and you are more likely to feel overwhelmed.  If you know you have an assignment coming up, do not put it off!  Often it will take longer than anticipated, and there is always the chance of the internet going down.  This is a pain, but is not nearly as serious if you try to get assignments done early.</p>
<p>Third, take care of yourself.  Make courses and school work your top priority, but overall well-being is important.  You will be able to concentrate better if you get enough sleep.  Exercise and healthy eating are also more important than you might realize.  Even 30 minutes of exercise can make a big difference.  Not only will you feel better, it also helps your immune system stay strong.  Eating healthy will fuel your body in a good way and help you avoid sugar crashes and weight gain.</p>
<p>I wish you the best during your time here at this wonderful university.  This really can be the best time of your life.  It is a time of growth, changes, and shaping who you will be for the rest of your life.  Work hard, have fun, and reach for your fullest potential&mdash;you can do it!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alma from Texas</p>
<p>You are here at BYU-Idaho for many reasons, but a very important one is to obtain an education. When I first entered college, I took a lot of things for granted. I didn't realize that to be learning is a big blessing in our life. Not everyone gets the opportunity that we have to learn and choose a profession. As a freshman, settling into college, from a totally different state, was definitely a challenge. I learned that one must be able to adjust to our surroundings and be willing to put a lot of effort into what we do.</p>
<p>There are plenty of reasons why student fail in their academics. In my case, it was the fact that this is a church school and I have only been a member of the church for a year. Its hard to adjust to things, very. Then there may be a sudden tragedy. That was my case this past semester and I didn't know how to manage my time, my classes, and my grief. There is also illness, that affects students. Like I said, there are plenty of more reasons.</p>
<p>With these reasons in mind, I think I should advice students that whatever difficult situation they are going through, the school has plenty of resources to help them overcome these adversities. That's what I should have done when I was going through all these hard times during my first semester. There are tutors, counselors and our fellow professors and classmates that can help us overcome these things. Also, never forget that our Father in Heaven loves you. Remain firm in your faith and keep pressing forward. The first semester in college may be the most difficult. Adjusting to a new city, state, maybe even country, is difficult. Living away from home is too. But we should always remember to keep trying hard and not to give up.</p>
<p>If you get put in academic warning, the next semester, enroll for the necessary credits, seek help with your academic advisors, and enroll in tutoring. There are many things that the school offers so that as students we do not fail.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hadley from Idaho</p>
<p>Three things of advice:</p>
<p>1. I might sound really dumb when I say this but make sacrifices to do your school work over anything else. Don&rsquo;t go hang out with friends and put off homework until later, because when it will be due before you even get started most of the time if you put it off so DON'T PROCRASTINATE.</p>
<p>2. If you need help in a subject don&rsquo;t be scared to go to the resources available at the school to help you. I&rsquo;m not saying go there for every little thing though, just the things you really don&rsquo;t get. Try it yourself for an hour or two and if you don&rsquo;t get it by then then go get some help because they can really help you.</p>
<p>3. Stay true to the church and the school. When things are going good with you and the gospel then things will go good with school I promise. If you start to slack off going to church or don&rsquo;t read your scriptures as much as you need to then things will start to go downhill pretty fast. Take my word on it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Chelsea from Washington</p>
<p>If I could give advice to any upcoming freshmen about this school it would be to use all the accessible resources as possible, use your time wisely and start out with classes you think you could manage. These things will help you out a ton your first semester and could meant the difference between a pass and fail grade.</p>
<p>There are so many helpful tutors and teachers that are willing to put so much of their time into helping you with any of the questions you have on homework or anything in the lectures. Free tutors are something you should definitely take advantage of. We are really lucky to have the opportunity to have such a valuable tool accessible to us. The teachers are very helpful also and most of them take their personal time to help you with any problems you are having in class. You can email them at any time of the day and you are guaranteed a personal response. There is also an amazing library which you have easy access to at any time. That covers a very large range of topics and it is very useful when writing a paper.</p>
<p>Using your time in the most efficient and effective way possible in crucial in college. its so hard to focus on school up at college. especially your first year of college your finally free from your parents and rules and all you want to do is hang with your friends and party all night long. So its very easy to forget that you have a test or quiz you were supposed to be up all night studying for or a huge homework assignment due in the morning that you completely space on. So creating a schedule or limiting your partying and putting more time into your study&rsquo;s would be the best thing you could do for your grades.</p>
<p>Something I really wish I had done my first semester is take easier classes. I&rsquo;m not the smartest person in the world to begin with so I don&rsquo;t know what I was thinking when I tried to take all my hard classes my first semester. But my grades definitely suffered from it. I would take some of the easier classes just to see how I do with them and then take harder classes in the future when I feel I&rsquo;m ready to handle them. Taking too many hard classes can overwhelm you at times and cause you to be unfocused and very stressed.</p>
<p>So basically in conclusion I would really advice you to make the most of your time at BYU-IDAHO. take advantage of the tutors and ask the teachers for help and stay in contact with your mentors and counselor. Treat your education like a job. From eight to five stay focused on your studying and get your homework done and then you&rsquo;ll have time to relax and know that you have everything done. Have fun.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Heidi from Utah</p>
<p>Dear Student,</p>
<p>I just completed my first semester at BYU-Idaho, and I loved it! Good roommates, good classes and teachers, and just fun all around. There was however, one part that I didn&rsquo;t enjoy; end of semester grades.</p>
<p>First things first though. If you&rsquo;re reading this because you are just starting college here at BYU-Idaho, welcome! As I mentioned in the above paragraph, I&rsquo;ve loved it here, and I hope you do too. If you are continuing with your BYU-Idaho education, good for you; keep going! Now that I&rsquo;ve said my hellos, I can get to the main point of this letter, which is the riveting subject of succeeding in school and maintaining Satisfactory Academic Standing. Really though, it isn&rsquo;t too bad.</p>
<p>Picking back up where we left off in the first paragraph, most of the grades I got in my classes were lower, due to my own laziness. I&rsquo;ll spare you the short novel and just skip to the conclusion: because of my less-than-stellar GPA, I was put on Academic Warning and needed to complete the online Achieving Academic Success Workshop to help get me back up to Satisfactory Academic Standing. Despite my misgivings, it turned out to be a really good thing. I learned, among other things, how to calculate my SAP and what the BYU-I website had to offer by way of services. Looking back on my first semester and the AASW, I picked three points that I have learned, or three points that I should have focused more on, that would help in getting higher grades: eat your frog, study space, and persistence.</p>
<p>Eat Your Frog. One of the clips I watched while completing the AASW was all about this concept. The saying from which they pulled it was this: &ldquo;If the first thing you do each morning is eat a live frog, nothing worse can happen for the rest of the day!&rdquo; Agreed. Now, you don&rsquo;t want to really eat a live frog each morning, that wouldn&rsquo;t be good for you. But, if you do the biggest thing on your list, the homework or assignment you least want to do, and you do it first before everything else, than your day can only get better.</p>
<p>Another way to look at it is this: don&rsquo;t procrastinate. Procrastinating is hard work. I&rsquo;m not just saying that either, I speak from experience. After I saw that video, I decided to make that my motto, and it takes a huge load off your back when you get the hard stuff done first and you don&rsquo;t spend the rest of the day (or week, or semester) having it weigh on your mind.</p>
<p>Study Space. Where do you study for a class or do your homework? The library, your apartment, outside? I found that if I tried to study in my apartment, there were too many distractions. This might not be true for everybody, but it was certainly true for me. Especially if any of my roommates were home, it was extremely easy to distract myself from my homework by involving myself in whatever they were doing.</p>
<p>The atmosphere you&rsquo;re in affects how you act. If you are in an area where people are laughing and being active, or doing things other than homework, chances are that it will be harder to concentrate on your own work. The library is nice that way; everybody there (or most everybody) is working on their studies. Pick a place to study where there aren&rsquo;t a lot of distractions, where you will be able to work on just your homework.</p>
<p>Persistence. This goes hand-in-hand with the aforementioned concept of procrastination. Work before play holds true; even though it may be easier (at first) to play before you work, it pays off in the long run to do your work first. First and foremost, you&rsquo;ll probably get more sleep if you finish your homework before you go have fun. Just push through the work, and keep in your mind the future; think about the consequences of doing or not doing your work right now. Easier said than done, I know, but it will pay off.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s recap: Eating your frog equals no procrastination. It may seem easier, but you&rsquo;ll hate yourself at the end of the semester when you have to start a project due that&rsquo;s already late. The proper study space assists in your study instead of detracting. And finally, persistence will always pay off in the long run, and it you will feel accomplished. Got all that? It&rsquo;s not a whole ton, really. Just remember that sooner is better than later when it comes to your classes in college, and work through the hard times. One piece of advice my dad has always given me that I&rsquo;ve found true in my studies is this: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s easier to keep on top of the work than it is to dig yourself a hole and then try and climb out.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Best of luck in your studies!</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x44649" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
