<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57001" Name="Overview" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Overview</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Overview</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="text-align: center;">DEPARTMENT OF THEATRE &amp; DANCE</h4>
<p style="text-align: left;">The Theatre Area of the Department of Theatre &amp; Dance seeks to engage its participants in a vital dialogue that addresses the needs of a community, educates, and provides an active venue for social discourse and commentary. We offer courses that address the wide gamut of theatrical experience.<br /><br /> Students will find a broad foundation of classes and experiences designed to develop performance skills as actors and directors, to teach principles of theatrical design and technology, and to assist them in deepening their understanding of dramatic literature, theatre history and criticism.<br /><br /> We currently offer a Bachelor of Arts (BA) degree in Theatre and Speech Education, a BA in Theatre Studies with emphases, and an Associate of Arts degree in Theatre Studies. Students may also minor in Theatre and Speech Education, Theatre Arts, or Technical Theatre. Students seeking a Bachelor of Arts or Sciences Degree in Interdisciplinary Studies may choose a Theatre Studies Concentration to complement their studies. <br /><br /> To accommodate students on any track, we produce a diverse season of six shows annually, selected to complement our curriculum: two productions each in the Fall, Winter, and Spring semesters. These productions allow students to experience their course work first hand. Students may also gain experience participating in numerous student directed shows throughout the year. The auditions are open to anyone campus wide. In addition to participating as a performer, many opportunities are available to work backstage with lights, props, costumes and set construction. Students also gain valuable experience as assistant directors, stage managers and other vital roles. Wide participation in theatre as an elective is encouraged for all university students.<br /><br /> The Theatre Council, a student organization, holds regular activities allowing those interested to be involved with firesides, workshops, improvisation, celebrations, discussions and various theatre experiences. Membership is open to anyone who wants to participate.<br /><br /> <strong>Mission Statement</strong><br /><br /> We are committed to building on the mission of Brigham Young University-Idaho and of the College of Performing and Visual Arts. Our highest aim is to embrace talented students from throughout the Church and provide them spiritual and academic opportunities in all aspects of the creative process of theatre. This is achieved within an environment that fosters individual creativity and commitment to the principles of the restored Gospel. We are committed to training artists and disciple leaders--in various theatrical disciplines--who are prepared for lifelong learning as artists, parents, citizens and church members.<br /><br /> <strong>Guiding Principles</strong><br /><br /> <strong>Disciple-Leadership</strong><br /><br /> Recognizing the role artistic expression and culture has in changing lives, our graduates will provide leadership that serves and inspires in their families, in the Church, in their communities, and in their art. We provide a student-centered training environment that supports the development of a high standard of personal and professional ethics where students feel safe to take artistic and academic risks and enjoy a wholesome sociality. Everyone is a teacher and a learner.&nbsp;<br /><br /> <strong>Collaboration</strong><br /><br /> We support the unique voice of each student and also work toward a unified vision of collective goals. Working together, we value the contributions and accomplishments of each student and of the ensemble.<br /><br /> <strong>&nbsp;Rigor</strong><br /><br /> We provide current, comprehensive training in discipline-specific emphases offered through a liberal arts curriculum that integrates academic rigor with production-based techniques. With a sure sense of the value of hard work in our lives, we pursue excellence and challenge each other to increase our comprehension and application of theories and skills. We will strive to make the Department of Theatre and Dance at BYU-Idaho the place for young, gifted, and disciplined artists throughout the Church to pursue truth.<br /><br /> <strong>Creativity</strong><br /><br /> We nourish imagination and inspiration as we master the components of creating and telling great stories of all genres. We recognize the desire to create as one of the finer aspects of our nature and a characteristic we inherited from our Heavenly Father.<br /><br /> <strong>Diversity</strong><br /><br /> We recognize the truthfulness of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ and encourage living its principles while joyfully embracing the differences that enrich our department and enhance our artistry.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1854" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
