<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x57000" Name="FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>BYU-IDAHO THEATRE PROGRAMS FAQ </strong></p>
<p><strong>General Questions </strong><br /> &bull; <a href="#What theatre degree programs are offered through the BYU-IDAHO Department of Theatre and Dance?">What theatre degree programs are offered through the BYU-IDAHO Department of Theatre and Dance?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#How can I contact the Theatre office?">How can I contact the Theatre office?</a><br /><strong>Questions about the new Theatre Studies BA</strong><br /> &bull; <a href="#Is the Theatre and Speech Education degree being discontinued?">Is the Theatre and Speech Education degree being discontinued?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Do you offer a Musical Dance Theatre degree?">Do you offer a Musical Dance Theatre degree?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Theatre Studies is a BA degree; do I need to take a foreign language?">Theatre Studies is a BA degree; do I need to take a foreign language?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Does the Theatre Studies major require a minor?">Does the Theatre Studies major require a minor?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Other than the stated course work, what other requirements do I have to fulfill?">Other than the stated course work, what other requirements do I have to fulfill?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#What kinds of design, production and stage management opportunities do theatre students have?">What kinds of design, production and stage management opportunities do theatre students have?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#I&rsquo;m a transfer student. How will I know if credits I have earned in theatre classes and productions at my previous school will be accepted by BYU-Idaho&rsquo;s Theatre program?">I&rsquo;m a transfer student. How will I know if credits I have earned in theatre classes and productions at my previous school will be accepted by BYU-Idaho&rsquo;s Theatre program?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#So, do transfer students have a disadvantage?">So, do transfer students have a disadvantage?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#How do I apply for scholarships in Theatre?">How do I apply for scholarships in Theatre?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Can I take theatre classes without being formally admitted into a theatre degree program?">Can I take theatre classes without being formally admitted into a theatre degree program?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Can I participate in acting performances if I am not a major?">Can I participate in acting performances if I am not a major?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#What can a Theatre Studies degree prepare me to do?">What can a Theatre Studies degree prepare me to do?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Should I plan for graduate school after completing my degree in Theatre?">Should I plan for graduate school after completing my degree in Theatre?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#I am a Theatre and Speech Education student; can I change my major to Theatre Studies?">I am a Theatre and Speech Education student; can I change my major to Theatre Studies?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#Are there jobs in the department for me to develop my skills?">Are there jobs in the department for me to develop my skills?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#The Theatre Studies degree offers different emphases; what is an 'emphasis?'">The Theatre Studies degree offers different emphases; what is an &ldquo;emphasis?&rdquo;</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#What is the difference between the Theatre Studies 'degree' and the Theatre Studies 'emphasis?'">What is the difference between the Theatre Studies "degree" and the Theatre Studies "emphasis?"</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#What if I chose an emphasis that interests me, but it turns out I'm not suited for it? Can I use the classes I have already taken?">What if I chose an emphasis that interests me, but it turns out I&rsquo;m not suited for it? Can I use the classes I have already taken?</a><br /> &bull; <a href="#How do I become a major?">How do I become a major?</a></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong>GENERAL QUESTIONS</strong></p>
<p><strong><a name="What theatre degree programs are offered through the BYU-IDAHO Department of Theatre and Dance?"></a> What theatre degree programs are offered through the BYU-IDAHO Department of Theatre and Dance? </strong></p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Bachelor of Arts, Theatre Education (major and minor) <br /> o&nbsp;&nbsp; Bachelor of Arts, Theatre Studies (major and minor) <br /> o&nbsp;&nbsp; Associate of Arts, Theatre Studies <br />o&nbsp;&nbsp; Theatre Studies Concentration (for interdisciplinary studies)<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="How can I contact the Theatre office?"></a>How can I contact the Theatre office?</strong></p>
<p>Department of Theatre and Dance, Theatre Office<br /> 126 Snow Rexburg, ID 83460-1215 <br /> Phone: 208-496-4820 <br /> Email: theatre@byui.edu <br /><br /></p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>QUESTIONS ABOUT THE NEW THEATRE STUDIES B.A.<br /></strong></p>
<p><strong><a name="Is the Theatre and Speech Education degree being discontinued?"></a>Is the Theatre and Speech Education degree being discontinued?</strong></p>
<p>No. We still fully support our teaching program.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Do you offer a Musical Dance Theatre degree?"></a>Do you offer a Musical Dance Theatre degree?</strong></p>
<p>No. You may consider an interdisciplinary degree that involves a combination of studies in music, theatre and dance.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Theatre Studies is a BA degree; do I need to take a foreign language?"></a>Theatre Studies is a BA degree; do I need to take a foreign language? </strong></p>
<p>No. However, depending on your career goals, studying a foreign language may be advantageous. The Academic Discovery Center can assist you in the selection of foundations and elective classes that compliment a theatre major. <br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Does the Theatre Studies major require a minor?"></a>Does the Theatre Studies major require a minor? </strong></p>
<p>No. You may choose to have a minor in another discipline in addition to your degree in Theatre or you can pursue more credits in Theatre classes to deepen your training. See the catalog for specific requirements.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Other than the stated course work, what other requirements do I have to fulfill?"></a>Other than the stated course work, what other requirements do I have to fulfill?</strong></p>
<p>Many of the classes require lab or service hours intended to give you hands-on experience. You will want to immerse yourself in these opportunities as much as possible. Additionally, each emphasis requires you to meet with a jury of faculty who will assess your progress in your declared emphasis every two semesters that you are on campus.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="What kinds of design, production and stage management opportunities do theatre students have?"></a>What kinds of design, production and stage management opportunities do theatre students have? </strong></p>
<p>The department produces an ambitious, varied season of plays and musicals on two different stages. We also collaborate from time to time with other departments to produce operas, concerts and other events. Under the direction of faculty and professional artists, students have opportunities to work back stage, in the shops, as design assistants, technicians, researchers, or stage managers on all productions.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="I&rsquo;m a transfer student. How will I know if credits I have earned in theatre classes and productions at my previous school will be accepted by BYU-Idaho&rsquo;s Theatre program?"></a>I'm a transfer student. How will I know if credits I have earned in theatre classes and productions at my previous school will be accepted by BYU-Idaho's Theatre program? </strong></p>
<p>We have articulation agreements with many colleges and universities. Contact the Academic Discovery Center for already known equivalencies. Other courses and experiences are examined case-by-case by the department chair and faculty mentors. If you have a syllabus from your previous class, it may help us determine an acceptable substitution. See the catalog for more information about transfer requirements.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="So, do transfer students have a disadvantage?"></a>So, do transfer students have a disadvantage? </strong></p>
<p>In some ways, yes. Students are encouraged to begin their training at BYU-Idaho as early as possible to take advantage of project and experiential opportunities and proper course sequencing. We have a small faculty and thus some required courses are offered on a rotating schedule. Transfer students may have difficulty getting in sync with course offerings. Transfer students also bring a different perspective that enhances our learning environment. If you are transferring, there are many people who will help you to matriculate successfully into the department. Contact us; we'll be happy to help.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="How do I apply for scholarships in Theatre?"></a>How do I apply for scholarships in Theatre? </strong></p>
<p>Scholarships are awarded to department pre-major, major, and minor students, incoming and continuing. Applications are available online. Please check the website for application deadlines and requirements.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Can I take theatre classes without being formally admitted into a theatre degree program?"></a>Can I take theatre classes without being formally admitted into a theatre degree program? </strong></p>
<p>Yes! Most of our classes are open enrollment classes, though certain prerequisites may be required for individual courses. Check the catalog for special requirements.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Can I participate in acting performances if I am not a major?"></a>Can I participate in acting performances if I am not a major?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, there are many performance opportunities for non-theatre students. Although casting preference may be given to on-track majors, most auditions for acting parts in BYU-Idaho theatre productions are open. <br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="What can a Theatre Studies degree prepare me to do?"></a>What can a Theatre Studies degree prepare me to do?</strong></p>
<p>Both the BA and the AA degree programs address a variety of student interests to prepare you for a diverse array of post-baccalaureate options. You may enter directly into the workforce or attend graduate school in the several areas of theatre (or other disciplines altogether). The emphasis placed on liberal arts studies by many leading post graduate programs will make a Theatre Studies degree useful for those seeking further training in management, law, and academic careers, for example. Additionally, the creative and critical thinking skills and professional ethics you acquire while studying theatre arts will prepare you in your duties in your home, in your community, in your profession and in the Church.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Should I plan for graduate school after completing my degree in Theatre?"></a>Should I plan for graduate school after completing my degree in Theatre? </strong></p>
<p>It depends on your life goals. The program is designed to help you qualify for graduate study if you desire, and many theatre students find value in graduate school. An MFA, PhD or MBA, for example, can provide advanced training in areas of interest and qualify you to teach on the college or university level. <br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="I am a Theatre and Speech Education student; can I change my major to Theatre Studies?"></a>I am a Theatre and Speech Education student; can I change my major to Theatre Studies?</strong></p>
<p>It depends on your current credit status. Students with 60 or more credits are not able to change their major without an approved petition to the Academic Standards Committee. You will be asked to demonstrate your ability to efficiently and successfully complete the new major in a reasonable amount of time. Check with the Academic Discovery Center for information about changing your major.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="Are there jobs in the department for me to develop my skills?"></a>Are there jobs in the department for me to develop my skills?</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the hands-on requirements for many classes and labs, there are a few paid positions in our production shops as carpenters, welders, stitchers, painters, electricians and other technical jobs. Additionally, you may consider working as a teaching assistant, an office assistant or librarian in the script library. These positions are limited and quite competitive. Watch the student employment website for openings.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="The Theatre Studies degree offers different emphases; what is an 'emphasis?'"></a>The Theatre Studies degree offers different emphases; what is an "emphasis?" </strong></p>
<p>The Theatre Studies program offers focused studies to encourage a student toward a specific expertise in the following areas:<br /><br /> o&nbsp;&nbsp; Theatre Studies (flexible to your interests)<br /> o&nbsp;&nbsp; Performance and Directing<br /> o&nbsp;&nbsp; Design and Technology<br /> o&nbsp;&nbsp; Theatre for Youth<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="What is the difference between the Theatre Studies 'degree' and the Theatre Studies 'emphasis?'"></a>What is the difference between the Theatre Studies "degree" and the Theatre Studies "emphasis?"</strong></p>
<p>Think of it as a tree. The Theatre Studies <em>degree</em> is like the trunk of the tree; each <em>emphasis</em> is a branch-connected in a unique way. The Theatre Studies emphasis is deliberately intended to be open-ended to allow you more flexibility.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="What if I chose an emphasis that interests me, but it turns out I'm not suited for it? Can I use the classes I have already taken?"></a>What if I chose an emphasis that interests me, but it turns out I'm not suited for it? Can I use the classes I have already taken?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. The general Theatre Studies emphasis is designed to be open-ended enough to tailor to your career goals. Students who may not be suited for another emphasis (or who fail to make sufficient progress in another emphasis) can still graduate in general Theatre Studies.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><a name="How do I become a major?"></a>How do I become a major?</strong></p>
<p>Qualified students can declare a Theatre Studies major by contacting the Academic Discovery Center (ADC). However, you won't be able to specify an emphasis until you have completed an introductory cluster of 12 credits. Check the catalog for a list of the theatre classes you should take in your first two semesters. (If you are a transfer student, we will want to make sure that what you've already taken will prepare you for what's to come. Counsel with the ADC to find out what will transfer)<br /><br /> Theatre Studies in an open-enrollment program. Nevertheless, after completing the introductory cluster, students must fill out a declaration form. This helps us to serve you and track your progress. Generally speaking your process will be like this:<br /><br /> 1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Declare your intent to be a Theatre Studies major<br />2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Complete the Fundamentals cluster<br />3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Get a Theatre Studies Declaration packet at the Theatre Office<br /> 4.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Meet with the Academic Discovery Center<br /> 5.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Meet with a faculty mentor <br /> 6.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Submit materials according to packet instructions <br /><br /></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1854" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
