<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57443" Name="FAQ About Class Planning" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ About Class Planning</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently asked questions about class planning, including when to register, declaring or changing majors/minors, etc.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<!--Q Anchor list--> <ol>
<li><a href="#1">When do I register for classes?</a><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"> </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"><a href="#2">How many credits should I take?</a></span></li>
<li><a href="#3">How do I know what classes to take?</a></li>
<li><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"><a href="#4">Should I complete all my Foundation classes before taking my declared major classes?</a></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"><a href="#5">I came to BYUI before Foundations and have returned, which catalog year do I follow?</a> <br /></span></li>
<li><a href="#6">What if all of the classes I want are full?</a></li>
<li><a href="#7">What if I am a transfer student, how do my credits transfer?</a></li>
<li><a href="#8">Who is my advisor?</a><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"> </span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"><a href="#9">How do I declare/change my major or minor?</a></span></li>
<li><a href="#10">Do I need a minor?</a><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;"> </span></li>
<li><a href="#11">What if I am undecided about what I want to do?</a></li>
<li><a href="#12">What if I know what career I want but don't know what major I need to qualify?</a></li>
<li><a href="#whattools">What tools are available to help with the class registration process?</a></li>
<li><a href="#14">When I am off -track, can I still take classes?</a></li>
<li><a href="#15" title="Foreign Language Credit">I just returned from a mission and would like to test out of a foreign language. How do I do that? </a></li>
</ol> <!--Body Copy List--> 
<hr />
<h3><a name="1"></a>1. When do I register for classes?</h3>
<p>A: Here is a link to the registration calendar: <a href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/RegSchedule.htm">http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/RegSchedule.htm</a></p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="2"></a>2. How many credits should I take?</h3>
<p>A: Students should be aware of the following credit requirements when deciding how many credits to take:</p>
<ul>
<li>12 credits are required to be considered a full-time student </li>
<li>14 credits are required to be eligible for university scholarship </li>
<li>15 credits are required to graduate in eight semesters or four years and for the Fast Grad program</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h3><a name="3"></a>3. How do I know what classes to take?</h3>
<p>A: Please see our <a href="x30742.xml" title="Recommended Course Sequences">Recommended Course Sequences</a>.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="4"></a>4. Should I complete all my Foundation classes before taking my declared major classes?</h3>
<p>A. No. In order to graduate within 8 semesters, you will need to be aware of sequencing in your major. Please see our <a href="x30742.xml" title="Recommended Course Sequences">Recommended Course Sequences</a>.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="13"></a><a name="5"></a><a name="5"></a>5. I came to BYUI before Foundations; now I have returned, which catalog year do I follow?</h3>
<p>A: Visit with your declared major's <a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Center</a> to see which year is best for you, depending on how many general  education classes you have taken and when your previous catalog year  expires.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong> </strong><a name="5"></a><a name="6"></a>6. What if all of the classes I want are full?</h3>
<h5></h5>
A: When a class you want to add is full, consider the following options: <ol start="1">
<li>Take it at another time. The most desirable class times fill quickly. Often, early morning or late afternoon sections remain open. It is better to have the class at an inconvenient time than not to have it at all. (Remember, each semester you will get an earlier registration and more class choices as your credits accumulate.)</li>
<li>Keep checking back. Seats open up in filled sections frequently as students rearrange their schedule and add and drop classes. If there is a class you really want, keep checking back to see if a seat opens up.</li>
<li>Even though a certain schedule of classes is recommended there are many alternatives. If you meet the pre-requisites, almost any course is available to you. For Foundation classes, feel free to look at second and third semester recommendations for more class options. If you need help identifying other class choices contact your major's <a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Center</a>.</li>
<li>As a last resort, students can go to the class they'd like to add on the first day of the semester. Often, teachers will have a few seats they can assign that day.</li>
</ol>
<h5>NOTE: Please remember that the Academic Discovery Centers can't add students to full classes.</h5>
<hr />
<h3><a name="7"></a>7. What if I am a transfer student, how do my credits transfer?</h3>
<p>A: If you are a transfer student without an associate (AS or AA) degree you may have some transfer classes that can substitute to fulfill our Foundations requirements. Depending on your major, you can meet with an advisor in the <a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Center </a>to see if substitutions can be made. If you are a transfer student with an associate (AS or AA) degree your Foundations requirements are complete except for the capstone (FDCNC 250) and remaining religion requirements including FDREL 200.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="8"></a>8. Who is my advisor?</h3>
<p>A: Every student is assigned a faculty mentor. However, in regard to class planning, students do not generally meet with their faculty mentor until their junior year. Faculty mentors mostly help with upper-division class planning as it relates to career strategy and graduate school. <br />As freshmen and sophomores, students receive advising help from their major's <a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Satellite Center</a>. Satellite Advisors are experts in class planning for their particular areas. Also, there is the Academic Discovery Center, which is the center over general advising for Foundation requirements and major/career exploration.</p>
<p>For more information on finding your advisor, <a href="x30664.xml" title="Advisors">click here</a>. View the <a href="x28937.xml" title="Roadmap">Roadmap</a> for information on when and why you should meet with your Faculty Mentor.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="9"></a>9. How do I declare/change my major or minor?</h3>
<p>A: Changing majors and minors cannot be done online. Instead, to declare/change your major or minor, please visit the <a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Satellite Center </a>over the <strong>new major</strong> you'd like to declare.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="10"></a>10. Do I need a minor?</h3>
<p>A: Some majors require you to have a minor or clusters, while others do not. To find out about your major's specific requirements check the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog" title="Catalog" target="_blank">Catalog</a> for details. If you have any questions once you have checked the catalog, please contact your major's <a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Satellite Center</a>.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="11"></a>11. What if I am undecided about what I want to do?</h3>
<p>A: If you are unsure about what you want to declare for a major or pursue as a career, we recommend taking General Studies 100 (GS 100), <a href="x31903.xml" title="Exploration">Career Exploration</a>. The 1 credit class is designed to assist in making a decision concerning your career or major. <a href="x31905.xml" title="Assessments">Career assessments</a> will help you assess personal interests, work styles, preferences, and skills to determine your career path. At the conclusion of the class, you will gain a better understanding of the job market and careers available to you.</p>
<p>Another option is to take Advising 101 (ADV 101), <a href="x31903.xml" title="Exploration">Undecided to Decided</a>. This class can be done before you get here. This zero-credit option gives you an online class designed to be done at your convenience. During this class you will be working at your own pace through six online discovery exercises. These exercises take you step-by-step through your major selection process. At the conclusion of the class, you will have selected a major and created a class plan for that major. Since this class is not offered for credit it is not available through the registration system. Instead, interested students should register on the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/advising/u2d">U2D Web site</a>.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="12"></a>12. What if I know what career I want but don't know what major I need to qualify?</h3>
<p><span style="font-family: georgia,palatino;">A: We have an excellent site called Careers to Majors that recommends majors that will help qualify you for your career goals. We also have a site called Majors to Careers that can help you figure out what to do with your major once you enter the workforce. </span></p>
<p><a href="x35702.xml" title="Career to Major">Career to Major</a></p>
<p><a href="x35833.xml" title="Major to Career">Major to Career</a></p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="whattools"></a>13. What tools are available to help with the class registration process?</h3>
A: Helpful class planning links include: <ol start="1">
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/catalog/">Catalog</a> - The catalog is very useful not only to look at classes, but for other campus policies and rules. Most questions you have can be answered by looking in the catalog. </li>
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/Catalog/2010-2011/foundation%20Requirements.pdf">Foundations </a>- Foundation classes are required for all new students. </li>
<li><a href="x24269.xml" title="Academic Discovery Center Locations">Academic Discovery Centers </a>- The Academic Discovery Center can help with general class planning. The Academic Discovery Satellite Centers can help with major class planning. </li>
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/registrarsoffice/Docs/REG%20FAQs.pdf">Tutorials</a> - These are short movies that show you how to navigate the school's registration Web pages. </li>
<li><a href="http://web.byui.edu/gradplan/" title="Graduation Planner">Grad Planner </a>- Plan out your class sequencing from your first semester to graduation.</li>
</ol> 
<hr />
<h3><a name="14"></a>14. When I am off -track, can I still take classes?</h3>
<p>A: You have the option of taking night classes through <a href="http://www.byui.edu/cc/" title="Community Connections" target="_blank">Community Connections</a> or taking online classes.</p>
<hr />
<h3><a name="15"></a>15. I just returned from a mission and would like to test out of a foreign language. How do I do that?</h3>
<p>A: There are a couple different methods of recieving credit for foreign language classes—<a href="http://www.byui.edu/foreign-languages-literatures/department-policies" title="Foreign Language Department Policies">examinations or vertical credit</a>. Here are some additional resources on recieving credit for foreign languages:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/foreign-languages-literatures/resources/language-exams-for-credit" title="Foreign Language Exams for Credit">Foreign language examinations at BYU-Idaho</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/foreign-languages-literatures/resources/placement-exam" title="Foreign Language placement exams">Foreign language placement exams</a></li>
<li><a href="http://flats.byu.edu/" title="Foreign Language Exams at BYU">Foreign language exams not offered by BYU-I are available at BYU</a> (these are offered on our campus once each fall and winter semester)</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
