<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 6.0.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<DetailPage ID="x57647" Name="Exploration Courses" Layout="default.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Exploration Courses</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Exploration Courses</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Exploration Courses</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Exploration Courses at BYU-Idaho</MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x14" Name="RelatedLinks" label="Related Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="RelatedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2><img alt="The Ricks and Hinckley Buildings" src="Images/new_image_structure/administrative_departments/career_and_academic_advising/090722Ricks-Hinckley-pan3.jpg" /></h2>
<h3>BYU-Idaho offers two courses to help students decide what their major should be. Neither course is required, but Career and Academic Advising recommends both to students who have yet to decide what their major will be. The courses guide students through self-discovery projects and career assessments to identify their strengths and interests. Students learn exploration techniques to define and clarify career plans, helping them decide which major to select at BYU-Idaho.</h3>
<br /><br />
<h1>General Studies 100</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This course guides students through self-discovery projects and career assessments to identify their strengths and interests. Students learn exploration techniques to define and clarify career plans, helping them decide which major to select at BYU-Idaho. GS 100 is a block class worth one credit toward graduation. Students enroll in this class through the regular registration process.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1>Undecided to Decided</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Students complete this online course at their own pace, receiving no credit toward graduation. Undecided to Decided presents six online exercises that introduce students to the step-by-step major selection process. The six online discoveries include:</p>
<br /><ol>
<li>Self-Assessment: See how your interests, abilities and values apply to possible career choices.</li>
<li>Career Match: From your self-assessment see what careers interest you.</li>
<li>Career Facts: Further explore selected careers to find the best fit for you.</li>
<li>Major Match: Discover which majors match the potential careers you've chosen.</li>
<li>Review Options: Research the majors recommended for your ideal careers.</li>
<li>Declare Choice: Create an eight-semester graduation plan for the major you've selected.</li>
</ol>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/advising/u2d/register.htm">Register Here </a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1>Student Feedback</h1>
<p><br />Many students have given their reaction GS 100 and ADV 101. Some of their thoughts and feedback is listed below:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>I realize (now) that majors are more flexible than I thought they were. By picking a major I'm not choosing a life-long career.</h3>
<h4>&ndash;A freshman from Denver, Colorado</h4>
<h3></h3>
<h3>There are a few majors that I skipped over, and some of the majors I wanted to do sound awful! Some majors I never thought of (doing) sounded great!</h3>
<h4>&ndash;A freshman from Layton, Utah</h4>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>I think that with narrowing down the choices it has become easier to see what it would be like in each of those different major choices.</h3>
<h4>&ndash;A freshman from Provo, Utah</h4>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>I found out that there are a few more jobs that I might like than I had originally thought.</h3>
<h4>&ndash;A freshman from Rigby, Idaho</h4>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>I have come to the conclusion that I should do something in the medical field. I still don't know exactly what I want to major in but this class gave me some interesting ideas!</h3>
<h4>&ndash;A freshman from Idaho Falls, Idaho</h4>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ImageComponent" Name="LeftColumnImageComponentList" label="Left Column Image Component List" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x946" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></DetailPage>
