<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57971" Name="Help Wanted - Local Job Postings" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Help Wanted</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">List of local job postings that are temporary - just a few hours, few days or few weeks.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Looking for a little extra cash or gas money? This page contains odd jobs and tasks listed by local community members - you'll find personal service needs like painting a house, helping someone move, raking leaves and yard work, etc.</span></p>
<p><strong>These are jobs for which someone would like to hire a student for only a few hours or a few days</strong>.</p>
<p>For career and "regular" employment postings, internships, etc - please be sure to visit <a class="extLink" href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator" target="_blank">Career Navigator</a>.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho strives to ensure all postings are legitimate, and advises you to use caution and common sense in applying for any position.</p>
<p></p>
<hr />
<p>Company: USSF<br /> Contact Phone:&nbsp;530-524-1936<br />Location: Rexburg/Idaho Falls<br /> Job Title: Soccer Referee $10-$25 an hour!<br /> Job Description: If you want to ref any soccer games this season you must attend a mandatory certification class this Thursday, Friday and Saturday. (28-30 of March) Call or Text me anytime. This is your last chance to get certified. If you love soccer, this is the job for you. Call or text me anytime for more info. <br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Pass certification test<br /> Start Date:&nbsp;Now<br /> Duration / End Date:<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;August</span><br /> Hours:&nbsp;About 10 a week<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;$10-25<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Contact Grant- 530-524-1936<br /> Application Deadline: 3/27/13<br />Posted: 3/26/13</p>
<hr />
<p><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Company:&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Jacobson Concrete</span><br /><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">Location:</span><span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;Rigby, Idaho</span><br /> Email Address:&nbsp;Calls only<br /> Job Title:&nbsp;Construction<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;Setting wall forms, flatwork, tying rebar, Manual labor, heavy lifting, motivated to be a hard worker<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;No Requirements or Qualifications</span><br /> Start Date:&nbsp;April 1, 2013<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;Summer Job<br /> Hours:&nbsp;40 to 45 hours/ week<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;$10/Hour<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Call Bryant @ (208) 521-7451<br />Posted: 3/20/13</p>
<hr />
<p>Contact Name:&nbsp;Brie Anderson<br />Location: Rexburg, Id<br />Job Title:&nbsp;Nanny<br />Job Description: Looking for someone to watch my three kids on most Mondays and Thursdays from 7:30 am to 5:30pm, ages 4 years, 2 years, and 4 months. Starting date would be April 15, 2013. Please email me a little about you and send with your references.<br />Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Would like CPR certified but not required. Good with kids. <br /> Start Date:&nbsp;April 15, 2013<br /> Duration / End Date:&nbsp;End of semester or longer<br /> Hours:&nbsp;7:30- 5:30<br /> Pay / Wage:&nbsp;DOE<br />How to Apply:&nbsp;Please email me at <a href="mailto:tjbrieanderson@gmail.com">tjbrieanderson@gmail.com</a> with a little about yourself and send 2-3 references with it.<br />Posted: 3/20/13<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;"><br /></span></p>
<hr />
<p>Company:&nbsp;Fall Creek Homes<br />Location: Ammon, ID<br /> Email Address:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:office@fallcreekhomes.net">office@fallcreekhomes.net</a><br /> Job Title:&nbsp;Construction Clean up<br /> Job Description:&nbsp;Local builder is seeking a miscellaneous labor worker for part time work. Must have own transportation and a cell phone. Individual will be doing clean up of job sites and other miscellaneous jobs that are needed. There is no set schedule for this, it is on as need basis. Must be able to start right away. Will pay $ 10 per hour.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications:&nbsp;Own transportation and cell phone<br /> Start Date:<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">&nbsp;Right away</span><br /> Duration:&nbsp;Unknown<br /> Hours:&nbsp;No set schedule<br /> Pay / Wage: $10.00<br /> How to Apply:&nbsp;Email resume to <a href="mailto:office@fallcreekhomes.net">office@fallcreekhomes.net</a><br /> Application Deadline:&nbsp;4/1/13<br />Posted: 3/20/13</p>
<hr />
<p>Job Title: Childcare<br /> Job Description: Looking for someone to watch my 3 children (4, 3 &amp; 5 months) 3-4 afternoons/early evenings a week in my home. The hours may vary, so you need to be available after 11:00 am. We are looking for someone long term. You would need to be staying for at least spring semester - preferably all year long. We would consider another mom with a child at home. Please email experience/resume, references &amp; availability (including long term) to <a href="mailto:kes04005@byui.edu">kes04005@byui.edu</a><br /> Requirements / Qualifications: Must be available after 11:00am. Need to be able to provide references. Previous childcare experience preferred.<br /> Start Date: ASAP<br /> Duration / End Date: Through at least spring semester<br /> Hours: approx. 15-20<br /> Pay / Wage: DOE<br /> How to Apply: Email Kara at <a href="mailto:kes04005@byui.edu">kes04005@byui.edu</a> with experience/resume, references &amp; availability</p>
<hr />
<p>Job Title: Home health assistant<br /> Job Description: Go into our Mother's home daily for 1 hour in the morning to help her with putting on ortapedic stocking and ankle brace. Also helping he with her medications and other small things she may ask help with.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications: Prefer someone with CNA training. Kind and patient. Patience and Kindness are needed.<br /> Start Date: As soon as possible<br /> Duration / End Date: No forseeable end date<br /> Hours: 1 hour per day in the Morning after 8:00<br /> Pay / Wage: $10.00 per hour<br /> How to Apply: Call Mauna Rae Allen at 745-6689 or 390-6566<br /> Application Deadline: Taking applications until job is filled.</p>
<hr />
<p>Position: Temp. Video Editor<br /> Company: Intermountain West Communications Co. - KRNV-TV<br /> Job Type: fulltime<br /> Hours: TBD<br /> Job Description: Passion for news; Ability to edit video gathered by photojournalist and news feeds; Experience editing Precis/Edius Systems a plus; Newsroom computer experience preferred (iNews for Windows); Ability to meet daily deadlines, and work cooperatively with other staff members and the public Good telephone etiquette; Possess valid drivers license with a clean driving record, and please provide a current Motor Vehicle Report (MVR) upon application; Ability to carry fifty pounds of television equipment; Willing to learn news photography; and Pass pre-employment drug test.<br /> Temporary position - no benefits<br /> Edit news video for voice-overs, sound-bites, and packages; Re-edit material and edit videotape from photojournalists and network feeds; Coordinate video to ensure proper playback in the newscasts; Maintain video archives; Enter information into newsroom computer; and<br /> Perform other tasks related to the position as assigned, which may include website contribution.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /> Date Available: 3-4-13<br /> Contact Info:<br />Carrie&nbsp; Walker<br /> <a href="mailto:jobs@mynews4.com">jobs@mynews4.com</a><br /> Fax: 775-785-1208<br /> Instructions: Email resume to <a href="mailto:jobs@mynews4.com">jobs@mynews4.com</a> or mail to KRNV<br /> 1790 Vassar Street<br /> Reno, NV 89502<br /><br /></p>
<hr />
<p>Company: Premier Therapy Assoicates<br /> Job Title: Part Time Secretary (2)<br /> Job Description: We are a private speech, occupational and physical therapy clinic. We are in need of 2 part time secretaries. One in our Rexburg office and one in our Rigby office. Duties will include but not limited to, answering phones, contacting insurance companies, filing, scheduling appointments, transitioning of clients, file audits. Hours adjustable except when needed to fill in when full time secretary is out. <br /> Requirements / Qualifications: Excellent customer service skills. Ability to manage time effectively. Be a self starter. Ability to manage children. Phone and typing skills.<br /> Start Date: Upon Filled<br /> Duration / End Date: None<br /> Hours: Varies<br /> Pay / Wage: Depends on Experience<br /> How to Apply: **Resumes only please.** We are a busy office and can not take phone calls regarding this job. Please deliver resumes to our office. <br /> Application Deadline: 03/29/2013<br /> Email Address: <a href="mailto:swensonspeech@gmail.com">swensonspeech@gmail.com</a></p>
<hr />
<p>Company: Garbage Guy<br />Location: Queen Creek, AZ<br />Job Title: Summer Help<br /> Job Description: Junk and Trash clean-up and loading. Working outside in Arizona. Able to lift heavy loads and work in heat.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications: Clean Driving Record Self-motivated hard worker. Heavy lifting and furniture moving Careful, conscientious, customer-focused <br /> Start Date: May-June Flexible<br /> Duration: Summer<br /> Hours: 30-40 hours flexible<br /> Pay / Wage: $10-12/hr<br /> How to Apply: Email contact information, cover letter describing qualifications for this job, resume and available start and end dates to <a href="mailto:Robert@GarbageGuy.com">Robert@GarbageGuy.com</a><br /> Application Deadline: May 15</p>
<hr />
<p>Job Title: Graphic Designer<br /> Job Description: Media organization, LoveWater Publishing, LLC., has a temporary job opening for a graphic design student to make a slight modification to our logo. We are redesigning our business card, stationary and brochure.<br /> Requirements / Qualifications: Person must be proficient in Adobe Photoshop, Indesign and Illustrator. Student must complete this job in a timely fashion. <br /> Start Date: Immediately<br /> Duration / End Date: One time job<br /> Hours: Depends on experience<br /> Pay / Wage: $50 one time<br /> How to Apply: Email cover letter and resume to <a href="mailto:Jobs@LoveWaterPublishing.com">Jobs@LoveWaterPublishing.com</a><br /> Other / Comments: This is a temporary job and other jobs will become available in the Spring. This is a great opportunity to add experience to your resume.</p>
<hr />
<p>Company: Starving Student Card Fundraiser</p>
<p>Job Title: Sales Representative <br />Job Description: Sales of Starving Student discount cards to students and the local community. <br />Start Date: 3/6/2013<br />Duration/End Date: Varies <br />Hours: 15 hrs per week <br />Pay/Wage: Commission based on a percentage of sales with bonus incentives<br />How to apply: Call or text either Jeremy Foster at (409)553-6347 or Mike McBride at (208)547-7753 <br />Other/Comments: This position has very flexible hours that you set yourself each week and it has the potential to make a high hourly wage in addition to bonuses</p>
<hr />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
