<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x57969" Name="Sample of Fraudulent Email" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample of Fraudulent Email</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Sample of Fraudulent Email</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Below is a sample of an email that was received as a result of responding to a fraudulent posting. The "business" named was a reputable business, which has been deleted to protect their reputation. Note the typographical and grammatical errors.</p>
<p>This "job" is an example of a posting where the company will "process transactions" through your bank account. They usually send you a "test" job - to see if you can "follow through quickly." They plan on sending you a check, which you deposit. After 24 hours, you are supposed to send them a certified check via Western Union (or other method), keeping a percentage for yourself. The check then turns out to be bogus, so your bank charges you for the original check, the transaction check, plus related fees - usually hundreds, if not thousands, of dollars. Ouch!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***************************************</p>
<p>Hello Megan,</p>
<p>Please read the job description carefully.</p>
<p>ABOUT US - [Company] specialises in industrial,stage hardware abseiling and climbing techniques except Lighting. Combined with traditional methods, we achieve total access to high rise structures., [Company]     provides end-to-end solutions to its clients,with operations spanning USA, Canada and Australia, we have leveraged the advantage of global operations in providing high quality, cost-effective, Stage Hardware and Equipment.We are capable to provide a clear path to achieve high-performance Hardware operations.  Our value proposition is simple: To bring substantial value to our client globally requirements by Lowering Costs, Improve Processes, Increase Revenue, Quality Improvements and Strengthen Customer relationships.</p>
<p>JOB POSITION - We are currently seeking part time employees for our ever-growing Accounts Receivable Department. This position offers you a good pay ranging from 10% of processed transactions as they are steady and continuous with an average transaction amount of $5,000.00. You can handle as many as 3 transactions in a week as most payment are made install-mentally. The pay is great enough to encourage you to work hard and efficiently while it's more than enough for [Company]     to stay in business. As part of our ongoing Multi Level Marketing Network, we seek capable individuals to work for us as our Cash processor. You can easily make $1000- $3,000 or more in a week by working for us as Sub-contractor in your geographical location, you will be in charge of receiving payment on behalf of our affiliates and Small business organizations that are registered under us.</p>
<p>JOB RESPONSIBILITY - The position of Cash Applications Account entails the following duties: You will be receiving transaction payments from verified buyers which will be mailed via secured courier services, You will have this payment processed and have the processed payment transferred to the suppliers/vendors or directly to the company. Note that NO form of investment or start up fee is needed or required from you and this job will take only 1-3 hours of your time per week.</p>
<p>REMUNERATION - Your pay is 10% of the amount received from the buyer and all charges during processing will be deducted from the balance This makes your pay a fixed 10% of the total amount processed. You can handle as much as 3 or more transactions per week and on 3 transactions you're sure of earning nothing less than $800.00 weekly.</p>
<p>The working hours are flexible as all you will be doing is processing of transaction payments and completing the transaction to the suppliers. You will be required to check your e-mail regularly for transaction updates. Working with us will also not disturb your other jobs (If you have any) as we require that applicant only have easy access to the internet so as to be easily reachable and respond/carry out instructions sent to them efficiently. You will be required to show your continued interest in this position by sending the following information.<br /><br />Full Name:<br />Mailing Address {No P o box}:<br />City:State:Zip Code:<br />Mobile Phone #:<br />Contact Phone #:<br />Alternative Contact e-mail address:<br /><br />Best Regards,<br />Robert Holcomb.<br />Hr. Department.<br />[Company]    . <br />Copyright © 2012 [Company]    .</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
