<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57975" Name="Networking Tips" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Networking Tips</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Why networking is important for building a career, and how students can become effective networkers.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Networking is the process of using currently existing or newly developed acquaintances to help in your job search.</p>
<p>Statistics show that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nearly 75% of all jobs are acquired through some type of networking. </li>
<li>80-90% of the time, employers will hire people that they already know. </li>
<li>85-90% of all jobs are never formally advertised. </li>
</ul>
<p>When a company has an opening, most hiring managers will start their search by asking fellow employees if they know any good candidates. If you come to someone's mind because you have effectively networked, you will have a greater chance of being considered for positions that are never even posted.</p>
<ul>
</ul>
<h2>How Does Networking Work?</h2>
<p>Through your networking, you contact employers and other potentially helpful individuals directly. A networking contact can provide industry information, notify you of openings, or even supply you with the names of individuals who might be able to assist you.</p>
<p>Networking is not a one time event. It is a continuous process. It is never too early to start networking. Over time, your network will expand and multiply. The sooner you start, the sooner you can build a network that is effective enough to obtain employment possibilities.</p>
<h2>Who Should Be In My Network?</h2>
<p>Virtually anyone can be in your network. Naturally, the people closest to you (like relatives and friends) are the best place to start. It's not just about who you know, it's about who THEY know!</p>
<p>Begin by listing the names, addresses, and phone numbers of contacts who might be helpful in your job search. The following is a sample of categories from which to obtain names.</p>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="70%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td bgcolor="#EFEFEC">Relatives</td>
<td bgcolor="#EFEFEC">Friends</td>
<td bgcolor="#EFEFEC">Teachers</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Neighbors</td>
<td>Church Members</td>
<td>Classmates</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td bgcolor="#EFEFEC">Parent's Friends</td>
<td bgcolor="#EFEFEC">Former Employers</td>
<td bgcolor="#EFEFEC">Former Co-workers</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Constantly update these names and try to stay in contact with them. When you meet someone new, be sure to ask them if it would be okay if you contact them in the future, and add them to your contact list. If someone gives you a business card - they're on the list. Then, when the time comes that you are seriously looking for employment, begin by contacting those with whom you are most familiar.</p>
<h2>How Do I Get Started?</h2>
<ul>
<li>Have a plan - don't just make random calls and contacts.</li>
<li>Know yourself - what are you looking for, strengths, interests, career goals, etc.</li>
<li>Practice your "Me in 30 Seconds" statement, sometimes known as your "elevator pitch". You generally have 30 seconds to make that first impressions - be prepared! (Attending a <a class="intLink" href="x28932.xml" title="Career Workshop">Career Workshop</a> can help you develop your statement)</li>
<li>Don't be afraid to start conversations</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Is Your Future a Mystery?</strong></h3>
<p>Here is the video which contains the word of the day, valid ONLY for WEDNESDAY, May 23. Once you have the word of the day, you should then visit the Career Networking Center in 127 Manwaring Center (on WEDNESDAY), where you can swipe your i-card to enter to win the free iPad. You may enter once per day Monday through Thursday. Be sure to return to our Facebook page for the next word of the day. For complete rules, <a href="x42470.xml" title="Open House">click here</a>.     Good luck!</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/lUMvwNDg9SU" width="560"></iframe> 
<hr />
<h2>What do I say?</h2>
<p>As you contact these people, your objective will be to obtain information on potential employment opportunities.</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduce yourself</li>
<li>Tell the person how you got their name/contact information</li>
<li>State your reason (briefly) for contacting them (see samples below)</li>
<li>Ask if this is a good time to talk, and/or ask if they would have some time to meet you in person</li>
<li>Have the conversation. Do NOT monopolize the conversation - networking is not about YOU. The point is to learn about the person you are talking to, their experience and recommendations, what connections they have, and to invite further conversations. </li>
<li>Thank them for their time, determine if a follow-up conversation is appropriate, and when would be the best time to do so.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Samples of Key Conversation Points</h2>
<p><strong>Initial Phone Contact</strong><br /> "Hi, I'm Holly Jones, a marketing student at Brigham Young University-Idaho. I received your contact information from the Alumni Database. I'm not calling for a job - I would like to ask you some career-related questions about the Seattle advertising market and your position as a marketing director. Your professional insight will assist me with my job search. If you are not free at this time, I'd be happy to set up another time to talk briefly in person or over the phone."</p>
<p>Depending on how the conversation progresses, be prepared with well-developed questions based on research you have already done and be prepared to discuss why you have an interest in that industry. Remember to speak clearly and show enthusiasm to make up for the lack of non-verbal communication.</p>
<p><strong>Email or Letter Contact</strong></p>
<div style="margin: 20px; padding: 65px; border: 1px solid #000;">
<p>Dear Mr. Contact,</p>
<br />
<p>I am currently a marketing student at Brigham Young University-Idaho. I was referred to you by Jerry Jones from XYZ company in Phoenix. He recommended you as an excellent source of information on the communications industry.</p>
<p>As the Regional Marketing Manager for First National Bank, I'm sure you are very busy. Would you be able to chat for 15 minutes to answer a few questions about some employment trends in marketing you've noticed and to offer advice on what you think makes a candidate competitive? We can talk by phone or via email, whichever you prefer. Please call me at 208-123-4567 or email at student@byui.edu.</p>
<p>I have attached my résumé for your convenience. Suggestions about the résumé content or format are welcomed. I appreciate your help. Thank you for time. I look forward our conversation.</p>
</div>
<p><strong>After a Class Presentation</strong></p>
<p>"Hi, I'm Holly Jones. Thank you for coming in to talk to our class about marketing in the digital age. It's really interesting to see the connection between what we are learning in class and how marketing is managed from those dealing with these real issues every day. I'd like the chance to learn more about today's topic and especially about your company. Would you mind if I followed up with a few more questions via email in the future? May I have your business card?"</p>
<p><strong>When Introduced at a Business Meeting, Career Fair or Social Event</strong></p>
<p>The key is to ask a lot of questions about the person with whom you are sitting. Converse about topics that are important to that person, however, at the appropriate time, let the person know about your background and future plans. Again, do not monopolize conversations. Your purpose should be to get this person on your team.<br />"I'll be graduating from BYU-Idaho in July with a BS in Communication and an emphasis in Public Relations. I have some PR-related experience creating press releases as part of my internship at Top Marketing, where I also participated in planning their annual sales event. Currently I'm seeking a PR position, possibly in event management."</p>
<p><strong>Responding to "We Don't Have Any Jobs Openings Now"</strong></p>
<p>"That's okay. I am really interested in talking with you about your role within the firm, your career path and advice you would have for someone who plans to pursue public accounting."</p>
<p>Remember that although your ultimate goal is to secure employment, that networking is about making lasting connections and great impressions - so when an opportunity becomes available, you are the first person they think about.</p>
<h2>General Networking Tips</h2>
<ul>
<li>Clearly pronounce your name</li>
<li>Smile, offer your firm and confident hand to shake, and establish eye contact.</li>
<li>Do your research about their company before you reach out to them. Have questions prepared ahead of time, if possible</li>
<li>Create an inventory of your accomplishments, including your educational background and work history,  to keep at hand should a chance encounter become a contact</li>
<li>Make a list of the assets you will bring as a prospective employee</li>
<li>Practice! You want your conversation to be natural, rather than forced. If you don't know what to say after you introduce yourself, the silence may be awkward, and the contact will move on to someone else.</li>
<li> Always be polite and appreciative and respectful</li>
<li>Do not monopolize their time</li>
<li>If you get voice mail, be brief (10-20 seconds), speak clearly and leave phone #, but say you will call back on a specific date/time</li>
<li>Do not ask for a job</li>
<li>It's always better to meet in person, if possible</li>
<li>Use your off-track to do your most effective networking</li>
<li>Conduct informational interviews<strong> </strong>with your contacts and ask for referrals for additional meetings</li>
<li>Bring business cards and a pen</li>
<li>Write some notes so you'll remember the details on who you have just met on the back of the business cards you collect or in a notebook</li>
<li>When networking online, keep track of who you've emailed and where you have posted so you can follow up</li>
<li>It is YOUR responsibility to follow through with referrals</li>
<li>Always thank contacts in writing (email is fine)</li>
<li>Be willing to network for other people, too. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<ol style="margin-top: 0px;"> </ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
