<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x57990" Name="On-Campus Service Missionaries" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">On-Campus Service Missionaries</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">On-Campus Service Missionaries</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div style="float: right; width: 475px;">Dale and RoseAnn gunther are lifelong residents of Utah. Dale served a mission to the Great Lakes (Michigan, Indiana &amp; Ohio) from 1958-60. After his return, he met RoseAnn and they dated for a year and were married December 15, 1961. Roseann interupted her education and worked to put Dale through Byu where he obtained a B.S. Degree in finance and banking. Over their married years she became a mother to 7 children and 13 &ldquo;foster children&rdquo; who lived in their home 1, 2, or 3 at a time over a twenty year period. We had lots of family fun during those years and our 7 natural children learned to appreciate different cultures and personalities. We now have 36 grand &amp; one great.<br /><br /> Dale began his career as president of a family heating and air conditioning business started by his grandfather over 100 years ago. Our eldest son is co-president of the company and is the 4th generation to manage the business. In 1979, Dale transitioned from the hvac business to the Bank of American Fork, a local community bank, where the Gunther family has a major financial interest. Dale was named president in 1988 and served in that capacity for 17 years. He remains active as vice chairman of the board of directors. After his retirement, he was elected to the American Fork city council where he served for 6 years. During his career, he has served in many church callings such as bishop, high council member, stake president and branch president at the mtc in provo. His last church calling was teaching the gospel doctrine class in sunday school &amp; temple ordinance worker.<br /><br /> In addition to her full time motherhood, RoseAnn has been active in many church callings such as ward relief society president and stake young women&rsquo;s president in addition to several calls as advisor to young women. In 1988 she was called to be the stake young women&rsquo;s president. She felt a strong impression to involve the young women in the stake in serving others. She asked the stake president if she could use the &ldquo;punch and cookies&rdquo; budget to purchase materials that could be used to teach the young women skills such as making quilts &amp; building toys from scrap wood gathered from construction sites. After the first year in this work, she told the stake president they had over 400 items to deliver for distribution. The stake president told her there was not a need in our stake and she should find another agency that could use the items. She discovered that the church had recently started a humanitarian department. She contacted them and they took the items and were able to distribute them. Some of the items were sent to orphanages in Romania where there was a lot of news about needs there. Since that time, under the encouragement of subsequent stake presidents, she has organized humanitarian service activities which are held each wednesday at our stake center. There are 80 to 100 volunteers that come each week to put together items such as school kits, hygiene kits, birthing kits, quilts, toys etc. Which are shipped to countries throughout the world and locally as well as needs throughout our country.<br /><br /> We are excited to be a part of the missionary service here at BYU-Idaho and look forward to serving with the career service missionaries.</div>
<div style="width: 200px;"><img alt="On-Campus Service Missionaries" height="250" src="Images/advising/Gunthers.jpg" title="On-Campus Service Missionaries" width="200" />
<p style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 0px;"><strong>Elder Dale Gunther<br /> Sister RoseAnnGunther</strong></p>
<p style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 0px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 0px;"><em>Manwaring Center 129B<br /></em></p>
<p style="margin: 0px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin: 0px;">Elder Gunther: 208-496-9815</p>
<p style="margin: 0px;">Sister Gunther: 208-496-9816</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
