<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57976" Name="Networking Questions" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Networking Questions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Several questions students can review to help them conduct an effective informational interview.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Informational Interview Questions to Ask</strong></p>
<p>The following questions are intended to help you build a detailed picture of the occupation. Use these questions only as a guideline. Your interview will be most effective if you formulate questions that reflect your genuine curiosity about careers.</p>
<p><strong>Occupational Questions:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>What is the title of the person you are interviewing?</li>
<li>What are other commonly-used titles for the position?</li>
<li>What are the duties performed during a typical day? Week? Month? Year? Does s/he have a set routine? (As the person describes the duties, ask what skills are needed). How much variety is there on a day-to-day basis?</li>
<li>What educational program is recommended as preparation? (Distinguish between courses which are desirable and those which are indispensable.)</li>
<li>What kinds of courses are most valuable in order to gain skills necessary for success in this occupation? (Distinguish between courses which are desirable and those which are indispensable.)</li>
<li>What degree or certificate do employers look for?</li>
<li>What kind of work/internship experience would employers look for in a job applicant?</li>
<li>How can a person obtain this work experience?</li>
<li>Are any co-curricular activities recommended?</li>
<li>What steps besides meeting educational and experiential requirements are necessary to "break into" this occupation? (i.e. - exam? interview? union membership?)</li>
<li>What are the important "key words" or "buzz words" to include in a resume or cover letter when job hunting in the field?</li>
<li>What are opportunities for advancement? To what position? Is an advanced degree needed? (If so, in what discipline?)</li>
<li>Which skills are most important to acquire? (i.e. - which skills do employers look for?)</li>
<li>What are the main or most important personal characteristics for success in the field?</li>
<li>What are the different settings in which people in this occupation may work (i.e. - educational institutions, businesses, etc.)?</li>
<li>What other kinds of workers frequently interact with this position?</li>
<li>Is there evidence of differential treatment between men and women workers with respect to job duties, pay, and opportunities for advancement?</li>
<li>What are the employment prospects in the advisor's geographic area? Where are the best employment prospects? What are the employment prospects at the advisor's company? Is mobility a necessary factor for success?</li>
<li>What are some related occupations?</li>
<li>What are the different salary ranges?</li>
<li>Does the typical worker have a set schedule (i.e. - 8 a.m. to 5 p.m.) or are the hours flexible?</li>
<li>What are the demands and frustrations that typically accompany this type of work?</li>
<li>Is there a typical chain of command in this field?</li>
<li>How can you determine that you have the ability or potential to be successful in this specific occupation?</li>
<li>Is this a rapidly growing field? Is it possible to predict future needs for workers in this field?</li>
<li>What types of technology are used and how are they used?</li>
<li>Where might job listings be found?</li>
<li>What entry level positions are there in this field that a liberal arts graduate might consider?</li>
<li>What does the advisor know now which would have been helpful to know when s/he was in your shoes?</li>
</ol><strong>Functional Questions:</strong><br /><ol>
<li>How many hours does the advisor work?</li>
<li>What sort of education does the advisor have?</li>
<li>What has been the advisor's career path from college to present?</li>
<li>What are the satisfying aspects of the advisor's work?</li>
<li>What are the greatest pressures, strains or anxieties in the work?</li>
<li>What are the major job responsibilities?</li>
<li>What are the toughest problems and decisions with which the advisor must cope?</li>
<li>What are the dissatisfying aspects of the work? Is this typical of the field?</li>
<li>How would the advisor describe the atmosphere/culture of the work place?</li>
<li>Does the advisor think you left you out any important questions that would be helpful in learning about the job or occupation?</li>
<li>Can the advisor suggest others who may be valuable sources of information?</li>
</ol>
<p>(from <a href="http://jobsearch.about.com/" title="Networking Questions" target="_blank">Ask.com</a>)</p>
<ol> </ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
