<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57964" Name="Cover Letters and Follow-up Letters" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Cover Letters and Follow-up Letters</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Resources and guidlines for wrting cover letters and follow-up letters.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>The purpose of a cover letter is to introduce yourself when you can't do it in person and emphasize points on your résumé that are specific to the job you are applying for.</p>
<p>The following bullets give a general outline for what may be included in a cover letter:</p>
<p>Opening Paragraph</p>
<ul>
<li>State why your are writing. Specify the name of the position that you are seeking. </li>
<li>Mention how you heard of the opening - use mutually known names. </li>
</ul>
<p>Body Paragraph(s)</p>
<ul>
<li>Explain why you are interested in the job. Specify how your education and work experience would benefit <em>them</em>. If it is an internship, briefly describe how the job would benefit you. </li>
</ul>
<p>Closing Paragraph</p>
<ul>
<li>Reiterate why you want the job. </li>
<li>Facilitate the opportunity for an interview. </li>
<li>Thank them.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Cover Letter Tips that Get Results</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Write your letter to the specific person that you think will hire you</strong><br />Face it: Starting with "To Whom It May Concern" is rather ho-hum to the reader. Take the time to find out the name of the person that will be reading your letter and address it specifically to that person. Know their name and title. You can find the name of the person by calling the company directly, searching for it via the internet or in a variety of other ways.</li>
<li><strong>Do your research </strong><br />The more "generic" your cover letter, the less successful it is likely to be. You want to demonstrate that you have done your homework and know important things dealing with the company. Company web sites, annual reports, and newspapers can give you the necessary information. Customizing your letter to a particular company is impressive and makes you stand out from the pack of job seekers.</li>
<li><strong>Tell what you can do for the company, not what the company can do for you</strong><br />Hirers aren't impressed with cover letters that begin by explaining what you want a company to do for you. ("I am an experienced accountant looking for a mid-sized, dynamic accounting firm with opportunities for development"). Instead, begin by stating a specific way you can help the company accomplish a particular goal, preferably giving an outstanding example of a related accomplishment ("Having had direct responsibility for three successful mergers in the energy industry, I am an ideal candidate to assist you with making a smooth transition in your recent merger with Company X").</li>
<li><strong>Be specific about the job you are seeking</strong><br />The "I can do anything you want, just put me where I'm needed" approach will get your letter filed in the wastebasket. Employers want you to have already done your homework and figured out exactly what job you want. The time to explore other opportunities within the company will come, if at all, during the interview if the interviewer asks about other options.</li>
<li><strong>Quantify your accomplishments</strong><br />After your initial attention-grabbing statement of how you can help the company and stating your greatest related accomplishment, list four or five additional accomplishments bulleted and quantified. Numbers are effective and help you stand out as a prospective candidate. Rather than bulleting "Worked with sales team to increase sales effectiveness", say "Responsible for increasing team sales by 37% in two years."</li>
<li><strong>Mention only accomplishments that directly relate to the job you're applying for </strong><br />You probably have achieved many things that don't relate directly to the job you're trying to land. Organizing a global conference of 3000 attendees is a terrific accomplishment to mention if you're applying for an event-planning job, but not if you are trying to get hired as a newspaper editor. In other words, list relevant accomplishments. Your other accomplishments can be listed in your résumé.</li>
<li><strong>Keep it brief, concise and simple</strong><br /> Your cover letter should be short and to the point. Rarely should it be longer than one page. Remember, you are trying to capture the reader's interest in knowing more about you. Telling your life story is boring and will weaken the strength of your cover letter.</li>
<li><strong>Make it easy on the eyes</strong><br />When you've finished writing your letter, print it up and take a look at it. Is it visually appealing? Is there plenty of white space (using bullets increases the white space)? Does it look un-crowded? Or is it filled with complicated sentences and jammed to the margins? Does it look like a letter you would want to read? Have others look it over before you submit it to the company.</li>
<li><strong>Close stating that you will contact them </strong><br />You are writing the cover letter to get an interview. Due to the fact that the reader of the letter is most likely a busy individual, it is critical that you take the initiative to follow up. At the end of your letter, write something like I will contact you on Tuesday March 23 to verify that you have received this letter, my résumé and to answer any other questions that you may have. That follow up phone call shows that you are taking the initiative and could be your chance to set up an interview.</li>
<li><strong>Follow Through </strong><br />People are busy, and even though they intend on contacting you, it may be up to you to continue the communication. Being persistent is a great quality. You may have to call back several times or even write a second letter. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Sample Cover Letters</h2>
<p>To learn about how to tailor your résumé to your audience, read the <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/tailor_coverletter.pdf" title="Tailoring your Cover Letter and Resume PDF" target="_blank"> Tailoring Your Cover Letter and Résumé</a> PDF document.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/GeneralCoverLetterGuidelines-DosAndDonts.pdf" title="General Cover Letter Guidelines" target="blank">General Cover Letter Guidelines</a></li>
<li><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/GeneralCoverLetterFormat-Sample.pdf" title="General Cover Letter Sample 1" target="_blank">General Cover Letter Sample #1</a></li>
<li><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/JoshuaBurt_cover_a.pdf" title="General Cover Letter Sample 2" target="_blank"> General Cover Letter Sample #2 (Style A)</a></li>
<li><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/JoshuaBurt_cover_b.pdf" title="General Cover Letter Sample 3" target="_blank"> General Cover Letter Sample #2 (Style B)</a></li>
<li><strong>General <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/StacyTooneCoverLetter.pdf" title="Stacy Toone Cover Letter"> Cover Letter</a> Sample #3 (With Matching <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/StacyTooneResume.pdf" title="Stacy Toone Resume"> Résumé</a>)</strong></li>
<li><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/BlockLetterFormatTemplateB220.pdf" title="Block Letter Format Template" target="_blank">Block Letter Format(for B 220 students)</a></li>
<li><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/BlockFormatCoverLetterSample.pdf" title="Block Format Cover Letter" target="_blank">Block Format Cover Letter Sample</a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>Follow-Up Letters</h2>
<p>In addition to cover letters, it is sometimes necessary to write a follow-up (or thank you) letter. This usually follows an interview and is a good way to show additional interest in the job or internship. It also sets you apart from the crowd by reminding them of your interview once all the others are done. Here are some tips for writing follow-up letters:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thank the interviewer.</li>
<li>Refer to something in the interview that will remind them who you are.</li>
<li>Mention any points that you were not able to bring up during the interview.</li>
<li>Reiterate your eagerness to hear from them concerning their hiring decision.</li>
<li>Letters should be sent immediately after the interview to ensure that it arrives before a decision has been made.</li>
<li>Follow up with a thank you note even if you receive a rejection.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<ul>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
