<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57985" Name="Internship Basics" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Internship Basics</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">An introduction to Academic Internships at BYU-Idaho.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2>What is an internship?</h2>
<p>The purpose of an internship is to obtain practical and valuable work experience, to apply skills and knowledge learned in school, and to gain exposure to various job opportunities. An internship must:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be a job directly related to your major.</li>
<li>Be registered for credit.</li>
<li>Be approved by your Department.</li>
</ul>
<p>Introductory level internships are a great opportunity for students to "test drive" careers - giving them the chance to see what workers in that industry do from 8-5 Monday thru Friday.</p>
<p>Required internships should generally be a "stepping stone" into your future career. Internships are typically 40-hour a week positions that last for the length of a semester (14 weeks).</p>
<h2>Who should complete an internship?</h2>
<p>Everyone. Nearly every BYU-Idaho student will be required to complete an internship (or other experiential learning) in order to graduate. Internships are still highly recommended to those who aren't required to complete them.</p>
<p>Some departments may require more than one internship; some allow up to three experiences during your overall educational experience at BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p>You can find out if your department requires an internship by checking with your department coordinator. Additionally, internships will appear on your grad report - look for course numbers ending in "98" (198, 298, 398, 498); regardless of what the name of the course is (work experience, internship, applied course-work), all internship course numbers end in "98".</p>
<p>Note: Nursing students will complete their "clinicals" through the Nursing Department. Education majors (if your major has the word "education" attached to it) will perform student teaching in lieu of their internship. Be sure to check with your department for specifics.</p>
<h2>Where should students work?</h2>
<p>Internships are typically done outside of the Rexburg/Intermountain West region. It's a great opportunity to explore new places and regional culture. So far, BYU-Idaho interns have worked in all 50 states and many foreign countries.<br />Thousands of internship Experience Providers are currently registered in the BYU-Idaho Internship Database, Career Navigator.</p>
<p>Introductory level internships can be done at businesses within the industry to give you a feel for the work.<br />Required internships should be done AT the business you'd like to work for after graduation, or at a company similar in size and function.</p>
<p>Since you will most likely be completing your internship outside the area, it's best to plan ahead educationally as well as financially.</p>
<h2>When should you do your internship?</h2>
<p>Your Department Coordinator will be able to give you a better idea of when you should complete your internship, based on the coursework you have completed. A basic outline would be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Introductory level internships, if your department allows them, are typically done between the sophomore and junior year.</li>
<li>Required internships are typically done between the junior and senior year.</li>
<li>Internships should be done when you are "off-track"</li>
<li>Some departments require more than one internship. Be sure you know your department's requirements, to ensure that you are able to work the internships into your overall 4-year schedule.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Why should you do an internship?</h2>
<p>An internship will give you experience that no class or course work can provide. It gives you the opportunity to apply what you've learned in the classroom in real-life situations, learn from people in the industry who have hands-on experience, and get your "hands dirty" by giving you the chance to work alongside the experts.</p>
<h2>How do you get started?</h2>
<p>Students are responsible for lining up their own internship experiences, but we're definitely available to help you! Follow these steps to get started:</p>
<ul>
<li>Visit with your department internship coordinator to discuss internship requirements and/or prerequisites - before the end of your sophomore year if possible.</li>
<li>Through regular job search, networking, advising, and/or your department coordinator, find the appropriate internship. Internships MUST be directly related to your major.</li>
<li>Fill out the necessary paperwork and present it to your department coordinator for approval &amp; processing.</li>
<li>You must be registered for an internship BEFORE beginning work. No credit will be given for previous/past experiences.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
