<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x57999" Name="Los Angeles Service Missionaries" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Los Angeles Hub</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A short biography and contact information for the Los Angeles Service Missionaries.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div style="float: left; width: 200px;"><img alt="Los Angeles Hub Missionaries" height="250" src="Images/advising/Expeditions/Walburgers.jpg" title="Los Angeles Hub Missionaries" width="200" />
<p style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 0px;"><strong>Gary Walburger &amp;<br /> Judy Walburger</strong></p>
<p style="margin: 0px;"><em>15710 Youngwood Dr.</em></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 5px;"><em>Whitter, CA 90603</em></p>
<p style="margin: 0px;">Cell (Gary): (310) 600-7919</p>
<p style="margin: 0px;">Cell (Judy): (562) 947-3412</p>
<p style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 15px;"><a href="mailto:missionary_la@byui.edu">missionary_la@byui.edu</a></p>
<p><a href="x28979.xml">Learn more about Los Angeles »</a></p>
</div>
<div style="width: 475px; float: right;">Jeanne was born of immigrant parents in the Panama Canal Zone where her father was stationed in the US navy. After several moves her father retired from the service in San Diego California where Jeanne grew up. At the early age of 10 Jeanne joined the church through the missionary efforts of a good LDS friend. Being the only member of her family in the church, she has had to develop a strong independence and a determination for success which has forged her into a powerful missionary and a great advocate for the church. Upon graduation from High School, she spent two years at BYU-Provo, then had to drop out for lack of financial support. Nonetheless, she has been a licensed realtor for 29 years. She has become self educated in many areas including human relations, sales, communications, finance, and real estate ownership and management. And, while rearing three daughters of her own and foster mothering a Navajo Indian daughter, a new member daughter, and three unwed mothers, in addition to several church leadership positions, she has built a substantial real estate business which we presently own and she manages. Jeanne is truly a high energy person, an eloquent speaker, a great communicator and a very likeable person.
<p> </p>
<p>Ralph was born in Provo, Utah and grew up on a dairy farm in Heber. After High School he entered BYU in Provo where he majored in Accounting, Business Management and Economics. Ralph obtained a Bachelors degree in 1965 and a Masters of Accountancy degree in 1967. His first job was with the national CPA firm, Touche Ross 'amp; Co where he worked for 5 years. In 1972 Ralph left Touche to accept a position as a financial analyst and internal audit manager with US Industries, a large international conglomerate.They owned many divisions in various businesses, and he had a great opportunity to learn. Jeanne and Ralph were married in 1972. After three years USI asked Ralph to leave the corporate office to take over the financial control of an ailing division, Riviera Manufacturing Co. which was a large furniture manufacturer and retailer. Over three years he and two other executives helped engineer the acquisition of the company. They owned and operated the company until he sold his interest in 1982. Ralph's next two years were spent consulting with troubled companies. Then, in 1984, he accepted a CFO position with a large garment manufacturing company in Los Angeles, Shades of California. With this beginning in the garment industry he spent the next 15 years as CFO or four large garment companies. During this time, Ralph's night job was doing the accounting for his wife's growing real estate holding and management company. Now his night job has become his day job and he manages the finances of their real estate company full time.</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
