<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x58024" Name="International Requests" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">International Requests</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Information for students who would like to perform an international academic internship.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>All internships are academic courses, and regular registration deadlines apply. In the case of international internships &ndash; additional time consideration must be given in order to ensure adequate review and approval time.</p>
<p>International experiences must fit the University&rsquo;s internship guidelines, including but not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Experience must last a minimum of 7 weeks. Students who are in-country for only a few weeks (less than 7) will not receive approval if that is the extent of their request. Students may work for the organization in addition to time spent in-country &ndash; but the additional time must be at the organization&rsquo;s headquarters, working on tasks related to their major. Recruitment of other volunteers typically does not qualify in this regard. Pre-travel planning on-campus or outside an organization&rsquo;s headquarters is generally not approved.</li>
<li>Experiences solely during the Summer Session do not qualify for credit. Experiences must be tied to the Spring Semester (with a start date no later than the start date of the 2nd block), or tied to the Fall Semester (with an end date no earlier than the last day of the first block).</li>
<li>Some countries are restricted for student travel. Countries listed on the US State Department&rsquo;s Travel Warning list are not approved for student travel. Countries on the Travel Alert list may be considered under certain circumstances. Students may visit the websites below for information on student travel restrictions.
<ul>
<li><a href="http://Travel.state.gov" target="_blank">Travel.state.gov</a> &ndash; US State Department&rsquo;s website. Travel Warnings, Alerts, and country-specific information.</li>
<li><a href="http://Travelsmart.byu.edu" target="_blank">Travelsmart.byu.edu</a> &ndash; Details country-specific information, and includes student travel restrictions. If a country/city is restricted, requests are typically denied.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>International requests will be considered when documentation is received. Approvals will not be given without complete documentation, verbal requests will not be considered.</p>
<p>Additional information will be gathered, and students will be required to respond to certain safety &amp; security messages (generally emailed).</p>
<p>Students who submit requests more than 60 days in advance may receive a preliminary approval for travel. However, based on the timeline, if registration is not open for the requested semester, then an additional safety &amp; security check and approval may be conducted when registration opens and before a student will be registered for the course.</p>
<h3>Requirements</h3>
<ol>
<li>All international requests must receive approval from the President&rsquo;s Council &ndash; <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/InternationalRequestInstructions.pdf" target="_blank">additional documentation is required</a>.</li>
<li>Requests MUST be submitted prior to starting the internship and before leaving the United States, and received with adequate notice to allow proper research and decision-making time (typically a minimum of 30-60 days in advance, and PRIOR to booking tickets and travel). Requests from students who are already in-country will typically be denied.</li>
<li>Students MUST have an in-country, on-site supervisor in order to apply to receive credit. Students who do not know this information in advance will not receive approval for credit until this information is obtained. U.S. based supervisors do not fulfill the requirement unless they will be in attendance in-country and on-site during the entire course of the internship. The supervisor must be qualified to oversee the student&rsquo;s work relative to their major, to offer assistance and teaching on the job.</li>
<li>Students are required to have international health coverage while in-country, and must complete and sign the &ldquo;Acknowledgement of International Health Insurance&rdquo; form and submit it with their request. Forms may be obtained from the Internship &amp; Career Services office in MC 129A; you may call to request these forms be sent to you by calling (208) 496-9826 or via email at internships@byui.edu.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Note for International Students going "home" for their internship:</h3>
<p>Due to accreditation and immigration issues, you must complete the additional documentation. Safety and security checks will not prevent you from returning home. This documentation will be used to explain why you are registered for courses at BYU-Idaho (in Rexburg) and why you are home instead of "in class".</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
