<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x58043" Name="Interview SchedulesOLD" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Interview Schedules</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Interview Schedules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2>Thursday, February 23rd</h2>
<hr />
<h3>American Virtual Academy</h3>
<p><a href="http://americanvirtualacademy.com/" title="AVA">Website</a><br />Majors: Creative Writing, Computer Information Technology, Marketing, Professional Writing, Video<br />American Virtual Academy is one of the nation's premier online educational providers. We empower education through innovative technology and a commitment to keep students motivated to learn.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with American Virtual Academy <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "American Virtual Academy".</p>
<h3>Clearwater Analytics</h3>
<p><a href="http://clearwater-analytics.com/" title="Clearwater Analytics" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Computer Engineering<br />Clearwater is an innovative leader providing investment portfolio reporting and analytics for institutional investors in over 4,500 organizations. We leverage web-based software (SaaS) and world-class client service to maximize the visibility, transparency, accountability and efficiency of investment portfolios. With clients that span the insurance, technology and consumer sectors, to name a few, our solutions provide reporting and analytics on over $650 billion in assets. Corporate standouts like Group Health, 21st Century Insurance, WellCare, Cisco, Seagate, Oracle, Yahoo!, Costco, Netflix, Facebook, Best Buy and others trust Clearwater to navigate and streamline the complexities of aggregating, reconciling, validating and reporting on financial portfolios. We also partner with more than 50 custodians, asset managers, dealer/brokers and electronic trading portals to deepen the perspective and our reach into the financial world.<br /> Clearwater transforms the current, limiting status quo of portfolio reporting and reconciliation. Replacing laborious, manual aggregation and accounting, our solution matches the speed of the marketplace. Headquartered in dynamic and scenic Boise, Idaho, with an office in the financial district of New York City, Clearwater’s technology sets a standard for responsive and responsible investment portfolio reporting– making significant ripple effects throughout the industry.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Clearwater Analytics <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "Clearwater Analytics".</p>
<h3>Davis School District</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.davis.k12.ut.us" title="Davis School District" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Davis School District sits between the snow-capped Wasatch Mountains and the Great Salt Lake, extending from North Salt Lake to Sunset City. The District is just minutes away from major universities, medical centers, performing arts centers, world class ski resorts and breathtaking national parks and monuments. Davis School District has been nationally recognized for excellence in education and is known as an educational leader within the state of Utah.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Davis School District visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>Entheos Academy</h3>
<p><a href="http://entheosacademy.org" title="Entheos Academy">Website</a><br />Majors: Elememtary Education K-9, Middle School Art, Middle School Career and Technical Education, Middle School Language Arts, Middle School Math, Middle School P.E., Middle School Science, School Counselor, Special Education - Elementary,<br />Entheos Academy, an Expeditionary Learning Charter School serving grades K-9, is located in Kearns, Utah with a 2nd campus opening in the fall of 2012 in the Magna, Utah area. Each school serves approximately 500 students. Entheos has partnered with Expeditionary Learning Schools (ELS), one of the nations top ten school reform models, to implement its educational vision of a comprehensive education program emphasizing high academic achievement through active learning, character growth, service, and teamwork. Entheos Kearns was the first EL school in Utah.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Entheos Academy visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>LDS Church - Family History</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.familysearch.org/careers" title="LDS Church - Family History">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Linguistics<br />Employees and Interns will gain experience supporting and delivering systems and services to users at Church Headquarters and millions of users throughout the world. These positions offer a unique and exciting opportunity to work for one of the largest Information Technology centers in the Wasatch Front.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with LDS Church - Family History visit their booth at the Discovery Fair .</p>
<h3>Little America Hotels</h3>
<p><a href="http://littleamerica.com" title="Little America Hotels">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors<br />Little America has many great summer/fall work positions available. We also offer very inexpensive on-site housing, which provides you with a great opportunity to save money for school.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Little America Hotels <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "Little America Hotels". You can also visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>Thomas Edison Charter Schools</h3>
<p><a href="http://littleamerica.com" title="Thomas Edison Charter Schools">Website</a><br />Little America has many great summer/fall work positions available. We also offer very inexpensive on-site housing, which provides you with a great opportunity to save money for school.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Little America Hotels <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "Little America Hotels". You can also visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>Uinta County School District #1</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.uinta1.com" title="Uinta County School District #1" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Evanston is nestled in the foothills of the beautiful Uinta Mountains at an elevation of 6,794 feet above sea level. It is located on the banks of the winding Bear River in the far southwest ocrner of Wyoming. The community is only three miles east of the Utah/Wyoming border and only an hour and a half way from Salt Lake City, UT. Our mission is to provide powerful instruction that is relevant and challenging. We commit to provide daily experiences that prepare students for the 21st century, build positive relationships and encourage maximum student effort.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Uinta County School District #1 visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h2>
<hr />
Friday, February 24th</h2>
<hr />
<h3>Barton Consulting</h3>
<p><a href="http://bartonseo.com" title="Barton Consulting , LLC">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Communications, Computer Science, English<br />Barton Consulting is a local Rexburg company that provides quality search engine optimization, web design, and web programming services.  Barton prides itself on their top notch skills and customer support. Barton is actively hiring talented computer programers, and internet marketers.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Barton Consulting visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>CBIZ / Mayer Hoffman</h3>
<p><a href="http://CBIZ.com" title="CBIZ MHM LLC" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Accounting<br />CBIZ MHM LLC, the 7th largest CPA firm in the nation is seeking interns for its Southern California Offices for the fall semester, 2012.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with CBIZ / Mayer Hoffman<a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "CBIZ / Mayer Hoffman".</p>
<h3>Clearwater Analytics</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.usaa.com/careers" title="USAA" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Information Technology<br />As a Fortune 200 financial services company with more than $147 billion in owned and managed assets, USAA is on a mission to facilitate the financial security of our members, the men and women of the U.S. military and their families worldwide. Headquartered on a showcase campus in San Antonio, Texas, USAA attributes its long-standing success to its most valuable resource, our 24,000 employees. They are the heart and soul of our member-service culture.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Clearwater Analytics<a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "Clearwater Analytics".</p>
<h3>Davis School District</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.davis.k12.ut.us" title="Davis School District" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Davis School District sits between the snow-capped Wasatch Mountains and the Great Salt Lake, extending from North Salt Lake to Sunset City. The District is just minutes away from major universities, medical centers, performing arts centers, world class ski resorts and breathtaking national parks and monuments. Davis School District has been nationally recognized for excellence in education and is known as an educational leader within the state of Utah.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Davis School District visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>LDS Church</h3>
<p><a href="http://ldschurch.jobs" title="LDS Church">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Management Information Systems<br />The Information and Communication Services Department of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints provides IT support for all departments of the Church.  We develop, support and maintain all Church software, web sites and technology for areas of the Church such as Seminaries and Institutes, Missionaries, Temples, Church History, LDS.org, operations, Members and Leaders, Facilities and eCommerce.  We are located in Riverton, Utah.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with LDS Church <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search any available interviews for "LDS Church". Or you can also visit their booth at the Discovery Fair.</p>
<h3>Melaleuca</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.melaleuca.jobs" title="Melaleuca" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Accounting, Business Management, Finance, Marketing, Supply Chain, Information Technology<br />Melaleuca is among the fastest growing health and wellness companies in the world. We are searching for bright, motivated individuals to work in our global headquarters in Idaho Falls. You can enjoy a lifelong career with a multi-national company without ever leaving Southeast Idaho, where good schools and safe, values-oriented communities abound. We invite you to learn more at our campus presentation and booth at the career fair.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with Melaleuca <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "Melaleuca".</p>
<h3>USAA</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.usaa.com/careers" title="USAA" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Information Technology<br />As a Fortune 200 financial services company with more than $147 billion in owned and managed assets, USAA is on a mission to facilitate the financial security of our members, the men and women of the U.S. military and their families worldwide. Headquartered on a showcase campus in San Antonio, Texas, USAA attributes its long-standing success to its most valuable resource, our 24,000 employees. They are the heart and soul of our member-service culture.</p>
<p>To sign up for an Interview with USAA <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator">visit Career Navigator</a> and use the search bar to search interviews for "USAA".</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
