<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x58042" Name="Information SessionsOLD" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Information Sessions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Information Sessions in conjunction with the Discovery Fair formerly Career Internship Graduate and School District fairs.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>*To recieve a reminder about an Information Session go to <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/" title="Career Navigator" target="_blank">Career Navigator</a> and find the Information Session under the Events tab. RSVP to the Information Session of your choosing and an email will be sent to you the day before the event.</p>
<h2>Wednesday, February 22nd</h2>
<hr />
<h3>American Virtual Academy</h3>
<p>5:30pm - 6:30pm<br />MC 176B<br /><a href="http://americanvirtualacademy.com/" title="AVA">Website</a><br />Majors: Creative Writing, Computer Information Technology, Marketing, Professional Writing, Video<br />American Virtual Academy is one of the nation's premier online educational providers. We empower education through innovative technology and a commitment to keep students motivated to learn.</p>
<h3>Circle Four Farms</h3>
<p>5:30pm - 6:30pm<br />Benson 287<br /><a href="http://www.murphybrownllc.com" title="Circle Four Farms">Website</a><br />Majors: Agriculture – Agbusiness, Animal Science etc.<br />Around here, people matter. We employ more than 6,000 across the country and offer a wide variety of career opportunities. Since we’ve grown Murphy-Brown into a vertically integrated company, you can find positions in every aspect of pork production. Our workforce is made up of people with a strong work ethic who thrive in a challenging yet stable environment.</p>
<h3>Cleveland Chiropractic College</h3>
<p>5:30pm - 6:30pm<br />MC 174B<br /><a href="http://www.cleveland.edu" title="Cleveland Chiropractic College">Website</a><br />Majors: Pre Med/Pre Chiropractic<br />For more than eight decades, Cleveland Chiropractic College has been the place to learn this science, philosophy and art. More than one in every 10 chiropractors practicing in North America is a Cleveland graduate. A career in chiropractic gives you the freedom to determine how, where and in what specialty areas you will practice.  At Cleveland Chiropractic College, you will put health and healing into your own two hands.</p>
<h2>Thursday, February 23rd</h2>
<hr />
<h3>Concordia University</h3>
<p>12:00pm - 1:00pm<br />MC 174A<br /><a href="http://www.concordialaw.com" title="Concordia University School of Law" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Concordia University School of Law is a new law school located in Boise, Idaho.  Our inaugural class will begin Fall 2012.  We are currently accepting applications for our full-time and part-time scheduling options.</p>
<h3>Eastern ID Entrepreneurial Center</h3>
<p>6:00pm - 7:00pm<br />MC 372<br /><a href="http://www.idahoecenter.org" title="Eastern ID Entrepreneurial Center">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Communication, IT<br />Serving Southeastern Idaho, Montana, and Wyoming, the Eastern Idaho Entrepreneurial Center (E Center) provides area entrepreneurs and businesses with tools to grow their businesses, prepare for various funding opportunities, and overcome specific business challenges. Through the intern consulting program, the E Center provides clients with short-term, low-cost, professional consulting services. The opportunity to work as a junior analyst while an undergraduate student is rare, making internships at the E Center competitive. The E Center demands professionalism and quality.</p>
<h3>HELP International</h3>
<p><span style="text-decoration: line-through;">2:30pm - 3:30pm</span> <strong>TIME CHANGE</strong>: 4:00 to 5:00 p.m.<br />MC 372<br /><a href="http://help-international.org" title="HELP International" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Advertising &amp; Marketing, Art &amp; Music, Business, Biology, Construction Management, Education &amp; Elementary Ed, Engineering/Pre-engineering, English, Exercise Science, Finance &amp; Accounting, Health Science, History, Home and Family Living, Political Science, Public Health, Pre-Dental &amp; Pre-Med, Recreation Management, Social Work, Sociology<br />HELP is a registered 501(c)3 nonprofit organization specializing in three core competencies: (1) public health, (2) education and (3) entrepreneurship/business projects. Though HELP has engaged in primary aid relief in the form of earthquake and tsunami aftermath relief efforts, its primary drive is to work more in the context of secondary development relief with training initiatives, and program partnering. HELP currently runs programs in El Salvador, India, Uganda, Peru, Tanzania, Thailand, Belize and Fiji. HELP has grown and changed through the years and continues to focus on facilitating poverty alleviation worldwide by adhering to its mission to fight poverty and empower people</p>
<h3>Journeys</h3>
<p>2:30pm - 3:30pm<br />MC 176C<br /><a href="http://journeysdda.com" title="Journeys" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: All majors<br />Come and make a difference in our local community with an internship at Journeys! We are a developmental disabilities agency serving special needs children and adults in our day program. Interns provide developmental therapy, lead group, organize field trip, and creating meaningful, lifelong relationships, and become part of our management team. We have an amazing company culture and provide excellent training. This is a hands-on experience you will never forget!</p>
<h3>LDS Church - Family History</h3>
<p>11:00am - 12:00pm<br />MC 372<br /><a href="http://www.familysearch.org/careers" title="LDS Church - Family History">Website</a><br />Majors: Information Technology<br />Employees and Interns will gain experience supporting and delivering systems and services to users at Church Headquarters and millions of users throughout the world. These positions offer a unique and exciting opportunity to work for one of the largest Information Technology centers in the Wasatch Front.</p>
<h3>Mcpartland Group Life Insurance</h3>
<p>3:00pm - 4:00pm<br />MC 176A<br /><a href="http://www.mcpartlandgroup.com" title="The McPartland Group of Guardian Life Insurance">Website</a><br />Majors: All Majors<br />The McPartland Group of Guardian Life was founded with the goal of assisting our clients in every aspect of their financial lives.  We've provided the most personal service available, thus earning us a reputation for excellence in our industry.  For each of our clients we strive to help create financial stability and security to provide financial independence.</p>
<h3>Melaleuca</h3>
<p>6:00pm - 9:00pm<br />MC 387<br /><a href="http://www.melaleuca.jobs" title="Melaleuca">Website</a><br />Majors: Business, Communication, Information Technology<br />Melaleuca is among the fastest growing health and wellness companies in the world. We are searching for bright, motivated individuals to work in our global headquarters in Idaho Falls. You can enjoy a lifelong career with a multi-national company without ever leaving Southeast Idaho, where good schools and safe, values-oriented communities abound. We invite you to learn more at our campus presentation and booth at the career fair.</p>
<h3>Seattle University School of Law</h3>
<p>2:30pm - 3:00pm<br />MC 174A<br /><a href="http://www.law.seattleu.edu" title="Seattle University School of Law" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Seattle University School of Law, the largest and most diverse law school in the Northwest, is dedicated to the twin priorities of academic excellence and education for justice. The School of Law is home to a talented faculty of committed teacher-scholars and prides itself on its academic rigor, its devotion to social justice and its commitment to personal and practical education that prepares its graduates for a lifetime in law at the service of justice.</p>
<h3>University of Wyoming - College of Law</h3>
<p>2:30pm - 3:30pm<br />MC 176B<br /><a href="http://www.uidaho.edu/cogs" title="University of Wyoming College of Law" target="_blank">Website</a><br />The University of Wyoming College of Law may be the smallest public law school in the country, but the quality of education and diversity of experiential learning opportunities rival our national competitors. Small class sizes promote student-faculty interactions that are often unavailable at larger institutions; our classrooms and moot courtrooms offer state-of-the-art technology and design; four clinical programs, an international human rights practicum, a rural law center, and growing externship and internship programs give our graduates the experience they need to hit the ground running when they enter the legal profession; and, our faculty bring expertise and experience to the classroom while maintaining active contributions to legal research and inquiry. The college is proud of what it has to offer prospective students.</p>
<h3>USAA</h3>
<p>5:00pm - 6:30pm<br />105 Austin<br /><a href="http://www.usaa.com/careers" title="USAA" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: Computer Science, Information Technology<br />As a Fortune 200 financial services company with more than $147 billion in owned and managed assets, USAA is on a mission to facilitate the financial security of our members, the men and women of the U.S. military and their families worldwide. Headquartered on a showcase campus in San Antonio, Texas, USAA attributes its long-standing success to its most valuable resource, our 24,000 employees. They are the heart and soul of our member-service culture.</p>
<h2>Friday, February 24th</h2>
<hr />
<h3>Jacob Lake Inn</h3>
<p>9:00am - 4:00pm<br />MC 176A<br /><a href="http://jacoblake.com" title="Jacob Lake Inn" target="_blank">Website</a><br />Majors: All majors<br />Jacob Lake Inn was established in 1923 and has provided an oasis for travelers visiting the North Rim of the Grand Canyon ever since. We have a hotel restaurant, gift shop, country store and service station and are looking for young people to staff positions in those areas. We guarantee at least $1,100.00 per month and we pay for housing and food. We provide a wonderful work environment and insist on LDS standards.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
