<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x58027" Name="Internship FAQ" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Internship FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently asked questions and important information about academic internships at BYU-Idaho.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong>Do I have to do an internship?</strong>
<p>Most students on campus will be required to complete an internship. Check with your <a href="x24268.xml" id="link4" title="Contact US">Department Coordinator</a> for complete information.</p>
<strong>What are my responsibilities?</strong>
<p>First, you must meet all of your department's pre-requisite requirements and, as a student, you are responsible for securing an internship for yourself. This process is similar to obtaining a job: you must find, apply for and receive an offer. You must be registered for the internship before you begin working, and there is some paperwork involved. Once you have secured your internship, immediately contact your department's internship coordinator who will lead you through the rest of the process.</p>
<strong>How do I find an internship? Who can help me?</strong>
<p>Although you control your destiny, we have plenty of resources to help you. You can browse the <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/sso/students/" title="Career Navigator - Student Login" target="_blank">Career Navigator</a> database for available postitions, schedule an appointment with one of our student mentors to <a class="intLink" href="x28931.xml" title="Career Prep">strengthen your resume and interviewing skills</a>, or learn more about networking and job search tips in our <a href="x25502.xml" title="Additional Resources">Resources</a> section.</p>
<strong>Are internships paid?</strong>
<p>Our records indicate that approximately half of our interns are in paid positions. This varies by college, department and major - as well as by company and industry. Since you are responsible for finding your own internship, it's up to you to determine what type of position you select. Some industries, such as health care and education, typically offer unpaid internships. However, in the business sector, you can expect to receive some sort of compensation, whether an hourly wage or a salary.</p>
<strong>How do I register for an internship?</strong>
<p>Once you've secured a position, you'll need to start the <a class="intLink" href="x29026.xml" title="Internship Registration">paperwork process</a>. You'll obtain the appropriate signatures, and ultimately bring your paperwork to the Academic Discovery Center in the MC. Once everything is in place, you'll be authorized to add the class to your schedule.</p>
<strong>Do I need insurance during my internship?</strong>
<p>All students will need to carry health insurance during their internship, whether through the University or through a family/private insurance company. Depending on the company/organization you are working for and the state in which they are located, Workers Compensation may apply to any accidents. Your employer will take care of the necessary details for you. Employers may verify states' requirements by searching this website: <a href="http://www.dol.gov/dol/location.htm" title="External - U.S. Department of Labor" target="_blank">http://www.dol.gov/dol/location.htm</a></p>
<p>By being registered for an internship, each intern will be covered by a $1 million liability policy during the semester of their experience. This will cover you in case of a major mishap while on the job.</p>
<strong>What do I do when I'm done?</strong>
<p>You'll want to ensure that everything is wrapped up with your employer as far as assignments and projects are concerned. You will be emailed a reminder to return to Career Navigator to complete an evaluation. In addition, you should also check in with your Department Coordinator to see if there are any final evaluations, assignments or reports that you need to submit.</p>
<strong>Are internships pass/fail, or do I receive a grade?</strong>
<p>All internships are academic courses, and you will receive credit and a grade. You will be registered for a course under the direction of your Department Internship Coordinator. They will review all associated assignments and evaluations and issue a grade when your experience is complete. Any questions about grades issued should be discussed with your coordinator.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
