<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x58017" Name="Registration" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Registration</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Information about registering for an internship, including how and when to register, and the requirements for student and employer. </Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>All internships at BYU-Idaho are academic courses, and therefore you must register for credit just as you would for any other course on campus. However, the registration process differs from how you register for your other classes. Read below to learn how to get this process started.</p>
<h2>When do I need to register?</h2>
<p>An internship is just like any other course - you must register BEFORE beginning work. Think of it this way - you wouldn't attend a Math class for weeks before registering for it, you register for the class and then begin attending. The same holds true for an internship course.</p>
<p>You should secure your internship and allow yourself plenty of time to get registered, usually 30 days or so before starting work.</p>
<p>Regular registration deadlines apply, especially for students seeking financial aid to help with their tuition costs.</p>
<p>Those who apply beyond these guidelines will not receive credit for their experience. Credit will not be given for "past experience".</p>
<p>For registration deadlines please see the campus calendar or contact us for more information.</p>
<h2>How do I register?</h2>
<p>Click this link for complete&nbsp;<a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/0212InternshipInstructionSheet.docx" title="Internship Instructions" target="_blank">Internship Submission Instructions</a></p>
<p>The following steps are the basic guidelines for internship registration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Find and secure an internship position.</li>
<li>Fill out an Internship Approval form (under 'Experiential Learning') on&nbsp;<a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com/students/">Career Navigator</a>.</li>
<li>Print and take to your Faculty Coordinator OR save as a PDF document (from the 'Print' option) and email to your <a href="x29025.xml" title="Internship Coordinators">department coordinator</a>&nbsp;for approval.</li>
<li>The department coordinator will approve and forward the internship request to the ADC for final processing.</li>
<li>Upon completion, the Academic Discovery Center will authorize you to register for the appropriate course.&nbsp; You will then receive <span style="text-decoration: underline;">TWO EMAILS</span> with important information on registering the internship and completing all necessary activities to receive credit for it.</li>
<li>Unless otherwise directed in the emails <span style="text-decoration: underline;">YOU</span> will be responsible for registering for the course once authorized. Failure to do so in a timely manner may result in lost credit.</li>
<li>Begin working. Be sure to complete all syllabus assignments and all&nbsp;<a href="http://www.byui.edu/academic-discovery-center/students/internship-info-and-services/complete-an-internship-evaluation" title="Evaluations">evaluations</a> to ensure that you will receive credit for your internship.</li>
</ul>
<h2>What does my Experience Provider need to do?</h2>
<p>Each company that hosts BYU-Idaho interns must have a "Master Agreement" on file with the University. This agreement outlines the responsibilities of the student, the Experience Provider, and the University. Click here to see a sample of the <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Advising/MasterAgreementOutline.pdf" title="Master Agreement Outline PDF" target="blank">Master Agreement Form</a> and an outline of these responsibilities. (Note: this is NOT the official document).</p>
<p>It is the student's responsibility to ensure this document is in place before beginning work.</p>
<p>To complete the master agreement, your employer simply goes to <a href="https://byui-csm.symplicity.com"> Career Navigator</a> and registers - the master agreement is the last step in the registration process.</p>
<p>Additionally, near the end of your internship your supervisor will receive instructions on completing an evaluation of your performance, which is then sent to your department coordinator for grading purposes.</p>
<p>Some departments may require your supervisor to complete reports or other evaluations during your experience. Check with your coordinator for more information.</p>
<h2>Are there any other requirements?</h2>
<p>Yes! Each department sets their own guidelines for internships. Each department coordinator has developed a <a class="intLink" href="x29025.xml" title="Syllabi">course syllabus</a> for internships. You will always have some sort of academic requirement such as daily journal entries, a weekly check-in, monthly reports, etc. Be sure to obtain a copy of the course syllabus before starting work. Part of your grade will depend on the assignments you complete.</p>
<h2>How can I check my registration status?</h2>
<p>There are several steps that need to be taken to register a student for an internship.</p>
<p>To check your registration status, go back to Career Navigator and click on the &ldquo;internships&rdquo; button &ndash; your status will be indicated next to your request. If you have any questions about your status, you may contact the Academic Discovery Center.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
