<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x58051" Name="Internship Service Missionary Open Houses" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Hub Service Missionary Open Houses</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Information about Hub Service Missionary Open Houses, which is where students can meet with internship service missionaries from several different cities each semester.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h2>Next Open House: September 2012</h2>
<h2>
<hr />
What happens at an Open House?</h2>
<p>The open house is just that - an open house: you are welcome to come and go during the event.</p>
<p>Throughout the Open House, the Service Missionaries from each city will give periodic presentations about their city, focused on demographics, transportation, economy, and so forth.</p>
<p>Each presentation typically lasts 5-10 minutes, followed by brief Q &amp; A.</p>
<p>Every 15-20 minutes, a signal is given and you are free to move to another presentation/city that interests you. The process is repeated to give you the opportunity to visit with the missionaries in as many cities as possible.</p>
<h2>Why should you come to an Open House?</h2>
<p>The purpose is to help you network, rather than find you a job. The missionaries' goal is to supplement the research and contacts you have already made, and help you in your search for a job, internship, housing, etc. They will ask you what kind of things you have already done, applications you have submitted, internet searches and calls you have made - then work with you to maximize your results. They can tell you about housing, local transportation, singles branches and more. Ultimately, you will be responsible for following up with them, at which time they can offer any additional resources they may find for you.</p>
<h2>Setting Interview Appointments with the Missionaries</h2>
<p>Following the Winter and Fall Open Houses (and sometimes in Spring semester), the missionaries typically set aside a day to meet individually with students. These appointments are designed to allow the missionaries to get to know you better. Appointments should be utilized if you are seriously considering relocating to the missionaries' city, and are looking for specific information in regard to opportunities. They will have you fill out an information sheet that they can refer to later when they return home, so they can contact you with any additional resources they find.</p>
<p>If you are still in the preliminary stages of research and aren't ready to commit to a city, you are welcome to <a class="intLink" href="x35066.xml" title="Service Missionaries">contact the Service Missionaries</a> any time - usually by email.</p>
<h2>Open House Schedules</h2>
<p>Hub Service Missionary Open Houses at BYU-Idaho are scheduled three times per year to give students the opportunity to meet face-to-face with Hub Service Missionaries from thirteen cities across the United States. The Hub Service Missionaries come to campus to conduct information sessions and one-on-one interviews with students interested in internships and jobs in their city.</p>
<h3>March</h3>
Service Missionaries from Denver, Salt Lake City, New York City, Chicago, Washington DC, Idaho Falls and Portland are scheduled for an Open House. This year the event will take place on March 21st.
<p> </p>
<h3>September</h3>
Service Missionaries from Phoenix, San Jose, Boise, Dallas, Seattle, Los Angeles, and Idaho Falls come to campus for an Open House.
<p> </p>
<h3>June</h3>
In June, all of the missionaries come to BYU-Idaho to conduct a thirteen-city Open House.
<p> </p>
<p><strong><a href="x29018.xml" title="Open Houses">Click here</a> for open house dates &amp; times.</strong></p>
<br />
<h2>More about the Service Missionaries</h2>
<p>Hub Service Missionaries serve one to two years in their home cities. Their calling is to open doors of opportunity for BYU-Idaho students as they seek internships and careers. Hub Service Missionaries are an excellent resource because of their connections and experience with local business and industry leaders.</p>
<p><a class="intLink" href="x35066.xml" title="Expeditions &amp; Service Missionaries">Click here</a> for more information on the Hub Program and Service Missionaries.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17690" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
