<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x58332" Name="Avoid Email Scams" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Avoid Email Scams</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Tips on how to avoid email scams</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Email provides us a convenient and powerful communication tool. Unfortunately, it also provides scammers and other malicious individuals an easy means for luring potential victims.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho does not give out student email addresses, nor randomly send out student resumes. Please note that through Career Navigator, you can "opt in" to have your resume included in "resume books". These books allow employers to review student profiles and resumes for qualified candidates, which they may then contact in regard to a job opening or internship. If you do not wish to participate, you simply do not opt in. If you change your mind, you may change your settings at any time.</p>
<p>If you have a question about an email you have received <em>via Career Navigator</em>, or suspect it is not legitimate, you may forward the message to careernavigator@byui.edu for review. (Do not forward non-CN emails, as we cannot verify their validity.)</p>
<p>The US Computer Emergency Readiness Team (US CERT) has put together a document and list of resources to help you avoid being scammed. <a href="http://www.us-cert.gov/reading_room/emailscams_0905.pdf" title="CERT Document" target="_blank">Click here for the article</a> with accompanying links.</p>
<h3>Summary</h3>
<ul>
<li>Unsolicited commercial email, or "spam," is the starting point for many email scams.</li>
<li>Many email scams have existed for a long time. In fact, a number of them are merely "recycled" scams that predate the use of email. </li>
<li>Bogus business opportunities promise the opportunity to make a great deal of money with very little effort.</li>
<li>Emails are crafted to look as if they've been sent from a legitimate organization.</li>
<li>Versions of "419" scams promise to give you a "cut of the proceeds" if you comply. In short - they promise to send you a check, which you deposit in your account. Within a certain time-frame, you are required to then send a cashier's check or "Western Union" the money - minus the amount you get to keep - back to them. However, their original check bounces, leaving you on the hook with your bank for the entire amount.</li>
<li>In short, if you discover an email in your inbox proposing a complicated arrangement to secure and split funds, you can safely assume someone is trying to ensnare you in a 419 scam. </li>
</ul>
<h3>What You Can Do to Avoid Becoming a Victim</h3>
<ul>
<li>Filter Spam. Because most email scams begin with unsolicited commercial email, you should take measures to prevent spam from getting into your mailbox.</li>
<li>Regard unsolicited email with suspicion.</li>
<li>Treat email attachments with caution.</li>
<li>Never send personal information to a source you have not verified.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Use Common Sense</h3>
<p><strong>Don't Believe Everything You Read</strong>. Scammers and spammers will tell you that someone you trust has given them your email address: your school, a friend, or a family member. Generally this is not true, there are many ways to obtain your email address, especially your school email.</p>
<p><strong>Verify the Sender.</strong> Most legitimate companies have their own email domain. Use caution when a business email comes from a hotmail account (also live.com) or other non-business domain.</p>
<p><strong>Learn the email policies of the organizations you do business with.</strong> Most organizations doing business online now have clear policies about how they communicate with their customers in email. Many, for instance, will not ask you to provide account or personal information via email. Understanding the policies of the organizations you do business with can help you spot and avoid phishing and other scams. Do note, however, that it's never a good idea to send sensitive information via unencrypted email.</p>
<p><strong>Consider the Job.</strong> Why would a legitimate business need to process payments via a college student? Even "busy" businesses typically have accountants or accounting departments.</p>
<p><strong>Find the Company Website and Job Postings.</strong> If the company truly offers this position, it should be on their company website. Don't click on a link in their email - do a web search for their site; link could take you to questionable sites or start a malicious download or virus.</p>
<h3>What To Do If You Have Become a Victim of a Scam</h3>
<p>If you have become a victim and lost money, you should notify your local police department and follow their instructions. You will typically want to forward the original email as an attachment - don't copy and paste the message, they will need the original header information.</p>
<p>Protect your personal information - if you have released any account numbers, contact the account holders (banks, credit card companies, etc) immediately.</p>
<p>Keep your virus scanning software current, and run a scan to see if you've downloaded malicious content. If so, have your computer cleaned by reputable resource.</p>
<h3>Additional Resources</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.us-cert.gov/reading_room/emailscams_0905.pdf" title="US CERT Report" target="_blank">Full US CERT Report</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ftc.gov/opa/1998/07/dozen.shtm" title="FTC Dozen Scams" target="_blank">FTC Unveils "Dirty Dozen Email Scams"</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.secretservice.gov/faq.shtml#faq13" title="SS 419 Scam" target="_blank">Secret Service: "Reporting 419 Scams"</a></p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17690" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
