<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x58587" Name="I-Learn News" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">I-Learn News</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">I-Learn News</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<link href="prebuilt/stylenew/css/OpenClose.css" media="screen, projection" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
<p>I-Learn Newsletters</p>
<p>2012 - <a href="Documents/academic-technology-support/winter12.pdf">Winter</a> ,&nbsp; <a href="Documents/academic-technology-support/spring12.pdf">Spring</a> ,&nbsp; <a href="Documents/academic-technology-support/fall12.pdf">Fall</a></p>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>Faculty Technology Center Services</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide">We are available to help set up and organize I-Learn courses, provide hands-on training for I-Learn, and supply training and assistance for other software applications. We can also help create instructional materials for teachers to use in their courses. We are here to help make using campus technologies easier for faculty members. <br /> <br /> The FTC is located on the 3 <sup>rd</sup> floor of the McKay Library, room 355. Our hours are 8am to 6pm, Monday through Friday. We are closed for Devotional. </div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>Gradebook Overview</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide"><strong>Changing the Display Options</strong> <br /> By default, grades in the gradebook are viewed in percentage form. From time to time, however, it makes more sense to view the grades as points. Teachers can control how they and their students view the gradebook. To change how the <em>teacher</em> views scores in the gradebook, click "Display Options" in the top left corner of the gradebook, then click "Score Display Options". Changing how <em>students</em> view the gradebook is done in the "Grading Categories" tab in the Course Plan. By double-clicking on the name of the category, teachers can set how students view their grades. <br /> <br /> <strong>"Weight in Category" vs. Points</strong> <br /> When creating an assignment, discussion board, or journal in the course plan, there are two boxes where you can enter score options. One is labeled "Relative weight in category", and the other is "Grading Scale". To illustrate how these options affect the final score, here is an example: Let's say that you use a weekly assignment to keep track of participation points. Your class meets three times per week. To keep the scoring simple, you make your assignment worth three points, and award one point for each day that a student attended a class. However, you would like each class to be worth more than one point in the students' overall grades. You would like each week of participation to have a weight of 20 points. This is an example of where these two options come in handy. Under "Grading Scale" you would enter "3" to signify that the assignment will be graded out of 3 points. Under "Relative Weight in Category" you would put "20" to make the 3 points have a larger impact on the students' overall grade. Having these two different options allows you to simplify grading and reduce headaches. <br /> <br /> <em>For a more in-depth explanation of working with the Gradebook, see the tutorials at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats/tutorials/">www.byui.edu/ats/tutorials</a></em> . </div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>Groups Overview</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide">Group Setup in I-Learn is used to set up a single course with multiple sections, or as a way to separate students into groups for collaborative assignments, discussion boards, and other purposes. Groups can be comprised of any number of students. When creating assignments, assessments, or other items in the course plan, you can adjust the item settings to apply to all groups or to individual groups. You can also create different group sets, which contain different groups. This allows you to create as many different groups throughout the semester as you would like. When creating a group set, you will be able to specify the group set name, the number of groups you would like created or the approximate number of students per group, and how the group members will be assigned (alphabetically, randomly, etc...). When working with groups, especially within discussion boards, it is important to establish the desired groups and settings for the assignment before students begin submitting their assignments. <br /> <br /> <em>For a more in-depth explanation of working with groups, see the tutorials at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats/tutorials">www.byui.edu/ats/tutorials</a> .</em> </div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>Things to Know When Calling the FTC</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide"><em>Course ID:</em> The course ID allows us to find your course more quickly than searching by the course name (for example, there are a lot of Math 108 courses). It can be found by double-clicking the BYU-Idaho logo in the upper right-hand corner of the screen. <br /> <br /> When you call, make sure you have the course or program that you need to help with open. <br /> <br />While we are happy to help you in any way possible, there are some things that you may not be aware that you can do on your own! For example, you can:
<ul>
<li>Assign sections to your courses</li>
<li>Add assistants</li>
<li>Create course content</li>
<li>Upload resources (i.e. PowerPoint presentations and PDF files)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>New ATS Website</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide">Academic Technology has a new website! You can use our website to look up tutorials, find out who your ISR is, and learn about technology assistance available on campus. <br /> <br /> Here are some important links to remember: <br /> <br /> <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats">www.byui.edu/ats</a> - Academic Technology homepage <br /> <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats/ftc">www.byui.edu/ats/ftc</a> - Faculty Technology homepage <br /> <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats/isr">www.byui.edu/ats/isr</a> - A list of ISRs and their assigned areas <br /> <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats/tutorials">www.byui.edu/ats/tutorials</a> - Tutorials for various campus technologies </div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>Have You Met Your ISR?</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide">ISR stands for "I-Learn Service Representative". Eight employees in the FTC are assigned to be ISRs. Each ISR is trained to provide personalized assistance to their assigned departments. They are able to answer any questions or concerns you may have about I-Learn. In addition to I-Learn, ISRs can provide one-on-one training for commonly used programs including the Microsoft Office Suite, the Adobe Suite, Box.com, Qualtrics, and Adobe Connect. <br /> <br /> One of the ways in which ISRs can help faculty members is through an office visit. This will allow your ISR to visit with you in a comfortable setting, using your own equipment. To arrange for an office visit with your ISR, call x7230 or send an e-mail to <a href="mailto:ilearntraining@gmail.com">ilearntraining@gmail.com</a> . A list of ISRs and their corresponding departments is available at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ats/ftc">www.byui.edu/ats/ftc</a> .</div>
<div class="open_text">
<div class="posMark"></div>
<strong>I-Learn Information Meeting Fall 2012</strong></div>
<div class="close_text hide">The following are videos from the I-Learn Information Meeting held in the fall of 2012. <br /> <br /> <a href="http://youtu.be/NOUG2cO3rQc">Up and Coming Developments in I-Learn</a> <br /> <br /> <a href="http://screencast.com/t/zpxR4Zrxh">Groups</a> <br /> <br /> <a href="http://www.screencast.com/t/ZceH19Bh6W">Gradebook Tips</a> <br /> <br /> <a href="Documents/academic-technology-support/ftc lingo.swf">FTC Lingo</a> <br /> <br /> <a href="http://www.screencast.com/t/47NFkqEu">What is an ISR?</a> </div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x15119" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
