<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x58768" Name="Talent Manager"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Manager</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Managers are required to meet weekly throughout the entire semester with the Talent Performance Board, as well as hold an additional weekly planning meeting with their committee until the show is over.  There will also be some additional time devoted to carrying out various assignments related to the show, pertaining to auditions, set-up, etc.</p>
<p><strong>Theatre Workshops<br /></strong>Student managers would most likely participate through acting in a student written and student directed play.  There is some commitment involved as most productions take between 6 and 12 weeks to run.</p>
<p><strong>Broadway Review<br /></strong>Popular Broadway hits make this a popular show among students.  The manager would be overseeing the committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include auditions, publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Acoustic Café</strong><br />A smaller and much more laid back version of Guitars Unplugged, this show is held in the Manwaring Center Theater or Crossroads in a "café" atmosphere.  The manager would be overseeing the committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include auditions, publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>I-Cover<br /></strong>This show features cover songs in a band setting, with a minimum of three people per band.  The manager would be overseeing a committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include auditions, publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Battle of the Dance<br /></strong>Contrary to the name, there is no battle, but there is a lot of fun dancing involving everything from Ballroom to Hip-Hop.  The manager would be overseeing a committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include auditions, publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Film Festival<br /></strong>This show provides an opportunity for the students who have been involved in the Film Making Workshops to show their films to the student body.  The manger would be overseeing a committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Best-of Show</strong><br />This popular show combines the best-of acts from the shows held during the semester.  The manger would be overseeing a committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Grand Pianos Live</strong><br />This show revolves around the piano and involves everything from classical music to pop.  The manager would be overseeing a committee and ultimately responsible for a successful show.  Responsibilities of the committee would include auditions, publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Barbershop Music</strong><br />Student volunteers would most likely learn how to conduct Barbershop music from experienced directors, or they would help recruit more students who would be interested in learning how to sing Barbershop once a week.</p>
<p><strong>Writing Workshop<br /></strong>This position would be facilitating interested students who would like to share their writings and teach each other in a weekly workshop type setting.</p>
<p><strong>Dance Workshops<br /></strong>Student volunteers would most likely teach basic dance instruction to those students who would normally feel "awkward" learning how to dance in a more formal setting.  Dance taught will include modern, jazz, swing or ballroom.</p>
<p><strong>Poetry Workshops<br /></strong>Student volunteers would most likely teach basic poetry guidelines on a weekly basis.</p>
<p><strong>Comedy Workshops<br /></strong>These positions would be involved in teaching the basics of impromptu comedy with other interested students in a weekly workshop type setting.</p>
<p><strong>Film-making Workshops<br /></strong>Student volunteers would most likely teach basic film making techniques once a week to interested students.  They may also help the student teacher by overseeing the availability of equipment and room scheduling.</p>
<p><strong>Poetry Slam<br /></strong>This position would be facilitating interested students who would like to share their poetry and receive feedback and insights in a weekly workshop type setting.</p>
<p> </p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
