<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x58754" Name="Wellness Director"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Director</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wellness Directors</strong></p>
<p>As a director, you'll have the opportunity to direct, teach, train, counsel, and provide vision to students who are building programs and events in Activities. In this position you'll learn, stretch, grow and also help grow others. Directors work with each other to help the Activities program reach its objectives.</p>
<p>A good director is actively engaged in the organization's activities and programs. Directors have to have served at the coordinator level or equivalent to apply.</p>
<p><strong>General Responsibilities</strong></p>
<p>Set up and direct weekly council meetings with coordinators (approx.. 1 hr)<br />Participate in weekly directors' council meeting (approx. 1 hr)<br />Counsel regularly with Student Area Director and area Advisor.<br />Invite individuals to participate in the program.<br />There is a time commitment of 8-10 hrs. each week with some weeks requiring 10-20 hours.</p>
<p>There are two directors in Wellness Activities, Instructor and Events Director and Biggest Winner and Consultant Director.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor and Events Director</strong></p>
<p>Directs, teaches, trains, counsels, and provides vision. Assists instructor coordinator and advisor in selecting fitness class instructors. Holds coordinators accountable for interviewing, selecting and training others. This position reports to the Student Area Director.</p>
<p><strong>Biggest Winner and Consultant Director<br /></strong>Directs, teaches, trains, counsels and provides vision. Holds coordinators accountable for interviewing, selecting and training others. This position reports to the Student Area Director.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
