<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x58738" Name="Area Directors Page" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Area Directors Page</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Area Directors Page</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<img height="223" src="Images/activities/Get-involved/area-directors-big(0).gif" width="652" /><br /><br />
<div class="hiddenText" style="display: block;">
<div class="content">
<p style="text-align: right;"><strong><strong><a href="https://byui.qualtrics.com/SE/?SID=SV_5BVoPQHkqDIetTK">&gt;&gt;&gt;Student Leader Application&lt;&lt;&lt;</a></strong></strong></p>
<h2><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Student Area Directors </strong></span></h2>
<p>A Student Area Director oversees an entire area of Activities.  Student Area Directors are primarily responsible for teaching, training  and empowering the Student Directors in that area. They also meet with  other Student Area Directors to Council about Activities-wide issues.</p>
<p>Teach/Empower/Grow others</p>
<p>Student Area Directors are responsible to teach and empower Student  Directors sufficiently that they can succeed in their roles. This is  done by teaching the following:</p>
<p>The mission and vision of the University, the Activities Program and their area.</p>
<p>The structure of the Activities Program and their stewardship area.</p>
<p>The roles of the student leaders in Activities and their stewardship area.</p>
<p>The doctrines and principles of disciple-leadership found in the LBF  manual and the scriptures, and how those principles and doctrines apply  to what the leaders are actually doing in their stewardships.</p>
<p><strong>Administrative</strong></p>
<p>New Student Area Directors counsel with the current Student Area  Director, current Student Director and Advisors in the selection of new  Student Directors for their area.</p>
<p>Student Area Directors assist in selecting a new Student Area Director for their area.</p>
<p>Hold Student Directors accountable</p>
<p>Area Directors are responsible to hold Student Directors accountable  for their stewardship. This requires that Area Directors understand not  only their own stewardship but also the stewardship of the Student  Directors.</p>
<p>Understand and apply the Student-Leader Model.</p>
<p>Responsible for and aware of what happens in the area.</p>
<p>Area Directors are not responsible to create and execute all that  happens in their area, but they are expected to know what is happening  at all levels in their areas and to ensure that programs and events are  done to an acceptable level and standard.</p>
<p>Area Directors are responsible to oversee marketing efforts in their area.</p>
<p>With other Student Area Directors, coordinate efforts for  organizational representation at campus wide events (NSO, Spirit Week,  etc.)</p>
<p><strong>Counsel</strong></p>
<p>Student Area Directors meet and counsel regularly with Student Directors as well as observe and provide feedback.</p>
<p>Student Area Directors meet and counsel weekly with other Student  Area Directors regarding general Activities issues and to study and  prepare together for training within their areas.</p>
<p><strong>Communicate</strong></p>
<p>Return and report</p>
<p>Student Area Directors are responsible to Area Coordinators and return and report regularly.</p>
<p>The Student Area Directors council is responsible to the Activities Directors.</p>
<p>Area Communication</p>
<p>Student Area Directors work with their Student Directors to see that  effective communication processes are in place which include all of the  student leaders in that area.</p>
<p><strong>Continuity</strong></p>
<p>Student Area Directors are responsible to see that pertinent  information about their area is passed on to the succeeding Student Area  Director.</p>
<p><strong>Student Area Director Guidelines</strong></p>
<p>As you consider a student leadership experience in the Student  Activities Program, please review the Mission Statement and following  guidelines:</p>
<p>MISSION STATEMENT: <br />Student Activities invites individuals to  experience the power of acting for themselves through involvement in  student-led programs and events.<br /><br />1. HONOR CODE / DEVOTIONALS <br />Student  Leaders are expected to be exemplary in living the Brigham Young  University-Idaho Honor Code. Student Leaders are expected to attend  BYU-Idaho weekly devotionals. Devotional dress is encouraged when  possible. <br /><br />2. SCHOLARSHIP/EMPLOYMENT <br />Student Leaders will receive a full-tuition scholarship upon being selected and meeting the following qualifications:</p>
<p>a. On track during the semester serving and a matriculated full-time  student (14 credits minimum). Does not have to be on track to apply, but  must be in town for all training.<br />b. Completed no more than 129 cumulative credits prior to the semester they serve.<br />c. Must have earned a minimum of 30 credits at BYU-Idaho prior to the semester they serve.<br />d. Maintain a minimum 2.5 GPA and no University restrictions.<br />e. Serve an average of 10 hours per week. (There may be occasional times in the semester when more time is required.)<br />f.  If employed, it is recommended that the student leader not work more  than 10 hours per week at an on/off campus job. Employment should be in a  different area from where the student director is currently receiving a  scholarship.<br />g. May only serve as a Student Director one semester. May only serve as a Student Area Director one semester. <br />h.  Student Area Directors must have previous experience at the coordinator  level or above. Student Directors should have had previous experience  at the manager level or above.</p>
<p><br />3. RESPONSIBILITIES <br />Student Leaders will attend retreats,  meetings, and other events as announced. Student Leaders will enable  students to lead, guide, and direct those serving on their boards as  they plan and organize activities. <br /><br />4. AVAILABILITY <br />Must be  available to their student leaders and advisors on a regular basis  throughout the semester, including checking e-mails regularly for  Activities communications. <br /><br />5. COUNCIL MEETINGS <br />Student  Leaders are expected to attend Activities Council Meetings as scheduled.  &nbsp;The Student Leader will also hold weekly council meetings for the  purpose of leadership training, planning, organizing, etc. in their own  area. <br /><br />6. ADVISOR <br />Student Leaders will meet regularly with their advisor for purposes of training, evaluation, planning, etc.<br /><br />7. EXPERIENCE <br />Student  Area Directors must have previous Activities experience at the  coordinator level or above. Student Directors should have had previous  experience at the manager level or above.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="x34041.xml">&gt;&gt;Back to Main Get invovled Page.</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6793" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
