<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x58752" Name="Wellness Managers"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Managers</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Managers counsel regularly with their Student Coordinator. They also invite individuals to serve as group leaders or committee members. They set up and direct regular council meetings with their group leaders and committee and invite individuals to participate in Wellness programs.</p>
<p>Managers can expect to serve 2-4 hours each week, with occasional weeks of 4-10 hours. The following list shows the type of manager positions available.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Workshop Manager:</strong> Select, lead and counsel with committee members to plan, organize and administer the event. Reports to the Programs and Events Coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Publicity Manager:</strong> Assist other students and the publicity coordinator in marketing the programs and events within the wellness program.  Report to the Publicity Coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Fitness Consultant:</strong> If you are selected to train, you will create workout plans that meet the needs of the individuals or groups. You will train in the fitness center during your available hours and work with the consultant coordinator and other trainers to invite, educate and motivate the BYU- Idaho population on weight training. Reports to the Fitness Consultant coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Fitness Instructor:</strong> If you are selected to teach, you will teach during your available hours and work with the instructor coordinator and other instructors to invite, educate and motivate the BYU-Idaho population in your fitness classes. Reports to the Instructor coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Biggest Winner Challenge Manager:</strong> Create and administer the challenges for the Biggest Winner contestants to help reach their team fitness goals and points. Reports to the Fitness Instructor Coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Biggest Winner Nutrition Manager:</strong> Find students that are willing to council the Biggest Winner contestants in their individual nutrition goals. Create and schedule calendar and appointments for the nutrition committee and contestants with their weekly weigh in and nutrition consultations. Be a trouble shooter for the nutrition program. Reports to the Biggest Winner Coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Programs and Events Managers</strong>: You will choose the event you're interested in hosting. Help organize and administer the event.  Reports to the Programs and Events Coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>5 K Managers:</strong> You will help organize and administer the 5 k. Reports to the Programs and Events coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Lazyman Ironman Manager:</strong> You will help organize and administer the event. Reports to the Programs and Events coordinator.<br /><br /><strong>9 Week Challenge Manager:</strong>  You will administer the online event. Compile the results and send the data to the Programs and Events coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Competition Manager:</strong>  You will plan and administer the event. Reports to the Programs and Events coordinator.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
