<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x58781" Name="Social Coordinator"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Coordinator</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Social Activities has a few options for Coordinator positions. Read about them below:</strong></p>
<strong>
<p><strong>Social | Events / Dance Coordinator Application</strong></p>
<p>The student in this position will work with managers to plan ongoing campus events. The Coordinator does not actually plan the event, but rather, supports the Managers in their individual and committee responsibilities.</p>
<p>Must be available for weekly meetings. A Social Board meeting is held on Mondays at 5 P.M. and a Coordinators Council is held Thursdays from 2:00 to 3:00.<br />Take turns conducting weekly Social Board Meeting.<br />Attend weekly Coordinators meeting<br />Hold one-on-ones with managers at least every other week while maintaining weekly contact.</p>
<p>Ability to work well with others, provide support and feedback to committee.</p>
<p>Provide oversight of ongoing events occurring the current Semester. Organization, delegation, and follow-up are key elements of success in this position.</p>
<p>Must plan and attend one overnight retreat.</p>
</strong>
<p><strong>Social Activities - Publicity Coordinator</strong></p>
<p>Publicity Coordinators provide leadership and feedback to Managers and Volunteers as they publicize and promote events. Most areas of Activities have a Publicity Coordinator for each category. There are two main components to the responsibilities of the Publicity Coordinator.</p>
<p><strong>Leadership Role</strong></p>
<p>The Publicity Coordinator works with individual program and event managers to organize their promotional efforts. They help managers inform students about upcoming events and invite them to participate. They are also responsible to make the best use of the publicity and marketing budget allocated to each area and/or category. This requires coordination with Student Managers, Student Coordinators and Student Directors. The majority of the Publicity Coordinators' time will be spent functioning in this role.</p>
<p><strong>Specialized Role</strong></p>
<p>The Publicity Coordinator also works with Activities Communications in a specialized role to provide publicity and marketing direction to event and program managers. Publicity Coordinators work with Activities Communications to receive training and advice. Publicity Coordinators understand BYU-Idaho and Activities guidelines for use of logos, images and appropriate language when publicizing events. They provide feedback to Student Managers and their volunteers when creating printed and electronic promotions for their events. Coordinators do not need to be graphic designers, copywriters or advertising specialists, but a strong interest in written and visual communication will contribute to a positive experience.</p>
<p><strong>Time Commitment for Coordinators</strong></p>
5-7 hours per week.]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
