<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x58769" Name="Talent Director"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Director</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Director Responsibilities</strong></p>
<p>The Student Director for <strong>Talent Exploration Board </strong>would be responsible for teaching and training coordinators who would be ultimately responsible for providing opportunities for students to explore their talents in such areas as art, music, dance and theater. This position would involve at least three meetings per week which would include a Talent Performance Board meeting, an Activities Council Meeting and a meeting with the adviser. Other meetings with coordinators would probably be needed. A Student Director could expect to put in at least ten hours per week. An applicant should have had previous experience on the Talent Exploration Board at a manager or coordinator level.</p>
<p>The Student Director for <strong>Talent Performance Board </strong>would be responsible for teaching and training coordinators who would be ultimately responsible for providing opportunities for students to perform in both auditioned and non-auditioned settings. Such events include Guitars Unplugged, Nashville Nights, Grand Pianos Live, Broadway Revue, etc. as well as non-auditioned opportunities such as Music Outlet. The Student Director would be responsible for making sure standards and policies are maintained and that there is a wholesome and uplifting atmosphere at these events. This position would involve at least three meetings per week which would include a Talent Performance Board meeting, an Activities Council Meeting and a meeting with the adviser. Other meetings with coordinators would probably be needed. A Student Director could expect to put in at least ten hours per week. An applicant should have had previous experience on the Talent Performance Board at a manager or coordinator level.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Cannot have more than 129 credits total</p>
<p>Must have at least a 2.5 GPA</p>
<p>Must be a full time, on-track student</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
