<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x58767" Name="Talent Volunteer"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Volunteer</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Volunteer staff make up the largest group of students that help run Activities. Being a staff member is a great way to jump in and get involved, develop skills, meet people and help create exciting events and programs at BYU-Idaho. Volunteers work with managers who oversee the planning, organization and execution of specific events and programs.</p>
<p>Start your own workshop or help with any of the following:</p>
<p>Barbershop Workshop</p>
<p>Writers Workshop</p>
<p>Capoeira Workshop</p>
<p>Art Workshop</p>
<p>Dance Workshops: Hip Hop, Swing, Ballroom</p>
<p>Theater Workshops</p>
<p>Guitar Workshops</p>
<p>Pep Band</p>
<p>Poetry Slams</p>
<p>So You Think You Can Kareoke?</p>
<p>Music Outlet (weekly informal opporunties for students to share original music)</p>
<p>Or Start your own! - Click on the "Create an Activity" link from our homepage</p>
<p><strong>Auditioned Shows Opportunities</strong></p>
<p>Volunteering for these events would include helping the managers to organize events which include auditions publicity, and marketing. Duties would include weekly meetings in addition to the auditions and event. Some of the shows may include:</p>
<p>Acoustic Cafe (An informal show featuring Acoustic guitar in a "cafe" type setting)</p>
<p>Broadway Revue (A show featuring Broadway music in song, dance or theater)</p>
<p>Guitars Unplugged (A show featuring the guitars in a larger band setting)</p>
<p>I-Cover (A show featuring "cover" songs in a band setting)</p>
<p>Battle of the Dance (A show featuring dance)</p>
<p>Film Festival ( A show featuring student films)</p>
<p>Grand Pianos Live (A show featuring the piano)</p>
<p>Best of Show (The last show of the semester featuring the "best" from all of the other shows)</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
