<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x59430" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dodgeball Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27035" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>Field and Boundaries</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The dodgeball playing field shall be held with the basketball court lines.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The basketball center line shall act as the dodgeball  center line and may not be crossed by active players during play.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Exception: An active player may inadvertently cross the center  line during the opening rush of the game. This shall be considered legal  provided the crossing involved is caused by the person's momentum in  attempting to secure a ball from the center line and does not result in a  lingering presence or an attempt to eliminate an opponent from the  opponent's side of the line. An advantage may not be gained from this  crossing.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During play, all in-active players shall remain within the designated bench area.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During play, all active players shall remain within the basketball court boundary lines.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players may pass through their end-line only to retrieve  stray balls that have not been picked up or returned to play and are  lying on the ground.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players may not:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Have any part of their body contact the playing surface on or over a side-line.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Exit or re-enter the field through their side-line.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Leave the playing field to avoid being hit by or to attempt to catch a ball.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Have any part of their body cross over the center line and contact the ground on their opponent's side of the court.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players leaving the field to retrieve balls are out of play until their return and may not be hit for OUTS.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players leaving the field to retrieve balls must return immediately upon securing said balls.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Balls leaving the playing field shall be rolled directly onto the field by bench players.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Balls may not be passed to active players from the bench area.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Balls bounding from one field area to another shall remain  out of play until they can safely be retrieved. Players are not to leave  their play area to retrieve such balls.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players deemed to have illegally left the playing field shall be declared OUT.</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><em>Match/Game Play</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each match won will be worth 1 point. The winner will be  the team that accumulates the most points in the allotted game time</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Games will consist of two twenty minute halves. Half time will not exceed five minutes.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;A coin toss shall allow the toss winning team to choose  their side for the first game. The teams shall switch sides between each  game.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Overtime periods shall continue the alternation set in regulation but will only occur in post-season play.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The object of dodgeball is to eliminate all opposing players by getting them OUT which occurs when:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;An opposing player is hit with a LIVE thrown ball below the shoulders.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; NOTE: If a player ducks or takes a position with their head below  where their shoulders would normally be when standing (crouching,  kneeling, sitting, rolling or laying) and this is clearly the cause for  the player being hit above the shoulders, the player is OUT and the  throw is considered legal.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; a player catches an opposing player's thrown LIVE ball.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; an opposing player is caused to drop a held ball as the result of  a thrown LIVE ball, usually, but not necessarily always, when a ball is  being used to block a thrown ball.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; an opposing player illegally steps out of bounds.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;A LIVE ball refers to a ball that strikes or is caught by  an opposing player without/before contacting the ground, another player,  ball, official or other object.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player may use a ball to block throws from opposing players.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Once players are OUT, they must immediately drop any balls  in hand and exit the playing field at the nearest point, end-line or  side-line</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players may be re-activated during a game. This is done by a  team-mate catching a live ball thrown from the opposing team.&nbsp; When  caught the player that is re-activated must return to the game in the  order they were eliminated.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players OUT may not eliminate opposing players. Example: If  a player is hit with a legal throw and then catches another legal  throw, the second thrower is NOT eliminated.</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Timing and Substitutions</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All players are in jeopardy until the court officials recognize and signal a time-out or end of regulation.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All throws released prior to the official whistle for  time-out or end of regulation are LIVE until becoming dead. A throw  released prior to the official whistle can eliminate an opposing player.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Substitutions may not be made during a game.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Exception: Injured, non-eliminated players may be replaced during  a game but are ineligible for the remainder of that particular match.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Substitutions may only be made from game to game in a match.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Beginning a Game</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All six (6) dodgeballs shall be placed on the center line with three (3) on each side of the center circle.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players begin each game behind their end-line for the Opening Rush.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the official's signal, teams may approach the center-line to retrieve their dodgeballs.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any balls dropped in the Opening Rush rolling over the  center line and toward the opponent are lost to that opponent and may  not be retrieved.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A FALSE START will be called if players cross their  end-line prior to the official's game start signal. A false start  results in a ball being taken from the offending team's side of the  center line and place on the opponent's side. This will be repeated for  each infraction.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All balls must be carried or passed behind the attack line (volleyball 10-foot line) before</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; being legally thrown at an opponent.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Once a ball has been moved behind the attack line, it may be thrown from anywhere on</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the team's side of the court, including in front of the attack line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Once all balls are in play following the Opening Rush, all attack line restrictions end.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
