<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x59424" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bowling Coed Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27025" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>The Lineup</em><br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (3-on-3) When necessary, a coin toss will determine which  team will set its line-up first in the first game. The opposing team  will set its line-up first in the second game. An additional coin toss  will be held to determine which team will set its line-up first in the  third and final game.<br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To set a line-up, a team will determine which of its  players will bowl for the game and also determine the order of the  bowlers. Traditionally, the best bowler bowls first with the worst  bowler filling the last position in the order.<br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When beginning a head-to-head game with one less than the  standard number of players, the open position will be the last position  in the order. The position may not be filled until the next game begins.  When beginning a Baker-scored game with one less than the standard  number of players, the open position will be the first position in the  order.<br /> <br /></p>
<p><em>Rules</em><br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; RecSports bowling follows the general rules set forth by the ABC (American Bowling Congress).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Scoring - 5-on-5 Play</em><br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Three rounds are bowled with rounds 1 and 3 consisting of a  Baker-scored game. Round 2 consists of a each team member bowling a  complete game in a head-to-head match-up with the opposing team.<br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the first and third game, the Baker scoring system will be utilized.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Each player in the lineup will complete one frame in successive  order until 10 frames have been completed.&nbsp; For example, player A will  bowl frames 1 and 6; player B bowls frames 2 and 7, etc. The player who  begins the 10th frame of the game will execute all deliveries for that  frame.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The scores of the opposing teams are then compared with the higher score being awarded 4 points.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Teams with less than a full lineup will receive a score of zero  (0) for the open position in the rotation for the purposes of  determining the team total score.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the second game/round, head-to-head scoring will be utilized.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The team which wins the first Baker game must set its lineup first for the head-to-head game.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Each player will bowl all 10 frames in this round. Head-to-head  scores are compared with each player who wins the head-to-head matchup  earning 1 point for his/her team. In case of tie, each tied player earns  1/2 point.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Additionally, the team with the most total pins in the game (sum  of all 5 players) will earn an additional 3 points. If tied, each team  will receive 1.5 points.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Teams with less than a full lineup of will receive a score of 60  for the open position. The open position will automatically lose the  point to the opposing team, regardless of the opposing team member's  score for the game.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A total of 16 points are possible, therefore 8.5 points are  required for a victory in the match. If a team tallies 8.5 points in  just two games, it is not required to bowl the third game.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; In the event of a tie in total team points after three games, the  total number of pins for the entire match will serve as the  tie-breaker. In championship round play, a fourth Baker-scored game will  be bowled to break the tie.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Scoring - 3-on-3 Play</em><br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Three players from each team will match-up head-to-head in each game.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Each player who wins a head-to-head matchup will receive one  point. In the event of a tie, each tied player will receive 1/2 point.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; When one less than the standard number of players bowl for one  team, the open position will receive a score of 80 or the average of the  other three bowlers, whichever is lower. The open position will  automatically lose the head-to-head matchup, and the 1 team point, to  the team with four players regardless of the pin total in that position.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The team with the most total pins for the game will receive 2 additional points. If tied, each team will receive 1 point.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Three games will bowled with the point scores added from each  game to obtain the final team point score. Less than three games may be  bowled upon mutual agreement of team captains. If a team tallies 8  points in just two games, it is not required to bowl the third game.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; In the event of a tie in total team points after three games, the  total number of pins for the entire match will serve as the  tie-breaker. In championship round play, a fourth, Baker-scored game  will be bowled to break the tie.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
