<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x59446" Name="Rule 3: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 3: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Floor Hockey Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27050" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The game will consist of two (2) periods of twenty (20)  minutes each. The game time is running time. There will be a two minute  break between periods.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each team will be permitted to have two (2) timeouts per  game. The length of each timeout shall be one (1) minute. The running  clock will stop during timeouts. The team who calls the timeout must be  in possession of the puck.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;When a team is winning by five (5) or more goals, with two  minutes left on the game clock, the game will end by mercy rule.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Regular season games can end in a tie. No overtime period will be played.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; During the playoffs, games tied at the end of regulation will  enter a three-minute sudden-victory overtime period. If additional  overtime periods are needed, a 1-minute intermission will be observed  between overtime periods. Teams do not receive additional timeouts for  the overtime period.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em><em>Game Play</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Face-offs: A face-off will be utilized to begin each period  and to resume play after any stoppages. All face-offs shall occur at  designated locations. At the beginning of each period, and following  scores and penalties, the face-off shall be at center court. During a  face-off there shall be NO movement until the puck has been dropped. All  players must be on their defensive side of the floor during face-offs.  An imaginary line that bisects the face-off area determines the  defensive side. The blades of the players facing off must be  perpendicular to the line bisecting the face-off area.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Disallowed Goals: Goals will not be counted if the stick is  held and/or brought above waist level. Goals will not be counted if the  puck is intentionally kicked into the goal. Goals will not be counted  if the puck is batted into the goal with the hand. Goals will not be  counted if a player from the offensive team is in the goal crease.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Crease Rule: At no time is a player of the offensive team  permitted to enter the goalie's crease with any portion of the body. If a  goal is scored while the player is illegally in the crease, it shall be  disallowed. A face-off occurring at the nearest face-off area will  resume play. However, if the official determines that the goalie was  interfered with, an interference penalty will be assessed. An offensive  player's stick is not allowed to enter the crease at any time. If an  offensive player places the stick in the crease area, they will be  penalized for interference. This includes breaking the plane of the  crease with the follow through of a shot. If this occurs, the goal will  not be permitted. If the official determines that the goalie was  interfered with, an interference penalty will be assessed. Goalies are  permitted to leave the crease area to establish a better angle of  defense or to play the puck. However, the goalie may not leave the  crease for purposes of freezing the puck outside the crease area. The  player will promptly be penalized for delay of game.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Holding the Stick: The carrying of a stick above the normal  standing height of the waist is prohibited and a minor penalty will be  assessed. This includes the process of a shot, including the follow  through, and the goal will be disallowed.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hand Passes: If a player closes his hand on the puck, play  will be stopped and puck will be awarded to the opposing team at the  nearest free shot location. Players may bat the puck straight down with  their hand, but such action may not result in the puck being directed  towards a teammate.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kicking the Puck: Players may stop the puck with their  feet, but may not use their feet to guide the ball to a teammate. A  violation results in the puck being awarded to the opposing team at the  nearest free shot location.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Running fouls (without penalty minutes) including high  sticking, hand passing, kicking the puck, player/stick in the goal  crease, and dangerous play or sliding by any players and goalie freezing  the puck outside of the crease area.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Penalties</em><br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delay of Game (Minor Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Delay of game shall be called if any player falls on the puck. A  Minor Penalty shall be assessed on the player other than a goalkeeper  who deliberately fall on or gathers a puck into his/her body. Any player  who drops to his/her knees to block shots should not be penalized if  the puck is shot under them or becomes lodged in their clothing or  equipment. Any use of the hand to make the puck unplayable will be  penalized promptly.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on a goalkeeper who (when his/her body is  entirely outside the boundaries of his/her own crease line) deliberately  falls on or gathers the puck into his/her body, which is not a shot on  the goal.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any players (including goalkeeper) who delays  the game by deliberately displacing a goal from its normal position. The  official shall stop play immediately when a goal has been displaced.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player, including the goalkeeper, who  holds or freezes the puck with his/her stick, feet, or body along the  wall in such a manner as to cause a stoppage of play.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elbowing and/or Kneeing (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who uses his/her elbow or knee in  such a manner as to foul an opponent in any way. Floor Hockey in a  Non-Contact Activity --- No Intentional Contact!</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Slashing (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who impedes or seeks to impede the progress of an opponent by slashing with the stick.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Flagrant slashing will constitute a Misconduct Penalty. Any  player who swings his/her stick at another player in the course of any  altercation shall be subject to a game Misconduct Penalty.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Spearing (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who spears or attempts to spear an  opponent. Spearing shall be defined as stabbing at an opponent with the  point of the stick blade while the stick is being carried with one hand  or both hands.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tripping (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who shall place his/her stick,  knee, foot, arm, hand, or elbow in such a manner that it shall cause an  opponent to trip or fall.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hooking (Minor Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who impedes or seeks to impede the progress of an opponent by hooking with his stick.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Interference (Minor Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who interferes with or impeded the  progress on an opponent who is not in the possession of the puck.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who deliberately knocks a stick out of an opponent's hand.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;Shall be called on any player who prevents an opponent from regaining his/her stick once it has been dropped.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who throws the stick towards an  opposing player with the puck in a manner that would distract said  opponent. A Misconduct Penalty will also be assessed in this instance.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who intentionally fouls form behind  thus preventing a reasonable scoring opportunity. The violating player  shall be automatically ejected with a designated player from the floor  serving a five-minute Major Penalty. There are no penalty shots.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Holding (Minor Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who holds an opponent with hands or stick or in any other manner.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Butt Ending and Cross Checking (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who "cross checks or butt-ends" or  attempts to "butt-end" an opponent. NOTE: Attempts to butt end shall  include all cases where a "butt end" gesture is made regardless whether  body contact is made or not.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Charging (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Shall be called on any player who runs or jumps into or charges an opponent.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Roughing (Major Penalty)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Roughing is defined as any type of unnecessary and/or intentional  contact. Players must play the puck with the stick at all times. Using  the body to gain an advantage, or playing against an opponent's body and  not the puck, is not permitted.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Penalty Assessment</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MINOR PENALTY --- Two (2) Minutes. For a minor penalty on  any player, other than the goalie, the player shall be ruled off the  floor for two minutes during which time no substitute will be permitted  for that player. A minor penalty ends when a goal is scored by the  offended team or at the end of 2 minutes of served penalty time. In the  event of 2 or more players from the same team serving minor penalties  simultaneously, once a goal is scored by the offended team the penalized  player who has served the most time will have his/her penalty ended.  The remaining players will remain in the penalty box until their time  has expired or additional goals are scored.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;MAJOR PENALTY --- Five (5) Minutes. For a major penalty on  any player, other than the goalie, the player shall be ruled off the  floor for five minutes during which time no substitute will be permitted  for that player. A major penalty ends only at the end of 5 minutes of  served penalty time. Goals scored by the offended team do NOT end a  major penalty. The entire 5 minutes must be served.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;Penalty minutes will carry over into successive periods including overtime.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;A goalie may receive any minor or major penalty as if he/she were a player on the floor.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The team captain shall designate a player currently on the  floor when the penalty occurs to serve the penalty in place of the  goalie.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the goalie receives a Misconduct Penalty, he/she is  ejected from the game. A new Goalie is placed in the game and the team  captain shall designated a player currently on the floor (at the time of  the penalty) to serve the penalty in place of the goalie.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Misconduct Penalty shall be assessed on any player for  obscene, profane, or abusive language directed toward the officials,  opponents, and/or Intramural Sports supervisors.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Misconduct Penalty shall be assessed on any player who  persists in disputing or showing disrespect for the rulings of an  official.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Misconduct Penalty shall be assessed on any player who  intentionally knocks or shoots the puck out of the reach of an official.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Misconduct Penalty shall be assessed on any player who  deliberately throws any item or equipment prior, during, or after the  game. Said player will be immediately ejected from participation in the  game. Reinstatement procedures must be followed. A fine may be assessed  for broken or damaged equipment.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Misconduct Penalty shall be assessed on any player who  persists, after a warning by the official, in any conduct (including  threatening or abusive language or gestures) designed to intimidate an  opponent into obtaining a penalty.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Play resumes following the assessment of a penalty with the  awarding of the puck to the offended team at the nearest free shot  location or a face-off in the event of fouls against each team.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
