<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EventsDetail ID="x59586" Name="50-Lap Relay" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Event Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">50-Lap Relay</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">50-Lap Relay</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Event Details" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Friday, June 22, 2012<br />7:00 p.m.<br />BYU-Idaho Stadium</p>
<p>"Biggest and Best Activity for Wards!"<br />"Builds Ward Unity Like None Other!"<br /><br />50-Lap Co-ed Relay:  Women run odd-numbered laps; men run even-numbered.</p>
<p>Rest of the ward cheers from the stands.</p>
<p>Ice Cream sandwiches for all ward members (participants and spectators).</p>
<p>Pizza party for winning team (provided at later date)<br /><br />Entry fee: $35 per ward (charged to ward account)<br />$10 discount for teams registering by Tuesday, June 19<sup>th</sup>.</p>
<p>Register your ward online <a href="mailto:relay@byui.edu">here</a>.</p>
<p>Event details (see below)<br /><br /><a href="mailto:stutzd@byui.edu">Questions???</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="Semesters" label="Available Semesters" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><AvailableFall type="boolean" label="Available Fall" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</AvailableFall><AvailableWinter type="boolean" label="Available Winter" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</AvailableWinter><AvailableSpring type="boolean" label="Available Spring" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</AvailableSpring><AvailableSummer type="boolean" label="Available Summer" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</AvailableSummer><xPower Type="List" List="Date" Name="DateElements" label="Dates" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" display="localdateshort" Expanded="true"><Date type="date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" display="localdateshort" Expanded="false" UTC="true">20120622T18:00:00</Date></xPower><AdditionalInformation type="dhtml" label="Additional Information" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="686">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="191">
<p> </p>
</td>
<td valign="top" width="495">
<p align="center"><strong>50-Lap Relay Event Information<br /></strong>Friday, June 22, 2012, Stadium track, 7:00 p.m.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>1.             The relay consists of each team running 50 segments, or legs. Each leg, except for the first and last legs, is 400 meters long (one lap around the outdoor track). The race begins with the first runner on each team lined up at the starting line in the infield, starting at the same time. The race continues until each team's 50th leg runner crosses the relay finish line.</p>
<p>2.             The distances of the 1st and 50th legs vary depending on which exchange zone the team is assigned (see diagram on back).</p>
<p>3.             Women run odd-numbered legs; men even-numbered ones. Thus, women run legs 1, 3, 5, ..., 47, 49. Men run legs 2, 4, 6, ..., 48, 50.</p>
<p>4.             Teams consist of between 2 and 50 runners. Having a different person run each leg is encouraged. However, if teams consist of fewer than 25 women and 25 men, then some team members may run multiple legs. Remember that only women may run odd-numbered legs and only men may run even-numbered ones.</p>
<p>5.             The person running the 1st leg lines up at the starting line at the south end of the infield (see diagram). At the "Go" command, she runs towards the north end of the infield, staying to the right of the cones before turning left onto the track. She remains on the track, running in a counter-clockwise direction the rest of her leg. She continues running until reaching the team's exchange zone to pass the baton to her teammate.</p>
<p>6.             Persons running legs 2-49 each run one complete lap around the track, receiving and handing off the baton within the team's assigned exchange zone (see diagram).</p>
<p>7.             The person running the 50th leg receives the baton in his team's exchange zone and runs around the track until reaching orange cone at the north end of the track. He then turns left around the cone onto the infield and continues running until crossing the Relay finish line (see diagram).</p>
<p>8.             The primary purpose of the Relay is to get people involved in a physical fitness activity, working together as a team toward a common goal. Hopefully, one common goal is to complete the relay with every member of the team having done his/her best. We realize the support given by ward members in cheering their team members and encouraging them as they run around the track may be just as vital to the team's success as those individuals actually involved in running the relay.  As an incentive to realize these purposes, <strong>all</strong> <strong>ward members that run a leg of the relay plus ward members that come to cheer on your team will receive ice cream afterwards.  The winning team will receive a free pizza party (provided at a later date)!</strong></p>
<p>9.             Relay ceremonies begin at 7:00 p.m.  The Relay itself starts at 7:10 p.m.</p>
<p><strong>Instructions for Team Captains </strong></p>
<p>The captain is responsible to make sure that each runner on the team a) understands and follows these instructions, and b) is aware of the location, determined in advance by the captain, where the team will meet together the evening of the relay. At this meeting the captain should distribute the numbers and pins to each team member, give the baton to the person running the 1st leg, and give last-minute instructions.</p>
<p>1.             The captain should pick up the team's packet Friday, June 22<sup>nd</sup>, between 6:15 and 6:45 p.m. at the check-in table at the southwest end of the track. The packet will include numbers and safety pins for each runner and a baton .</p>
<p>2.             Numbers must be pinned on the <strong>front </strong>of the shirt and be visible while the person is running his/her leg. Each runner must wear the race number whose last 2 digits corresponds with the leg number he/she is running (for example, the person running the 1st leg must wear the race number with the last two digits "<strong>01</strong>").</p>
<p>3.             Only 2 members from each team should be on the track at any given time during the relay. They are: 1) the person running with the baton and 2) the person waiting in the exchange zone to receive the baton. All other relay members should be in the infield or stands watching and cheering on their team. Note: <strong>Outgoing runners must enter the exchange zone from the outside lanes of the track. </strong></p>
<p>4.             To register, a representative from each ward (team) must register by emailing <a href="mailto:relay@byui.edu">Relay@byui.edu</a> to confirm: (1) your intent to participate in the Spirit Relay, and (2) the name of the ward (team) and captain.  The non-refundable entry fee is $35 per team.  Teams registering by Tuesday, Jun. 19, will receive a $10 discount.<br /><strong><br />**BYU-Idaho Standards apply.  No painted faces please (this includes both participants and spectators)**</strong></p>]]></AdditionalInformation></xPower><EventImage type="imagefile" label="Event Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" Width="200" Height="280" Alignment="right" Border="" Expanded="true" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">Admin_Offices/Activities/Sports/Events/50-Lap Relay/relay2.jpg</EventImage><xPower Type="List" List="Images" Name="Images" label="Gallery Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="false" Height=""><Images type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="28" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="30" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace=""></Images></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6793" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></EventsDetail>
