<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x59606" Name="Golf Scramble Rules" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Golf Scramble Rules</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Golf Scramble Rules</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110819T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rules 1: Game Play</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Players</em></strong></p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There will be a $6 entry fee to play in this tournament.</p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players must provide their own set of clubs.</p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Inform managers if you have a Teton Golf Season Pass.</p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each team will consist of two (2) players and will compete against another team of (2) two.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Men's, women's, and coed teams will all play in the same division.<strong></strong></p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Men tee off from the blue tees and women from the red tees.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each team will be paired with another team for each tee time.<strong></strong></p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A two-person scramble format will be used. These rules can be found in this information sheet.<strong></strong></p>
<p>&bull;&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All rules of etiquette and fair play should be followed during the tournament.<strong></strong></p>
<p><em>Location</em></p>
<p>Tournament of nine (9) holes will be located at the Municipal Golf Course (26 Airport Road, Rexburg) Near the Rexburg Airport.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Game</em></p>
<p>USGA golf rules will govern play. In a scramble format, both team members tee off on each hole and then decide which tee shot they like best and mark the spot with a tee or ball marker. The other player picks up his/her ball and places it within one club length (no closer to the hole) of the marked spot.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Both players hit their shot from the chosen spot. This procedure is followed on every shot for the remainder of the hole, including putts. The ball should be marked on the putting green also. Putts need to be made within 6 inches of the marked spot (no closer to the hole). The first ball to go in the hole is counted for the team score. If the ball you choose to play is in a hazard (sand, water, etc.), or in the rough, you cannot drop the ball outside of the hazard or rough even if relief is within one club length away. Men will always tee off from the blue tees. Women will always tee off from the red tees. Each team member must use at least three tee shots during the nine holes. A mark on the scorecard to indicate whose tee shot was used on each hole is required-you will forfeit any team awards if you do not do so. All rules of etiquette and fair play should be followed during the tournament.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Awards</em></p>
<p>There will be overall team awards given to the top three teams. Individual awards will also be given for closest to the pin, longest putt made, and longest drive.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Longest Putt Made:</em></p>
<p>This competition has one<strong> </strong>division. If your putt is the longest made, write your name on the marker card and place the marker in the ground on the spot from where you putted the ball. Once the marker has been placed in the ground, it should stay there until someone else makes a longer putt. Then, that person should repeat the procedure of writing their name on the card below the other name(s) and place the marker at the spot. Use the flag as a measuring rod if it is a close call.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><em>Closest to the Pin: </em></p>
<p>This competition has one division. If your tee shot is closest to the hole, write your name on the marker card and place the marker in the ground on the spot where your ball came to rest. Once the marker has been placed in the ground, it should stay there until someone else hits a closer shot. Then, that person should repeat the procedure of writing their name on the card below the other name(s) and place the marker at the spot. Use the flagstick as a measuring rod if it is a close call.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><em>Longest Drive:</em></p>
<p>This competition has one<strong> </strong>division. If your drive is the longest, write your name on the marker card and place the marker in the ground on the spot where your ball came to rest. The ball must be in the cut fairway to count. Once the marker has been placed in the ground, it should stay there until someone else hits a longer drive. Then, that person should repeat the procedure of writing their name on the card below the other name(s) and place the marker at the spot.<strong></strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
