<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x59988" Name="Service Volunteer"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Volunteer</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Volunteers</strong></p>
<p>Volunteers make up the largest group of students that help run Activities. Being a volunteer is a great way to jump in and get involved, develop skills, meet people and help create existing events and programs at BYU-Idaho. Volunteers work under the direction of managers who oversee the planning, organization and execution of specific events and programs.</p>
<p>Volunteers can do the following within Service Activities.</p>
<strong>
<p> </p>
<p>Special Needs Volunteer</p>
</strong>
<p><strong>Merit Badge Pow Wow Volunteer</strong><br />If selected to fill a position in the Merit Badge Pow Wow program, you will serve on a council with other student volunteers to assist with the planning, organizing, and recruiting of students willing to be Merit Badge counselors in a variety of areas. Council members must be able to attend a weekly meeting, volunteer 3-8 hours a week, and follow through with commitments.</p>
<p><strong>Charity Date Auction Volunteer</strong><br />If selected to fill a position in the Charity Date Auction program, you will serve on a council with other student volunteers to assist with the planning, organizing, and implementation of the annual Charity Date Auction event. Council members must be able to attend a weekly meeting, volunteer 3-8 hours a week, and follow through with commitments.</p>
<p><strong>Teton Marathon Volunteers</strong><br />If selected to fill a position in the Teton Marathon, you will serve on a council with other student volunteers to assist with the planning, organizing, and recruiting of students to assist with the Teton Dam Marathon event. Council members must be able to attend a weekly meeting, volunteer 3-8 hours a week, and follow through with commitments.</p>
<p><strong>SnoFest Volunteers</strong><br />If selected to fill a position in the SnoFest program, you will serve on a council with other student volunteers to assist with the planning, organizing, recruiting of students to assist with the SnoFest event. Council members must be able to attend a weekly meeting, volunteer 3-8 hours a week, and follow through with commitments.</p>
<p><strong>School Carnivals</strong><br />If selected to fill a position with School Carnivals, you will serve on a council with other student volunteers to assist with the planning, organizing, recruiting of students to assist with the School Carnivals that take place at the area elementary schools during Halloween. Council members must be able to attend a weekly meeting, volunteer 3-8 hours a week, and follow through with commitments.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
