<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x59975" Name="Managers"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Managers</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Managers</strong></p>
<p>Student Managers are responsible for the planning and execution of events with the help of a council of volunteers. Managers counsel with their Coordinator about their stewardship and how to meet the needs of the students.</p>
<p>Teach/Empower/Grow others</p>
<p>Mangers are responsible to teach and empower their volunteers. This includes teaching the<br />following:</p>
<p>The mission and vision of the University and the Activities Program.<br />The mission and vision of your particular area.<br />The structure of the Activities Program.<br />The roles of the student leaders in Activities.<br />The doctrines and principles of disciple- scriptures and how those principles actually doing in their stewardships.<br />The Student-Leader Model.<br />The tactical responsibilities of the Manager position.</p>
<p><strong>Administrative</strong></p>
<p>Recruit and choose members of your council.</p>
<p>Managers, in conjunction with their student leaders, plan and execute the events and activities in their area.</p>
<p>Understand and apply the Student-Leader Model.<br />Delegate responsibilities.<br />Hold students accountable.<br />Manage the event with the help of their student volunteers.</p>
<p><strong>Counsel</strong></p>
<p>Managers counsel regularly with their Coordinator about the event that the Manger is responsible for and about the growth of the students the Manger has stewardship for.<br />Managers meet regularly with their council to plan, organize, and run the event they are responsible for.</p>
<p><strong>Communicate</strong></p>
<p>Return and report</p>
<p>Managers are accountable to their Coordinator and need to return and report regularly about their stewardship.</p>
<p>Area Communication</p>
<p>Mangers work with their Coordinator to see that effective communication processes are in place.</p>
<p>Continuity</p>
<p>Mangers are responsible to see that pertinent information about their event is recorded and saved for future access.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
