<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x59994" Name="Outdoor Coordinator"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Coordinators</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coordinators</strong></p>
<p>Though not involved in the tactical planning and execution of events, coordinators oversee specific programs in Activities. They lead, train, counsel and help managers succeed as they run programs and events. In Outdoor there are coordinator positions for Recreation and Skills and Publicity.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Recreation and Skills Coordinators<br /></strong>These coordinator positions are not open for application. They are offered by invitation only of the advisors as they require specific experience and skill sets.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>The only coordinator position that takes applications in Outdoor is the Publicity Coordinator.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Publicity Coordinator - </strong>Publicity Coordinators provide leadership and feedback to Managers and Volunteers as they publicize and promote events. This position is a time commitment of 5-7 hours per week. There are two main components to the responsibilities of the Publicity Coordinator.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Leadership Role</strong></p>
<p>The Publicity Coordinator works with individual program and event managers to organize their promotional efforts. They help managers inform students about upcoming events and invite them to participate. They are also responsible to make the best use of the publicity and marketing budget allocated to each area and/or category. This requires coordination with Student Managers, Student Coordinators and Student Directors. The majority of the Publicity Coordinators' time will be spent functioning in this role.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Specialized Role</strong></p>
<p>The Publicity Coordinator also works with Activities Communications in a specialized role to provide publicity and marketing direction to event and program managers. Publicity Coordinators work with Activities Communications to receive training and advice. Publicity Coordinators understand BYU-Idaho and Activities guidelines for use of logos, images and appropriate language when publicizing events. They provide feedback to Student Managers and their volunteers when creating printed and electronic promotions for their events. Coordinators do not need to be graphic designers, copywriters or advertising specialists, but a strong interest in written and visual communication will contribute to a positive experience.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
