<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.101 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x59932" Name="Manager" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Manager</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Manager</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Managers are required to meet weekly throughout the entire semester with the Talent Performance Board, as well as hold weekly planning meetings with their committee.&nbsp; Additional time will be devoted to carrying out various assignments related to the shows/workshops, pertaining to auditions, set-up, etc.</p>
<p><strong>Show Managers:</strong></p>
<p>Show managers oversee the committee and are ultimately responsible for a successful show.&nbsp; Responsibilities of the committee would include auditions, publicity, media services, performers meetings and other logistics involved in producing this show.</p>
<p><strong>Broadway Revue - </strong>Students are given the opportunity to perform a song or to a song from a musical of their choice. This performance can be in a variety of formats: song, dance, theater etc.</p>
<p><strong>Acoustic Caf&eacute; - </strong>Usually the first show of the semester, this free guitar show is held in the MC Crossroads allowing for a more laid back atmosphere.</p>
<p><strong>I-Cover - </strong>This show features cover songs in a band setting, with a minimum of three people per band.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Battle of the Dance - </strong>Contrary to the name, there is no battle, but there is a lot of fun dancing involving everything from Ballroom to Hip-Hop.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Film Festival - </strong>This show provides an opportunity for students to show their personal films to the student body.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Best-of Show - </strong>This popular show combines the best-of acts from the shows held during the semester.&nbsp; The manager for this show is also in charge of organizing the voting process and selecting the best performers from each show.</p>
<p><strong>Grand Pianos Live - </strong>This show revolves around the piano and involves everything from classical music to pop.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Guitars Unplugged - </strong>A Guitar show featuring original and cover songs in a larger band setting.</p>
<p><strong>The Folk Show (NEW SHOW!) -</strong> A new show with a folk music theme.</p>
<p><strong>The Beatles Show (NEW SHOW</strong>) - Students are invited to sing, dance, play with a band or other performances along to a Beatles song, or with a Beatles theme.</p>
<p><strong>Nashville Nights - </strong>This show is dedicated to country music; students have the opportunity to perform their favorite songs.</p>
<p><strong>BYU-I's Got Talent - </strong>This is a variety show where students with unique and interesting talents are invited to perform, this can be everything from Juggling and Magic to Beat Boxing and Hip Hop Dancing.</p>
<p><strong>Magic Moments - </strong>A Disney themed show.</p>
<p><strong>Academy of Comedy - </strong>Students perform Improv skits in shows multiple times throughout the semester. Manager of Academy of Comedy is also the manager of the Improv Comedy Workshop.</p>
<p><strong>Last Poet Standing - </strong>In this semester long show, participants recite their original poetry each week in hopes that the audience keeps them for another round.</p>
<p><strong>I-Live Sketch Comedy - </strong>For this show auditions are held at the beginning of the semester and participants perform sketches that have been written by other BYU-Idaho students.</p>
<p><strong>Show Choir - </strong>An auditioned group that meets weekly to learn songs and choreography. Like Glee, BYU-Idaho style.</p>
<p><strong>Mad Flow Hip Hop Show - </strong>A show dedicated to Hip-Hop. Come sing, dance, or rap to covers or originals.</p>
<p><strong>Laugh Out Loud -</strong> A Stand Up comedy show.</p>
<p><strong></strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Workshop Managers:</strong></p>
<p>Workshop managers are responsible for leading a group of students in learning new skills. They work with their committee to run weekly workshops in which time is dedicated to a prepared lesson plan as well as giving the opportunity to practice their new skills.</p>
<p><strong>Writing Workshop </strong><strong>- </strong>This workshop facilitates interested students who would like to share and develop their writing skills. All levels of writing welcomed.</p>
<p><strong>Dance Workshops - </strong>Ballroom, Swing, Hip Hop, Break dancing and Country Dance Workshops are offered and give opportunity for students of all levels to participate by learning or teaching their desired dance form.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Comedy Workshops - </strong>Improv and Stand-Up Comedy Workshops are offered.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Film Workshop - </strong></strong>Can be organized based on the needs of the workshop attendees with the focus on helping students to prepare films that they can then submit the Film Festival.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Debate Workshop - </strong>Students learn and practice the art of debate.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Jugglers Workshop - </strong>Students can learn how to juggle and other circus like talents.</p>
<p><strong>Capoeira Workshop</strong> - A combination of Brazilian Martial Arts and Dance</p>
<p><strong>Guitar Workshop - </strong>Students gather together to Improve or learn how to play the guitar or ukulele.</p>
<p><strong>Stadium Singing</strong> - Every Sunday students gather under the stadium to sing hymns together.</p>
<p><strong>Karaoke Night</strong> - YouTube Karaoke in the Crossroads.</p>
<p><strong>Music Outlet</strong> - Weekly open mic night where students can perform their own songs or cover a song of their choice.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6793" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
