<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x60336" Name="Show Checklist" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Show Checklist</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Show Checklist</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">BYU-Idaho Talent activities SHOW CHECKLIST</BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">One of the most important responsibilities of your job as manager is to provide leadership experiences for other students.  Share the responsibility and blessings that come with leadership.  Don't do it all yourself!</MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>SHOW CHECKLIST</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Immediately:</span></strong><strong> </strong></p>
&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Meet with your Assistants and Coordinator for training </strong>
<p>Your coordinator has had previous experience and should be able to answer most of your questions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Organize a committee</strong></p>
<p>One of the most important responsibilities of your job as manager is to provide leadership experiences for other students.&nbsp; Share the responsibility and blessings that come with leadership.&nbsp; Don't do it all yourself!</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Interview and select 3 - 6 students (depending on size of show) in addition to your assistants.&nbsp; Your Coordinator should give you applications of students who have applied.&nbsp; Interviewing helps you get a commitment from them.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hold regular Committee Meetings&nbsp; - schedule a room with Sister Powell (<a href="mailto:powellkr@byui.edu">powellkr@byui.edu</a>)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Always have an agenda&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Sample agenda:&nbsp; Opening prayer; spiritual thought; report on assignments; new business; new assignments; closing prayer)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Keep it to 30 minutes or less.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have someone keep notes during meeting and keep track of expenditures.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegate <span style="text-decoration: underline;">meaningful </span>assignments (auditions; publicity; media concerns; ticket office, etc.)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Encourage them to build their own subcommittees if they need help (handing out fliers, etc.)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Trust them but give them deadlines for reporting back</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>CREATE A THEME FOR YOUR SHOW. </strong></p>
<p>You'll need a theme when you start thinking about lighting, decorating, and marketing.&nbsp; Plus, it's a great way to start getting yourself and your committee excited!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>ARRANGE TO HAVE YOUR AUDITION PACKETS PUT TOGETHER AND TAKEN TO THE M.C. 101 ACTIVITIES OFFICE &nbsp;IMMEDIATELY, REGARDLESS OF WHEN YOUR SHOW IS.</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Sign-Up sheets and Audition Packets</strong>:&nbsp; Fill in the name, date, place of your auditions on appropriate lines and then run off&nbsp; 35 copies (Guitars Unplugged will need about 90) of&nbsp; the "Group Information Sheet" and "Rule Sheet" from the Auditions section of&nbsp; your binders. Use the Library Copy Spot (account # 3611-11-5100).&nbsp;&nbsp; Staple the two sheets together to be handed out to the students who sign up and put in binder (from your folder). Fill out the Audition Sign-up sheet and the Fact Sheet which are stapled inside of folder and take to M.C. Information Desk. Keep checking back to make sure they don't run out of the packets.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Review summaries from previous shows</strong><strong> </strong>(In binders)</p>
<p>Start filling out the summary template as you go so you can leave a detailed summary after the show is over.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>BEGIN THE MARKETING PROCESS - Meet with Marketing Coordinator!</strong></p>
<p>Get &nbsp;ideas and themes for publicity - you can even have a design done, but the marketing coordinator must approve everything and&nbsp; needs to make sure the proper logos, etc. are on the posters.&nbsp; Be creative!&nbsp; Use Facebook, word of mouth, noon day booths (need to schedule spots with Sister Powell), web banners, etc.&nbsp; START EARLY!!! It takes longer than you think to get posters&nbsp; - at least 4 weeks!</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">POSTER PROCESS</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">:</span></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have design created by you or a committee person - Insert into approved template at <a href="http://www.byui.edu/identity/template/activities/print/postersvertical/default.htm">http://www.byui.edu/identity/template/activities/print/postersvertical/default.htm</a></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; E-mail to:&nbsp; <a href="mailto:ucidentity@byui.edu">ucidentity@byui.edu</a> for approval;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After approval, take or e-mail to copy spot (account #:&nbsp; 3613-01-6060) usually run off about 20</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have finished posters stamped in M.C. 101 - they will be removed if not stamped.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hang with a paper clip in appropriate spots on approved poster strips (no taping on glass, etc.)</p>
<p>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Three weeks prior to show:</span></strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>HANG POSTERS&nbsp;&nbsp; (</strong>See process above in Marketing Process)</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Schedule a room for Performers Meeting<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong>Contact Sister Powell to schedule a room for your performer's meeting which should be held about 3 days prior to your show.&nbsp; Take this information to the Events Services meeting with you so they can plan ahead to be there.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Two weeks prior to show:</span></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Attend Events Services Meeting</strong><strong> </strong>(See Show Schedule for date, time and place - in binder)</p>
<p>This is extremely important!&nbsp; It is a mandatory meeting and the show could be cancelled if this meeting is missed.&nbsp; Make sure the person who attends this meeting is also at the sound checks, auditions and at the show.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Be prepared with the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Media Meeting Agenda</span> in your binders.&nbsp; Know the answers to the things listed such as media budget, time show starts, if you're going to have an emcee, if you need projectors etc.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Be aware of any deadlines they give you . <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Make sure the information they request is turned in on time</span>!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Auditions</strong><strong> </strong>(See schedule for your audition date)</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>LYRICS: </strong>Lyrics must be e-mailed to committee (talentperformanceshows@byui.edu) prior to auditions.&nbsp; If they are not appropriate (check rule sheet) let them know in advance so they can change songs.&nbsp; A hard copy must also be brought to auditions.&nbsp; No changing of&nbsp; lyrics in cover songs!</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>JUDGES and JUDGES Meeting</strong><strong>:</strong> Your judges can make or break the show.&nbsp; They are responsible for selecting <span style="text-decoration: underline;">appropriate music</span> and ensuring the standards.&nbsp; They need to be trained well!</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Select 3-5 students with some experience in music or dance, but also some regular students.&nbsp; Try to have the same judges for the entire time if possible.&nbsp; Judges cannot be in the show!</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Judges Forms:&nbsp; Make copies of the Judge's application and Judges Rule Sheet for each judge.</p>
<p>(in binder under auditions)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Judges Meeting:&nbsp; Have a meeting with them within the week prior to auditions to train them on the standards, lyrics, (see auditions rules form), etc.&nbsp;&nbsp; Remind them to dress up and be respectful of those auditioning.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Snacks.&nbsp; If your judges will be at auditions for four hours you may want to purchase some snacks for them, but don't eat in front of performers and be frugal with your snacks ($25 - $30) limit. You can get the credit card from Sister Powell -M.C. 101 - be sure to save receipts and return the credit card and receipts the next day.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Get the judges I-numbers and names for the data base.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>NIGHT of AUDITIONS: </strong></p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have one or two committee people outside the audition room to check off the scheduled performers and to make sure they have the appropriate 2 forms (Group Information Sheet and signed Rule Sheet) and a copy of their lyrics.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All students performing must be a student (they can be off -track but not graduated) or the spouse of a student.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>IMMEDIATELY FOLLOWING AUDITIONS: </strong></p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; E-mail the list of who will be performing to <span style="text-decoration: underline;">everyone</span> who auditioned, not just the performers.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; E-mail PERFORMERS ONLY the time, date &amp; place of the mandatory Performer's Mtg.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">E-mail a list of the performers , committee members &amp; judges with their I-numbers to Sister Powell</span> at <a href="mailto:powellkr@byui.edu">powellkr@byui.edu</a> for data base statistics and post on I Learn page for the best of managers. (MANDATORY!)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">E-mail Media Technical Information Sheet to Events Services</span></strong> (in binders) with the technical needs of each performer in order of performance to &nbsp;<a href="mailto:bensonl@byui.edu">bensonl@byui.edu</a> within two days of your auditions.&nbsp; (They get real cranky if they don't have this by the Monday before your show.)&nbsp; Also e-mail a copy of the tech sheet to the Best Of Managers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">One week prior to show:</span></strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Ticket Office : </strong>(as soon as auditions are over) <strong> </strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Turn in the number of seats needed for performers, your committee people, and judges to Ticket Office to ensure them a seat at the show.&nbsp; Pick up that number of wrist bands from the Ticket Office so they can go in and out prior to the show without needing a ticket.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Performer's Meeting ( </strong>usually held about 2 or 3 days before the show<strong>)</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Immediately after auditions you should e-mail the performers and let them know when and where you will meet.&nbsp; This meeting is MANDATORY for the performers!</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; E-mail a reminder of the date and time to Events Services several days &nbsp;prior to meeting.&nbsp; (<a href="mailto:bensonl@byui.edu">bensonl@byui.edu</a>)</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During this meeting, the following should be reviewed:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; rules of the show (see rule sheet in binder)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; honor code (appropriate dress, lyrics, etc. to not offend the spirit)</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; schedule for sound checks&nbsp; - about every 10 minutes in <span style="text-decoration: underline;">reverse order</span> from show</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Events services representatives will be there to answer questions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Night of Show:</span></strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Sound Checks&nbsp; (Not a dress rehearsal)</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Held 2-3 hours before the show.&nbsp; Every performer <span style="text-decoration: underline;">MUST </span>come to their scheduled sound check so that the media service specialists can set their equipment, etc.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">The&nbsp; order of sound checks will run backwards from the last performer to the first.</span></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The media services will want to run through each act quickly and may not have time to play the entire piece so prepare the performers ahead of time.</p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Show!</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All performers should be seated a &nbsp;half hour before the show.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One member of your committee will be a stage director.&nbsp; This person will help the performers on and off the stage and keep communication with the sound and light specialists.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have a prayer prior to the show</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Be careful with the use of emcees.&nbsp; The most effective shows just announce the numbers from behind stage and keep it moving.&nbsp; If you do any thank you's, etc. keep them short and do it before the last number so you can end with the last number.&nbsp; Then have media services put on music or something so everyone knows it has ended. Your ending can make or break your whole show.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have a good time and enjoy the show!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Within 1 week after show:</span></strong></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Find out from Best Of Managers which performers were chosen for Best of and e-mail that information to all of the performers immediately! </strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>E-mail your tech sheet to the Best of Managers if you haven't already done so.</strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>CONTINUE TO ATTEND TALENT BOARD MEETINGS TO SHARE WHAT YOU LEARNED! yOU MAY EVEN WANT TO VOLUNTEER ON ANOTHER SHOW.</strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p>&uuml;&nbsp; <strong>Summary: </strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Use <span style="text-decoration: underline;">the summary template</span> in your binder for future managers.&nbsp; Sister Powell can e-mail you the template.&nbsp; Please list all information asked for in the template!&nbsp; Be specific and write down things you wish you'd have known!&nbsp; Include information on money you spent, the schedule, theme, problems, successes, and the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">names and I-numbers of all</span> participants, committee members and judges.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; E-mail a copy of the summary to Sister Powell at <a href="mailto:powellkr@byui.edu">powellkr@byui.edu</a> so she can put it on the computer for next semester's managers.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x6793" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x6784" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
