<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x60693" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Futsal Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x33988" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<meta content="text/html; charset=utf-8" http-equiv="Content-Type" />
<title>Untitled Document</title>
<p><strong>Rule 2: Play </strong></p>
<p><em>Start of Game</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Before play begins, a coin is  tossed and the team that wins the toss will have the choice of kicking off or  deciding which goal to defend. The second half play will begin with a kickoff  by the team that did not kickoff to start the game.</li>
<li>After the referee has given a  signal, the game shall be started. The ball is in play when it is kicked in any  direction. If the ball is not properly touched, the ball will again be placed  on the kickoff mark and the kickoff will be retaken.</li>
<li>The kicker may not touch the  ball again until it has been touched by another player.</li>
<li>A dropped ball is a way of  restarting the match after a temporary stoppage. Play may also be restarted  with an indirect free kick if, in the opinion of the officials, one team had  clear possession of the ball when the stoppage occurred.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Timing</em></p>
<ul>
<li>The duration of the game shall  be two (2) equal halves of twenty (20) minutes. Halftime shall not exceed five  (5) minutes.</li>
<li>The addition of time will be  at the discretion of the official.</li>
<li>Time shall be extended to  permit the taking of a penalty kick awarded before the sounding of the final  whistle to end each half.</li>
<li>Regular season games may end  in a tie.</li>
<li>During playoffs, the following  overtime procedures will be used:
<ul>
<li>A five (5) minute sudden-death  overtime period will be played.</li>
<li>If teams are still tied at the  end of overtime, the best out of five penalty kicks will win.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Teams will decide which player  takes the penalty kicks and take turns on goal with the other team.</li>
<li>If still tied at the end of  five attempts, each team will continue to select one player at a time to kick  until the score is no longer tied.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Scoring</em></p>
<ul>
<li>A goal is scored when the  whole ball has passed over the goal line, between the goal posts and under the  crossbar, provided that no infringement of the rules has been committed  previously by the team scoring the goal. If the official’s whistle sounds  before the ball passes fully into the goal, the goal shall not be allowed.
<ul>
<li>A goal may be scored directly  from a goal kick or a corner kick, but only against the opposing team.</li>
<li>A goal may be scored if a  goalkeeper throws, punts, or dropkicks a ball into their own goal.</li>
<li>A goal cannot be scored  directly from a kick-in; it must touch a member of either team before crossing  the goal line to be counted as a goal.</li>
<li>Goals may be scored directly  from a direct kick, but must be touched by another player on an indirect kick.</li>
<li>When a female scores it will  count as two (2) points, a male is only one (1) point.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Mercy Rule</em></p>
<ul>
<li>If a team is ahead by seven or  more goals with two minutes remaining in the second half, the game shall be  called. If a team takes the lead by seven goals during the final two minutes of  the second half, the game shall be called.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Ball In and Out of Play</em></p>
<ul>
<li> The ball is out of play when:
<ul>
<li>It has completely crossed the  goal line or touch line whether on the ground or in the air</li>
<li>The official sounds his/her  whistle</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> The ball is in play at all other times,  including when:
<ul>
<li>It rebounds from a goalpost,  crossbar, or corner flag post and remains in the field of play</li>
<li> It rebounds off of the official when he/she is  on the field of play</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>There will be no whistle to  restart play except:
<ul>
<li>When a team asks the official  for five yards</li>
<li>When play has been stopped to  caution or eject a player</li>
<li>For a penalty kick</li>
<li>When a goal is scored</li>
<li>The ball is out of play when  it touches the ceiling or net (the restart will be an indirect kick for the opponent  from the spot of last touching).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Fouls and Misconduct</em></p>
<ul>
<li> Free kicks shall be classified under two  types:
<ul>
<li> Direct – from which a goal can be scored  directly against the offending side. All direct kicks awarded in the penalty  area shall merit a penalty kick</li>
<li> Indirect – from which a goal cannot be scored  unless the ball has been touched by a player other than the kicker before  passing into the goal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Offenses for which a Direct kick  shall be given are:
<ul>
<li>Kicking or attempting to kick an  opponent</li>
<li>Tripping or attempting to trip  an opponent</li>
<li> Jumping at an opponent</li>
<li>Charging an opponent (A fair  charge is one in which a player makes non-violent shoulder to-shoulder contact  with an opponent, with the arms and elbows close to his/her own body, at least  one foot on the ground, and the ball within playing distance</li>
<li> Striking or attempting to strike and opponent</li>
<li> Pushing an opponent</li>
<li> Holding an opponent</li>
<li>Spitting at an opponent</li>
<li> Slide tackling an opponent</li>
<li> Intentionally handling, carrying, striking, or  propelling the ball with a hand or arm</li>
<li>Using foul or abusive language  directed towards a player or official</li>
<li>Handling by the goalkeeper  outside the penalty area</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Offenses for which an Indirect  free kick shall be given are:
<ul>
<li>Playing the ball a second time  before it has been touched by another player at the kickoff, a  throw-in/kick-in, a drop kick, a free kick, a corner kick, or a goal kick</li>
<li>Obstructing the progress of an  opponent</li>
<li> Playing in a dangerous manner (i.e. high kick,  playing on the ground)</li>
<li>If the goalkeeper takes more  than six seconds while controlling the ball with their hands before releasing  it into play</li>
<li> If the goalkeeper touches the ball with their  hands after receiving it directly from a throw in/ kick-in taken by a teammate</li>
<li> If the goalkeeper touches the ball with their  hands after it has been deliberately kicked to him/her by a teammate</li>
<li> A player prevents the goalkeeper from  releasing the ball from his/her hands</li>
<li>A player commits any offense  for which play is stopped to caution or dismiss a player</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>When a Direct or Indirect free  kick is being taken, all opposing players shall be at least five yards from the  ball until it is kicked unless they are standing on their own goal line.</li>
<li>If a Direct or Indirect free  kick is kicked directly into a team’s own goal, a corner kick is awarded to the  opposing team.</li>
<li> Treat all free kicks to be taken in the goal  area by the defense as a goal kick</li>
<li>An Indirect kick to be taken  in the goal area by the offense shall be taken from the top of the goal area  line</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Penalty Kick</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Awarded for any infringement  of the rules, within the penalty area, that would require a direct free kick  (including kicking the ball so that it touches the ceiling).</li>
<li>A penalty kick shall be taken  from the penalty mark. While the kick is being taken, all players with</li>
</ul>
<p>the exception of the player  taking the kick and the opposing goalkeeper, shall be within the field of<br /> play but outside the penalty  area and at least 5 yards from the penalty mark.</p>
<ul>
<li> The opposing goalkeeper may only move  laterally on his/her own goal line between the goalposts, until the ball is  kicked.</li>
<li>The player taking the kick  must kick the ball forward.</li>
<li>Should the ball hit the  goalposts or crossbar and rebound into play, the player who kicked the ball must  not play it again until it has been touched by another player. Penalty:  Indirect free kick</li>
<li> The ball shall be deemed in play directly  after it is kicked.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Kick-In/Throw-In</em></p>
<ul>
<li> When the ball passes completely over a  sideline, it shall be kicked in from the point where it crossed the line by a  player of the team opposite to that of the player who it last touched.</li>
<li> A player shall:
<ul>
<li> Place the ball on the ground on or behind the  sideline and proceed to take the kick following the rules of an indirect free  kick. The ball shall be in play immediately after it has crossed over the line and  may be played by any player except the one who executes the kick-in. Five yards  shall be given, the same as all free kick situations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>If the ball is improperly  kicked into play, the restart shall be taken by a player of the opposing team.</li>
<li>If the ball fails to enter the  field of play, it shall be kicked again.</li>
<li> If an opponent interferes with or in any way  impedes the actions of the thrower/kicker while the kick-in is being taken, the  official will administer a yellow card for unsportsmanlike conduct.</li>
<li> Goalkeepers cannot handle a ball that is  kicked-in directly to them by their own team.</li>
<li>A goal cannot be scored  directly from a kick-in. It must touch a member of either team before crossing  the goal line to be counted as a goal.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Drop Ball</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Drop ball occurs:
<ul>
<li>When the ball is caused to go  out-of-bounds by two opponents simultaneously.</li>
<li>Following a suspension of play  for an injury or other situation in which no team has clear possession of the  ball.</li>
<li>A foul by both teams occurring  simultaneously.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The spot of the drop ball is  where the ball becomes dead unless this is in the goal area, in which case the  spot is the nearest point on the goal line in the field of play.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Goal Kick</em></p>
<ul>
<li>A goal kick shall be awarded  to the defending team when the ball crosses the goal line, having last been  touched by the attacking team.</li>
<li>Players opposing the kicker  shall remain outside the penalty area until the ball moves out of the penalty  area.</li>
<li>A player of the defending team  shall kick the ball from the ground at any point within the goal area.</li>
<li>A goal kick must clear the  penalty area and enter the field of play or the goal kick will be retaken.</li>
<li> After the goal kick leaves the penalty area,  any player except the one who executed the goal kick may play the ball.</li>
<li> Goal kicks are direct free kicks.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Corner Kick</em></p>
<ul>
<li>When the ball is last touched  by the defending team and goes over the goal line, a member of the attacking  team shall take a kick from within the quarter-circle at the nearest corner  flag.</li>
<li>Players of the team opposing  that of the player taking the corner kick shall not approach within 5 yards of  the ball until it is in play.</li>
<li> After the corner kick is first touched, any  player except the one who executes the corner kick may play the ball.</li>
<li>Corner kicks are direct free  kicks.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
