<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x60698" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Racquetball Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27057" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>Game </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A match is won by the first side to win two games.&nbsp; The  first two games will be played to 21 points, and the deciding game to 15  points.&nbsp; Games may be won by one point.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Service</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A coin toss or other suitable means will determine first  serve of the match.&nbsp; The individual who did not serve in the first game  will serve in the second game.&nbsp; If a third game is necessary, the  individual/team that has scored the most combined points from the first  two games shall serve first in the deciding game.&nbsp; In the event that  both player's/teams' scores are equal, the serve will be determined by  another coin toss.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The service is started from any place within the service  zone.&nbsp; No part of either foot may extend beyond either line of the  service zone.&nbsp; An individual may step on but not over the line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The server must remain in the service zone from the moment  the service motion begins until the served ball passes the short line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The server must call the score prior to beginning the  motion for serve.&nbsp; Service shall not be made until the receiving team is  ready.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The server must contact the ball on the first bounce.&nbsp; The  served ball must hit the front wall first and on the rebound hit the  floor behind the back edge of the short line, either with or without  touching one of the side walls.&nbsp; A balk serve or fake swing at the ball  shall be deemed an infraction and be judged an "out", "hand out" or  "side out".</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A server is entitled to serve until:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The player commits an out serve.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The player commits two fault serves in succession.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The player hits his/her partner with an attempted return.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The player fails to hit the ball on the fly or first bounce or  fails to return the ball to the front wall on the fly (with or without  hitting any combination of walls and ceiling).</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The player commits an avoidable hinder.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Defective Serves</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are three types of defective serves:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Dead Ball Serve</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Fault Serve</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Out Serve</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dead Ball Serves</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; There is no penalty for a dead ball serve, nor do dead ball  serves cancel any previous illegal serve. The following are examples of  dead ball serves:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Hits partner:&nbsp; The ball hits the server's partner on the fly on  the rebound from the front wall while the server's partner is in the  service box correctly positioned</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Court hinders:&nbsp; The ball hits any part of the court that, under  local rules, is a dead ball.&nbsp; For a court hinder to be called there must  be no attempt to return the ball.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Broken ball:&nbsp; If the ball breaks on the serve, a new ball shall  be substituted and the serve shall be replayed, not canceling any prior  fault serve.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fault Serves</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The following serves are faults and any two in succession result in a side‑out (singles):</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Foot Faults</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The server does not begin the service motion with both feet in the service zone.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The server leaves the service zone before the served ball passes the short line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In doubles, the server's partner is not in the service box  with both feet on the floor and back to the wall from the time the  server begins the service motion until the ball passes the short line.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Short Serve:&nbsp; A short serve is any served ball that first hits the  front wall and on the rebound hits the floor on or in front of the  short line (with or without touching a side wall.)</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Three Wall Serve:&nbsp; Any served ball that first hits the front wall and on the rebound hits the two side walls on the fly.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Ceiling Serve:&nbsp; Any served ball that first hits the front wall and  then touches the ceiling (with or without touching a side wall).</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Long Serve:&nbsp; Any served ball that first hits the front wall and  rebounds to the back wall before touching the floor (with or without  touching a side wall).</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Out Serves</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Missed ball:&nbsp; Any attempt to strike the ball that results in a  total miss or in touching any part of the server's body other than the  racquet.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Non‑front serve:&nbsp; Any served ball that does not strike the front wall first.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Touched Serve:&nbsp; Any served ball on the rebound from the front  wall that touches the server (or server's partner not properly  positioned in the service box including the racquet) on a fly, or any  ball intentionally stopped or caught by the server or server's partner.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Crotch Serve:&nbsp; If the served ball hits the crotch of the front  wall and floor, front wall and side wall, or front wall and ceiling; it  is considered "no good" and is an out serve.&nbsp; A serve into the crotch of  the back wall and the floor is good and in play.&nbsp; A served ball hitting  the crotch of the sidewall and floor (as in a "Z" serve) beyond the  short line is "good" and in play.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Illegal hit:&nbsp; Any illegal hit (contacting the ball twice, carries  or hitting the ball with the handle of the racquet or part of the body  or uniform) results in an out serve.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Fake or Balk Serve:&nbsp; Such a serve is defined as a non‑continuous  movement of the racquet towards the ball as the server drops the ball  for the purpose of serving and results in an out serve.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Out of Order Serve:&nbsp; In doubles, when either partner serves out  of order, any points which may have been scored during an out of order  serve will be automatically void with the score reverting to the score  prior to the out of order serve.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Out of Court Serve:&nbsp; Any served ball that first hits the front  wall and, before striking the floor, goes out of the court that has been  declared out of play for a valid reason.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Safety Zone Violation:&nbsp; If the server, or doubles partner, enters  into the safety zone before the served ball passes the short line, it  shall result in the loss of serve.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Return of Serve</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After the ball is legally served, one of the players on the  receiving side must strike the ball with the racquet either on the fly  or after the first bounce and before the ball touches the floor the  second time. The ball must be returned to the front wall, either  directly or after touching one or both side walls, the back wall or the  ceiling or any combination of those surfaces.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A returned ball may not touch the floor before touching the front wall.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Failure to return a serve results in a point for the server.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Rallies</em></p>
<p>Each legal return after the serve is called a rally.&nbsp; Play during rallies shall be according to the following rules:</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Only the head of the racquet may be used at any time to  return the ball.&nbsp; The racquet may be held in one or both hands.&nbsp;  Switching hands to hit a ball, touching the ball with any part of the  body or clothes, or removing the wrist thong result in loss of the  rally.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In attempting returns, the ball may be touched or struck  only once by a player or the result is a loss of rally.&nbsp; The ball may  not be "carried".&nbsp; (A carried ball is one which rests on the racquet in  such a way that the effect is more of a "sling" or "throw" than a hit.)</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Failure to make a legal return during a rally includes:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball bounces on the floor more than once before being hit.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball does not reach the front wall on the fly.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball exits the court via the open area of the back wall results in a point or side out.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A ball, which obviously did not have the velocity or direction to hit the front wall, strikes another player on the court.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A returned ball that hits or touches the player's partner on the same play before the opposing team plays the ball.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The player or partner commits an avoidable hinder.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Return Attempts:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; In singles, if a player swings at but misses the ball, the player  may continue to attempt to return the ball until it touches the floor  for the second time.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; In doubles, if one player swings at but misses the ball, both  partners may make further attempts to return the ball until it touches  the floor the second time.&nbsp; Both partners are entitled to return the  ball.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is suspicion that a ball has broken on a rally, play shall continue until the end of the rally.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In singles a single hand out equals a side out and retires  the server.&nbsp; In doubles a single hand out equals a side out on the first  service of each game; thereafter, two handouts equal a side‑out and  thereby retires the serving team.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Dead Ball Hinders</em></p>
<p>Dead ball hinders result in the rally being replayed without penalty  and the server receiving two serves.&nbsp; A dead ball hinder occurs when:</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hitting an Opponent: Any returned ball that touches an  opponent on the fly before it returns to the front wall.&nbsp; The player  that has been hit or nicked by the ball may make the call.&nbsp; It must be  made immediately.&nbsp; Any ball, which hits an opponent, that obviously did  not have the velocity or direction to reach the front wall shall not  result in a hinder (and shall cause the player or team that hit the ball  to lose the rally).</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Body Contact: If body contact occurs which was sufficient  to stop the rally, either for the purpose of preventing injury by  further contact or because the contact prevented a player from being  able to make a reasonable return, it shall be declared a hinder.&nbsp; Body  contact, particularly on the follow through is not necessarily a  hinder.&nbsp; Either player involved in the contact shall make the call.&nbsp;  This is an honor call and should not be abused or taken advantage of.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Screen Ball: Any ball rebounding from the front wall close  to the body of a player on the side which just returned the ball which  interferes with or prevents the returning player side from seeing the  ball.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back Swing Hinder: Any body contact either on the back  swing or in route to or just prior to returning the ball which impairs  the hitter's ability to take a reasonable swing.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Safety Holdup: Any player about to execute a return who  believes she/he is likely to strike his opponent with the ball or  racquet may immediately stop play.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Interference: A player loses a shoe or other equipment or any other outside interference occurs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Avoidance</em></p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While making an attempt to return the ball, a player is  entitled to a fair chance to see and return the ball.&nbsp; It is the  responsibility of the side that has just served or returned the ball to  move so the receiving side may go straight to the ball and have an  unobstructed view of the ball after it leaves the front wall.&nbsp; However,  the receiver must make a reasonable effort to move toward the ball and  have a reasonable chance to return it in order for a hinder to be  called.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="avoidable_hinders"></a><em>Avoidable Hinders</em></p>
<p>An avoidable hinder, results in the loss of a rally.&nbsp; An avoidable  hinder does not necessarily have to be an "intentional" act and is a  result of any of the following:</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The individual does not move sufficiently to allow an opponent an open shot.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The individual moves into position affecting a block on the  opponent about to return the ball, or in doubles, one partner moves in  front of an opponent as the partner of that opponent is returning the  ball.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The individual intentionally moves in the way and is struck by the ball just played by the opponent.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The individual deliberately pushes or shoves the opponent during a rally.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The individual moves so as to restrict opponent's swing so  that the player returning the ball does not have a free unimpeded swing.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Deliberate shouting, stamping of feet, waving of racquet or  any manner of disrupting the player whom is hitting the ball.</p>
<p><a name="time_outs"></a><em>Time Outs</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During games to 15, each player or team is allowed two  30‑second time‑outs; one additional 30‑second time‑out in the tie  breaker.&nbsp; A time out may not be called once the server begins the  service motion.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In case of injury, (other than muscle cramps and pulls,  fatigue and other ailments that are not caused by direct contact on the  court) individuals will be awarded an injury time out.&nbsp; If the injured  player is not able to resume play, the match will be declared a default.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the case of equipment problems, individuals must use a  time‑out to change equipment.&nbsp; In unusual situations, players should  consult the sport supervisor on duty.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Between games, a five-minute rest period will be allowed.&nbsp;  If both parties are ready to play sooner than 5 minutes, they may start  the next game.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
