<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x60680" Name="Rule 3: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 3: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Flag Football Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27042" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>Start of Game</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Before play begins, a coin is tossed and the team that wins  the toss will have the choice of kicking off or deciding which end zone  to defend. The second half play will begin with a kickoff by the team  that did not kickoff to start the game.</p>
<p><em>Timing</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Games consist of two 20-minute halves. The clock stops the  last two minutes of the second half, otherwise, the clock will run  continuously barring timeouts.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each team is permitted two (2) time-outs per half and one  (1) additional time-out during the entire tiebreaker. Timeouts do not  carry over.</p>
<p><em>Ball in Play, Dead Ball, Out-of-Bounds </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ball in Play</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The offense must snap the ball within 25 seconds after the referee has sounded his/her whistle.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: Delay of Game, 5 yards.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ball is Declared Dead When</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A forward pass strikes the ground or is caught simultaneously by opposing players.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A backward pass or fumble by a player strikes the ground.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A runner has a flag belt removed legally by a defensive player.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A runner is legally touched with one hand between the shoulders  and knees, including the hand and arm, once the flag belt is no longer  attached.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A snap hits the ground.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A muff of a kickoff or protected scrimmage kick strikes the ground.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The passer is de-flagged before releasing the ball.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fumbles</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A fumble or backward pass is dead at the point it hits the ground and belongs to the offensive team unless lost on downs.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Out-of-Bounds</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A ball in player possession is out-of-bounds when either the ball  or any part of the runner touches the ground or anything other surface,  except a player or game official, which is on or outside a boundary  line. If the runner in-bounds, bumps into or is touched by a player or  an official on the sidelines out-of-bounds, the ball is still in play.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Series of Downs, Number of Downs </em><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The zone line-to-gain in any series shall be the zone (next  field marker) in advance of the ball, unless distance has been lost due  to penalty or failure to gain. In such case, the original zone (next  field marker) in advance of the ball at the beginning of the series of  downs is the zone line-to-gain. The most forward point of the ball, when  declared dead between the goal lines shall be the determining factor.</p>
<p><em>Kicking the Ball </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Punt</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The kick must be executed behind the scrimmage line within a reasonable time.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Neither team may cross the scrimmage line until the ball is kicked.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; There are no quick kicks. All punts must be announced to the referee.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; The receiving team may advance the ball 20 yards if the ball is kicked into the end zone.</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Snapping, Handing and Passing the Ball </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Scrimmage</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Snapping - the snap does not have to be between the snapper's  legs. The player receiving the snap must be at least 2 yards behind the  scrimmage line.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: Illegal Snap, 5 yards from the previous spot.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; During the snap, the men's or women's offensive team must have at  least four (4) players on their scrimmage line within one yard of the  scrimmage line.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: Illegal Formation, 5 yards from the previous spot.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; No player of the offensive team shall make a false start. A false start is any movement simulating the start of a play.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: False Start, 5 yards from the previous spot.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Encroachment - After the snapper has touched the ball, it is  encroachment for any player to break the plane of his/her scrimmage  line, except the snapper's right to be over the ball.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: Encroachment, 5 yards from the previous spot.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; All offensive players must be motionless for one second preceding  the snap. After all players are set, a player moving parallel to or  away from the scrimmage line is legal.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: Illegal motion, 5 yards from the previous spot.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; An offensive player that moves/shifts (other than going legally in motion) must stop for one full second before the snap.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: Illegal Shift, 5 yards from the previous spot.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Handing the Ball</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Any player may hand the ball forward or backward at any time.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Forward Pass</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; All players are eligible to touch or catch a pass. Only one legal forward pass per down is acceptable.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; A Forward Pass is Illegal:</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; If the passer's foot is beyond Team A's scrimmage line (first ball spotter orange) when the ball leaves his/her hand</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; If thrown after team possession has changed during the down</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; If intentionally grounded to save loss of yardage</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; If a passer catches his/her untouched forward or backward pass.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Second forward pass in that down</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Penalty: Illegal Forward Pass, 5 yards, spot of the pass, loss of down, if prior to possession change.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Interference</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; After the ball is snapped, and until it has been touched, there  shall be no offensive pass interference beyond the offensive scrimmage  line when the legal forward pass crosses the offensive scrimmage line  (orange ball spotter).</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: 10 yards from the previous spot and loss of down.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; After a legal forward pass is released by the passer and until it  is touched, there shall be no defensive pass interference beyond Team  A's scrimmage line while the ball is in flight which crosses the Team  A's scrimmage line.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Penalty: 10 yards from the previous spot and an automatic first down.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; If opposing players catch a pass simultaneously, the ball becomes  dead, is considered a completed pass, and belongs to the offensive  team.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Scoring Plays and Touchback </em><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Forfeit game - 1 point.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Touchdown - 6 points</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Safety - 2 points.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Try: Ball in play from the 3-yard line - 1 point; Ball in  play from the 10-yard line - 2 points; Ball in play from the 20 yard - 3  points.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Try: Once the scoring team's captain declares their choice  for a 1, 2, or 3 point try, the choice can only be changed by a charged  timeout by either team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Try: A defensive player may intercept a pass or fumble and  run it back for what would normally be a touchdown and score 3 points.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mercy Rule</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; If a team is 19 or more points ahead with two minutes to play, the game shall be over.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; If a team scores during the last 2 minutes of the game and the  score creates a 19 or more point difference the game shall end at that  point.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Conduct of Players </em><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There shall be no personal fouls committed by players, substitutes and coaches. Personal Fouls include:</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Using fist, foot, knee, or leg to contact an opponent; tackling  the ball carrier (disqualification); illegal contact; unnecessary  roughness, hurdling, roughing the passer (when the defender contacts the  passers arm)</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Offensive players may protect the runner by screening.  Illegal contact between the blocker/rusher will be called against the  player determined to have initiated the contact.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Penalty: Illegal Contact, 10 yards. (Similar to Basketball)</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The ball carrier shall not guard their flags by blocking  with arms, hands, or use of a stiff-arm block thereby denying an  opponent the opportunity to pull or remove the flag belt.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Penalty: Flag guarding, 10 yards.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tampering with the flag belt in any way to gain an  advantage including tying, using foreign materials, or other such acts.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Penalty: Unsportsmanlike Conduct, 10 yards from the previous spot, loss of down and player disqualification.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No player or non-player shall commit any unsporting acts.</p>
Penalty: Unsportsmanlike Conduct, 10 yards<br /><br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
