<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x60726" Name="Rule 2: Game Play" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Rule 2: Game Play</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Volleyball Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27090" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><em>Playing Area </em><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The walls are out of play.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player cannot enter an adjacent court in order to play the ball.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Balls can be played off of the ceiling or anything hanging  from it, as long as they do not make contact before entering the  opposing team's side of the court</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Scoring System and Coin Toss </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All matches will be the best two (2) out of three (3) games  decided by rally scoring. Non-deciding games will be played to at least  25 points with a two-point advantage. No game shall exceed 30 points.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A coin toss will determine who serves the first game of the  match. The captains call the toss of a coin. The winner of the toss  chooses; first serve or choice of court for the first game. The loser of  the toss receives the remaining options.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A new coin toss is performed before the third game, if necessary.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; After each game of the match, the teams will switch sides of the court.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any action, which, in the judgment of the referee unnecessarily delays the game, may be sanctioned.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When a fault is committed by the receiving team, a point is awarded to the serving team.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The deciding game of the match played to 15 points (capped  at 17 points), shall use the rally point system with a point awarded on  each service.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Substitutions </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Substitution of players may be made when the ball is dead, upon making the request to either referee.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Service</em></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The server shall have five seconds after the first  referee's whistle for service in which to contact the ball for service.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The service is considered good when the ball passes over  the net between the antennae or their infinite extensions. If the ball  hits the net and continues over, the ball can be played.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Co-ed serving order and positions on the court at service shall be an alternation of male-female or vice-versa.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The team not serving to start the match will serve to start the second game.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The team who receives the ball for service shall rotate one position clockwise before serving.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The player(s) of the serving team must not, through  screening, prevent the receiving player from watching the server or the  trajectory of the ball. Screening is illegal and a fault.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the time the ball is contacted for the serve, the  placement of players on the court must conform to the service order  (server is exempt from this requirement).</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Playing Faults </em></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each team is allowed a maximum of three (3) successive  contacts of the ball in order to return the ball to the opponent's area.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the ball is contacted three (3) times by a team, a female or male must contact the ball at least once.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players may have successive contacts of the ball during  blocking and during a single attempt to make the first team hit of a  ball coming from the opponents, even if the ball is blocked, provided  the ball is not held or thrown.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the ball visibly comes to rest momentarily in the  hands or arms of a player, it is considered as having been held. The  ball must be hit in such a manner that it rebounds cleanly after contact  with a player. Scooping, lifting, pushing, or allowing the ball to roll  on the body shall be considered to be a form of holding.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player is not allowed to attack the ball on the  opponent's side of the net. If the ball is contacted above the  attacker's side of the net and the follow through causes the attacker's  hand and arm to cross the net without contacting an opponent or the net,  such action does not constitute a fault.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Blocking</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; May be legally accomplished only by players who are in the front row at the time of service.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Back row players may not block or participate in a block, but may  play the ball in any other position near or away from the block.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Any player participating in a block shall have the right to make  the next contact, such contact counting as the first of the team's three  hits.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Blocking or attacking a served ball is a fault.</p>
<p>o&nbsp;&nbsp; Blocking of the ball across the net above the opponent's playing area shall be legal provided that such block is:</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; After a player has attacked the ball, or in the first referee's  judgment, has intentionally directed the ball toward the opponent's  playing area.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; After the opponents have completed their three hits.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; After the opponents have hit the ball in such a manner that the  ball would, in the first referee's judgment, clearly cross the net if  not touched by a player, provided no member of the attacking team is in a  position to make a legal play on the ball</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; If the ball is falling near the net and no member of the attacking team could reasonably make a play on the ball.</p>
<p>&sect;&nbsp; Co-ed - When only one male is in the front line at service, one  male back row player may be forward of the attack line for the purpose  of blocking. The male back row player who wishes to participate in the  block must be designated to the referee prior to the serve.</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Play at the Net </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A player's hair touching the net is not considered a foul.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Players are now permitted to penetrate the opponent's court  beyond the center line with the hand and foot. Touching the opponent's  area with a hand or foot is not a fault providing that some part of the  encroaching foot or feet remain on or above the center line.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A ball, which has penetrated the vertical plane above the net, may be played by either team.</p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Faults </em></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A double fault occurs when players of opposing teams  simultaneously commit faults. In such cases, the first referee will  direct a replay.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If faults by opponents occur at approximately the same  time, the first referee shall determine which fault occurred first and  shall penalize only that fault. If it cannot be determined which fault  occurred first, a double fault shall be declared.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the serving team, or a player on the serving team,  commits a fault, a point is awarded to the receiving team. If the  receiving team or a player on the receiving team commits a fault, the  serving team shall be awarded a point.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
