<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x60717" Name="Ultimate Frisbee Mixed Rules" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ultimate Frisbee Mixed Rules</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ultimate Frisbee Mixed Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27083" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;">
<p align="left"> <strong>Rule 1: Players </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<div align="left">The roster limit is 11</div>
</li>
<li>
<div align="left">Each team shall consist of seven players on the field, however, a game may begin with as few as five players</div>
</li>
<li>
<div align="left">There must be at least two of each gender on the field to begin the game (3 girls, 2 guys or 3 guys, 2 girls).</div>
</li>
<li>
<div align="left">All players must check in using a valid Photo ID</div>
</li>
<li>
<div align="left">Substitutions may occur after a goal, or to replace an injured participant.</div>
</li>
<li>
<div align="left">The opposing team may substitute if an injured player is substituted</div>
</li>
</ul>
<strong>
<p>Rule 2: Play</p>
<p>Start of Game</p>
<em>
<p>Timing</p>
</em></strong><em>
<ul>
<li>The game is won by the first team scoring fifteen goals and winning by two with a cap of seventeen, or by the team who has scored the most goals by the end of regulation.</li>
<li></li>
<li><em>There will be no overtime during regular season play.</em></li>
<li><em>During playoffs, if a game is still tied at the end of the time limit, then three minute overtime period shall be played</em></li>
<li><em>Each team is allowed two 30 second time outs per game.</em><em></em>A coin toss prior to the game shall determine who will throw the pull. The team winning the toss shall decide whether they want to receive or throw the pull or which end zone they would like to defend initially. The opposing team shall have the remaining options. The opposing team will get the option in the second half. Each half shall begin and end on the supervisor's whistle. </li>
</ul>
<em>
<p><strong>Scoring</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A goal is scored when a legally thrown pass is caught by a player who is in-bounds and beyond the goal line of attack</li>
<li>A player's first point of contact with the ground after catching a pass must be inside the goal line to be scored.</li>
<li>If a player's momentum carries them into the end zone after a catch, that player shall walk the disc to the nearest point on the goal line and continue play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mercy Rule</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Ultimate Frisbee will not use a mercy rule since the game will end with the first team to score fifteen goals.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Pull</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A pull shall begin each game and restart play after a goal.</li>
<li>The scoring team will pull and the teams will switch directions of attack</li>
<li>The puller and the receiving players must hold one arm in the air to signal readiness for play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Thrower</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The offensive player, who picks up the disc, must be the player to put the disc in play.</li>
<li>A pivot foot must be established by the thrower.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Receiver</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Once a pass in caught, the player must stop as quickly as possible and establish a pivot foot.</li>
<li>A player may bobble the disc prior to making a catch; however a player may not guide a disc to gain an advantage in disc position.</li>
<li>If offensive and defensive players make a simultaneous catch; the offense shall retain possession.</li>
<li>If the pass is caught while a player is in the air, the catch is not complete until the player has landed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>RecSports Mixed Ultimate Frisbee Rules</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A player who has fallen to the ground during a catch is allowed to stand up without a traveling violation being called.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Marker</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The marker is a defender who is within three feet of the throwers pivot foot or of the thrower if no pivot foot has been established.</li>
<li>The thrower has ten second to release the disc; the marker shall initiate the count by announcing "stalling" and then counting to ten loudly and clearly.</li>
<li>A marker may not be closer to the pivot or torso of the thrower than the diameter of a disc.</li>
<li>A marker may not block the vision of the thrower.</li>
</ul>
<p>The offence turns the disc over if:</p>
<ul>
<li>The marker's count reaches ten before the disc is released.</li>
<li>The thrower hands off the disc to a teammate.</li>
<li>The thrower catches their own pass, provided it was not tipped by another player.</li>
<li>The thrower requests a timeout without having any timeouts remaining.</li>
<li>One offensive or defensive player assists another in an attempt to catch of block a pass.</li>
<li>An offensive or defensive player use equipment to assist in an attempt to catch or block a pass.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fouls</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Incidental contact is acceptable in the play of ultimate disc.</li>
<li>A foul shall be called by the offended player if non-incidental contact causes the player to lose control of the disc, to miss an opportunity to make a play on the disc, to go out of bounds, or to not catch the disc.</li>
<li>The disc shall be returned to the spot of the of the throw when any foul is called</li>
</ul>
<p>Picks are illegal.</p>
<p><strong>Out of Bounds</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The perimeter lines are considered to be out of bounds</li>
<li>If a player's momentum carries them out of bounds after their first point of contact was in bounds, the player shall be ruled inbounds. The player will bring the disc back to the perimeter line to restart play.</li>
<li>The disc is considered out of bounds when it makes contact with an object, the ground, or a person who is out of bounds.</li>
<li>The disc shall be put back into play by walking it to the perimeter closest to where it became out of bounds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>End Zone</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>If a team gains control of the disc in the end zone they are defending, they may walk to the goal line and put it in play from the spot.</li>
<li>If a team gains or retains control of the disc in the end zone they are attacking, without scoring a goal, the disc shall be put in play on the goal line closest to the spot where it was caught</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Rule 3: Mixed Modifications</strong></p>
<ul>
<li> Each team shall consist of a maximum of four females or four males to begin a game.</li>
<li>There must be at least two players of each gender on the field to begin the game (2:3 or 3:2 if minimum players consist of 5).</li>
</ul>
<p>Note: A team will play with seven; therefore a full team will consist of a 3:4 or 4:3 ratio.</p>
<p><strong>Rule 4: Playoffs</strong> </p>
<p>Teams must also maintain a "3.5" sportsmanship average during the regular season and have zero forfeits to be eligible for the playoffs.</p>
<p>Sportsmanship points for each regular season contest will be added together and divided by the total number of contests held to find each team's sportsmanship average.</p>
</em></em><em>The game is made up of two twenty minute halves with a five minute half time.</em></span>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: small;">  Related links:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="x24368.xml">Return to Ultimate Frisbee</a></span><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="x24452.xml"></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="x24452.xml">Policies and Procedures</a> </span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
