<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x60700" Name="Soccer Mixed Rules" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Soccer Mixed Rules</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Soccer Mixed Rules</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27064" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left">
<p align="left">
<div align="left"><span style="font-size: small;"><em>Any rule not specifically covered will be governed in accordance with the National Federation of State High School Association Soccer Rules. </em> </span></div>
</p>
<span style="font-size: small;"> </span>
<div align="left"><span style="font-size: small;"></span></div>
 </p>
<span style="font-size: small;">
<p><strong>Rule 1: Players</strong> </p>
<p align="left">
<ul>
<li>Each team shall consist of eleven players on the field, however a team may begin a game with as few as eight</li>
<li>A minimum of 3 players of either gender are required to be on the field at all times.</li>
<li>All players must check in using a valid I-card or picture ID.</li>
<li>If during a game a team has fewer than five eligible players due to ejection, the game shall be terminated.</li>
<li>If during a game a team has fewer than five eligible players due to injury, the game may continue at the official's discretion.</li>
</ul>
<div align="left"><em></em></div>
 </p>
<em>
<p><strong>Substitutions</strong></p>
<p align="left">
<ul>
<li>Substituting may occur during your team's throw-in, your team's corner kick or any goal kick, after a goal is scored and any time that the opposing team is substituting a player.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Substitutes shall go to their team entry position and cannot enter the game until the player they are replacing is completely off of the field.</li>
<li>A player who receives a yellow card must be substituted.</li>
<li>Any player may change places with the goalkeeper, provided the official is informed before the change is made and the change is made during a stoppage in play.</li>
</ul>
</em>
<ul>
</ul>
<em><em>
<p align="left"><em>
<p>Start of Game</p>
</em></p>
</em></em>
<p align="left">
<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
</p>
<em><em>
<ul>
<li>After the referee has given a signal, the game shall be started. The ball is in play when it is kicked in any direction. If the ball is not properly touched, the ball will again be placed on the kickoff mark the kickoff retaken.</li>
<li>The kicker may not touch the ball again until it has been touched by another player.</li>
</ul>
</em></em>
<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
<em><em><em><em>
<p align="left"><em>
<p>Timing</p>
</em></p>
</em></em></em></em>
<p align="left">
<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
</p>
<em><em><em><em>
<ul>
<li>The addition of time will be at the discretion of the official.</li>
<li>Time shall be extended to permit the taking of a penalty kick awarded before the sounding of the final whistle to end each half.</li>
<li>A game shall become official at the completion of the first half.</li>
<li>There will be no overtime during the regular season. Tie scores will remain as such.</li>
</ul>
</em></em></em></em>
<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
<em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>
<p align="left"><em>
<p>Scoring</p>
<ul>
<li>A goal is scored when the whole ball has passed over the goal line, between the goal posts and under the crossbar, provided that no infringement of the rules (handling or other) has been committed previously by the team scoring the goal. If the official's whistle sounds before the ball passes fully into the goal, the goal shall not be allowed.</li>
<li>A goal CANNOT be scored directly from a throw-in. It must touch a member of either team before crossing the goal line to be counted as a goal.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Mercy Rule</p>
<ul>
<li>If a team is ahead by three (3) or more goals with two minutes remaining in the second half, the game shall be over. If a team takes the lead by three (3) goals during the final two minutes of the game, the game shall be over.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Free Kicks</p>
<ul>
<li>Free kicks shall be classified under two types: Direct (from which a goal can be scored directly against the offending side), and Indirect (from which a goal cannot be scored unless the ball has been played or touched by a player other than the kicker before passing into the goal).</li>
<li>Direct Kicks are awarded for the following offenses:</li>
</ul>
<p>Deliberately handling, carrying, striking, or propelling the ball with a hand or arm. Moving the hands or arms to protect one's self is deliberately handling.</p>
<p>Placing hands or arms on an opponent in an effort to reach the ball, or hold an opponent.</p>
<p>Pushing, striking or attempting to strike, jumping at, kicking or attempting to kick, tripping or attempting to trip, using the knee on an opponent, charging an opponent from behind.</p>
<p>Charging an opponent violently or dangerously. A player who leaves the ground with both feet and or throws his/her weight against an opponent is guilty of charging. A fair charge is one in which a player makes nonviolent shoulder-to-shoulder contact with an opponent, with the arms and elbows close to his/her own body, at least one foot on the ground, and the ball within playing distance.</p>
<p>The official will remove (red card), without caution, any player who charges into the goalkeeper in the penalty area, unless the goalkeeper is obstructing an opponent. Possession or control of the ball will include when the goalkeeper has the ball trapped by either or both hands or when bouncing it to the ground, or when the goalkeeper throws the ball into the air.</p>
<p>Charging an opponent while both feet are off the ground in an effort to head the ball.</p>
<p>Handling by the goalkeeper outside the penalty area.</p>
<p>Slide tackling</p>
<p>All direct kicks awarded in the penalty area are penalty kicks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Indirect Kicks are awarded for the following offenses:</li>
</ul>
<p>A player playing the ball a second time before it has been played by another player at the kickoff, a throw-in, a kick-in, a drop kick, a free kick, a corner kick, a goal kick, if the ball has passed outside the penalty area.</p>
<p>A player shall be penalized if he obstructs an opponent when not playing the ball.</p>
<p>If the goalkeeper, after deliberately parrying the ball, handles the ball again before it has left the penalty area or been touched by a player of the opposing team. Parrying is defined as a clear attempt by the goalkeeper to deliberately control and/or deflect a catchable ball down or out with the hands.</p>
<p>A substitution or re-substitution being made improperly.</p>
<p>Persons other than the players entering the field of play without the Referee's permission.</p>
<p>Dissenting by word or action from a referee's decision. (possible yellow card issued)</p>
<p>Interfering with the goalie or impeding in any manner while the goalie has possession of the ball.</p>
<p>Playing the ball in a manner dangerous to an opponent or oneself. (high kick, playing on the ground)</p>
<p>On any occasion when a player deliberately kicks the ball to his/her own goalkeeper, the goalkeeper is not permitted to touch it with his/her hands.</p>
<ul>
<li>When a direct or indirect free kick is being taken all opposing players shall be at least 10 yards from the ball until it is kicked, unless they are standing on their own goal line.</li>
<li>For a free kick to be taken in the goal area by the defense - treat it like a goal kick.</li>
<li>For an indirect kick to be taken in the goal area by the offense - take the kick from the goal area line.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Penalty Kick</p>
<ul>
<li>Awarded for any infringement of the rules, within the penalty area, that would require a direct free kick.</li>
<li>A penalty kick can be awarded irrespective of the position of the ball.</li>
<li>A penalty kick shall be taken from the penalty mark which is 12 yards from the goal line. While the kick is being taken, all players with the exception of the player taking the kick and the opposing goalkeeper shall be within the field of play but outside the penalty area and at least 10 yards from the penalty mark.</li>
<li>The opposing goalkeeper may only move laterally on his/her own goal line between the goalposts, until the ball is kicked.</li>
<li>The player taking the kick must kick the ball forward.</li>
<li>Should the ball hit the goalposts or crossbar and rebound into play, the player who kicked the ball must not play it again until it has been touched by another player.</li>
<li>The ball shall be deemed in play directly after it is kicked.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Throw-In</p>
<ul>
<li>When the ball passes completely over a sideline, it shall be thrown in from the point where it crossed the line by a player of the team opposite to that of the player who it last touched.</li>
<li>If the ball is improperly thrown into play, the restart shall be taken by a player of the opposing team.</li>
<li>If the ball fails to enter the field of play, it shall be thrown again.</li>
<li>If an opponent interferes with or in any way impedes the actions of the thrower while the throw-in is being taken, the official will administer a yellow card for unsportsmanlike conduct.</li>
<li>Goalkeepers cannot handle a ball that is thrown-in directly to them by their own team.</li>
<li>A goal cannot be scored directly from a throw-in. It must touch a member of either team before crossing the goal line to be counted as a goal.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Drop Ball</p>
<ul>
<li>When the ball is caused to go out-of-bounds by two opponents simultaneously.</li>
<li>Following a suspension of play for an injury or other situation in which no team has clear possession of the ball.</li>
<li>A foul by both teams occurring simultaneously.</li>
<li>The spot of the drop ball is where the ball becomes dead unless this is in the goal area, in which case the spot is the nearest point on the goal area in the field of play.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Goal Kick</p>
<ul>
<li>A goal kick shall be awarded to the defending team when the ball crosses the goal line, having last been touched by the attacking team.</li>
<li>Players opposing the kicker shall remain outside the penalty area until the ball moves out of the penalty area.</li>
<li>A player of the defending team shall kick the ball from the ground at any point within the goal area. A goal kick must clear the penalty area and enter the field of play or the goal kick will be retaken.</li>
<li>After the goal kick leaves the penalty area, any player except the one who executed the goal kick may play the ball.</li>
<li>The goalkeeper shall not pick up the ball and play it. Goal kicks are direct free kicks.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Corner Kick</p>
<ul>
<li>When the ball is last touched by the defending team and goes over the goal line, a member of the attacking team shall take a kick from within the quarter-circle at the nearest corner flag.</li>
<li>Players of the team opposing that of the player taking the corner kick shall not approach within 10 yards of the ball until it is in play.</li>
<li>After the corner kick is first touched, any player except the one who executes the corner kick may play the ball.</li>
<li>Corner kicks are direct free kicks.</li>
</ul>
<em>
<p>Breakaways</p>
<ul>
<li>If during a breakaway a player is deliberately taken down and there is a potential goal scoring opportunity, a red card will be issued and a direct free kick will be given. It will be upon the discretion of the official upon the severity of the foul.</li>
</ul>
</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></p>
</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em>
<p align="left">
<p><strong>Rule 3: Playoffs</strong><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></p>
</p>
<em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>
<p align="left">
<p> </p>
</p>
<strong><strong>
<p align="left"><span style="font-size: small;"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>
<p> </p>
</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></span></p>
</strong></strong><strong>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="x10243.xml">Return to Soccer</a></span></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="x24452.xml">Policies and Procedures</a> </span></strong></p>
</strong></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></span>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x6784" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
