<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.68 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_FullWidth ID="x61585" Name="Directions to Badger Creek" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Directions to Badger Creek</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">These are directions to Badger Creek from rexburg, Ashton and Driggs.</Abstract><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><strong> </strong></span></p>
<p align="left"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: small;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;"><strong>From Rexburg</strong></span></p>
<p align="left"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: small;">Travel North on Highway 20 for 4.0 miles. At the Highway  33 Junction turn right. Travel east for 39 miles. As you approach  Tetonia, the road will curve to the right. Turn off the highway (left)  about midway through the curve. Pass by the Rammels Valley Pack and  continue straight north about 3.0 miles. At the "T" junction, turn  right. Continue down the road until you come to the marked entrance of  BYU-Idaho Outdoor Learning Center. Take the second entrance next to the  large building with the light blue roof.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;"><strong>From Ashton</strong></span></p>
<p align="left"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: small;">Traveling South from West Yellowstone, Montana on  Highway 20, you will arrive at the city of Ashton, Idaho. Turn left at  the controlled intersection. (The Frost Top Drive-in is located on the  west side of the road.) Drive all the way through town. You will  approach the junction of Highway 32. Turn right (south). Travel  approximately 29.0 miles until you reach the junction of Highway 33.  Turn left. As you approach Tetonia, the road will curve to the right.  Turn off the highway (left) about midway through the curve. Pass by the  Rammels Valley Pack and continue straight north about 3.0 miles. At the  "T" junction, turn right. Continue down the road until you come to the  marked entrance of BYU-Idaho Outdoor Learning Center. Take the second  entrance next to the large building with the light blue roof.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;"><strong>From Driggs</strong></span></p>
<p align="left"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: small;">From Driggs continue North on Highway 33, following it  to Tetonia. Pass through the town. Approximately 0.6 miles past the  church the road will curve left. Turn off the highway (right) about  midway through the curve. Pass by the Rammels Valley Pack and continue  straight north about 3.0 miles. At the "T" junction, turn right.  Continue down the road until you come to the marked entrance of  BYU-Idaho Outdoor Learning Center. Take the second entrance next to the  large building with the light blue roof.</span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28802" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_FullWidth>
