<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x61724" Name="FAQ's" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Best of EFY: FAQ's</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Best if EFY FAQ's answers two main questions, Why is there a fee charged for CES Alumni and Community Connection programs and How are faculty selected for each of the programs?  You may review this page to find those answers</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3><strong>Why is there a fee charged for CES Alumni and Community Connection programs?</strong></h3>
<p>Tithing  funds are not used to support (CES) programs. "All (CES)  Alumni and  Community Connections' programs are financially  self-sustaining. Fees  are assessed." (Church Educational System, Church  Handbook of  Instructions - Book 1, 1998, p.117)</p>
<p>The  following statement in the 1998 Church Handbook of Instructions  under  the heading of "Optional Enrichment Activities", also guides (CES)   Alumni and Community Connections' efforts: "Units may sponsor optional   enrichment activities that are presented by Church-related entities.   Such activities include... Church university performance groups and   periodic major cultural events. Members may be charged a modest fee to   defray the cost of such events if the program is entirely optional, the   cost is not burdensome, and the event is not used to raise funds.  Budget  funds may be used to help those who want to attend but are  unable to  pay." (Church Handbook of Instructions, 1998 p. 138-139) In  accordance  with these guidelines, Alumni and Community Connections'  programs are  supported by participant tuition that is used to meet the  costs of  running the programs.</p>
<p>The  First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve have organized the   Church Educational System as a separate educational arm of the Church.   This is to keep the educational activities of the Church in a separate   line from the ecclesiastical line of the Church.</p>
<h3><strong>How are faculty selected for each of the programs?</strong></h3>
<p>Faculty  are selected from a large group of teachers who have been  cleared by  the CES Board of Trustees to teach for (CES) Alumni and  Community  Connections. These faculty come from varying background of  experiences.  Some faculty are teachers within the Church Educational  System  teaching in Seminaries and Institutes of Religion. Other faculty  are  teaching at the Church owned BYU and BYU-Idaho, while others are  proven  teachers with pertinent experience and qualifications.</p>
<p>Each  individual that teaches for (CES) Alumni and Community  Connections has  applied to do so, been cleared by their ecclesiastical  leader, and  approved by the appropriate office under the direction of  the Church  Board of Education. They are cleared to teach topics in their  field of  study, or cleared according to their experience and other  credentials.  Each presentation that is made at a CES Continuing  Education program  has been cleared by the Church Correlation Department.  Every effort is  made to help make the presentations uplifting,  edifying, and designed  to build testimonies in the Lord Jesus Christ and  His restored gospel.</p>
<p>We  know there are many excellent teachers throughout the Church. We   welcome your suggestions and recommendations concerning potential   faculty. As described above, there is a formal process by which a person   applies, is selected, and approved to become a teacher for (CES)  Alumni  and Community Connections' programs. Approval to teach does not   automatically result in an invitation to participate in a program.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28840" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28802" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
