<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x61894" Name="CE PMP Q9"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Which classes are included in the program?</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>The following are the "core" classes that are included in the PMP course work schedule:<br /><br /><strong>Religion Courses</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>FDREL 130 Mission Preperation</strong>. Using "Preach My Gospel" as a text, begin to develop your missionary skills.</li>
<li><strong>FDREL 121P Book of Mormon</strong>. 1st Nephi through Alma 29 designed for pre-missionaries.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Personal Skills</strong><br />
<ul>
<li><strong>FDENG 101 Writing &amp; Reasoning</strong> (Fall Semester only - Winter PMP students should take this during their first Fall Semester)&nbsp;Learn basic writing&nbsp;and reasoning skills.&nbsp; Dazzle your mission president and parents with letters that are well written, spelled correctly, and even punctuated.</li>
<li><strong>COMM 175&nbsp;Communication Essentials</strong> This new course focuses on public speaking&nbsp;and interpersonal communications.&nbsp; These two skills are paramount in mission service.&nbsp; Although this class does not fulfill Foundations requirements, it is well worth the 2 elective credits.</li>
<li><strong>GS 101 Principles of Personal Achievement</strong>. The capacity to determine one's success in college, on a mission, and in life, begins from within, from the way we see the world we live in and the attitudes we use to approach it. This course examines life from a principles and perspectives viewpoint, then encourages an application using the many resources available across campus.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Cultural Awareness</strong><br />
<ul>
<li><strong>FDINT 201 Global Hotspot: Pakistan</strong> - No the Church does not send missionaries to Pakistan and we have no indication they will any time soon.&nbsp; But using&nbsp;Pakistan as a giant case study, students will analyze how factors such as history, geography, economics, religion, natural resources, and language shape nations. Students will learn just&nbsp;how closely the nations of the world are connected, and why understanding such matters is important from a gospel and prospective missionary perspective.</li>
<li><strong>FDINT 205 China</strong>. Just as with the Pakistan course, no the Church does not send missionaries to China and we have no indication they will any time soon. But using China as a giant case study, students will analyze how factors such as history, geography, economics, religion, natural resources, and language shape nations. Students will learn just&nbsp;how closely the nations of the world are connected, and why understanding such matters is important from a gospel and prospective missionary perspective.</li>
<li><strong>FDHUM 105 Humanities. </strong>Understandinig a culture's history of art, music, literature, and cinema help to understand its people. This course focusses on works from Renaissance to modern times and helps broaden a pre-missionary's perspective.<strong><br /></strong></li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Foreign Language</strong><br /><br />
<ul>
<li><strong>SPAN 101 Beginning Spanish 1. </strong>For beginners and students with less than two years of high school Spanish.</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Science<br /><br /></strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>FDSCI 101 Science Foundations. </strong>An introduction to the nature, practice, power, and limitations of science, as well as relationships between science and religion, and science and society. These topics are explored through the study of selected episodes of scientifc discovery that demonstrate methodical and creative aspects of scientifc inquiry, and the self-correcting nature of science.<strong> </strong></li>
</ul>
<strong></strong>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
