<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x62128" Name="Pornography Awareness" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Pornography Awareness</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Pornography Awareness</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>POWER TO CHANGE</strong></p>
<p><br /><strong>What is Pornography addiction?</strong><br />Pornography addiction, then, is a condition in which a person becomes so dependent on pornography materials (either by reading or viewing it) for their physical and emotional satisfaction that they no longer feel able to stop, even though they know or have seen its negative consequences.</p>
<p><strong>What are the Symptoms of Pornography Addiction?</strong></p>
<p>One of the indicators of porn addiction is a substantial increase in the time spent on the consumption of pornography. While greater frequency is one of the things you should consider, this may not necessarily be the only indication.<br />For example when you spend hours and hours watching pornography and you didn't realize it.<br />If you initially started viewing free sites, for example, but now want greater variety or more videos and photos of a particular category, then you may end up spending a surprising amount of money on a number of sites and services.<br />Engaging in impulsive or risky behaviors just to get your porn fix is another indication of addiction. There are times when you may not have access to your own computer, especially if you are at work or at someone else's house. If your urge to access porn from wherever you are is so great, you just might end up doing it anyway even if you risk getting caught by your boss or your friend.<br />Finally, when you tried to stop consuming porn and experienced unexplained physical or psychological symptoms (e.g., anxiety, anger or irritability, depression, or some physical signs of stress) which disappear when you go back to viewing porn, then it's a very clear sign that you have already been addicted to pornography.</p>
<p><strong>How Did You Start Getting Addicted?</strong></p>
<p>Addiction to pornography can be likened to a host of other addictions and can be caused by pretty much the same things. If you are unhappy or feel a certain lack in some areas of your life, you may be more susceptible to becoming addicted, since the substance or activity of choice acts as filler to something that you felt was missing in your life.</p>
<p><strong>You are Hurting Yourself</strong></p>
<p> Many men don't realize that their porn addiction hurts them as well as their wife or girlfriend. Your girl knows about your porn addiction, whether you think so or not. This makes her feel inadequate in the bedroom, which leads to a lack of self-esteem and self-confidence. When a woman is suffering from low self-esteem, her performance in the bedroom also suffers. To put it bluntly, she's just not all that into it. That makes your sex life boring, which adds to the problem.</p>
<p><strong>The Importance of Seeking Help</strong></p>
<p>Be honest with yourself and admit that you have become addicted to pornography if most of the symptoms apply to you. By admitting that you have a problem, you will be taking the first step towards addressing it.<br />It may be hard for you to stop your addiction by yourself, so seek professional help.<br />It is important to have a trusted friend or a support system to assist you in your recovery efforts, because you could very quickly spiral back into the same unwanted behavior if you attempt to overcome the addiction alone.<br />Finally, remember that you have to want to overcome the addiction. You have to recognize its negative effects in your life and sincerely want to change. Knowing your value as a person will go a long way to help you in your goal of achieving a healthy sexual life.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Is this your case????</strong><br /><strong>You have the power to change!!</strong></p>
<p><strong>Do you feel trapped?</strong></p>
<p>"When someone has received the miracle of recovery through the Atonement in their lives, they want to shout from the rooftops about the Savior's power to heal."</p>
<p>The pure love of Christ can remove the scales of resentment and wrath from our eyes, allowing us to see others the way our Heavenly Father sees us: as flawed and imperfect mortals who have potential and worth far beyond our capacity to imagine. Because God loves us so much, we too must love and forgive each other."<br />- <strong>President Dieter F. Uchtdorf</strong><br /> <br />  <br />"I testify to you that your body, mind, and spirit can be transformed,<br />cleansed, and made whole, and you will be freed."<br />-<strong>Elder M. Russell Ballard</strong></p>
<p>"There is hope for the addicted, and this hope comes through the Atonement of the Lord Jesus Christ."<br />-<strong>Elder M. Russell Ballard</strong></p>
<p>"I am encompassed about, because of the temptations and the sins which do so easily beset me.<br />"And when I desire to rejoice, my heart groaneth because of my sins; nevertheless, I know in whom I have trusted.<br />"My God hath been my support; he hath led me through mine afflictions in the wilderness; and he hath preserved me upon the waters of the great deep.<br />"He hath filled me with his love, even unto the consuming of my flesh" (2 Nephi 4:18-21)</p>
<p><strong>How to Get Your Groove Back?</strong></p>
<p>&bull; Be your own best friend...<br />&bull; Self-esteem is how we feel or think about ourselves. You inherently know your values and your needs. <br />&bull; Get help and start to make changes, day-by-day and moment-by-moment that will bring your current reality into alignment with who you are as a person. The first important step in accomplishing this is to gain control over your internal critical self-talk. <br />&bull; Seek professional help <br />&bull; <br /> <br /> <strong>SCHEDULE</strong><br /><br /> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width: 559px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="153"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SUNDAY</strong></td>
<td valign="top" width="138"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; TUESDAY </strong></td>
<td valign="top" width="138"><strong>&nbsp; WEDNESADAY</strong></td>
<td valign="top" width="130"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; THURSDAY </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="153"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Men's PASG Meeting </strong> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; BYU-I Campus &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kimball 138,228,292 &amp;268 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rexburg, ID &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15 pm</td>
<td valign="top" width="138"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rexburg </strong> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Men's PASG Meeting </strong> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Madison High School &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Seminary &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2420 W University Blvd &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rexburg, ID &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15&nbsp;&nbsp;</td>
<td valign="top" width="138"><strong>&nbsp; Women's PASG Meeting </strong> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; BYU-I Campus &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kimball 228 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rexburg, ID &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15 pm</td>
<td valign="top" width="130"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rigby Men's PASG</strong> <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Meeting </strong> &nbsp; RIGBY HS Seminary Bld &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 288N. 3800 E. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rigby ID 83442 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NW Classroom &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15 pm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="153"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong> &nbsp;</td>
<td valign="top" width="138"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Women's Meeting </strong> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Madison High School &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Seminary &nbsp;&nbsp; 2420 W. University Blvd &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rexburg, ID &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15 pm</td>
<td valign="top" width="138"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rigby Family Support</strong> &nbsp;&nbsp; RIGBY Idaho Stake Center &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 258 W. 1<sup>st</sup> N. Rigby ID &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Seminary Room &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15 pm</td>
<td valign="top" width="130"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Women's Meeting </strong> &nbsp;&nbsp; RIGBY HS. Seminary bld &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 288N. 3800 E. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rigby ID 83442 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SW Classroom &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7:15 pm</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><br /><strong>TESTIMONIALS</strong><br />1. Addiction ruled my life. I had always thought that I just needed to try a little harder or to be a little better, but after ten years of drowning, I finally admitted that I could not to this by myself, or at least that I didn't have to. When I let go of that last shred of pride I finally started making progress. I agreed to go to an addiction recovery meeting. Here on campus I found others that were facing the same issue having the same struggles. I found strength and gained support that continued to inspire me as I stumbled my way through recovery. I wasn't perfect, but there was real progress, lasting progress. Piece by piece I was getting my confidence back. I took the fight off of its traditional battleground and provided myself a real change. At beating this I had to sacrifice, it was uncomfortable and difficult but with the Savior's help I did it. I cannot imagine being back in those chains and I cannot describe how much peace and confidence this freedom has given me. The Lord has begun to restore my life to me. My dreams have become more realities. I am married now and serve actively in the church. I have the confidence of my spouse and the knowledge that I can stand before my God today or any day. I have seen blessing after blessing and have been able to fully enjoy them without reservation. I have scars and there are still things I choose to give up, things I choose to sacrifice in order to indicate the changes that have taken place in me. But they seem like nothing compared to the power and peace of my recovery. My advice is; don't give up and don't let pride keep you from everything you have every wanted to enjoy in this life. There is still time to overcome all things through the Savior's help. Take advantage of the many blessings, tools, and resources this church and campus have to offer, and you will begin to see real progress, you will begin to hope again because you the power to change.<br /> <br /><strong>TIPS</strong><br /> Think carefully about why you want to avoid online pornography<br /> Make a promise to yourself that you will try not to watch pornography<br /> Look at yourself in the mirror<br /> Get rid of everything on your computer that is even remotely related to pornography.<br /> Don't spend lonely nights surfing the Internet<br /> Try not to be alone in a room with the computer<br /> Before turning on your computer, make a list (on paper) of all the things you want to accomplish<br /> Instead of spending so much time alone on the computer, develop an interest in something else<br /> Try to meditate for a few minutes during the day<br /> Think positive about yourself<br /> Install software to filter pornographic web content (see external links below)<br /> Keep your internet history - do not delete it</p>
<p><strong>FAMILY SUPPORT</strong><br />LDS Family Services -<br /><a href="http://www.providentliving.org/lds-family-services">www.providentliving.org/lds-family-services</a></p>
<p></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Steps you can take now:<br /><em>Prevent Recognize Overcome Support</em></p>
<p><strong>SUPPORTING PEOPLE WITH PORNOGRAPHY ADDICTION</strong><br />&bull; They may not agree that they have a problem.<br />&bull; They may not want to change what they are doing.<br />&bull; They may fear consequences (family or friends).<br />&bull; They may feel embarrassed, and not want to discuss it with you.<br />&bull; They may feel awkward about discussing personal issues with a professional.<br />&bull; They may be engaging in this addiction as a way to avoid dealing with another problem that bothers them more.<br />There is no fast and easy way help someone with an addiction. Overcoming an addiction requires great willpower and determination, so if they do not want to change what they are doing, trying to persuade them to get help is unlikely to work.<br />However, you can take steps that will help your loved one to make changes over the long term, and will help you to cope with a loved one with an addiction.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="x47203" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17637" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
