<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x62114" Name="Spirituality and Eating Disorders" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Eating Disorder Recovery: A Spiritual Perspective</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Spirituality and Eating Disorders from the BYU-Idaho Counseling Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<script type="text/Javascript">
   function expand(num) {
      var hidden = document.getElementById("hidden" + num);
      var expand = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (expand.innerHTML == "+") {
         expand.innerHTML = "-";
         hidden.style.display = "block";
      } else {
         expand.innerHTML = "+";
         hidden.style.display = "none";
      }
   }

   function hover(type, num) {
      var hover = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (type == 1) {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#999999";
      } else {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#007ebd";
      }
   }
</script>
<h4 align="center" style="text-align: left;">by Randy K. Hardman, Ph.D. and Michael E. Berrett, Ph.D.</h4>
<p> </p>
<p align="left">People who suffer from eating disorders battle intense emotions and  inner conflicts that negatively impact their recovery. For many of these  people, deep spiritual struggles are a major impediment to their  ability to recover from an eating disorder.</p>
<p align="left">The purpose of this article is to acknowledge the importance of  including a spiritual perspective in treatment and recovery from eating  disorders. We recognize that this spiritual perspective can be an  important part of recovery for many women and some men who have suffered  many years from the effects of a damaging eating disorder. We recognize  that an eating disorder has led many of these spiritually oriented  people away from personal and spiritual connections, religious  communities, and loving relationships that are so vital in their ability  to recover from the disorder. We believe that as people suffering with  eating disorders express and clarify their spiritual beliefs and then  begin to activate those beliefs in a more congruent fashion, they will  receive benefit in their healing process. We simply want to encourage  these women and men to take advantage of this spiritual source of  healing and empowerment that can help them in their journey of recovery.</p>
<p align="left">From our clinical experience working with women with eating disorders, we have observed women suffering from long-term eating disorders feel terribly alone, inadequate, unworthy, undeserving, and hopeless. Many  sufferers, at previous times in their lives, have felt a connection to God and a degree of personal spirituality. Some have participated in religious observations, but through the course of their eating disorder have, almost universally, lost those connections. They feel unworthy of love and acceptance from others, and in an act of self-rejection they believe that they are undeserving of God's love and acceptance as well.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The eating disorder consumed every aspect of my life. My life was  centered entirely around food and weight. I felt unworthy and  undeserving of having a relationship with God. I hated myself and did  not think it was possible for anybody, including God, to love me. I did  not feel that I was good enough to merit a relationship with God.  (20-year-old woman.)</em></p>
<p align="left">When incorporating a spiritual perspective into recovery from eating  disorders there is no need to be disrespectful of anyone's spiritual or  religious beliefs and behaviors. Be respectful of each person's  perspective and simply encourage them, within the context of what they  believe, to once again open the door to spiritual influence in their  recovery.</p>
<h4 align="left">Significant Spiritual Issues</h4>
<p align="left">Some of the significant spiritual issues that women with eating  disorders may encounter are: 1) negative image of God, 2) feelings of  spiritual unworthiness and shame, 3) fear of abandonment by God, 4)  intense difficulty surrendering and having faith, and 5) dishonesty and  deception.</p>
<h5 align="left"><em>Negative Image of God</em></h5>
<p align="left">When discussing their negative images of God, eating-disorder patients  tend to describe God much as they describe their parents. If they  perceive their parents as distant or unavailable, they often feel that  distance is true of God as well. If they perceive their parents as  rejecting, critical, controlling, angry, devaluing, shaming, etc., they  also often project these characteristics onto God. As the eating  disorder progresses, this negative image of God plays a significant role  in their disconnection from spiritually based relationships.</p>
<p align="left">Around the time my eating disorder started, I began to lose a connection  with God, and as I got sicker, I became totally disconnected from God,  even doubting his existence. My eating disorder made me want to pull  away from and go against my family and parents' belief, causing me to  pull away from God even more than I would have because my parents were  so strong in their spirituality. There were some days I would have gone  to church but had binged the night before and was too fat to go.  (18-year-old woman.)</p>
<h5 align="left"><em>Feelings of Unworthiness and Shame</em></h5>
<p align="left">A second spiritual issue that impacts eating disorder recovery is a deep  feeling of spiritual unworthiness and shame. Many of these women  believe that God and everyone else views them as unworthy, unacceptable,  and flawed. They often try to compensate for these feelings of  spiritual unworthiness through perfectionism and a relentless pursuit of  impossibly high standards. Their failure to meet these perfect  expectations only confirms their belief that they are unworthy of  spiritual connections or spiritual experiences. They decide that they  have disappointed God and are unworthy of his kindness and love. They  may feel undeserving of forgiveness or acceptance from anyone, including  God.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Throughout my eating disorder, my spirituality decreased  dramatically because of actions and behaviors I did to support my eating  disorder. The more wrong my choices and inappropriate my behaviors got,  the more I felt undeserving and unworthy of God's love. (23-year-old  woman.)</em></p>
<h5 align="left"><em>Fear of Abandonment by God</em></h5>
<p align="left">A third issue that arises among women with eating disorders is a fear of  abandonment by God. The desire to receive approval from other people is  a significant emotional issue and they fear that if they displease or  disappoint, then loved ones will abandon them. That fear and belief is  also projected onto their beliefs about God. A number of these women  have been sexually abused as children and they believe that God  abandoned them during the abuse. In such cases it becomes difficult for  them to trust again and believe that God will support and help them in  their times of need. These feelings of abandonment that originate in  childhood can become their reason for avoiding spiritual relationships  completely and can be deterrent to re-establishing spiritual connections  that can aid them in their recovery.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>My eating disorder destroyed my relationship with God. It blocked  me from him and I lost all faith and trust in God. I became very angry  with Him because I felt like He had abandoned me. Eventually, I just  stopped thinking about Him. My eating disorder became my God and my body  became the Devil. Now, I feel a lot of guilt and shame in denying Him.  (25-year-old woman.)</em></p>
<h5 align="left"><em>Intense Difficulty in Surrendering and Having Faith</em></h5>
<p align="left">A fourth spiritual issue that impacts eating disorder recovery is the  difficulty in surrendering, trusting, and acting in faith. Many  eating-disorder patients become experts at controlling or numbing their  emotions, and consequently are often unable to experience sensitive  spiritual feelings. They attempt to avoid experiencing emotions and the  associated primary emotional pain that contributed to their eating  disorder. Thus, to "let go" and begin to exercise faith and trust in God  becomes a frightening challenge to these women. They may feel so afraid  of losing control, or whatever sense of control their eating disorder  brings them, that they struggle with giving up control to a "higher  power."</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Becoming so obsessed with my body decreased my faith in everything I  believed. I wanted and knew that I could only go through this pain with  the help of God, but my life revolved around me. There wasn't enough  room in my heart for both my eating disorder and Heavenly Father. I had  to choose. I chose wrong and ended up in an eating disorder clinic.  (19-year-old woman.) </em></p>
<h5 align="left"><em>Dishonesty and Deception</em></h5>
<p align="left">A fifth spiritual issue that impacts recovery is dishonesty and  deception. Common coping strategies among eating-disorder patients  include: "covering up," secrecy, and blatant deception and lying. Many  feel a great deal of shame and remorse about their deception and lying,  compounded by feelings of guilt from too many failed promises to give up  their eating disorder. Many have lied over and over again to people who  love them, in order to protect their eating disorder. All of this leads  to the incorporation of "false pursuits" within the eating disorder  that become substitutes for the spiritual connections in their personal  lives.</p>
<h4 align="left">Ten Common False Pursuits of Eating Disorders</h4>
<p align="left">This section of the article will address ten false pursuits of an eating  disorder, their spiritual consequences, and some pathways that can help  women with eating disorders begin to change course and once again  reopen a more healing and helpful spiritual perspective in their lives  and in their recovery. These ten falsehoods are what those with eating  disorders pursue in place of, and often at the expense of, emotional and  spiritual nourishment in their lives.</p>
<p align="left">Click the (+) next to each topic to learn more.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td id="plus1" onclick="expand(1)" onmouseout="hover(2, 1)" onmouseover="hover(1, 1)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>1) An eating disorder can give a false sense of control</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden1" style="display: none;">
<p>Many of the women who suffer from eating disorders experience a tremendous fear of losing control or "not being in control." The pursuit of control at all costs eventually becomes the very narrow crusade of their eating disorder. They try to avoid any feelings associated with being out of control and also the literal experience of not being in full control of their environment. Many of these patients have suffered painful experiences in childhood which they could not control or stop. They have the illusion that by denying themselves food or getting rid of their food they are in control of their circumstance and can avoid the very things that they are so very afraid of, such as pain, disapproval, criticism, abandonment, etc.</p>
<p>One way this falsehood impacts their spiritual lives is that they will not let go of fear or mistrust enough to believe that someone outside of themselves can care for them, can accept them, or can even love them. They do not believe that another being, whether a person or God, will see more in them than they see in themselves. As a result, they keep people at a distance, refuse to allow vulnerability in themselves, and subsequently do not allow emotional intimacy or closeness in relationships. The openness and honesty necessary to create meaningful and responsive relationships does not occur. They substitute this false sense of control for meaningful and loving relationships. Experiencing vulnerability and trust in a safe relationship is the beginning step to change this pattern.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus2" onclick="expand(2)" onmouseout="hover(2, 2)" onmouseover="hover(1, 2)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>2) Eating disorders are a false form of communication about pain and suffering</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden2" style="display: none;">
<p>People with eating disorders recognize at some level that their eating disorder is a means of communicating, albeit indirect, their pain, suffering, and feelings of unacceptability. This form of communication is a false pursuit or false means of conveying the pain and misery of their lives in an attempt to solicit help from others. Because most people do not respond to this indirect communication in the way that is needed, it is not usually met with supportive, kind, reassuring, or comforting responses. People with eating disorders are usually told that they are selfish and seeking attention, or that they just need to eat. The way that this false communication about their pain impacts their spiritual life is that they are often not willing to be direct and honest with God either. Instead of expressing the pain they are feeling in their prayers or other communication with God, they talk about how fat they feel. Instead of sharing how lonely, inadequate, or empty they feel, they tell God and others what a bad person they are or how undeserving they are of love and acceptance. Part of spiritual healing comes out of directness and honesty in their relationship with themselves, with other people, and with God. Pain and internal suffering can be expressed and shared, eventually without shame, to those who will show empathy and validate their emotional experience.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus3" onclick="expand(3)" onmouseout="hover(2, 3)" onmouseover="hover(1, 3)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>3) An eating disorder can give a false sense of being the exception or exceptional</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden3" style="display: none;">
<p>The pursuit and feeling of being the exception can be a tremendous  barrier to recovery from eating disorders. Those who hold this belief  feel that somehow they are exempt from, or the exception to, love,  kindness, forgiveness, or support, and that somehow empathy, compassion,  mercy, and grace apply to other people but not to themselves. They feel  like there is something inherently wrong in them, and their shame-based  thinking tells them that: "Other people deserve kindness and love but I  don't. I deserve contempt, hatred, and rejection." In a sense, these  women become exceptional at their refusal to allow any kind of  acceptance, kindness or support to be beneficial to them. In a  paradoxical sense, this pursuit of being the exception, or exceptional,  is a false pursuit of being special.</p>
<p>This kind of "specialness" distorts their view of how they are unique  from other people and can lead them to feel that they have no potential  for recovery. Ironically, individuals in this situation will typically  do anything they can to help another person recover from their eating  disorder--believing the ability they lack still exists, but only in  others. This false sense of being the exception can be a major roadblock  to maintaining a spiritual life or a relationship with God. These  patients have usually stopped praying because they feel like they are  unforgivable, unacceptable, or undeserving of a relationship with God.  They feel too unworthy to ever be forgiven. And yet, it is this extreme  notion--that the rules are different for them, that keeps them from  actively pursuing the kind of relationship with God that would help them  in their recovery. It is sad that their own false pursuit of being the  exception reinforces their sense of aloneness and emptiness. Healing can  start when they are willing to be no better or no worse than any other  person and to share their similarities with others. Healing can start  when there are no special rules or requirements which apply only to them  and not to other people.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus4" onclick="expand(4)" onmouseout="hover(2, 4)" onmouseover="hover(1, 4)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>4) An eating disorder can be a false crusade for evidence and proof against self</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden4" style="display: none;">
<p>In time, a woman with an eating disorder uses the very eating disorder  itself as her evidence that she is bad, unacceptable, and deserving of  punishment. Some believe that if God and other people are not going to  punish them, then they should do it for themselves. Sufferers will use  all their time and energy to prove this terrible truth to God and others  and will add new degrading and demeaning experiences and events to  their list as proof for their deserved rejection, unkind treatment, and  pain. The spiritual consequence is that much of this pain comes from the  self-inflicted experiences of this false crusade. The message seems to  be that "even God could not like me." They become so busy proving  themselves right that there is no time to be wrong about their false  beliefs. Whenever they feel happy, hopeful, or peaceful they will chase  these positive feelings away by mentally beating themselves up with  their long list of personal negatives. The truth is that the illness or  "disorder" is not who they are. It is not their identity. As these women  begin to separate who they are from what they do, they can begin to  give up this false crusade against themselves.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus5" onclick="expand(5)" onmouseout="hover(2, 5)" onmouseover="hover(1, 5)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>5) An eating disorder can be a false pursuit of perfection</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden5" style="display: none;">
<p>This perfection is a rigid pursuit of something specific that is  unreasonable or unrealistic for anyone to obtain or maintain. Women with  eating disorders have deceived themselves into thinking that if they  obtain perfection in their bodies, in self-control over their bodies, or  in body image, that somehow this perfection will make up for their  other perceived inadequacies and failures. Many times we have heard  women with eating disorders talk about how they need to be perfect "for  everyone else," but this is really a false perfection because even when  they receive acceptance or approval, the best they can ever do in their  own minds is "break even." Consequently, any criticism or disapproval  creates intense feelings of failure and imperfection that feed the  eating disorder cycle, making it more intense and rigid.</p>
<p>In a sense, seeking perfection becomes a substitute for love. They have  externalized perfection assuming that if they can perform well or do  something very well it will translate into external validation (love)  from other people. The pursuit of perfection impedes them spiritually.  They neglect spirituality and higher love in pursuit of a kind of  physical and literal justification for their existence. "If I obtain  this perfection, I have a right to be here."</p>
<p>One of the things that happens in the religious community to women with  eating disorders is that they can become very discouraged, feeling they  can't live up to certain religious precepts and principles in a perfect  enough fashion. Instead of trusting that self-improvement is an ongoing  and unfolding process, they become perfectionistic and adopt an "all or  nothing" approach, leaving God out of their self-improvement pursuits.  In order to change the course of this perfectionistic pursuit, these  women need to learn that it is okay to make mistakes, and that through  their mistakes and subsequent corrections, they will make the  improvement in themselves that will, over time, make a significant  difference in their lives. It is also important that they come to  understand that their specific pursuit of being the best in the eating  disorder realm is why they often end up feeling unsatisfied and unhappy.  Letting spiritual influences help them make corrections, learn from  their experiences, and help them in their efforts to do things better,  becomes a positive journey instead of a negative one.</p>
<p>Letting spiritual influences help them make corrections, learn from their experiences, and help them in their efforts to do things better,  becomes a positive journey instead of a negative one.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus6" onclick="expand(6)" onmouseout="hover(2, 6)" onmouseover="hover(1, 6)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>6) An eating disorder can be a false form of comfort and safety</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden6" style="display: none;">
<p>For many, eating disorders relieve anxiety and help them avoid painful  emotions. This false sense of safety and comfort is a temporary absence  of pain rather than a true form of comfort.   Women with bulimia, often  describe their pursuit of bingeing and purging as an attempt to find  comfort and relief from the anxiety and tension that they are feeling.  It becomes a very unsatisfying and fleeting form of comfort in which,  almost before they are done with one binge and purge episode, it is  necessary to begin another. Certainly, this false sense of comfort,  relief, and safety that the eating disorder brings implies that the  eating disorder is the source and author of their comfort instead of  God.</p>
<p>The spiritual consequence in looking for immediate gratification and  immediate release from whatever they are experiencing is that it  distracts them from seeking a greater and more profound type of comfort.  They miss the soothing, lasting effects of knowing that there is  someone more powerful then themselves who desires to support and comfort  them, provide answers to their questioning, and bring healing to their  pain and emotional quandary. True safety and comfort for these women  comes from loving and accepting relationships and from knowing that they  are not alone in facing the ups and downs of life.</p>
<p> </p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus7" onclick="expand(7)" onmouseout="hover(2, 7)" onmouseover="hover(1, 7)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>7) An eating disorder can give a false identity and perception of self</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden7" style="display: none;">
<p>Invariably, women in treatment for severe eating disorders talk about  how the eating disorder has become their identity. They lose their sense of self and become frightened at the thought of giving up the  eating disorder asking: "Who will I be without it? This is me. This is  my life." They have an underlying feeling of emptiness and void, and  facing those feelings is a very threatening prospect without the false identity of their eating disorder. Anyone who spends all their mind, body, and soul in the energy of an eating disorder soon has no room for anything else.</p>
<p>We often say that it is hard to have an eating disorder and a life at  the same time.  Patients have to pick one or the other. When an eating disorder is their life, it also becomes their sense of who they are.  Certainly, this impedes their ability to make spiritual connections because an eating disorder is something one does and not who one is. By treating the eating disorder as who they are, they believe, "God could never accept me as an eating disorder," because they know implicitly the extreme costs and consequences of living their life this way. They return to spiritual hopelessness-- "If there is nothing else to me, how can God help me find the rest of me? How can God help me feel good about who I am if this is all there is? Is this all I'm good for?"</p>
<p>They will often say, "This is the one thing I can do better than anyone  else. This is the one thing that I can do well." Consequently, doing  the eating disorder well becomes a false form of acceptance, replacing  true acceptance from themselves and acceptance from God and other people  who recognize and value their unique human qualities. Part of a  spiritual reawakening is the discovery that who they are is more than  what they do. What anyone does, including those with an eating disorder,  can never express fully the unique and distinct person or the distinct  personal qualities and characteristics of the individual. Believing that  God or others can accept all of you with your strengths, weaknesses,  pluses, and minuses, and do so unconditionally with love and kindness,  is a spiritual experience that can help in the recovery process.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus8" onclick="expand(8)" onmouseout="hover(2, 8)" onmouseover="hover(1, 8)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>8) An eating disorder can be false compensation for the past</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden8" style="display: none;">
<p>Sometimes, an eating disorder is an attempt to compensate or make up  for past childhood abuse or trauma, family problems, and sometimes past  personal mistakes. And so, in a fashion, the eating disorder becomes a  false pursuit of penance. It becomes a way to justify one's existence by  trying to atone for past mistakes, pain, or negative experiences. This  false attempt to make up for the past, becomes a driving force for many  women with eating disorders. The message is, "the suffering that I  experience from denying myself through the eating disorder will  emotionally justify past errors, failures, and suffering."</p>
<p>One of the ways this attempt to compensate for the past greatly impedes  spiritual and religious activity is that it puts the burden on the  person suffering to do what only a higher influence can do to bring  healing, forgiveness, and relief from past trauma, abuse, or errors. In  essence, they are punishing themselves in an attempt to somehow resolve  the guilt and the pain of the past. Consequently, they overlook God as a  source of the comfort, inspiration, and guidance that they need. They  do not trust the counsel, encouragement, or comforting words of pastors,  ministers, family, or friends because somehow, they alone must make up  for what has happened instead of allowing God to help them resolve the  pain of these events. These beliefs become an ongoing crusade of  self-punishment that never leads to resolution, peace, or comfort, but  can actually become a way to reinforce their belief that no matter how  much they suffer, they will always be unacceptable and unworthy. Letting  go of the past is a spiritual process in which they can give away to  God what they cannot correct from the past, and ask for help to do  things differently in the present and future.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus9" onclick="expand(9)" onmouseout="hover(2, 9)" onmouseover="hover(1, 9)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>9) An eating disorder can be a false attempt to avoid personal responsibility for life</strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden9" style="display: none;">
<p>Without question, an eating disorder can become a tremendous  explanation and justification for the absence of an abundant life. It  becomes a sufferer's reason for everything that is missing. In that  sense, it becomes an indirect and false attempt at ownership or  responsibility for life choices. In essence, what women harboring this  false notion are saying is, "My choice to have an eating disorder  preempts all the other choices for which I am accountable and  responsible." Blaming life's troubles, relationship problems, feelings  of inadequacy, and their inability to function in life on their eating  disorder implicitly dismisses them from being accountable for their  life, as if it is beyond their direct control.</p>
<p>This pattern creates a roadblock to recovery because without  accountability and responsibility for the choices and consequences they  have created, there is no way for them to be empowered to choose  otherwise. They cannot change or let go of something until they first  take ownership for it. It is impossible to turn their lives over to God  if first they have not taken ownership for their lives and if they have  not been honest and open with themselves about their mistakes, poor  choices, and weaknesses. Responsibility is very different from blame,  judgement, or fault. It is an acceptance of the fact that much of the  eating disorder behavior, pursuits, and coping strategies are learned  and a willingness to admit that, "I learned it, I have choices about it,  and it is mine to change."</p>
<p>Once proper ownership is taken, then one can ask for help from  spiritual influences and others to make new choices. Those with eating  disorders can have difficulty approaching God honestly and  straightforwardly because they feel a victim of their eating disorder  rather than a collaborator and enabler of the eating disorder. We  encourage them to choose to be kind and patient with themselves as they  assume personal responsibility and learn from their choices along this  road to recovery. It is essential for them to face their lives directly  and without blame so they can begin to make better choices and see  options beyond their eating disorder.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus10" onclick="expand(10)" onmouseout="hover(2, 10)" onmouseover="hover(1, 10)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong>10) An eating disorder can be a false pursuit of approval</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden10" style="display: none;">
<p>Many women with eating disorders have substituted approval for true  acceptance and love. They often think approval is validation that they  are acceptable. The eating disorder and all it brings with it, including  societal approval for attractive body image, thinness, or external  beauty becomes their object of worship. Approval becomes a false form of  worship in which they let go of everything else that has meaning or  matters in life. Approval from others becomes their purpose in life. We  have heard many patients with eating disorders talk about how positive,  affirming, and congratulatory people were toward them when they lost  weight initially, in contrast to how bad they felt about themselves on  the inside. These temporary expressions of approval from other people  become the false pursuit of their lives as they obsess about and  actively pursue approval.</p>
<p>The problem, of course, in a spiritual context, is that approval from  others is not sufficient to bring change and healing. It does not last.  Approval is not deep enough; it is short lived. The free gift of  acceptance and a deep sense of acceptance that can be felt from other  people and from a relationship with God is a much more powerful  motivator and incentive for anyone to work with themselves, find  solutions, and make corrections. Approval becomes a very externalized,  narrow, and short-sighted solution for pain. Seeking the approval of  other people rather than the more healing acceptance that comes from God  leaves these women feeling empty and starved.</p>
<p>Godly approval does not carry the damaging conditions or expectations  that are so often found in human relationships. Godly approval can bring  peace, comfort, and hope rather than worry, anxiety, and pressure to  please other people. Acceptance and love are worth working for in  relationships in which people develop real, honest, and congruent  connections with God and with other people. Love is a change agent.  Approval is not. Love has greater influence in changing lives than  approval. Sometimes women with eating disorders use approval as love,  when in fact, it usually makes them feel very unlovable. Often, this  pursuit of approval gets in the way of giving love to other people.  Approval is about trying to get love, where acceptance is about giving  and receiving love. Giving love, service to others, and thinking about  someone other than themselves can open the door to a spiritual recovery  and a fulfilling life journey.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p align="left"><strong>Spiritual Interventions</strong></p>
<p align="left">There are numerous spiritual interventions that can be used to help in  someone's recovery from an eating disorder. A few mentioned here are:</p>
<ul>
<li> Teaching spiritual concepts </li>
<li>Encouraging the reading of religious and spiritual articles and literature </li>
<li>Encouraging prayer </li>
<li>Encouraging spiritual imagery and meditation </li>
<li>Encouraging forgiveness </li>
<li>Encouraging people to seek spiritual direction from their own religious leaders </li>
<li>Encouraging self-correction and self-kindness in recovery </li>
<li>Encouraging people to be involved in their own religious community, etc. </li>
</ul>
<p align="left">(For more detailed explanation, see P. Scott Richards, et al, "Spiritual  Issues and Interventions in the Treatment of Patients with Eating  Disorders"--Journal of Treatment and Prevention, Volume 5, Number 4,  Winter, 1997.)</p>
<p align="left">Certainly, what interventions are encouraged and emphasized are  dependent upon the individual and what they are willing to do within a  spiritual framework. The client always leads in her own spiritual  journey and recovery. She does most of the work outside of therapy with  occasional conversations within the therapy setting to encourage and  support this component of recovery.</p>
<p align="left">One of the things that we encourage in the beginning stages of recovery  is to start praying again, and in those prayers to be honest, direct,  and to tell the truth about their feelings, whether positive or  negative, distorted or accurate, and to begin to reopen the  communication with other people, with themselves, and with God.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Once I came to the realization that the only way I was going to  recover was through God, a huge weight was lifted off my shoulders. I  was humbled in His presence. I pray every time I feel anxious,  depressed, or not myself. I ask him to help me to work things out and to  listen to what is going on around me. As soon as I put my recovery in  God's hands, things started to fall into place. (19-year-old woman.)</em></p>
<p align="left">We are cautious not to tell people how to pray. We do encourage those  who believe in God to address that relationship in the context of prayer  and to begin to talk honestly and openly about internal experiences,  struggles, and emotional conflicts, and, in time, to begin to ask God  for help in sorting out and resolving these struggles. We encourage them  to listen for answers to their prayers and to use the understandings or  insights that may come to them.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>My relationship with God has helped me so much in my recovery.   Just knowing there is someone you can always turn to and trust always  gave me somewhat of a relief after I prayed--kind of a peaceful feeling.  It helped me see there is so much more to life. (20-year-old woman.) </em></p>
<p align="left">We have seen that women in treatment who are able to use prayer in the  stages of recovery begin to recognize an influence beyond themselves and  feel evidence that God is helping them as they include Him in their  eating disorder recovery.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Being able to feel like someone else is in control can help make me  feel better and feel like a weight is lifted off my shoulders when I  tell God my concerns. (23-year-old woman.) </em></p>
<p align="left">A patient who is in the severe stages of an eating disorder feels  powerless to change her course or correct it on her own. But when she  begins to feel help beyond her own to change her course and to begin to  do things she could not do on her own in her recovery, it strengthens  her hope and resolve to continue to develop and enjoy that personal  relationship with God.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>My spirituality and my relationship with God have given me hope and  strength. Whenever I'm too weak, out of control, or just lonely, I  close my eyes and imagine God and His angels with me. My faith is  unstable right now, but even that helps me. &gt;If ye have faith as  small as a mustard seed, nothing will be impossible for you.  (23-year-old woman.) </em></p>
<p align="left">This spiritual perspective of help in recovery is not without its  challenges. It is important to remember that oftentimes spiritual  recovery is an unseen, subtle, and quiet experience. It is also  important to remember that the intense worship of the eating disorder is  a hard thing to give up because it is so deeply based in fear and  self-contempt. The barriers to spiritual reconnection are often the very  things that influenced the onset and maintenance of the eating  disorder.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>I believe that God answered my prayers and my family's prayers for  making a way for me to get better. He helped me feel loved and not alone  in my most difficult days away from home. He gives me answers and  instructions that help me, makes me hopeful in the scriptures, and I  know that He is there to support me and help me recover. (18-year-old  woman.) </em></p>
<p align="left">We encourage women with eating disorders to regain spiritual connections  by participating in structured assignments and activities where  questions are asked and where they reflect and respond in writing. We  encourage readings that they can select, including books, scriptures,  writings, and affirmations. We encourage personal and private meditation  and self-reflections. We encourage prayerful hearts or spiritual pauses  in the course of their day. Support can also be given to help them  reconnect with their religious communities, activities, and structures  that many of these women have given up.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>I believe spirituality is a pivotal aspect of recovery. I don't  think it is possible to get through this without having faith in God or a  higher power. When I am in my eating disorder, I feel alone and tend to  isolate myself from the world. I feel lonely and disconnected. It is  easy to give up on life if you don't have a belief that there is  something greater than yourself to live for. (19-year-old woman.)</em></p>
<p align="left">In treatment, encouragement is given to reexamine or challenge the  beliefs from their earlier lives that had a negative impact on them  spiritually and religiously. We encourage them to reexamine old beliefs  and decisions and to make new decisions, changes, and develop new  direction for themselves within a spiritual and religious context.</p>
<p align="left" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>It is only through the grace of God that I was able to pull through  my eating disorder. Because of His unconditional love and the  Atonement, I am able to be whole once again. Never in my life have I  felt so much peace and comfort. I rely in Him in all I do. Praying for  strength daily, I am able to win this battle. (28-year-old woman.) </em></p>
<p align="left">A new hope for recovery is kindled when those suffering with eating  disorders begin to turn away from the false pursuits of the eating  disorder and embrace again their own spirituality.</p>
<p>Courtesy of Center For Change, Orem, Utah</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x24495" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
