<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x62139" Name="Healthy Diet" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Eating Healthy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Having a Healthy Diet from the BYU-Idaho Counseling Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Eating healthy is one of the founding blocks of a long quality life.   Ironically, in the wealthiest and best supplied countries in the world,  where food is easily accessible and, for the most part, affordable,  eating healthy is not a common behavior for the majority of citizens.   For example, in the last 50 years, America has become overweight, and  more than ever susceptible to heart diseases and various forms of  cancer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">There is a lot of confusion about what to eat and not to eat.  We hear  many voices saying "Lo here", and "Lo there..." and claiming to have  found the best way to achieve the ideal weight.  An inventory of some  current popular eating plans and diets shows they contradict each other  so much that it is impossible for a layperson to know what to follow  with a sufficient degree of confidence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">In addition, when it comes to food, our own personal choices get us in  trouble.  Frequently, we self-indulge at social occasions by stuffing  ourselves with oversize portions, or we skip meals altogether as an  attempt to regain control over our appetite.   We confuse emotional  hunger with true physiological hunger, and we eat so fast that the body  doesn't have time to let us know when we have had enough before reaching  an uncomfortable stuffed feeling.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">To make matters worse, students with low monetary funds may resort to  eating unbalanced meals that make them feel full quickly but bring  little nutritional benefits. Or, because time for them is a rare  commodity, they may not take the time to prepare meals, and instead buy  processed foods that have been modified and lost a lot of their  nutritional value.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">If you desire to maintain/develop healthy eating habits, use <strong><em>balance</em></strong> as your motto.  Balance means eating food that provides all three types  of nutrients plus fiber at every meal.  As a reminder, nutrients  comprise carbohydrates, protein and healthy--non-manmade/damaged--fats.   Fiber is found in abundance in non-starchy vegetables (other than  potatoes).  Your body absolutely needs all nutrient types on a daily  basis to build and regulate itself harmoniously.  Don't neglect any  nutrient or largely favor one over the others.  Imbalance will mess up  your metabolism and make it harder for you to feel happy and capable of  achieving in school.  Aim to prepare a balanced meal every time you eat  to facilitate digestion and assimilation, as nutrients act upon each  other during digestion and absorption.  Your body needs three meals a  day.  If you skip, you are more likely to overeat later on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Carbohydrates give us energy.  The best carbohydrates, those that will  not cause your blood sugar and insulin levels to sky rocket, are found  in whole grains such as whole wheat and brown rice.  In the Word of  Wisdom, the Lord tells us that grains are good for us.  Avoid carbs that  have been ultra-processed, such as white bread, and avoid simple sugars  that go through the blood stream fast, such as candy, chocolate bars,  etc.  Especially, don't have a candy bar alone for lunch!!  An excess of  carbs and insulin causes weight gain.  Don't be a sugar junkie!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Proteins are very important in building muscles and keeping organs  functioning properly.  Proteins are found in beans, all meats, eggs,  fish, and soy bean products like tofu.  There are proteins in most dairy  products such as milk, yogurt, and cheese.  Proteins are also found in  all nuts.  In addition to proteins, several of those foods also contain  other nutrients in small or large quantities depending on the food.  For  example, beans and milk contain carbohydrates, and eggs and nuts  contain fats.  Protein increases satiety; this means if you eat proteins  during a meal, hunger will come again later than if you did not have  any.  The counsel of the Lord is that we eat meats (flesh of beasts and  fowls) sparingly, and in the winter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Fat and cholesterol are necessary to life.  Our hormones, for example,  depend on fat.  An added bonus to fats is that they make food tastier!   Not all fats are healthy, however.  For cooking, common sources of  wholesome fats are oils such as canola and olive oils.  Those have been  found to be very beneficial to the human body.  The current consensus  among health experts is that saturated fats (fats that turn solid at  room temperature, like butter or fat in meat) need to be eaten sparingly  or, at least, in moderation.  Avoid man-made and damaged fats.   Examples are (partially) hydrogenated fats, trans fats, and fats that  are brought to very high temperatures as during deep frying process.   Unfortunately, a lot of store-bought foods such as crackers, cookies,  etc. are made with damaged fats.  This is a good reason to check the  labels.  Remember, fats are necessary to life, so don't eliminate foods  that contain them in their natural state (e.g., nuts, eggs). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Fiber and many vitamins are found in abundance in non starchy vegetables  and fruits.  Fruits have a lot more carbohydrates due to the natural  sugars in them; and vegetables contain more fiber ,which promotes  healthy intestinal function.  In the Word of Wisdom, we are told "fruit"  and "herb" are good for us.  Fruits and vegetables are loaded with  vitamins necessary for a healthy body.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">An easy way to remember to eat balanced meals is to divide your plate  into three parts approximately equal in size: One for protein, one for  carbohydrates and one for non starchy veggies.  Add a piece of fruit  and/or a dairy product and you have a balanced meal.  When snacking,  avoid eating a sweet treat by itself which would raise your blood sugar  too fast.  A better choice is to eat something with protein, like nuts,  because proteins slow down digestion and curb the appetite.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Another hint is to take a multivitamin, and calcium + vitamin D supplements daily to promote bone health.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">Nutritional advice is incomplete without the recommendation to exercise  and drink plenty of water daily.  A mix of cardiovascular exercise,  strength and flexibility/balance training is ideal.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">The BYU-Idaho Wellness Newsletter  provides extremely useful information  on health related topics including nutrition.  Check the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/campuswellness/Newsletters.htm" target="_self">website</a> and go to previous months newsletters for info and ideas.  Another helpful website is the <a href="http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/" target="_self">Harvard School of Public Health Newsletter website</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small; font-family: helvetica;">You can also get a free nutrition evaluation by visiting or calling the  BYU-Idaho Wellness Center, located in the Hart Building (same level as  the Fitness Center), and/or by participating in a <a href="http://www.byui.edu/campuswellness/StudentNutritionIncentive.htm" target="_self">wellness incentive program</a> that will keep you motivated.</span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x24495" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
