<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x62113" Name="Hidden Feelings" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Hidden Feelings from Surviving an Eating Disorder</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">An Extract from Surviving an Eating Disorder, BYU-Idaho Counseling Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong> </strong>
<h4 align="center" style="text-align: left;">by Siegel, Brishman, and Weinshel</h4>
<p> </p>
<strong> </strong>
<h4 align="center" style="text-align: left;">THE PSYCHOLOGICAL ASPECTS OF EATING DlSORDERS</h4>
<strong> </strong></p>
<p>When Joyce, a 23-year-old bulimic, came to our center for a treatment  consultation, she explained her situation this way: "I have a nice  apartment, a good job, a terrific boyfriend. Everything would be going  okay if it wasn't for the binging and vomiting.  I've tried to make  myself stop but I can't. If you could just help me get rid of the  bulimia, I'd be okay. I'm worried it's going to ruin my health."Joyce  was upset and confused by her eating disorder. Why was she binging, even  though it was so offensive to her? Was she lacking in willpower or  strength of character? When they learned of Joyce's eating disorder, her  parents were also confused. Joyce seemed to have everything going for  her. What was wrong? Joyce herself did not know. AD she knew was that  she could not stop binging and did not want to be fat. She would relieve  this awful fullness by vomiting. For Joyce, the reasons she was  compelled to binge and vomit were as unknown to her as they were to  those observing her.</p>
<h5>WHAT'S GOING ON INSIDE?</h5>
<p>An eating disorder is not merely a problem with food or weight. It is an  attempt to use food intake and weight control to solve unseen emotional  conflicts or difficulties that in fact have little to do with either  food or weight. An eating disorder is never simply a matter of  self-control. Healthier eating habits or stronger willpower is not the  missing ingredients that will make the problem disappear.</p>
<p>Anorexia, bulimia, and compulsive overeating never exist in a vacuum.  These disorders do not occur in an otherwise satisfied, productive, and  emotionally healthy person. At first, this may be a very hard concept to  accept. Often, people hope for something like a surgical procedure that  will "cut out" the behavior the way a surgeon removes the offending  tissues or organ. However, it is a destructive myth that the only  problem is the eating behavior.</p>
<p>After years of failed efforts to stop binging and vomiting on her own,  Joyce joined a support group to help her resist her strong urges to  binge. After several months in this group and when she was feeling less  isolated and frightened, Joyce was able to pay attention to the  connection between her eating and her feelings of anxiety and  discomfort:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I have this perpetual knot in my stomach. I was never even aware of it  before. It comes from worrying about 'them.' I don't know who 'they'  are-but I'm worried they will see me for what I really am, not the mature adult, but the insecure kid, It seems that  when I'm feeling the most  shaky about myself is when I binge."</em></p>
<p>No amount of praise or material reward could convince Joyce of her value  for long. She was driven to prove herself all the time, monitoring her  words and behavior in nearly all circumstances. Her self-consciousness  was ever present. The more anxious or self-doubting she became, the  harder she would work to prove herself. Binging and vomiting helped her  feel some relief from her vigilance; it was an attempt to make herself  feel better.</p>
<p>Jill, a 17-year-old anorexic, describes her experience:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"When I was starving myself, all I felt was that I had to. There was no rhyme or reason to it. You could not have convinced me it had anything to do with something  emotional or psychological. It took time for me to see how frightened I  was and how I had to feel in absolute control. It seems strange now,  even a little pathetic, but my eating was all I could control: I felt I  was more powerful than anyone when I wasn't eating. What a peculiar way  to feel competent."</em></p>
<p><strong>Is She Trying to Hurt Herself?</strong></p>
<p>"But it's so destructive. Is she trying to hurt herself?." Joyce's  mother wanted to know. The question is a common one. Eating disorders  are destructive. They take a great toll, emotionally and physically. But  this is not by design. Only when you understand the ways in which an  eating disorder is someone's attempt to feel better about herself or to  help her function in a world that feels intimidating can you see that  the destructiveness is a by-product of the problem, not an intent. In  fact, the self-destructiveness of compulsive overeating and bulimia  causes the individual great anguish and is often a motivator to stop.</p>
<p>"Tell me again about the side effects and risks of death," requested a  bulimic patient. "Maybe if I can really focus on how I am hurting  myself, I can finally stop."</p>
<p>With another patient, it took years of intensive therapy for her to see  and accept that her weight was part of a solution to an emotional  problem.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I always thought the weight was the obstacle. It was what kept me from a  happy life. Indeed, at 280 pounds, I and everyone else thought I was  just out to kill myself--a slow suicide. It is only recently that I've  begun to see that my deeper terror is that of feeling close to people. I built a natural barrier. No wonder every time I lost weight I ran right back to food."</em></p>
<p>In anorexia the destructiveness is flatly denied. Even on the brink of  death, the anorexic sees her starving as essential to her sense of  competence and self-esteem. It feels necessary to life, even as it  kills.</p>
<p>In every eating disorder, it is only when the person is able to find  healthier means of taking care of herself and generating internal  sources of self-esteem that she can give up the attempts at coping that  have, ironically and tragically, led to further emotional and physical  damage. Only by understanding the protective and adaptive functions of  these behaviors can you begin to appreciate why it may be so hard for  someone to just "give it up."</p>
<p><strong>An Eating Disorder is an External Solution to Inner Turmoil</strong></p>
<p>A focus on body size is a way to convert a worry about something inside  to something outside. For example, if the concern, "Am 1 good enough?"  becomes, "Am I thin enough?" the sufferer creates an external and  measurable scale of her self-worth that offers her a less painful and  more comprehensible way to cope with her fears.</p>
<p>Jennie, a 20-year-old overweight college student who was very pretty in  spite of 60 excess pounds, describes the phenomenon this way:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I wonder about why I can't lose the weight. Sometimes I think I stay  fat because everything that is wrong in my life can be attributed to  that. This way, if someone doesn't like me, I can always blame it on my  weight."</em></p>
<p>Not as observable as Jennie's weight was her fragile self-esteem. With or without excess weight,</p>
<p>Jennie felt herself to be unlovable and undesirable. By focusing on the  weight as the source of all discomfort, she could leave untouched the  confusing and tumultuous feelings inside of her. She had an excuse for  avoiding the social situations in which she felt timid and inept, and  she could attribute any disappointment or hurt to her weight. Being 60  pounds lighter risked the hurts without the ready explanation.</p>
<p>Allison, a 15-year-old bulimic, describes what food does for her:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I start to feel a terror, like a big, black cloud that creeps up. My thoughts start to race so fast</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>I don't know what they are. Then I go for the food. The food calms me,  distracts me. Even though I'm eating frantically and I don't taste a  bite, the terror subsides. Slowly, I'm back in a warm, familiar space  where everything is blocked out but me and the food."</em></p>
<p>Betty, a 30-year-old bulimic, began to discover that the eating disorder was more about feeling secure than about food:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"It started to dawn on me that the binging and purging weren't entirely  about my size and weight and then 1 noticed a certain pattern. When I  was with a man, I was not binging. If someone was sleeping in my bed at  night there was no urge to binge. It wasn't just that I couldn't binge  because someone was there, but that the urge was gone! I noticed this  when I started keeping a journal of my feelings and experiences, and it  floored me! I feel so safe and secure with a man, almost any man, that I  have no desire to eat. It's bizarre to me that</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>I can feel secure with a stranger."</em></p>
<p><strong>An Eating Disorder Can be a Form of Substance Abuse</strong></p>
<p>In Betty's case, she was able to substitute a man for the food in order  to calm her anxiety. She experienced a man as a warm, soothing body  rather than as a complex human being to interact with. In this way, a  man was like a substance rather than a person. Therefore, be it a man or  a binge, Betty was relying on an external substance to alleviate her  inner distress. When used for emotional purposes, food functions  similarly to a drug or alcohol: It provides escape.</p>
<p>As time goes on, food replaces people more and more in the world of the  sufferer, and the isolation increases. Said one 19-year-old coed who  would binge and vomit several times nightly:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"It got to be so that I would rather spend a Saturday night eating than  with my friends. Being with people felt superficial. I was just killing  time until I could go home and eat. I'd be carrying on a perfectly  normal conversation, but in the back of my mind, all I'd be thinking  about was all the food I could eat as soon as I left. I knew something  was wrong. I hated that food was so important, but 1 was trapped. I  couldn't get the thoughts of food out of my head and I didn't know any  way out."</em></p>
<p><strong>She May Also Be Depressed</strong></p>
<p>Many people with eating disorders grapple with low moods, low energy levels, and feelings of despondency and sadness.</p>
<p>In some cases, the intensity of the mood and the seriousness of  associated behaviors, such as severe sleep problems, lack of interest in  life, and constant self-deprecating thoughts indicate the presence of a  clinical depression.</p>
<p>Depression is usually associated with feelings of helplessness,  ineffectiveness, loss of control, and or unexpressed anger. The  relationship between feeling depressed and eating disorders is a  complicated one. Because bulimics and compulsive overeaters often feel  out of control, feeling depressed can be a frequent by-product of an  eating disorder. After all, how would you feel if you repeatedly  promised yourself to stop some destructive, disruptive behavior and  failed over and over again?</p>
<p>In many people, depression and mood swings are the result of the  disordered eating itself. Erratic and restrictive food intake can lead  to internal chemical imbalances that can wreak havoc with mood.</p>
<p>When this is the case, the mood swings and depressed feelings will be alleviated by a normal diet.</p>
<p>But for some proportion of sufferers, the syndrome or illness of  depression has preceded the eating disorder and may be physiologically  based. The relationship between eating disorders and depression is the  subject of much current research. Because the research is new, the  results are not conclusive, but they indicate that some people seem to  have depressions of a biological nature.</p>
<p>What proportion of the population this involves is still unclear. In  these cases, the eating disorder may be the attempt to alleviate or  anesthetize against the depression to make it bearable. The eating  disorder may well be someone's attempt at self-medication.</p>
<p>Sara spoke of her periods of extreme depression:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"These waves of lethargy and dullness would come over me. The day  before. I'd be fine, but then I would wake up and feel such utter  hopelessness and despair that there would be no point in going to work  or seeing friends. What seemed to offer pleasure yesterday looked bleak  and uninviting today. I couldn't move and I'd feel horrible about  myself. I don't know what makes me feel like this. But once I do, it  goes on for weeks and there is nothing I want to do but eat. And then it  lifts--as mysteriously as it began--leaving me 10 to 20 pounds  heavier."</em></p>
<p>Sara's depressions began years before the binging became a part of her  life. She had a history of depressive episodes, but as a child, her  depression manifested itself through sleep disturbances and crying  spells. When Sara reached 11 or 12, she found that eating alone in her  room seemed to comfort and calm her. Although she didn't know it, Sara's  use of food was an attempt at medicating herself for depression that no  one knew existed. What started out as a naive attempt to deal with her  depressive state quickly developed into bulimia.</p>
<p>Among the people for whom depression is associated with bulimia,  antidepressants can be a helpful aspect of treatment. In Chapter 6, we  discuss the use of medication and its treatment implications.</p>
<p><strong>An Eating Disorder is an Emotional Anesthetic</strong></p>
<p>Whether or not she is clinically depressed, someone with an eating  disorder always has a great deal of trouble acknowledging, accepting,  and enduring many of her own feelings. Sometimes they are the more  tender emotions like affection, longing, and dependence that cause  problems.</p>
<p>Sometimes conflictual feelings are the difficult ones, like wanting to  be grown-up and remain a child at the same time. Feelings can be, and  often are, intense for the eating-disordered person, who fears being  overwhelmed by them or, worse still, overwhelming others with them. The  fear of her feelings then exacerbates the problem, leading the person to  panic and rush to food.</p>
<p>Lyla, 25-years-old, ten years bulimic, and now in treatment, talks about her use of food in this way:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"Sometimes my head feels like it's going to explode. I can't stop  thinking about how I should have done something differently or how I  blew a relationship because of what I said. I feel like I'm going crazy  with my thoughts. I can't stop it except by doing one thing--and that's  eating. When I sit down with food, all I think about is how good it  tastes. Then, even when it stops tasting good, I still eat because it  puts me in a daze. I can stop thinking and just numb out. It's like  there's a fog around me."</em></p>
<p><strong>She Believes the Pain Will Never Go Away</strong></p>
<p>A person with an eating disorder often believes that painful feelings  will never go away on their own and nothing can be done to make them go  away.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"When people tell me the pain will pass or time will help, it makes me  laugh." said Carin, a 36-    year-old bulimic with a fifteen-year  history of the disorder. "These people can't be having the same feelings  I'm having. When I'm depressed, it's like going into a deep, dark pit  and you can't convince me there's a way out. There have been times in my  life I can stay in that feeling for months. And eating is the only  thing that distracts me. It is the only thing worth doing."</em></p>
<p>Carin's experience is a common one, particularly among bulimics. The  fear that pain will last forever and that there is no way out makes the  sufferer feel helpless and prevents her from finding solutions to  alleviate the discomfort.</p>
<p><strong>She Has Learned to Inhibit Feelings: "The Don'ts"</strong></p>
<p>We have all been raised with "don'ts": don't do this, and don't say that. Among the most common</p>
<p>"don'ts" in the personal histories of people with eating disorders is  don't be angry and don't be needy. Young girls who ultimately grow up to  struggle with eating disorders are often those who took to the classic  "good girl" model-sweet, charming, perfect little girls who are  unchallenging of authority, pleasing to others, and not aggressive.</p>
<p>Unlike their male counterparts, young girls are often encouraged to be  responsible caretakers, self-sufficient, and to watch out for other  people's feelings. As a result, they tend to keep a good deal of their  feelings, wishes, and needs private and secret--sometimes even secret  from themselves.</p>
<p>Angry, aggressive feelings are seen as bad and unacceptable rather than  the basis of healthy assertion. Because of this, young girls feel as  though they are "bad" for having these feelings.</p>
<p>Girls who become eating disordered have often grown up believing that  they should be undemanding of others. The good girl is the quiet, unseen  girl who learns not to show what is bothering her. She learns her  lessons well as we see in how she hides her emotions, even as her  disorder progresses. She learns to feel good about herself through  pleasing others, while her own "appetites" are suppressed. What other  people want seems justified; what she wants is a sign of selfishness.</p>
<h5>TROUBLESOME FEELINGS</h5>
<p>When feelings and needs are buffed, suppressed, or held back, they may  remain hidden or unexpressed but they do not go away. Underneath a  facade of control, optimism, or silence exist many complicated  experiences that cause the eating-disordered person much distress. The  following are some of the feelings and issues that cause the most common  problems:</p>
<p><strong>Needs for Approval/Needs for Nurturance:</strong></p>
<p>People with eating disorders tend to be more dependent than others. This  is true even when it does not look that way. The eating-disordered  woman relies more than most of us on other people's opinions and  reflections of her to determine how she feels about herself. This is why  eating-disordered people are terrified of criticism. Criticism not only  means that something they do or say is not approved of by others, but  it can be taken as a judgment about whether they are a good or bad  person.</p>
<p>As Lilly, a 25-year-old recovering anorexic, told us, "If someone didn't  like a dress I wore, it didn't just mean that they didn't like the  dress-it meant they didn't like me." She had not yet learned how to give  herself the support and validation she needed and thus she felt  dependent on others to give her the approval that she could not give  herself.</p>
<p>The eating-disordered person is not only in need of approval but inside  she is "hungry" for care and affection as well. Often, she has been so  attuned to everyone else's needs that her own have gotten overlooked.</p>
<p>Despite feelings of dependency, women with eating disorders do not want  to rely on or need other people. Feeling dependent or needy leaves them  feeling weak or like a failure, and is to be disowned and avoided at all  costs.</p>
<p>For some women, there is an intense fear that others will be overwhelmed  by their needs and leave them, or stop loving them, to avoid this, they  try to be perfect inside and out. The strain is enormous.</p>
<p>Amy, a 17-year-old bulimic, recently began to see how this fear affected her life.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I know it sounds crazy and isn't logical, but I genuinely feel that to be loved I must be perfect. If a guy doesn't like me I'm sure it's because I'm not thin enough, or  my hair isn't nice enough, or I'm not smart enough. Then I have to work  out, study harder, look better. It never occurs to me to think, 'Do I  like him?' All I can think about is that I'm not good enough."</em></p>
<p>The self-imposed demands of perfection and the tear of rejection that  eating-disordered people experience interfere with the development of  comfortable, intimate relationships. The dilemma is a difficult one. If  someone cannot reach out and allow herself to need someone else, to be  vulnerable to someone else, how can she really get to know that person  and let herself be known?</p>
<p>An experience we have heard often is that the only time someone with an  eating disorder lets someone else take care of her is when she is sick.  At other times, she does not feel she deserves the care and cannot allow  herself to be needy. In some cases, the inability to accept care is so  extreme that even when she is legitimately sick she will deny it.</p>
<p><strong>Feelings of Inadequacy:</strong></p>
<p>When someone grows up believing she should be stronger, more mature,  more capable than her years, she meets these expectations outwardly. But  her emotional, maturational development does not keep pace, and, in  fact, can be slowed up. This leads to the experience that one is  outwardly grown-up while an unacknowledged "little girl" remains hidden.</p>
<p>It is the little girl deep within the eating-disordered person who is  frightened, who suffers the feelings of inadequacy and fears being  overwhelmed. The competent facade and the exterior of independence make  it hard for the onlooker to believe how young, ungrownup, and incapable  an eating disordered person feels inside.</p>
<p>Abby, a 28-year-old recovering bulimic, talks about these feelings:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"At work I keep thinking that, at any minute, I'm going to be found out.  Everyone thinks I'm doing a good job but I feel like I'm getting away  with something and at the next step, the next task or  promotion, I'll blow it. I live in terror that they'll see through me,  see I really cannot do     the job. It's ludicrous; I do do the job--why  am I haunted by these fears? I feel schizophrenic- capable outside and  completely inept inside."</em></p>
<p>Tanya, a recovering anorexic, recalled how such feelings haunted her high school years.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I struggled so hard to feel I could handle it all. So instead of  getting 90 on the test, I had to get 100. The 90 would reveal how stupid  I really was. I was terrified I would fall apart. One slipup and all  would be lost. I'd be overwhelmed. I had terrible, terrible fantasies  about disintegrating, blowing up into nothing. The more I could control,  the more I could feel I was not going to disappear."</em></p>
<p><strong>Loneliness:</strong></p>
<p>Said Jim, a compulsive overeater,</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"When I'm at home alone, I get so lonely and it becomes a physical emptiness inside. Planning what to eat becomes an activity. It's like planning who I'll spend time with. Food definitely is my best friend."</em></p>
<p>Jim felt he was condemned to loneliness. His self-consciousness about  his weight kept him from taking part in activities and events. He  thought everyone would be as disgusted at the sight of him as he himself  was.</p>
<p>Sometimes this loneliness is like a feeling of emptiness, as though  there is nothing inside. Some people experience it as "a space . . . a  void."</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I feel so lost," Maddie, a 21-year-old, said of her evenings. "I'll be  fine as long as I'm busy, but as soon as I'm home alone, nothing seems  to satisfy me. I feel empty, lost, with this sense of vague uneasiness. I  try to read or work but I feel distracted, ungrounded. I want to be  'filled up.' I know my family is there and I can spend time with them,  but that doesn't do it for me. Sometimes drugs or alcohol seem to take  away that feeling. Other times, if I sleep with a guy, that might do it  too. But always, whether it's food, drugs, guys, or booze, it's always  temporary, leaving me feeling horrible about myself afterward, and empty  still."</em></p>
<p>Loneliness, sometimes felt as boredom, is a common experience of all eating-disordered people.</p>
<p>This feeling can occur despite the presence of other people.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"It is so peculiar," said Jerry, a 23-year-old bulimic during a group  therapy session, "how lonely I can feel even when I'm not alone. It's a  chilling feeling, like I'm cut off, all by myself in this world. It  scares me when I feel this."</em></p>
<p>These feelings are often intensified when people are, in fact, alone.  Some people experience being alone as though they were abandoned or left  behind. Thoughts of food or exercise can be company at such empty  times.</p>
<p><strong>Fears of People:</strong></p>
<p>As lonely as they are, eating-disordered people are often more  comfortable with food than they are with developing meaningful  relationships. Eating-disordered people have great difficulty trusting  people and relationships.</p>
<p>Some people fear losing themselves or their own identities in their  attempts to please another person. Others fear that the other person  will take over, dominating them and leaving them little room to be  themselves.</p>
<p>Jody, a 26-year-oid compulsive overeater, had trouble letting others get  near her for fear she would give up control just as she always had with  her mother.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"She was always doing things for me. It could be anything from changing  batteries in my radio to cleaning up my room. I guess she was just  taking care of me, but I felt like she was controlling everything and I  came to believe I couldn't take care of myself Now, I worry about this  whenever I get close to anyone else. t like being taken care of, but I  quickly feel controlled. I'm so confused about this that my  relationships are always in turmoil."</em></p>
<p>Many recovered compulsive overeaters have to contend with the fear of  getting close to people after they have lost weight. Sexual intimacy is  one aspect of emotional relatedness that can be avoided through binging  and weight gain.</p>
<p>Said Cindy, a 34-year-old compulsive overeater:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I was afraid to let a man near me. At 200 pounds, it wasn't much of a  worry. I wasn't even aware of my terror till I lost the weight and men  began to notice me. Then, what I had been avoiding all these years hit  me. What an eye-opener-even at 120 pounds I felt inadequate and  unworthy. So it wasn't the weight after all, it was me."</em></p>
<p><strong>Anger and Aggression:</strong></p>
<p>As we said earlier in this chapter, girls often feel differently about  their awn anger and aggression than boys. Anger and aggression are very  natural feelings that are the bases of healthy assertion.</p>
<p>But with girls who grow up to develop eating disorders, angry,  aggressive feelings are seen as bad and unacceptable. This often leads  to difficulty managing these feelings.</p>
<p>Suzanne, 15-years-old, put it this way:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I got the message loud and clear that my brothers are allowed to  disagree, fight, and be aggressive. Me? I'm supposed to be polite and  make sure I don't hurt anyone's feelings. I guess I learned that in  spades. As soon as I feel myself to be demanding or angry, I feel  terrible and selfish. With food, though, I can let this out. I tear at  if and eat with my hands. If anyone ever saw me, they wouldn't believe  I'm the same person. I'm in my own world and I don't care about anyone  else. If they saw me they'd know how selfish 1 can be, how angry, how I  don't really care about anyone; it would be a disaster. But at least  when I'm binging, no one gets hurt-except, I guess, me."</em></p>
<p>A child or teenager in conflict about her natural feelings of anger and  aggression grows up to be an adult with equal difficulties. Only the  context of her conflict broadens.</p>
<p>Jennifer, a 30-year-old corporate executive, describes how the  requirements of her work clash head-on with her discomfort asserting  herself:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"lt's bizarre-here I am in charge of a whole department and I'm  uncomfortable with the idea of offending anyone, making anyone mad at  me. Whenever I have to assert myself, which is often at this job, I  feel like I've done something wrong. Then, I go straight for the food.  Somehow when I'm eating, I can forget about how badly it all makes me  feel."</em></p>
<p>For the eating-disordered person who wants exclusively to be a nice,  pleasing person, the experience of anger and consequent aggression can  be very disruptive.</p>
<p>Some people manage that experience by dissociating the anger from  themselves.This means that they feel like they become someone else when  they binge.</p>
<p>Said Lettie, a 19-year-old bulimic:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"lt's like there is this horrible, binging monster inside who takes over  and I can't control it. When I'm binging, I'm like a different person.  I'll be nasty and not care about others. Usually, I'm a very nice  person-too nice. Usually, I'm the one who fakes care of everyone else  first and my own needs and feelings come last."</em></p>
<p>Other people have described this aspect of themselves as being "an  ogre," a "derelict," or "it's the dark side of me." One patient  suggested she was more in need of an exorcist than a therapist.</p>
<p>It is the "monster" that represents much that feels bad, out of control,  ugly, and distasteful about the sufferer. In the case of bulimics, this  monster is undone by purging; in the case of anorexia, defeated by  control. In either case, the feeling of being in a battle with oneself  is a part of daily life.</p>
<p><strong>Fears of Success:</strong></p>
<p>For many women in our society, the possibility of success and the  consequent feelings of competency can generate serious conflict. It can  go against the grain of the role of caretaker and puts women in a  position of authority which they may unconsciously undermine.  Eating-disordered women are particularly vulnerable to such conflict.  They feel guilty and undeserving when they taste success.</p>
<p>Lauren, 27-years-old, and a compulsive overeater, found that whenever  she did well at her job as an advertising executive, she would go home  and binge. As she explored her experience, it became clear that binging  was a way to sabotage her success.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"At first I feel terrific, in charge, successful, and then I begin to feel uneasy, guilty somehow. I feel like I'm defying the gods. This wasn't meant to be. I start to  worry what others will think of my achievements, and humiliation  creeps up on me. I'm sure they're going to be thinking I don't deserve this."</em></p>
<p>The binging not only numbed Lauren's uncomfortable feelings, but silently undid the success she would achieve at work.</p>
<p>Rachel, a 16-year-old bulimic, also struggled with the disquieting effects of achievement, but differently:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"When I do really well on an exam or with a project at school and the  teacher is really pleased, I  feel really good for a while. Then, I  begin to doubt it--my achievement and their opinion of it. I destroy it.  I think they are just telling me that I did well because they feel  sorry for me or because they are worried about me. I have to take it all  away. Sometimes, I think if I really  believed I did something well,  the pressure to keep it up would kill me."</em></p>
<p>At these times, Rachel would come home from school and binge and vomit to calm her uneasiness.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>"I'd go into panic thinking, 'Was I doing okay in school or not.'?' Part  of me believed I was doing    fine. Part of me doubted everything. It  was the worst feeling--like I didn't know who I was. When I ate, though,  all those feelings stopped and I could start over again-l could study,  or watch TV, or talk with my family and I'd be fine. Before that,  though, I felt like I was just 'losing it."'</em></p>
<p><strong>Anxiety:</strong></p>
<p>Anxiety is a signal. It can be a very useful tool, alerting us to  situations or events that make us feel vulnerable. And with this  awareness we can marshal our coping skills.</p>
<p>For example, if the idea of an upcoming exam makes us anxious, the  tension and uneasiness can be powerful motivators to study. Anxiety  provides the opportunity to prepare for the event by anticipating the  possible difficulties. Anxiety gives us the opportunity to act to  protect ourselves in potentially difficult situations.</p>
<p>People with eating disorders have difficulty using anxiety as a signal  to cope. Because they often feel themselves incapable of dealing with  stress, the anxiety becomes a signal of impending doom, a flag that  whatever is coming will be emotionally overwhelming. Anxiety is  something to be gotten rid of, not listened to. Therefore, the  experience of anxiety is often the trigger of a binge or of a tightening  of controls and intensified restriction (in the case of anorexia).  While these behaviors numb the anxiety, they do nothing to help the  person prepare for or protect against the actual cause of the anxiety.</p>
<h5>THE COMPLETE PICTURE</h5>
<p>Because the symptoms of binging, vomiting, exercising, or starving can  be so disruptive and frightening, it is easy to pay attention only to  those behaviors. To do so, however, misses the point. The overt symptoms  are just the tip of the iceberg. Beneath the surface lies a much larger  piece of the picture-a complicated and complex world of feelings and  experiences that are very much a part of the eating disorder. Both the  visible and invisible parts need to be acknowledged in order to  understand the disorders of bulimia, anorexia, and compulsive  overeating.</p>
<p>(For further explanation or understanding, please read other chapters in this book, Surviving anEating Disorder, by Siegel, Brishman, and Weinshel.)</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x24495" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17637" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
