<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x62107" Name="Decision Making" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Decision Making</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Decision Making</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Did you ever wish you didn't have to make decisions?&nbsp; Learning to make decisions and solve problems is an important part of our mortal existence.&nbsp; The way we use our God-given freedom to make decisions is of eternal significance.&nbsp;</p>
<h2>What Style of Decider are You?</h2>
<p>Eight styles of decision making were identified by researcher Lillian R. Dinklage.&nbsp; As you read through these styles, try to identify your own decision-making strategy.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Impulsive decider.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;One who takes the first alternative that is presented.&nbsp;<em> "Decide now; think later."</em></li>
<li><strong>Fatalistic decider.</strong> &nbsp;One who leaves the resolution of the decision up to the environment or fate.&nbsp; <em>"Whatever will be will be."</em></li>
<li><strong>Compliant decider. &nbsp;</strong>One who goes along with the plans of someone else for oneself rather than making one's own decision.&nbsp;<em> "If it's okay with you, it's okay with me."</em></li>
<li><strong>Delaying decider. &nbsp;</strong>One who delays thought and action on his problems until later.&nbsp; <em>"I'll think about that tomorrow."</em></li>
<li><strong>Agonizing decider. &nbsp;</strong>One who spends much time and thought in gathering data and analyzing alternatives, only to get lost amidst the accumulated date.&nbsp; The <em>"I can't make up my mind"</em> type.</li>
<li><strong>Intuitive decider. &nbsp;</strong>One who decides on what he or she feels but cannot verbalize it.&nbsp; This is the <em>"It feels right"</em> type.</li>
<li><strong>Paralytic decider. &nbsp;</strong>One who accepts the responsibility for his or her decision but is unable to do much toward approaching it.&nbsp; The <em>"I know I should, but I just can't get with it" </em>type.</li>
<li><strong>Planning decider. &nbsp;</strong>One whose strategy is based on rational approach with some balance between the cognitive and emotional.&nbsp; <em>"I am the captain of my fate; I am the master of my soul."</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Generally the Planning type of decision making is the most effective, but some people are able to effectively rely on the Intuitive type.</p>
<h2>Obstacles to Satisfying Decision Making</h2>
<p>Roadblocks to making satisfying decisions can originate either within ourselves or from outside ourselves.</p>
<h3>Internal Obstacles</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fear of making the wrong decision</li>
<li>Fear of taking a risk</li>
<li>Fear of failure</li>
<li>Fear of change</li>
<li>Lack of self-confidence</li>
<li>Ambivalence (that is, having conflicting feelings about the decision)</li>
<li>Procrastination (putting things off)</li>
<li>Stereotyping about self and other with respect to age, race, sex, etc. &nbsp;Example:&nbsp; I can't do that; I'm too young! (or, I'm too old, or I'm black, or I'm not smart enough, or I'm a woman, etc.)*</li>
</ul>
<h3>External Obstacles</h3>
<ul>
<li>Family expectations and responsibilities</li>
<li>Societal stereotyping with respect to age, race, sex, etc.* &nbsp;Example:&nbsp; You can't do that; you're too young! (or, you're too old, or you're black, or you're not smart enough, or you're a woman, etc.) &nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>*Note the difference between societal stereotyping and self-stereotyping.&nbsp; In one, others do it to you; and in the other, you do it to yourself.</p>
<h2>The Lord's Decision Making Instructions</h2>
<p>In Doctrine and Covenants 9:8-9, the Lord told Oliver Cowdery that he should:</p>
<ol>
<li>Study it out in your mind.</li>
<li>Ask the Lord if it is right.</li>
<li>If it is right, your bosom shall burn within you</li>
<li>If it is not right, you shall have a stupor of thought and forget the thing which is wrong.</li>
</ol>
<p>Guidance from the Holy Ghost doesn't always come in the form of a burning in the bosom or a stupor of thought.&nbsp; The Lord can guide us in other ways.</p>
<ul>
<li>The still, small voice (1 Nephi 17:45)</li>
<li>The voice of the Lord in the mind (Enos 1:10)</li>
<li>Peace in the mind (D&amp;C 6:23)</li>
<li>Received in the mind and in the heart (D&amp;C 8:2)</li>
<li>Mind becomes darkened (D&amp;C 10:2)</li>
<li>Enlighten the mind and fill the soul with joy (D&amp;C 11:13)</li>
<li>Line upon line, precept upon precept (2 Nephi 28:30)</li>
<li>Enter the heart with great force (Joseph Smith-History 1:12)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Studying It Out</h2>
<p>Depending on whether you are a planning decider or an intuitive decider, different decision-making processes will work better for you.</p>
<h3>Intuitive Decision Making</h3>
<p>Intuitive deciders often just need to ask a lot of questions in order to make decisions.&nbsp; The follow questions may be helpful in this process.</p>
<ol>
<li>What are the most important personal considerations about myself that will influence this decision?</li>
<li>What personal values do I possess that will influence this decision?</li>
<li>What experiences do I have to draw upon that will influence my understanding of how to proceed on this decision, and what does my experience tell me?&nbsp; What experience do others I know have that could help me in this decision?</li>
<li>What other resources can I use to help me with the decision?</li>
<li>What do the most significant people in my life think about how I am proceeding on this decision?</li>
<li>What possible solutions to the decision exist?&nbsp; Am I clear on all reasonable possibilities?</li>
<li>What would happen if I actually did solution a, b, c, d, . . .etc.?</li>
<li>What are my greatest strengths/weakness in decision making?</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bWGtjqv19ZA" title="Tevye" target="_blank">Tevye from <em>Fiddler on the Roof</em></a>, with his "on the other hand" strategy, is an example of an intuitive decider.</p>
<p>You can apply this strategy in the follow way:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Set up two chairs facing each other.&nbsp; Sit in one chair and discuss all the reasons for deciding in one way.&nbsp; Then move to the other chair and talk about the reasons for making a difference choice.&nbsp; Move back and forth between the two chairs, each time telling the "you" in the other chair why the option represented by this chair is the right one.&nbsp; Eventually you will find that this discussion helps you to clarify the issue and come to a conclusion that "feels right."</p>
<h3>Planning Decision Making</h3>
<p>Planning deciders work well with a step-by-step process, such as the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Identify and state the problem.</li>
<li>Collect data.&nbsp; Look at alternate ways of defining the problem.&nbsp; Redefine the problem if necessary, but defer making a judgment at this time.</li>
<li>Formulate all possible alternative solutions or decisions.&nbsp; Defer judgment</li>
<li>Evaluate tentative solutions or decisions in light of your self-evaluation (goals, values, abilities, interests, etc.).</li>
<li>Analyze the course of action in terms of risks and consequences of the tentative solutions or decisions.&nbsp; Consider all possible outcomes, with the advantages and disadvantages of each.</li>
<li>Decide on the most preferred solution/decision or strategy.</li>
<li>Counsel with the Lord.</li>
<li>Implement the decision.</li>
<li>Evaluate and revise if necessary.</li>
</ol>
<p>The following slideshow demonstrates a value-based decision-making matrix.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" height="400" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/14546601?hostedIn=slideshare&amp;page=upload" width="476"></iframe>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2>When Answers Don't Come</h2>
<p>Sometimes as we study out a question and pray about it, answers come but we do not recognize them until later.&nbsp; Sometimes it seems that we are not getting answers to our prayers.&nbsp; President Boyd K. Packer stated:&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Sometimes you may struggle with a problem and not get an answer.&nbsp; What could be wrong?&nbsp; It may be that you are not doing anything wrong.&nbsp; It may be that you have not done the right things long enough.&nbsp; Remember, you cannot force spiritual things.&nbsp; Sometimes we are confused simply because we won't take no for an answer. . . .&nbsp; Put difficult questions in the back of your minds and go about your lives.&nbsp; Ponder and pray quietly and persistently about them.&nbsp; The answer may not come as a lightning bolt.&nbsp; It may come as a little inspiration here and a little there, "line upon line, precept upon precept."&nbsp; Some answers will come from reading the scriptures, some from hearing speakers.&nbsp; And, occasionally, when it is important, some will come by very direct and powerful inspiration.&nbsp; The promptings will be clear and unmistakable.</p>
<p>Sometimes the Lord asks us to proceed without a clear confirmation.&nbsp; Elder Dallin H. Oaks said:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Even in decisions we think very important, we sometimes receive no answer to our prayers.&nbsp; This does not mean that our prayers have not been heard.&nbsp; It only means that we have prayed about a decision which, for one reason or another, we should make without guidance by revelation.&nbsp; If we do not receive guidance, we should act upon our own best judgment.</p>
<p>Elder John Groberg suggested that sometimes we will find the right path only by "eliminating the wrong decisions."&nbsp; He advised:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Because [the Lord] knows we need the growth, he generally does not point and say, "Open that door and go twelve yards in that direction; then turn right and go two miles. . . ."&nbsp; But if [a decision] is wrong, he will let us know -- we will feel it for sure.&nbsp; I am positive of that.&nbsp; So rather than saying, "I will not move until I have this burning in my heart," let us turn it around and say, "I will move unless I feel it is wrong; and if it is wrong, then I will not do it."&nbsp; By eliminating all of these wrong courses, very quickly you will find yourself going in the direction that you ought to be going.</p>
<p>It takes time and effort to develop righteous decision-making and problem-solving skills.&nbsp; We don't need to feel discouraged when things are not immediately clear to us.&nbsp; It's important to go forward in faith, praying and fasting for the influence of the Holy Ghost in our daily lives.</p>
<p>If we learn to "counsel with the Lord in all [our] doings," having faith that "he will direct [us] for good" (Alma 37:37), our spiritual discernment and wisdom will increase.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17637" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
