<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x62121" Name="Mindfulness and Meditation" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mindfulness and Meditation</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mindfulness and Meditation</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<script type="text/Javascript">
   function expand(num) {
      var hidden = document.getElementById("hidden" + num);
      var expand = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (expand.innerHTML == "+") {
         expand.innerHTML = "-";
         hidden.style.display = "block";
      } else {
         expand.innerHTML = "+";
         hidden.style.display = "none";
      }
   }

   function hover(type, num) {
      var hover = document.getElementById("plus" + num);

      if (type == 1) {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#999999";
      } else {
         hover.style.backgroundColor = "#007ebd";
      }
   }
</script>
<h3>Overview</h3>
<p>Walsh and Shapiro (2006) define meditation as a "family of  self-regulation practices that focus on training attention in order to  bring mental processes under greater voluntary control and thereby  foster general mental well-being and development and /or specific  capacities such as calm, clarity and concentration."  In meditation, one  learns to focus on a specific object in order to deepen ones' awareness  of the present moment, in a nonjudgmental way.  There are two major  branches of meditation practice that go hand in hand.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Concentration</strong> meditation involves focusing on a  specific object for an extended period of time to train the mind to  avoid wandering, and to become steady and rested.  Hence, concentration  meditation is a tool to achieve peace and stillness which prepare us to  hear the voice of the Spirit when He speaks.  "Be still, and know that I  am God" (Psalms 46:10).   That's why meditation has been found to help  with ailments such as anxiety, depression, insomnia, chronic pain, and  gastrointestinal distress.  Typical preferred meditation practices are  breathing meditation, listening meditation, mantra meditation, and  walking meditation, depending on personality, life style, preference,  and personal challenges.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>"Mindfulness </strong>meditation, in contrast, emphasizes  insight through the awareness of the present moment, a process of  self-awareness that non- judgmentally accepts everything that arises in  the mind and in the body" while focusing on an object, often the breath  (Hansen, Nielsen, &amp; Harris, 2008).  Hence, mindfulness meditation  enhances one's ability to see with clarity the kinds of thoughts and  feelings that arise in the mind with some degree of detachment.  Through  inward observing, meditators increase their opportunity for personal  transformation.  It is Nephi who cried: "I pray the God of my salvation  that he view me with his all-searching eye" (2 Nephi 9:44).  Mindfulness  meditation is often prescribed in psychotherapy and self -improvement  approaches.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h3>Concentration Meditation</h3>
<p>Click the (+) next to each topic to learn more.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td id="plus1" onclick="expand(1)" onmouseout="hover(2, 1)" onmouseover="hover(1, 1)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong> </strong><strong>1) Breathing Meditation-- the corner stone of all meditation practices </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden1" style="display: none;">
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>What is it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">All  you have to do is to notice and observe your breath; track how  your  breath moves in your body with each inhalation and exhalation.    With  experience you can learn to "send your breath" to different parts  of  the body.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Why use it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Use breathing meditation whenever you need to get centered, if stressed, fatigued, or overwhelmed.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>For how long?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Try 3 minutes at first, and work your way up to 20 minutes, eventually.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>How do I do it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Find  a quiet, relaxing environment.  It's especially important, when  you  are beginning, to avoid obvious distractions.  Turn off TV sets,   phones, or other noisy appliances.  If you play music, make sure it's   calm, repetitive and gentle, so as not to break your concentration.    Meditating outside can be conducive, as long as you don't sit near a   busy road or another source of loud noise.</p>
<p>You can  meditate on a chair, with your feet flat on the ground.  You  can also  sit on the ground using a cushion if the floor is  uncomfortable.  If  you choose to lie down, place a folded towel under  your knees for  support and keep your arms at your sides at a 45 degree  angle.  Be  careful that you are not so relaxed that you fall asleep.</p>
<p>Keep your eyes shut or you can also keep them half open gazing to the floor, one to two feet beyond your feet.</p>
<p>Let your  attention rest of the flow of your breath.  Listen to it, or  sense it  at the tip of your nostrils.  Beginners may find it easier to  count  their breaths.  Try counting your breath (on the in-breath or the   out-breath) from 1 to 10 and then, back from 10 to 1.</p>
<p>You will  soon notice that your mind wanders because you will lose  your  concentration.  If your mind starts wandering or bouncing from  thought  to thought, do not judge yourself for it, but simply and gently  bring  your attention back to your breath.  If you were counting, return  to 1  and start all over.  It's the practice of going back to the breath  that  trains your mind. In other words, don't judge yourself for getting   distracted; distractions provide you with the opportunity to build a   strong stable mind.</p>
<p>After  some time, begin to send your breath into areas of your body  that may  feel inert, dull, or usually "unreached" by the breath, such as  the  small of the back.  Don't force your breath, just breathe naturally  and  observe your breath.</p>
<p>At the end of your session, stretch and slowly move out of your meditation place.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus2" onclick="expand(2)" onmouseout="hover(2, 2)" onmouseover="hover(1, 2)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>2) Listening Meditation </strong> <strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden2" style="display: none;">
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>What is it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;">Listening  meditation invites you to engage with the sounds all around  you.   Instead of fighting noise, you work with it by listening to the   vibrations and the quality of the sounds rather than attending to the   information and meaning of the sounds.  Notice the energy of the sounds   and allow yourself to experience that energy with your senses.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Why use it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">When  you are in a crowded area, on the busy street or other public  place,  listening meditation comes handy.  When your mind is buzzing with   thoughts, you will welcome focusing outwardly for a few minutes.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>For how long?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Again start with 5 minutes and move up to 15-20 minutes, adding a couple of minutes at a time.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>How do I do it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Start  just like breathing meditation (see above).  Once centered,  open your  ears and tune your awareness to all the noises around you.   Take it all  in; don't favor one sound over another.  When distracted by a  thought  such as "that's a pretty bird's chirp", notice you've been  thinking and  gently return to just hearing the sounds around you.</p>
<p>After a few minutes, gently open your eyes and start moving.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus3" onclick="expand(3)" onmouseout="hover(2, 3)" onmouseover="hover(1, 3)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong><strong>3) Mantra Meditation </strong> <strong> </strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden3" style="display: none;">
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>What is it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">A  mantra is a word or set of words in an ancient language such as   Sanskrit (ancient language still spoken in India) that creates certain   vibration in the body when spoken.  The sound and vibration still the   mind and calm the body.   The words have deep spiritual meaning and have   been used for meditation for thousands of years by monks and others  who  practice it.  For example, an easy mantra to remember is "sat-nam"   (pronounce sut-nom) which literally means truth-identity.   In other   words, the intent of the mantra is to identify spiritual truth that   transcends doubt or fear.<strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Why use it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">You  can select the mantra you want to create a desired effect.  If  you  want more clarity in your mind and heart, then satnam is a good   choice.  If you want to feel more peaceful, the word "om" as a mantra   produces calming sensations in the body.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>For how long?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Start with a couple of minutes and gradually move up to 10 minutes.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>How do I do it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Start just like breathing meditation, getting focused and quiet the mind by focusing on the breath.</p>
<p>Take a  deep and long inhalation and as you exhale pronounce  out lout  and  slowly sat (sounding "suuuuuuut"); near the end of your exhalation,  say  nam (sounding "nommmm") and then take your next breath.  Pay   particularly attention to the vibrations the words create in your chest   cavity and elsewhere in your body.  Continue the pattern for a few   minutes.</p>
<p>When you  are ready to come out of the meditation exercise, take a  couple of  deep breaths and sense into the energy that flows in you as a  result of  your practice.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td id="plus4" onclick="expand(4)" onmouseout="hover(2, 4)" onmouseover="hover(1, 4)" style="font-weight: bold; padding: 0 5px 5px; cursor: pointer; background-color: #007ebd; color: #ffffff; border: 1px solid #ffffff;">+</td>
<td style="padding: 0pt 5px 5px;"><strong><strong>4)  Walking Meditation </strong> <strong> </strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td id="hidden4" style="display: none;">
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>What is it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Walking  meditation consists of slowing down the process of walking in  order to  increase awareness of each movement involved in the process of  walking  (lifting one foot, swinging it and putting it down).  Walking   meditation will help you develop more awareness in your daily life.    Indeed, actions are actually made of a series of sub-actions that come   together with intention.  This realization is important to understand   the connection between actions leading to other actions, and thoughts   leading to other thoughts.  When awareness develops so does agency and   therefore, personal choice and transformation.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Why use it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">When  you feel agitated or restless or too anxious for sitting  meditation,  walking is an effective way to channel the extra energy and  calm the  body.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>For how long?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Start  walking for five minutes, the equivalent of about 15 steps in  each  direction.  You can increase the time up to 15 minutes by  interspersing  walking with five minutes of sitting meditation.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>How do I do it?</strong></span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Find a private indoor or outdoor place away from onlookers that may distract you.</p>
<p>Stand in  a relaxed position, feet parallel, and arms along your sides  or hands  clasped in front of or behind you.  Look down about 6 to 8  feet ahead  of you as focusing directly on your feet may make you lose  your  balance.</p>
<p>The movement has three parts repeated twice:</p>
<ul dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li> First, inhale while lifting your right heel off the ground by keeping your right toes on the ground; exhale. </li>
<li> Second, inhale again as you lift your  right foot and swing it  forward and place the heel on the ground; exhale  as you place the rest  of the foot securely on the ground, transferring  the weight  and  balancing yourself. </li>
<li> Third, take a full breath (inhale and exhale). </li>
<li> Repeat with the left side. </li>
</ul>
<p>At first  it takes a bit of concentration and mental cues to remember  the  tempo.  But after some practice, you can really focus on your body   sensations only.  Go in one direction for 15 steps, and then turn around   and repeat.  The purpose of walking meditation is not to arrive   anywhere but to fully embrace the energy of the walking movement and   developing mindfulness of the present moment.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Mindfulness Meditation</h3>
<p>"Mindfulness meditation is not about achieving tranquility, rather  its aim is to see things as they really are and more clearly"  (Salzberg, 1995).  When practicing mindfulness meditation you simply pay  attention to the object of your meditation in the present moment,  non-judgmentally.  For example, when drinking a glass of water, bring  awareness to the way the water feels in your mouth from the moment it  touches your lips to the instant it hits your stomach and then  disperses.  The same kind of attending applies to internal processes  such as thoughts and feelings.</p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Why use it?</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Mindfulness is a form of brain training in that the brain slows down  to notice everything about a certain phenomenon or activity.  When it  comes to your thoughts and feelings, mindfulness helps you perceive more  accurately your experience, including your blind spots.  That's the  reason why mindfulness can lead to personal transformation.  Mindfulness  is also the gateway to enjoying the daily gifts of life more  abundantly, such as the sensations of the warm sun rays on your skin or  the song of a bird while taking a walk in the middle of a busy day.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">How long does it take?</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">To train your brain effectively, start with sitting five minutes  daily, and move your way up to 20 minutes.  You can also practice any  time, for a few minutes, as you mindfully eat, walk, do the dishes,  listen to someone speak, the goal being to live your life as mindfully  as possible, being present in the moment with your experience.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">How do I do it?</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 5px;">Start in the same posture as with breathing meditation, sitting or lying down.</p>
<p>Continue with a few moments of listening meditation.  Remember to not hold on to any sounds.</p>
<p>Focus on your breathing, in and out, without forcing anything.   You  may even want to internally say "in" and 'out".  That will be your home  base for the practice.</p>
<p>As you quietly breathe in and out, thoughts will start to pop up, or  feelings or physical sensations will manifest themselves.  Bring your full awareness to those, acknowledge their presence and then gently  return to home base, breathing in and out.  Do not rush the process.   Mindfulness is about acknowledging what is on your mind, not judging it  and letting it go by returning to the breath.</p>
<p>Traditionally, mindfulness meditation ends with an acknowledgment of  the positive energy created (acknowledgment, acceptance, and letting  go), and to dedicate it to others.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>:  Formal mindfulness meditation which  focuses on inner experience as described above should not be practiced  by individuals who are psychotic or losing/afraid of losing touch with  reality or by folks who have experienced trauma which still overwhelms  them, unless it is part of their treatment program.  Nevertheless, those  individuals can still practice daily moments of mindfulness of the  external world, especially when distressed.</p>
<p>There are many variations on meditation for different purposes, but you now have the basic instructions and rationale.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Extra tips</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>It is easy to lose track of time while meditating.  Some people find  it liberating to set a timer with a gentle ring (such as ringtones  found on cell phones).</li>
<li>Some people find it difficult to meditate immediately before  bedtime.  If you are sleepy, chances are you will fall asleep;  conversely, it may energize your mind, making it difficult to fall  asleep. </li>
<li>Don't expect immediate results.  Meditation works best when it is  done for its own sake, without becoming attached to the results.</li>
<li>Set aside time for daily practice.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<ul>
</ul>
<h3>Resources</h3>
<p>Hansen, K., Nielsen, D., &amp; Harris, M. (2008).  Meditation, Christian Values and Psychotherapy. <em>Journal for The Association of Mormon Counselors and Psychotherapists</em>, 32, 41-51.</p>
<p>Lefkowitz, F (2010). Meditation Made Easy. <em>Natural Health Magazine</em>, September/October 2010, pp 68-72.</p>
<p>Salzberg, S (1995). <em>Loving kindness: The revolutionary art of happiness</em>.  Boston: Shambhala Publications (Quoted in Natural Health Magazine, September 2010, p. 70).</p>
<p>Walsh, R. &amp; Shapiro, S.L. (2006).  The meeting of meditating  disciplines and western psychology: A mutually enriching dialogue. <em>American Psychologist</em>, 61 (3), 227-239.</p>
<p>Useful website:  <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/" target="_self">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/</a> -- access articles on meditation written by John Kabat-Zinn and Zindel Segal.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Spring 2011 Powerpoint Presentations</h3>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Presentation 1</span> An Invitation to Meditate (upload Powerpoint)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Presentation 2</span> How can Mindfulness and Meditation Help? (upload Powerpoint)</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Presentation 3</span> Mindfulness in the Service of a Christ-Centered Life (upload Powerpoint)<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Handout</span>:  Cultivating Christ-Like Qualities through Mindfulness Meditation (upload Handout)</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Suggested Readings</h3>
<p><em>Full Catastrophe Living</em> -- Jon Kabat-Zinn.</p>
<p><em>Mindfulness Based Cognitive Therapy for Depression</em> -- Zindel Segal.</p>
<p><em>Mindfulness in Plain English</em> - Bhante Henepola Gunaratana</p>
<p>Pubmed - Search engine for medical abstracts articles.  Access Jon Kabat-Zinn and Zindel Segal.</p>
<p><em>The Mindfulness Solution</em> - Ronald D. Siegel</p>
<p><em>Turning the Mind into an Ally</em> - Sakyong Mipham</p>
<p><em>When Things Fall Apart</em> -- Pema Chodron</p>
<p><em>Wherever You Go, There You Are</em> - Jon Kabat- Zinn.</p>
<p>Useful website: <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/" target="_self">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/</a> -- Access articles on meditation written by John Kabat-Zinn and Zindel Segal.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17637" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
