<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x62269" Name="Introduction" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Introduction</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Introduction</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Purpose</strong></span><em> </em></p>
<p>The Dean of Students Review Council is an educational process. The council is designed to protect the mission of the university and provide the reported student with fair process.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Administrative Responsibility </strong><em></em></span></p>
<p>The Dean of Students, or their designee, serves as the chair of the Dean of Students Review Council</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>University Employees</strong></span></p>
<p>These review procedures do not address sanctions of university employees.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Violations of Law</strong><em> </em></span></p>
<p>Students in the university community have the rights and obligations of citizenship. They are responsible for their personal conduct under applicable federal, state and local law, being neither excused nor protected from civil and criminal sanctions by their status as students.</p>
<p>Disciplinary proceedings may be carried out prior to, simultaneously with, or following civil or criminal proceedings off campus at the discretion of the <a href="x43013.xml">Student Honor Office</a>. Disciplinary sanctions shall not be subject to change because criminal charges were dismissed, reduced, or resolved in favor of or against the student.</p>
<p>When a student is charged by federal, state or local authorities with a violation of law, the university will not request nor agree to special consideration for that individual because of his or her status as a student. If the alleged offense is also being investigated by the Student Honor Office, the university may advise off-campus authorities of the existence of university standards. The university will cooperate with law enforcement and other agencies. Individual students and other members of the university community, acting in their personal capacities, remain free to interact with governmental representatives as they deem appropriate.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Terms and Definitions</strong><em> </em></span></p>
<p>The following terms or definitions are used in the <a href="x43539.xml">Dean of Students Review Procedures</a>. The list is not all inclusive or comprehensive but lists those most commonly used.</p>
<ol>
<li>The terms "university," "BYU-Idaho," and "BYU-I" mean Brigham Young University-Idaho.</li>
<li>The term "student" includes all persons taking courses at or through the university specifically including internships, students off-track, and persons taking continuing education and internet courses, whether the person is full-time or part-time, matriculating toward a degree or certificate or non matriculating. Individuals who withdraw or who are not enrolled for a particular semester but who have a continuing relationship with the university or who have been notified of their acceptance for admission are considered "students" for purposes of this document, as are individuals who are living in a student approved housing unit who meet the above criteria even though they may not be currently enrolled. The <a href="x42220.xml">CES Honor Code</a>, the principles and standards of <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.lds.org/youth/for-the-strength-of-youth?lang=eng">For the Strength of Youth</a></span>, <a href="x16319.xml">Apartment Living Standards</a>, and university policy apply both on and off campus.</li>
<li>The term "university official" includes any person employed by the university, performing assigned administrative or professional responsibilities.</li>
<li>The term "member of the university community" includes any person who is a student, faculty, staff, administrator, or any other person employed by the university.</li>
<li>The term "university premises" includes all lands, buildings, facilities, and other property in the possession of or owned, used or controlled by the university including adjacent streets and sidewalks.</li>
<li>The term "Dean of Students Council" means any person or persons authorized by the President of the university or <a href="x42341.xml">Dean of Students</a> to hear a review of a disciplinary sanction.</li>
<li>The term "Student Honor Office" in this document means the Director of the Student Honor Office, Administrators, and any persons in the Student Honor Office authorized by the President of the university to impose disciplinary sanctions upon any student(s).</li>
<li>The term "shall" is used in the imperative sense.</li>
<li>The term "may" is used in the permissive sense.</li>
<li>The term "class day" means any day that orientation, class days, reading days, or exams are scheduled.</li>
<li>The term "policy" is defined as the written regulations of the university as found in, but not limited to, the <em>CES Honor Code</em>, <em>For the Strength of Youth</em>, <em>Apartment Living Standards</em>, and statements of policy published by the university.</li>
<li>The term "complainant" means any person who submits information about an infraction of university standards or relevant university policies when a student believes that they have been the victims of another student's misconduct, that student/victim will have the same rights under these procedures as those rights which are accorded the "accused student" or "alleged perpetrator".</li>
<li>
<div align="left">The terms "accused student" or "alleged perpetrator" means any student or individual accused of violating university standards or relevant university policies.</div>
</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43094" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x42756" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
