<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x62273" Name="Jurisdiction" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Jurisdiction</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Jurisdiction</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong></strong>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Proscribed Conduct</span></strong></p>
<p><strong><em></em></strong><em></em>Generally, BYU-Idaho jurisdiction and discipline shall encompass behavior committed by any person who has been admitted to the university and shall specifically include those whose enrollment is pending in an upcoming semester, who is off-track, who is on holiday, when the university is not in session or who is at home. Any behavior which may adversely affect the interests of the university or which violates the student's personal commitment to the <a href="x42220.xml">CES Honor Code</a>, the principles and standards of <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><a href="https://www.lds.org/youth/for-the-strength-of-youth?lang=eng">For the Strength of Youth</a></em></span>, the <a href="x16319.xml">Apartment Living Standards</a> or other university policies may be the cause for review and discipline by the university.</p>
<p>Students will be responsible for their conduct at all times and in all places, both on and off campus, while they are students of BYU-Idaho.<strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Conduct Rules and Regulations</strong></span></p>
<p>Any student found to have committed or to have attempted, aided, abetted, assisted, or incited to commit the following misconduct may be subject to separation from the university:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. Violation of the CES Honor Code, the principles and standards of <em>For the Strength of Youth</em>, Apartment Living Standards, and university policy.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. Acts of dishonesty, including but not limited to the following:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">a. Cheating, plagiarism or other forms of academic dishonesty.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">b. Knowingly furnishing false information to any university official, faculty member, office, or department.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">c. Forgery, alteration or misuse of any university document, record or instrument of identification.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">d. Tampering with the election of any university recognized student organization.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. Disruption or obstruction of teaching, administration, disciplinary proceedings, or other university activities, programs or functions, including its public service functions on or off campus.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">4. Physical abuse, verbal abuse, threats, intimidation, harassment, stalking (to follow or otherwise make unwanted contact with a person repeatedly), coercion and/or other conduct which threaten or endanger the health or safety of any person, the interference with another student's academic performance, or any behaviors as outlined in the university Disruptive Behavior Policy.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">5. Inappropriate conduct relating to a person's gender which creates an intimidating, hostile, or offensive campus, educational, or working environment for another person. This includes unwanted, unwelcome, inappropriate, or irrelevant sexual or gender-based activities or comments.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">6. Attempted or actual theft of or damage to property of the university or property of a member of the university community, or other personal or public property.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">7. Hazing, or offensive conduct which endangers the mental, emotional, or physical health or safety of any student, including any activity which would degrade, humiliate, and embarrass a person or behavior which defaces, destroys or removes public or private property for any purpose that is inappropriate. The express or implied consent of the victim will not be a defense. Apathy or acquiescence to these behaviors are not acceptable neutral acts but may be treated as a violation of these rules.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">8. Failure to comply with directions of university officials or law enforcement officers acting in performance of their duties and/or failure to identify oneself to these persons when requested to do so.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">9. Unauthorized possession, duplication or use of keys to university premises or unauthorized entry to or use of premises.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">10. Violation of any university policy, rule or regulation published in hard copy or electronically by the university.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">11. Violation of federal, state or local law at any time or place.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">12. Use, possession or distribution of narcotic or other controlled substances except as expressly permitted by law.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">13. Use, possession or distribution of alcoholic beverages.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">14. Illegal or unauthorized possession of firearms, explosives, other weapons, or dangerous chemicals (including the preparation or detonation of dry ice bombs) on university premises or in or around approved student housing, or use of any such item, even if legally possessed, in a manner that harms, threatens or causes fear to others.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">15. The inappropriate activation of any emergency warning equipment or the false reporting of any emergency, the removal, damage or tampering with fire safety or other emergency warning equipment, or the failure to evacuate a university building or facility when a fire alarm is sounded.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">16. Participation in any campus demonstration which disrupts the normal operations of the university and infringes on the rights of other members of the university community; leading to or inciting others to disrupt scheduled and/or normal activities within any campus building or area; intentional obstruction which unreasonably interferes with freedom of movement, either pedestrian or vehicular, on campus.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">17. Obstruction of the free flow of pedestrian or vehicular traffic on university premises or at university sponsored or supervised functions.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">18. Conduct which is disorderly, lewd, or indecent; constitutes a breach of the peace; or aiding, abetting or procuring another person to breach the peace on university premises or at functions sponsored by or participated in by members of the university community.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">19. Theft or other abuse of computer time or violations of the university Computer Security Policy, including but not limited to:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">a. Unauthorized entry into any file, to use, read, or change the contents, or for any other purpose.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">b. Unauthorized transfer of any file.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">c. Unauthorized use of another individual's identification, password or computer privileges.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">d. Use of computer facilities to interfere with the work of another student, faculty member or university official.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">e. Use of computer facilities to send obscene, abusive or inappropriate messages.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">f. Use of computer facilities to interfere with normal operation of the university network or computer system.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">20. Misuse of the <a href="x43539.xml">Dean of Students Review Procedures</a>, including but not limited to:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">a. Falsification, distortion or misrepresentation of information before the <a href="x43601.xml">Dean of Students Review Council</a>, <a href="x43013.xml">Student Honor Office</a> or any other university administrator or employee.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">b. Disruption or interference with the orderly conduct of a council meeting.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">c. Instituting a council proceeding or Student Honor Office investigation knowingly without cause.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">d. Attempting to discourage an individual's proper participation in or use of the Student Honor Office or the Dean of Students Review Council.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">e. Attempting to influence the impartiality of a member of the Dean of Students Review Council prior to, and/or during the course of a council proceeding.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">f. Harassment (verbal or physical) and/or intimidation of a member of the council prior to, during and/or after a proceeding.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">g. Failure to comply with the sanction(s) imposed under the Dean of Students Review Procedures.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">h. Influencing or attempting to influence another person to commit any misuse of the Dean of Students Review Procedures.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">21. Possession of more than one BYU-Idaho student ID card, lending or using another student's card, misuse of student ID number, or the impersonation or unauthorized representation of the university.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Academic Standards</strong></span><em> </em></p>
<p>Academic misconduct may constitute grounds for university discipline, including separation from the university.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Non students</strong></span><em> </em></p>
<p>The Dean of Students Review Council has no jurisdiction to sanction non students. However, information regarding the misconduct of non students may be provided to the Student Honor Office and/or the Director of Admissions if it is relevant to the decisions regarding future admission.</p>
<br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43094" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x42756" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
