<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x62280" Name="Dean of Students Review Council" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dean of Students Review Council</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Dean of Students Review Council</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em> </em></strong><strong><em></em></strong><em></em></p>
<p>1. Dean of Students Review Council is held in a confidential setting in the interests of the student and the university. Individuals providing information or statements shall be allowed to participate at the discretion of the council and will be invited into the meeting at an appropriate time.</p>
<p>2. If a council member's association with a student appearing before the council is such that they are personally acquainted with the student or is unable to render a fair and impartial decision, the member has a duty to disqualify himself/herself. Any member of the council may be disqualified if the student shows that a bias exists on the part of that member toward the student.</p>
<p>3. A council meeting involving more than one student involved in the same incident, may be conducted either separately or jointly at the discretion of the <a href="x42341.xml">Dean of Students</a> or his/her designee.</p>
<p>4. The student may, at any time, request a change of schedule to provide for a more adequate presentation of his/her case. Such requests will be considered by the Dean of Students or his/her designee. If there appears to be a compelling reason to postpone the review, the Dean may cancel or reschedule the review.</p>
<p>5. The Dean of Students or his/her designee may accommodate concerns for personal safety, well-being and/or fears of confrontation of the complainant, accused student and/or other witness during the review by providing separate facilities, by using a visual screen, and/or by permitting participation by telephone, videophone, closed circuit television, video conferencing, videotape, audio tape, written statement, or other means as determined by the Dean.</p>
<p>6. The council shall invite and encourage the student to respond to the allegations. The student may present facts in his/her own behalf, request assistance in getting other persons having first-hand knowledge of the matter at issue to attend the council meeting, ask questions of those making statements or providing information to the council and offer his/her own statement and recommendation for disposition of the matter. No character witnesses or statements will be allowed.  The council may request persons having first-hand knowledge to appear or offer written statements if the student is, through his/her own efforts, unable to secure their attendance.</p>
<p>7. The student shall not be required to make any statement. If he/she should choose to make a statement, he/she may refuse at any point to answer any question.</p>
<p>8. The student may be accompanied to the meeting by an advisor of his/her choice. The advisor may be a faculty or staff member, fellow student, parent, or other person so long as the availability of the advisor does not substantially hamper the timeliness of the council meeting. The advisor may not be an attorney unless he or she is a parent of the student. The university may not be represented by legal counsel, but legal counsel for the BYU-Idaho Office of the General Counsel may be consulted by the Dean on procedural issues. The advisor may not represent the student during the meeting and will not be permitted to address the council.<sup> </sup>The student will be expected to speak for himself/herself at all times. The advisor may be asked to leave the council meeting if he/she becomes disruptive or violates this policy.</p>
<p>9. The secretary assigned to the council will be responsible for taking brief, summary minutes of the meeting. These minutes will be the official record of the proceedings. No verbatim recording of the meeting will be made.</p>
<p>10. Witnesses may be invited to address the council during the meeting to present pertinent information and answer questions from council members. The accused student may direct questions to the witness through a member of the council. This will facilitate the process and preserve the educational tone of the review process and avoid the creation of an adversarial environment.</p>
<p>11. Pertinent records, exhibits and written statements may be accepted as information for consideration by the council.</p>
<p>12. The Dean of Students or his/her designee has the responsibility to ensure that appropriate procedures are observed during the review process. The Dean or his/her designee should: (a) make an initial response to any procedural questions that arise, (b) alert the council to the procedural implications of any action which they are considering, (c) identify any inconsistencies between the <a href="x43539.xml">Dean of Students Review proceedings</a> and the actions of the council or its individual members at any point in the proceedings, and (d) in situations where the Dean feels it is desirable or the council instructs him/her to seek further guidance, seek out and present to the council additional relevant information which may be available from the experience of previous councils or from other sources. The Dean of Students and/or the University Legal Counsel have the authority to alter these procedures provided the substituted procedures are fair to the student.</p>
<p>13. If a student does not appear before the Council at the appointed time, the decision of the <a href="x43013.xml">Student Honor Office</a> will stand, provided the Council is satisfied that the student has been given adequate notice.</p>
14. Formal rules of process, procedure and/or technical rules of evidence, such as are applied in criminal or civil court, are not used in Dean of Students Review Council proceedings.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x43094" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x42756" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
