<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x62353" Name="Frequently Asked Questions" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Frequently Asked Questions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Have a question. Find your answer here.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="#StudentTickets">I am a student, how many tickets can I purchase?</a></li>
<li><a href="#SmokeHaze">Will there be theatrical smoke and haze at this event?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Parking">Is parking available for graduation and other events?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Campus Map">How do I find the building on campus that I need?</a></li>
<li><a href="#SeatingChart">How can I look at seating for the event?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Hotels">What hotel accommodations are available in Rexburg?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Wheelchair">How do I obtain a wheelchair?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Pictures">When can I take pictures?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Doors">What time do the doors open?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Child">Does my small child need a ticket?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Refunds">Can I exchange my tickets for another show or receive a refund for any tickets I do not use?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Food">Can I bring food or drink to events?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Late">What happens if I arrive late to a performance?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Program">What about program content?</a></li>
<li><a href="#WillCall">What is Will Call?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Print">What is Print @ Home?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Copy">What if I print more than one copy of my Print @ Home ticket or a photocopy is made?</a></li>
<li><a href="#notprint">Why isn't Print @ Home Available for all events?</a></li>
<li><a href="#orderconfirmation">How do I know my order went through and that I have tickets?</a></li>
<li><a href="#TheaterEtiquette">What is proper "theater etiquette" when attending an event?</a></li>
<li><a href="#Dress">How do I dress for this performance?</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p><strong> <br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="StudentTickets"></a><span style="font-size: 14.190000000000001pt; line-height: 1.2em;">I am a student, how many tickets can I purchase?</span></h2>
<p>Students are allowed to purchase two tickets at the student price if the other ticket is for a BYU-I student. If not, the non-student ticket will be charged at the community patron price.</p>
<h2><a name="SmokeHaze"></a>Will there be theatrical smoke and haze at this event?</h2>
<p>Almost all events have theatrical smoke and haze. If you have special concerns, please contact the Ticket Office at (208) 496-3170 before purchasing tickets for the event.</p>
<h2><a name="Parking"></a>Is parking available for graduation and other events?</h2>
<p>Click on the link below for parking guidelines: <a href="http://www.byui.edu/driveorwalk/interactive_map.htm">http://www.byui.edu/driveorwalk/interactive_map.htm</a> .</p>
<p>The following services have been made available for events at the BYU-Idaho Center:</p>
<p>-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Handicap parking in the lot south of the building<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Three drop-off zones adjacent to the facility<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Parking attendants directing visitors to the closest available spaces</p>
<h2><a name="Campus Map"></a>How do I find the building on campus that I need?</h2>
<p>Campus map. <a href="http://www.byui.edu/maps/">http://www.byui.edu/maps/</a></p>
<h2><a name="SeatingChart"></a>How can I look at seating for the event?</h2>
<p>Click on the links to the following locations seating charts:</p>
<p><a href="Documents/event-services/Maps/BYU-Idaho Center.jpg">BYU-Idaho Center</a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/event-services/Maps/Stadium.pdf">BYU-Idaho Stadium</a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/event-services/Maps/Barrus.pdf">Eliza R. Snow Barrus Concert Hall</a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/event-services/Maps/hart.pdf">John W. Hart Auditorium</a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/event-services/Maps/Kirkham.pdf">Oscar A. Kirkham Auditorium</a></p>
<p><a href="Documents/event-services/Maps/Snow.pdf">Eliza R. Snow Drama&nbsp;Theater</a></p>
<h2><a name="Hotels"></a>What hotel accommodations are available in Rexburg?</h2>
<p>A listing of local accommodations can be found on the <a href="http://www.rexcc.com/">Rexburg Chamber of Commerce</a> website.</p>
<h2><a name="Wheelchair"></a>How do I obtain a wheelchair?</h2>
<p>Wheelchairs are only available for temporary use in the BYU-Idaho Center. Wheelchairs can be acquired by going to the Ticket Office in the BYU-Idaho Center. They are to be used for transportation of persons with mobility impairments to assist them to their seating area. Patrons should bring their own wheelchair if they need transportation from their vehicle to the facility.</p>
<p>It is important to notify the Ticket Office at the time of purchase of your access needs including seating, assistive listening, or other needs. Each individual with ADA seating accommodations may have a maximum of two companions in the same area.</p>
<h2><a name="Pictures"></a>When can I take pictures?</h2>
<p>The camera policy for most events is NO picture taking or audio or video recording. If you have questions, contact the Ticket Office at the event location.</p>
<h2><a name="Doors"></a>What time do the doors open?</h2>
<p>Doors open 30 minutes before showtime except in the BYU-Idaho Center where doors open one hour before the start of the event.</p>
<h2><a name="Child"></a>Does my small child need a ticket?</h2>
<p>All patrons entering the building are required to have a ticket. Children under two years of age generally do not need a ticket, however, most events at BYU-Idaho have an age restriction. Many performances are not recommended for children under the age of six. Please check with the Ticket Office or the ticket website if you are unsure if a performance is appropriate for younger audience members.</p>
<h2><a name="Refunds"></a>Can I exchange my tickets for another show or receive a refund for any tickets I do not use?</h2>
<p>There are no refunds given. Tickets may be exchanged for the same event shown on multiple nights. Before purchasing tickets, carefully review your event and seat selection for correctness.</p>
<h2><a name="Food"></a>Can I bring food or drink to events?</h2>
<p>No food or drinks are allowed into most campus events.</p>
<h2><a name="Late"></a>What happens if I arrive late to a performance?</h2>
<p>For most events you may lose your seating if you are not in your seat 10 minutes before the start of the performance. Those tickets are released to those waiting in the stand-by line. <strong>Theatre events have a no-admittance policy once the play has begun</strong>. For music events you will be let in when there is a break in the music.</p>
<p>Seating is not released in the BYU-Idaho Center or the Hart Auditorium.</p>
<p>Because parking can be difficult to find in close to curtain time, we encourage you to arrive at least 30 minutes prior to an event to ensure that you are in your seat at the proper time.</p>
<h2><a name="Program"></a>What about program content?</h2>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Ticket Office does not sponsor any events. The Ticket Office is solely a service operation for other programming organizations. Although the Ticket Office tries to be knowledgeable about all the events for which it provides ticketing services, questions or concerns about specific program content or selection should be directed to the sponsoring organization.</p>
<h2><a name="WillCall"></a>What Is Will Call?</h2>
<p>Will Call is when your tickets are waiting for you at the Ticket Office. The person whose name is on the order is the only one allowed to pick up those tickets unless another name was given at the time of order.</p>
<h2><a name="Print"></a>What is Print @ Home?<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong></h2>
<p>Print @ Home is a new delivery option available on some events. &nbsp;When ordering, you have the option to pick your delivery method. &nbsp;These tickets can be printed on your home printer. Tickets will be scanned at the event for verification.</p>
<h2><a name="Copy"></a>What if I print more than one copy of my Print @ Home ticket or a photocopy is made?<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong></h2>
<p>Only the first scan of the barcode on your ticket will be allowed entry. Printing additional tickets for event into an event is illegal and subject to prosecution.</p>
<h2><a name="notprint"></a>Why isn't Print @ Home available for all events?<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong></h2>
<p>Only venues with the appropriate scanning equipment can offer Print @ Home.</p>
<h2><a name="orderconfirmation"></a>How do I know my order went through and that I have tickets?<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong></h2>
<p>Once you receive your email conformation, you have your tickets.</p>
<h2><a name="TheaterEtiquette"></a>What is proper "theater etiquette" when attending an event?</h2>
<p>We wish for every guest to have a wonderful, unforgettable experience during their visit. To provide that assurance, all noise making devices (cell phones, pagers, wristwatch alarms) are to be turned off. Guests should remain seated during all productions while keeping chatter to a very minimal level.</p>
<p>Candy wrappers and other noises made by food or beverage consumption can also be a distraction, so we ask that you keep this in mind during the show.</p>
<h2><img name="Dress" />How do I dress for this performance?</h2>
<p>Dress for events is specified on the tickets for the event. There are two main types of dress, these are Event and Classroom.</p>
<h4>Classroom dress</h4>
<p>Follow the guides for ordinary student dress and grooming which can be found at http://www2.byui.edu/StudentHonor/UniversityStandards.htm#dress-and-grooming</p>
<h4>Event Dress</h4>
<p>Men should wear:</p>
<p>Dress pants or suit with a collared shirt, tie, and dress shoes.</p>
<p>Women should wear:</p>
<p>Modest dress or skirt, a blouse, and dress shoes.</p>
<p>Denim is not appropriate for either gender to wear nor are flip flops. Sweaters or "sweat shirts" do not count as concert dress.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28892" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
