<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_FullWidth ID="x62514" Name="FAQ" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ</Abstract><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Frequently Asked Questions</h4>
<hr style="color: #fff; background-color: #fff; border: 1px dotted gray; border-style: none none dotted;" />
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">We have compiled a list of your most frequently asked questions and provided answers for your quick reference.  Please click on either a subject or a specific question and you will be taken to that subject/question and you may review its explanation; however, if you don’t see an answer to a question you have, please fill out this <a href="x28373.xml" title="My Account Questions">form</a>, and we'll contact you as soon as possible with an answer to your question.</p>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: none;">
<li>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a href="#pa">Personal Account</a></h4>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: none;">
<li><a href="#pa1">How can I access my personal account online?</a></li>
<li><a href="#pa2">How do I find out more details about a charge on my personal account?</a></li>
<li><a href="#pa3">How do I know a payment or how my financial aid was applied to my Personal Account?</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a href="#tf">Tuition and Fees</a></h4>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: none;">
<li><a href="#tf1">When are tuition and fees due?</a></li>
<li><a href="#tf2">What happens if I don’t pay my tuition and fees by the deadline?</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a href="#rf">Refunds</a></h4>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: none;">
<li><a href="#rf1"> I was enrolled as a full-time student then dropped some classes after the registration deadline, causing me to become a part-time student...how come I didn't receive a refund?</a></li>
<li><a href="#rf2">Can I receive a tuition refund if I was registered for first block and full semester classes, but withdrew from school after the registration deadline?</a></li>
<li><a href="#rf3">Do I get a refund for dropped second block classes if those classes have not yet started?</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<br /> <br />
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="pa">Personal Account</a></h4>
<hr style="color: #fff; background-color: #fff; border: 1px dotted gray; border-style: none none dotted;" />
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="pa1">How can I access my Personal Account online?</a></strong></p>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">
<li>Go online to my.byui.edu, or click on the my.byui.edu link on the BYU-I homepage</li>
<li>Login using your BYU-Idaho username and password</li>
<li>Click on the ‘Finances’ tab</li>
<li>Click on the ‘View Account Summary’ link</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="pa2">How do I find out more details about a charge on my Personal Account?</a></strong><br /> If you don't understand a charge related to tuition or fees, please contact the Bursar's Office and speak to a Student Accounts Specialist.  If you don't understand a charge from the University Store, Housing, Student Health Center, or other miscellaneous charges, please contact the specific campus department where the charge originated.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="pa3">How do I know how a payment or how my financial aid was applied to my Personal Account?</a></strong><br /> If you need further information about how a payment or financial aid were applied to outstanding debts, please contact the Bursar's Office and speak to a Student Accounts Specialist.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="tf">Tuition and Fees</a></h4>
<hr style="color: #fff; background-color: #fff; border: 1px dotted gray; border-style: none none dotted;" />
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="tf1">When are tuition and fees due?</a></strong><br /> Tuition and fees are due one week after the beginning of the semester, if you are enrolled in any full semester class. If you are only registered for First Block, Second Block, or Summer Session classes, tuition and fees are due one week after the beginning of classes for that block or session.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="tf2">What happens if I don’t pay my tuition and fees by the deadline?</a></strong></p>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">
<li>A one-time late charge of 5% plus a service charge of 1% per month of any unpaid balance will be assessed.</li>
<li>A financial hold will be placed on your account, prohibiting class registration for any subsequent semester, or your ability to earn an official transcript.</li>
<li>If the debt continues to be unpaid, collection activities will commence, up to and including collection by a third-party collection agency (which may result in reporting to credit bureaus).</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="rf">Refunds</a></h4>
<hr style="color: #fff; background-color: #fff; border: 1px dotted gray; border-style: none none dotted;" />
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="rf1">I was enrolled as a full-time student, then dropped some classes after the registration deadline, causing me to become a part-time student…how come I didn’t receive a refund?</a></strong><br /> No refunds for tuition and fees are given for dropped classes after the registration deadline unless you completely withdraw from school, and any refund is pro-rated based upon the number of days attended up to 60% of the block or semester.  After the 60% point of a block or semester, there is no refund for withdrawal from school.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="rf2">Can I receive a tuition refund if I was registered for first block and full semester classes, but withdrew from school after the registration deadline?</a></strong><br /> You may receive a pro-rated refund for the full semester classes dropped after the registration deadline upon withdrawal.  Any refund for the first block classes would depend on whether you withdrew prior to the "W" date for that block.  Please contact a Student Accounts Specialist for guidance in your specific situation.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong><a id="rf3">Do I get a refund for dropped second block classes if those classes have not yet started?</a></strong><br /> Yes.  You will receive a refund for the second block classes if the second block classes have not started or the Registration Deadline has not passed, even if you have full semester classes.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_FullWidth>
