<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_FullWidth ID="x62616" Name="Local/Regional Transportation" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Local/Regional Transportation</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Local/Regional Transportation</Abstract><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">The Bulletin Board on the University website includes a ride selection, enabling enrolled students to list their needs for a driver or passengers.  Authentication required.  Additional helpful information when planning for travel includes:</p>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle;">
<li>Local Chambers of Commerce (including links to motel accommodations)</li>
<li>Maps of driving directions</li>
<li>Travel tips</li>
</ul>
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Flights</h5>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">The closest commercial airport is Idaho Falls, 25 miles south of Rexburg.  SkyWest, a Delta connection, and Horizon Air, an Alaskan Airlines connection, are the major providers.  Salt Lake City, about 260 miles south of Rexburg, has the closest international airport.</p>
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Commercial Ground Transportation</h5>
<table border="1" frame="border" rules="all" style="border: 1px solid #000000;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td>Contact Information</td>
<td>Local/Rexburg</td>
<td>Idaho Falls</td>
<td>Salt Lake City</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>TRPTA</td>
<td>356-9033 or 522-2278 or 529-1489</td>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td align="center"><strong>X</strong></td>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Greyhound</td>
<td>1-800-454-2487</td>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td align="center"><strong>X</strong></td>
<td align="center"><strong>X</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Salt Lake Express</td>
<td><a href="http://www.saltlakeexpress.com">www.saltlakeexpress.com</a>/656-8824 or 1-800-356-9796</td>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td align="center"><strong>X</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br />
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Taxi Cab Companies</h5>
<table border="1" frame="border" rules="all" style="border: 1px solid #000000; width: 40%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 30%;">Easy Way Taxi</td>
<td style="width: 10%;">525-8344</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 30%;">Safe Ride Taxi</td>
<td style="width: 10%;">206-7592</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 30%;">SOS Transportation, Inc.</td>
<td style="width: 10%;">542-2333</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br />
<h5 style="font-weight: bold;">Travel Agencies</h5>
<table border="1" frame="border" rules="all" style="border: 1px solid #000000; width: 50%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25%;">Morris Murdock Travel</td>
<td style="width: 25%;">523-3300 or 1-800-227-4270</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25%;">Sunrise Travel</td>
<td style="width: 25%;">234-2386 or 1-800-234-3272</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br />
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Easy-Way Taxi and Deliver</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Offers services between Rexburg and Idaho Falls.  Because the needs of BYU-Idaho students is sporadic, it is advised to plan ahead when using taxi service.  Call (208)525-8344.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Greyhound</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">With more than 3,700 locations in North America (excluding Alaska and Hawaii), Greyhound offers a lot of choices in planning travel.  They are also willing to do charters exclusively for BYU-Idaho students, if the demand is high enough (26 students going to the same destination).  Call (800)454-2487.  The Idaho Falls operation of TRPTA cooperates for extended services options.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Morris Murdock Travel</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">A regional agency offering assistance with travel arrangements from their office in Idaho Falls.  Call (800)227-4270, or fax (208)523-3300. See <a href="http://www.morrismurdock.com">www.morrismurdock.com</a>.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Safe Ride Taxi</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Safe Ride Taxi offers services locally in Rexburg and between Idaho Falls and Rexburg 24/7.  Call (208)206-7592.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Salt Lake Express</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Offers daily ground transportation to and from Salt Lake City, Utah (airport and downtown) and Boise, Idaho (airport and Boise State University).  As part of the National Trailways Transportation System, they offer convenient round trips daily leaving Rexburg in the morning and arriving back in late afternoon or evening.  The Salt Lake Express provides service to and from the Salt Lake City International Airport and the following communities: BYU-Idaho, Rexburg, Rigby, Idaho Falls, Blackfoot, Pocatello, Brigham City, Ogden, Layton, Kaysville, Farmington, Centerville, Bountiful.  Call (208)656-8824 or (800)356-9796 or visit online at <a href="http://www.saltlakeexpress.com">www.saltlakeexpress.com</a>.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Sunrise Travel, Inc.</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">A full-service travel agency with offices located in Idaho Falls and Pocatello.  Contact them at (800)234-3272.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">TRPTA</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Community and Rural Transportation is a non-profit corporation which offers services between Idaho Falls and Rexburg and also within the two cities.  They offer semi-fixed routes, dial-a-ride, and subscription service.  TRPTA buses do not normally operate on Saturday, Sunday, or holiday.  Contact them at (208)356-9033 or (208)522-2278.  TRPTA and PTA bus services cooperate for extended services options.</p>
<br />
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong>BYU-Idaho does not provide or sponsor any transportation for its students unrelated to approved academic classes.  There are, however, several travel options offered by companies in the community.  Shown above is a partial list of companies offering travel options.  This list is provided for your convenience and to help you weigh the options and make decisions based on your own special needs and preferences.  These listings are informational only.  BYU-Idaho does not endorse any of these companies nor has BYU-Idaho investigated any of these companies to determine their safety record, their compliance with state or federal regulations, or their business standing.  Before using any of these carriers, BYU-Idaho recommends that you determine that they are appropriate for your needs.  Because service may be limited, the best plan for travel is to make plans early.  Planning helps students and their families have the reassuring knowledge that things are taken care of in advance.  It also helps the companies offer services to fill the students' needs.</strong></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18419" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_FullWidth>
