<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x62611" Name="Group Travel Procedures" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Group Travel Procedures</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Group Travel Procedures</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110907T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Contents</h4>
<ol start="1" style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li><a href="#Introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#Deposits">Deposits</a> 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li><a href="#Academic_Deposits">Student Academic Tours</a></li>
<li><a href="#Performance_Deposits">Student Performance Tours</a></li>
<li><a href="#Community_Deposits">Community Patron Tours</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#Payments">Payments</a></li>
<li><a href="#Charge_Categories">Tour Charge Categories (Student Academic Tours Only)</a></li>
<li><a href="#Revenue">Revenue Credited To the Tour Accounts</a> 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li><a href="#Academic_Revenue">Student Academic Tours</a></li>
<li><a href="#Performance_Revenue">Student Performance Tours</a></li>
<li><a href="#Community_Revenue">Community Patron Tours</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#Recording">Payment and Recording of Expenses</a></li>
<li><a href="#CES_Policy">CES Policy for International Tour Groups</a></li>
<li><a href="#Insurance">Health Insurance for International Tour Groups</a></li>
</ol>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Introduction">Introduction</a></h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">There are three categories of tours: (1) Student Academic Tours, (2) Student Performance Tours, and (3) Community Patron Tours. There are some variations in the handling of each type of tour as noted below.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Deposits">Deposits</a></h4>
<ol start="1" style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li><a id="Academic_Deposits">Student Academic Tours</a> 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>All tour participants must first be admitted to BYU-Idaho either as summer-only, non-matriculated or matriculated students before their tour application forms and deposits can be accepted. When admitted, each student will be issued a BYU-Idaho ID number, which will then be used for all transactions. All applicants must be registered for at least one academic course before they can participate on any Student Academic Tour. 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 45px;">
<li>To be considered for admission as summer-only or non-matriculated students, applicants must complete Parts A, B and D (bishop's endorsement) of the BYU-Idaho application form and submit their application fee (if it has not been previously paid). Summer-only and non-matriculated students cannot register for regular, on-campus Fall or Winter courses.</li>
<li>Students in the process of applying to gain matriculated status at BYU-Idaho may participate in an academic tour under summer-only or non-matriculated status (subject to acceptance by the Admissions Office) if they complete the materials outlined in the previous paragraph. Their admission to the University as a matriculated student will be considered separately.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The initial tour deposits accompanied with an official Tour Application Form must be delivered or mailed to the Cashiers Office. Secretaries and tour directors should not accept deposit payments. However, if any payment is received, it should be sent or taken immediately to the Cashiers Office. Do not hold any money. Also, they should not accept an application form until it has been validated showing payment of the deposit. Subsequent tour fee and tuition payments are also made at the Cashiers Office.</li>
<li>Each day the Cashiers Office will send validated application forms to the Accounting Office. Student names will be entered into the tour report file to allow the creation of reports for tour directors listing the applicants and the amounts of their deposits and payments. The application forms will then be forwarded to the tour directors.</li>
<li>If students make only partial payments on their initial tour deposit, the money will be credited to their personal deposit account at the Cashiers Office. These partial deposit payments will not be considered a tour deposit and will not ensure a reservation for the tour until paid in full.</li>
<li>If the deposit is received by mail, a receipt will be attached to the application so the director can give it to the student. Since receipts are proof of payments, students should keep copies of all receipts.</li>
<li>Deposits are credited to a separate category in each student's account. Students do not have access to deposits unless the money is released by the tour director. If a student is unable to go, each tour director will determine the amount to be refunded to the student, if any. The unrefunded balance will be transferred to the tour account. The tour director should contact the Accounting Office at ext. 1900 when such a determination is made.</li>
<li>Tour directors may request a report that will show the names of applicants along with deposits and payments made. To obtain this report, call the Accounting Office at ext. 1900.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a id="Performance_Deposits">Student Performance Tours</a> 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Initial tour deposits accompanied with an official Tour Application Form must be delivered or mailed to the Cashiers Office. Secretaries and tour directors should not accept deposit payments. However, if any payment is received, it should be sent or taken immediately to the Cashiers Office. Do not hold any money. Also, application forms should not be accepted until they have been validated showing payment of the deposit. Subsequent tour fee payments are also made at the Cashiers Office.</li>
<li>Each day the Cashiers Office will send validated application forms to the Accounting Office. Student names will be entered into the tour report file to allow the creation of reports for tour directors listing the applicants and the amounts of their deposits and payments. The application forms will then be forwarded to the tour directors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a id="Community_Deposits">Community Patron Tours</a> 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Initial tour deposits accompanied with an official Tour Application Form must be delivered or mailed to the Cashiers Office. Secretaries and tour directors should not accept deposit payments. However, if any payment is received, it should be sent or taken immediately to the Cashiers Office. Do not hold any money. Also, application forms should not be accepted until they have been validated showing payment of the deposit. Subsequent tour fee payments are also made at the Cashiers Office.</li>
<li>Each day the Cashiers Office will send validated application forms to the Accounting Office. Each applicant&rsquo;s name will be entered into the tour report file to allow the creation of reports for tour directors listing the applicants and the amounts of their deposits and payments. The application forms will then be forwarded to the tour directors.</li>
<li>If an applicant has a BYU-Idaho ID number, it will be used as his/her account number. If not, the Accounting Office will set up a new account number.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Payments">Payments</a></h4>
<ol start="1" style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>All tour payments must be made at or mailed to the Cashiers Office. Secretaries and tour directors should not accept payments, but if received, they should be taken immediately to the Cashiers Office. Tour fee payments will be credited to the same category on each applicant's account as the initial deposit.</li>
<li>Tour directors will be responsible to ensure that applicants meet tour payment deadlines.</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Charge_Categories">Tour Charge Categories (Student Academic Tours Only)</a></h4>
<ol start="1" style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>Charges will consist of the following: 
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>INITIAL DEPOSIT -- the non-refundable part of the total tour cost</li>
<li>TOUR FEE -- total cost of the tour, which includes the initial deposit but not the tuition or other charges; includes HTH International Insurance where applicable</li>
<li>TUITION -- based on the number of credits</li>
<li>HEALTH INSURANCE -- BYU-Idaho tour insurance, if not covered by private insurance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>It is the responsibility of the travel leader to verify with the Student Health Center that all students that will be traveling are properly insured and to obtain a completed insurance waiver card for each new or former student claiming private insurance coverage. The tour director should make a copy of each student's insurance card and bring them on the tour. For international travel, the tour director should also retain a copy of each student's HTH Insurance card, passport, and/or visa. A copy of these documents should be left with the sponsoring department. A completed insurance waiver card must be included for each new or former student claiming private insurance coverage.</li>
<li>Prior to the departure date, the tour director should work with the Registrar's Office to register participants for classes.</li>
<li>After class registration is completed, a Fee and Schedule Form showing the classes, charges, payments (not the deposit), and the amount still owing should be requested by the tour director and mailed or given to each participant. The Registrar's Office will mail these upon request. The tour director may wish to review these forms before mailing or distributing.</li>
<li>All charges except for deposits will be posted to each student's account when the semester or term begins.</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Revenue">Revenue Credited to the Tour Accounts</a></h4>
<ol start="1" style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li><a id="Academic_Revenue">Student Academic Tours</a> -- Deposits will be credited as Tour Revenue when the tour director sends a final list of participants to the Accounting Office just prior to or after the tour has begun. This list should also include those deposits that have been forfeited.</li>
<li><a id="Performance_Revenue">Student Performance Tours</a> -- Payments will be credited as Tour Revenue when the tour director sends a final list of participants to the Accounting Office just prior to or after the tour has begun.</li>
<li><a id="Community_Revenue">Community Patron Tours</a> -- Payments will be credited as Tour Revenue when the tour director sends a final list of participants to the Accounting Office just prior to or after the tour has begun. This list should also include any deposits that have been forfeited.</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Recording">Payment and Recording of Expenses</a></h4>
<ol start="1" style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li>If a tour account has not been established, the director should contact the Accounting Office as soon as the tour has been approved. No expenditures or commitment of funds should be incurred until this happens.</li>
<li>The tour director need not wait for the Tour Revenue to be credited to their account before they can spend money. Some expenses will rightfully occur long before the tour actually begins.</li>
<li>Regular procedures should be used to request and make payments prior to departure on the tour: i.e., Check Requests, Department Hand Checks, CPOs, wire transfers, etc. Tour directors can contact their division chair or secretary for help with the best method to cover expenses, or they can call the Accounting Office at ext. 1900. Tour directors are encouraged to utilize the Travel Office (ext. 2340) in making arrangements for their tour.</li>
<li>The GROUP TRAVEL EXPENSE REPORT form (GTE) must be used to record all travel advances. Advances can be obtained either in cash at the Cashiers Office (if a large amount is needed, contact the Cashiers Office so that the amount needed will be on hand) or by check (submit a check request to Accounts Payable). If money is obtained to exchange dollars into foreign currency, it is still considered as an advance to the tour director.</li>
<li>A travel advance is considered a loan to the employee or tour director. These funds must be accounted for either in the form of receipts and/or by returning money to the Cashiers Office within five days after returning from the tour. Contact Accounts Payable in the Accounting Office if an extension is needed. Whether or not an extension is needed, the excess money should be deposited at the Cashiers Office within the five days.</li>
<li>The GTE form is used to record a summary of all the expenses incurred during the tour, either from the cash advances (including foreign currencies) or from credit cards. This form is completed upon return from the tour. The travel clerk in the Accounting Office will be happy to assist in the completion of this report.</li>
<li>A Detail of Cash Expenses envelope must be used during the tour to record details of all expenses, whether in U.S. or foreign currency. All receipts are placed in the envelope after being referenced and recorded on the envelope. Each currency exchange should also be recorded on this envelope. A separate envelope is used for each currency. If foreign currency is obtained from an ATM machine, the amount should be recorded even though the U.S. currency equivalent will not be known until the credit card statement is received.</li>
<li>Upon return from the tour, the director should bring the Detail of Cash Expenses, including receipts to the travel clerk in the Accounting Office. The travel clerk will assist the director in summarizing expenses on these forms and help complete the GTE form.</li>
<li>Either corporate credit cards (Travel and/or Tour Cards obtained from BYU-Idaho) or personal credit cards can be used to pay trip expenses. Tour directors are encouraged to use credit cards instead of travel advances where feasible. Corporate credit cards can be obtained from Financial Services. Remember that the tour director (or employee) is personally responsible for payment of all charges on corporate travel credit cards as well as personal credit cards. If a Tour Card is used for purchases the University pays the card company directly but the expense would still need to be recorded on the GTE. An envelope will be provided by the accounting office to keep all receipts from credit card charges.</li>
</ol>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong>Tour directors should contact Accounts Payable in the Accounting Office before they leave to receive the proper forms and assistance for keeping track of expenses and receipts.</strong></p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="CES_Policy">CES Policy for International Tour Groups</a></h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">In a few emergency situations CES higher education performing groups while on tour have sought help from international administrative or mission offices in paying bills, exchanging currency, etc... The following items should be kept in mind when planning and conducting international tours.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Touring groups should plan appropriately to handle their own expenses while on tour, including carrying a Tour card to pay local expenses of the group. International administrative offices should be contacted for assistance only in the case of unforeseen circumstances.</p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;"><a id="Insurance">HTH Insurance for International Tour Groups</a></h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">All international tours involving students are required to purchase HTH Worldwide Health Insurance. This supplemental insurance provides coverage for sickness and injury while traveling abroad. HTH also provides services to coordinate medical care and ensure that individuals get the best service possible. HTH Insurance may also be purchased for Community Patron Tours although it is not mandatory. Additional information about the insurance as well as how to procure coverage can be found at the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/financial-services/risk-management" title="Risk Management">Risk Management website</a>.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18419" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
