<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x62822" Name="Student Area Director" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Gateway Seminars Leadership Description</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The student area director position for Gateway Seminars is a paid leadership position that requires working a certain amount of hours each week to fulfill the expected responsibilities.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h1><br />Student Area Director Position</h1>
<h3><br />Overview</h3>
<p>The student area director position for Gateway Seminars is a paid leadership position, which may require 3-4 hours per week for the current semester and up to 8 hours per week for next semester. The responsibilities for this position will begin upon selection, which will occur around <strong>March 1st</strong>. During this start-up semester, you will be in the process of creating new leadership councils for each seminar type while still fulfilling current obligations in the program.</p>
<p>This position requires that you are available from 4:30 p.m. to 6 p.m. every Monday and from 5:00 p.m. to 8:30 p.m. on one or more of the following nights: Tuesdays, Wednesdays, or Thursdays for periodic monitoring of the Gateway Seminar program.<br /><br /></p>
<h2>Responsibilities</h2>
<p>The responsibilities for student area director for Gateway Seminars include the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Have an understanding and vision of the Gateway Seminar program.</li>
<li><span>Oversee and monitor the progress and effectiveness of all aspects of the program, assisting with solving problems appropriately that arise and ensuring the quality and success of the Gateway Seminar program.</span></li>
<li><span>Begin immediately the process of interviewing and selecting new leadership directors for each seminar type and assisting new directors in the selection of their leadership councils. </span></li>
<li>Meet regularly with the program advisor for training of responsibilities, planning and execution of the program's expectations, reporting of and feedback about the progress and status of the program.</li>
<li>Meet regularly with each director ensuring that he or she is well-trained and understands his or her responsibilities. Monitor the leadership development of each director and ensure that his or her councils are functioning effectively.</li>
<li>Use the leadership principles from Counseling with Our Councils and the "Learning by Faith" manual to develop the leadership capacity of each director and council.<br /><br /></li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<h2>Qualifications</h2>
<p>Qualifications for the area director positions include the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Prior experience in the Gateway Seminar program, preferably leadership experience</li>
<li>The desire and time necessary to make this program's success a primary focus; high involvement in other campus activities or program is not recommended and must be discussed with the program advisor</li>
<li>An ability to train and develop the leadership capacity of student directors and ensure that student directors are performing their responsibilities effectively</li>
<li>An ability to use and teach others the principles of counseling with councils as the process for timely and effective communication, resolving issues and problems that arise, and receiving divine guidance and inspiration in the execution of the program</li>
<li>Must be on track and have a minumum GPA of 2.8</li>
<li>A commitment to living the BYU-Idaho honor code and dress and grooming standards as an example for other students to follow</li>
<li>Name can be cleared with the Dean of Students office</li>
</ul>
<h3>Application</h3>
<p>If interested in this position, please complete the <a href="https://cms.byui.edu/emp/sites/crawfordv/Lists/Gateway%20Seminars%20Area%20Director%20Application/Item/newifs.aspx?List=adb66ddd-6fb5-4ab4-9477-00d376b5c250&amp;isdlg=1">electronic application</a> and submit it by <strong>Friday, March 1st.&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>You will be contacted for an interview shortly after the deadline. If you have any questions, email Brother Van Crawford at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:crawfordv@byui.edu" target="_self"><span><span>crawfordv</span>@<span>byui</span>.<span>edu</span></span></a> or visit with him in MC 129.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xpowercomponent_Optional Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x34838" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x18525" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
