<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x63025" Name="Physicians and Staff" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physicians and Staff</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physicians and Staff of the BYU-Idaho Student Health Center</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<link href="Documents/health-center/topper.css" rel="stylesheet" /> <link href="Documents/health-center/css/layout.css" rel="stylesheet" />
<style><!--
body #content_zone .titlehead {  
      border-bottom: solid thin #0070C0;
   }
   body #content_zone .comment {    
      color: #0070C0;
   }

   body #content_zone .titlefull {
      width: 100%;
   }
--></style>
<div id="content_zone">
<div id="topper">
<div class="titlehead titlefull">Staff</div>
</div>
<table border="0" class="clear" id="staff">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Dr. Bradbury" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Bradbury.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Dr. Andrew Bradbury, Medical Director</h4>
<p>Dr. Bradbury, a Fellow of the American Academy of Family Physicians, received his MD degree from Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia in 1986. His lengthy military service includes Flight Surgeon in Afghanistan, Iraq, and Saudi Arabia. Dr. Bradbury joined the Student Health Center in 2000, becoming Medical Director in 2011.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Dr. Rammel" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Rammell.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Dr. Corey Rammell, Physician</h4>
<p>Dr. Rammell, a Ricks College alumnus, is a board certified physician of the American Academy of Family Physicians. He graduated from the University of Utah School of Medicine in 1990 and completed his residency training at the University of Wyoming Family Practice Residency in Casper. Starting in 1993, he practiced full scale family medicine, served as Chief of Staff, and practiced Emergency Medicine services for Madison Memorial Hospital. Dr. Rammell joined the Student Health Center in the fall of 2011.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Dave Holland" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Holland.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Dave Holland, MSN, RN, FNP</h4>
<p>Dave graduated from Ricks College in 1984. He then studied at Idaho State University where he received a bachelor's degree in nursing. He received his master's degree from Idaho State University in 1995 and is certified as a family nurse practitioner. Dave is a member of the American Academy of Nurse Practitioners, and joined the Student Health Center in 1995.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Lori Parker" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Parker.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Lori Parker, RN, BSN, MSN, FNP-C</h4>
<p>Lori graduated as a nurse practitioner in 2004, and since then has worked at the Ashton Medical Clinic in Ashton, Idaho, and the Student Health Center. Lori has over 20 years of experience in a variety of patient settings, including medical/surgical, open-heart intensive care unit, trauma intensive care unit, and recovery room.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Christy Goodman" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Goodman.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Christy Goodman, MHS PA-C</h4>
<p>Christy graduated from Ricks College in 2000, and then proceeded to Lock Haven University of Pennsylvania, where in 2005 she received her Master of Science Degree in Health Science as a certified Physician Assistant. Christy spent a year working in cardiology, treating acute and longstanding heart patients as well as chronic disease processes, prior to joining the Student Health Center in 2006.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Terry Anderson" height="211" src="Images/health-center/Anderson.jpg" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Terry Anderson, PA</h4>
<p>Terry graduated from Saint Louis University in 2002 with a master's degree in medical sciences as a Physician Assistant. Terry has since worked at Portneuf Medical Center in Pocatello, Idaho, in the Convenient Care and Emergency Room departments. Terry joined the Student Health Center in 2010.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Marilyn Walker" height="214" src="Images/health-center/walker.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Marilyn Walker, RN</h4>
<p>Marilyn graduated from the Ricks College nursing program in 1980 and has worked as a medical/surgical nurse and an emergency room nurse ever since. She is certified in Advanced Cardiac Life Support, Pediatric Advanced Life Support, and is Trauma Nurse Core Course Certified. Marilyn joined the Student Health Center in 1990.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Tiffany Paepke" height="214" src="Images/health-center/paepke.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Tiffany Paepke, RN</h4>
<p>Tiffany received two degrees from Ricks College: physical education (1986) and nursing (1989). She has since worked as a medical surgical nurse at Madison Hospital, and at Bannock Regional Medical Center on the surgical floor and as the afternoon charge nurse in same-day surgery. Tiffany also worked for several local providers in the clinical setting until joining the Student Health Center in 2005.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Shawn Andreasen" height="214" src="Images/health-center/andreasen.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Shawn Andreasen, Pharmacy Director, R.Ph.</h4>
<p>Shawn received his bachelor's degree in microbiology with a medical emphasis from BYU Provo, and received his doctorate of pharmacy degree from Idaho State University. Shawn joined the Student Health Center in 2004.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Ruth Clark" height="214" src="Images/health-center/clark.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Ruth Clark, Office Assistant</h4>
<p>Ruth was born and raised in Rexburg and has been working in the medical field since 1973, holding a variety of responsibilities. She joined the Student Health Center in 1994 and currently assists with insurance billing, manages payroll, and provides specialized student support, including insurance issues.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Lorraine Cziep" height="214" src="Images/health-center/cziep.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Lorraine Cziep, MT (ASCP)</h4>
<p>Lorraine graduated from Ricks College before attending BYU Provo, where she received a Bachelor of Science degree in microbiology and chemistry. While working at Madison Memorial Hospital in Rexburg, Idaho, she was responsible for the microbiology department and worked in chemistry, hematology, serology, and blood bank. Lorraine joined the Student Health Center in 1990.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Katie Scadden" height="214" src="Images/health-center/scadden.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Katie Scadden, MT</h4>
<p>Katie graduated from Weber State College as a Medical Technologist, after which she worked in the Bacteriology Department at the University of Utah. Before joining the Student Health Center in 2004, Katie worked for Dr. Krell in Idaho Falls for over 14 years.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Lisa Nelson" height="214" src="Images/health-center/nelson.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Lisa Nelson, RT</h4>
<p>Lisa graduated from Ricks College with an associate degree in health science and from Idaho State University with a bachelor's degree in radiographic science. For over 13 years, she has worked in the hospital setting covering several specialties, including radiographic procedures, surgeries, CT scans, mammograms, nuclear medicine, and MRIs. Lisa joined the Student Health Center in 1996.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Vickie Christensen" height="214" src="Images/health-center/christensen.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Vickie Christensen, RT</h4>
<p>Vickie graduated from Community College in Denver, Colorado, and became registered as a Radiologic Technologist in 1982. She then spent 10 years working at Porter Memorial Hospital in Denver, Colorado, and another 10 years working at Eastern Idaho Regional Medical Center in Idaho Falls, Idaho, gaining valuable experience in the operating room, emergency room, and cardiology catheter lab. Vickie joined the Student Health Center in 2001.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Tammy Einerson" height="214" src="Images/health-center/einerson.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Tammy Einerson, Operations Manager</h4>
<p>Tammy received her coding certification from Weber State University, after which she worked for Duchesne County Hospital and Ashley Valley Medical Center. She then ran a highly successful medical billing business, Medical Billing and Management Services, for over 20 years. Tammy joined the Student Health Center in 2010.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="height: 250px;"><img alt="Shaun Orr" height="214" src="Images/health-center/orr.png" width="158" /></td>
<td>
<h4>Shaun Orr, Student Health Center Director</h4>
<p>Shaun received his Masters of Business Administration degree from Idaho State University in 1996. Since then, he held several responsibilities at Eastern Idaho Regional Medical Center, including budgeting and forecasting for over 100 departments, coordinating $42 million hospital construction and expansion, and facilitating expansion of hospital services to Yellowstone National Park. Shaun joined the Student Health Center in 2004, and has since then overseen the shift to a student-managed Student Health Center.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<iframe frameborder="0" height="240" id="footer" scrolling="no" src="http://www.byui.edu/Documents/health-center/footer.html" width="320"></iframe></div>
<script type="text/Javascript">
var staff = document.getElementById("staff");

   for (var i = 0; i < staff.children[0].rows.length; i++) {
      if (i % 2 != 0) {
         staff.children[0].rows[i].className = "highlight";
      }
   }
</script>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><!--071613 xpowercomponent_Optional to xPower--></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x28441" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></Content>
