<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x63208" Name="What if it's not blockable by my Administrator?" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">What if it's not blockable by my Administrator?</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">What if it's not blockable by my Administrator?</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1><strong>What if it's not blockable by my Administrator?</strong></h1>
<ol start="1">
<li>If you&nbsp;<strong>KNOW&nbsp;</strong>the sender, and want to continue receiving legitimate mail from them, &nbsp;contact the sender and advise them that their webmail account has been compromised and is being used to send spam.&nbsp; The account owner should secure their account by&nbsp;<strong>changing the account password</strong>.&nbsp; If the spam activity persists after the password is changed, they should contact the technical support at their webmail provider (AOL, Yahoo, etc) to seek assistance securing the account.</li>
<li>If you&nbsp;<strong>DO&nbsp;<em>NOT</em>&nbsp;KNOW</strong>&nbsp;the sender (or know the sender but do not want to receive mail from them):<ol>
<li>Add the sender's address to your&nbsp;<strong>personal blocklist on Proofpoint</strong>. &nbsp;Access your Junk Mail profile at any time from&nbsp;<a href="https://spamdigest.byui.edu:10020/" target="_self">https://spamdigest.byui.edu:10020/</a>(Use your regular password but with your_full@email.address as the username.) &nbsp;This will cause all messages from the specified sender to be quarantined, regardless of spam score.</li>
<li>Add the sender's address to your Blocked Senders list in&nbsp;<a href="x36009.xml">Outlook</a>.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p>Read on if you'd like to know more.</p>
<p>Many people receive spam messages from an address at a large webmail provider (usually AOL, Yahoo, Hotmail), where the content of the messages is usually just a single URL.</p>
<p>These messages are likely a class of spam sent from&nbsp;<strong>compromised (hacked) but legitimate</strong>&nbsp;webmail accounts.&nbsp; What is apparently happening in these cases is a spammer has obtained control of a webmail user's legitimate account, and is using it to send spam without the knowledge of the account owner.&nbsp; The spam messages are typically sent to other addresses associated with the account -- addresses in the address book, and/or addresses parsed from messages in the sent &amp; received mail spool for that account.&nbsp; This implies that the owner of the sending account is likely to be someone who has corresponded with your user (i.e. someone your user knows directly -- a friend or business associate), or possibly someone who is "connected" indirectly with your user, perhaps by being a cc recipient on a message sent by a third party to both your user and the spam source account.<br />These messages tend to be characterized by minimal content&nbsp; -- usually the Subject header line is empty, and the body is also empty except for the payload URL being advertised.&nbsp; The URL itself is often a web page on a legitimate hosting service, or a page placed on a compromised but legitimate web server.&nbsp; That being the case, the only features that can potentially be used to identify the message as spam are the sender address itself, and the URL.&nbsp; Since the sender address is legitimate, it is typically inappropriate for Proofpoint to include it in the spam definitions provided to all customers.&nbsp; This leaves the URL as the only appropriate feature to block the message, and this is usually not known in advance of its use in spam.&nbsp; As a result, it is very difficult to block these messages using the base spam classifier in PPS.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35726" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
