<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x63403" Name="Contract Addendum" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Contract Addendum</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Contract Addendum</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<!-- MENS NAV BAR -->
<div><img height="56" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/blank.png" width="65" /><!-- Home Button --><a class="intLink" href="x8708.xml"><img height="76" onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/H.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/H-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/H.png" width="134" /></a><!-- On Campus-Housing --><a class="intLink" href="x45370.xml"><img height="76" onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/O.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/O-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/O.png" width="162" /></a><!-- Men's Active --><a class="intLink" href="x45443.xml"><img height="76" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/M-active.png" width="128" /></a><!-- Women's Housing --><a class="intLink" href="x45444.xml"><img height="76" onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/W.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/W-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/W.png" width="155" /></a><!-- Volunteer --><a class="intLink" href="x45445.xml"><img height="76" onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/V.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/V-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/V.png" width="111" /></a><!-- Buy/Sell --><a class="intLink" href="x46042.xml"><img height="76" onmouseout="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/B.png';" onmouseover="this.src='Images/housing/navbar/mens/B-hover.png';" src="Images/housing/navbar/mens/B.png" style="margin: 1px -1px;" width="135" /></a></div>
<!-- END NAV BAR -->
<div><img height="88" src="Images/housing/On campus/Mens Housing/Lamprecht-title.png" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="950" />
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><em>Contract Addendum</em></h3>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em><em><img height="20" src="Images/housing/blank.png" width="72" /></em></em><hr /></div>
</div>
<div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ADVERTISING</strong></span>: No advertising or soliciting is permitted in housing complexes. Solicitors should be reported to the manager.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>BICYCLES, SCOOTERS, SKATEBOARDS</strong></span>: Students may not store bicycles in the apartment/building at any time. Students should register their bikes with University Security. There is no charge to register a bike. Students are responsible to remove bikes from campus when leaving BYU-Idaho. Students are encouraged to use a bike lock to secure their bike. Bike racks are provided at each complex. Bicycles, scooters, skateboards, etc. should not be ridden inside the complex.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>DAMAGES</strong></span>: Students are liable for any damages to the complex. When more than one person is involved, each person will share in the expense. When students know who is responsible for any damage in public areas, they should provide such information to the manager or University Security. Individuals will be charged the actual cost including labor charges.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>DECORATIONS</strong></span>: Appropriate decorations (posters, pictures, etc.) are encouraged. Since no items may be attached to the walls or doors with tape or nails, a special adhesive will be provided for attaching posters, etc., to the walls and doors. Sidewalk chalk and window paint should not be used anywhere in the complex. Bottles of any kind should not be stacked in the windows.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>DRESS AND GROOMING</strong></span>: Students and guests are expected to observe BYU-Idaho dress and grooming standards within the courtyard, lounge, laundry room, garbage rooms and walkways of each complex. Shorts can be worn by students in these areas as long as they are modest in length. Swimwear should not be worn in these areas.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ELECTRICAL APPLIANCES</strong></span>: Students should be especially careful in the use of curling irons, toasters, slow cookers, irons, candle warmers etc. These appliances may cause damage to carpet, furniture, and countertops. Plug in skillets or hot plates are not permitted in Chapman Hall.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ENTERPRISES AND BUSINESSES</strong></span>: The operation of a business enterprise in the complex is prohibited.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EVACUATION PROCEDURES</strong></span>: Students are expected to evacuate the complex when a fire alarm is sounded. They should also be considerate of and obey the manager or other authority in the event of an emergency. Emergency drills will be conducted once a semester at the discretion of the manager without prior notice.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FIRE/SAFETY</strong></span>: All open flames and burning embers, such as candles and incense are prohibited. Tampering, disabling, or destroying any smoke detector or alarm is prohibited. Students should extinguish grease fires appropriately by covering the pan with a lid or damp cloth. Fire extinguishers should not be used to extinguish a grease fire. Please report all fires no matter how small to the manager.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FURNITURE</strong></span>: No furniture may be moved out of the room, apartment, or lounge to which it is assigned. Furniture should not be stacked. Used furniture is not permitted in order to prevent potential bed bug infestations.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>HOUSEKEEPING</strong></span>: Students are required to maintain order and cleanliness in their living accommodations at all times. Room/apartment clean checks are performed regularly. Students will supply their own cleaning products to clean their room/apartment. Cleaning supplies must be appropriate for the task, such as using toilet bowl cleaner to clean toilets or sanitizers and scrubbing pads to clean sinks. Students will be charged $10/hr. per university employee if cleaning has to be performed by the university either during the semester or following the checkout.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>KEYS</strong></span>: Keys to rooms or apartments and mailboxes will be issued by the manager during the check-in process. Students are advised to keep their rooms or apartments locked at all times when not occupied. No BYU-Idaho keys are to be duplicated. The typical cost for replacing a key is $10 and $35 dollars to rekey the apartment if the key is lost.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>LAUNDRY FACILITIES</strong></span>: Coin-operated washing machines and dryers are installed in the laundry room in each complex for the exclusive use of students in that building. Members of the opposite sex are not allowed in the laundry room.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>LINEN</strong></span>: BYU-Idaho provides a mattress cover on all mattresses. Students need to bring their own bedding and towels. All beds require extra-long sheets (80 inches). The typical cost for replacing a mattress cover is $20.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MAINTENANCE</strong></span>: Students are responsible to notify the manager as soon as possible if they notice anything in an apartment or room that requires repair work or maintenance. Requests for maintenance can be submitted via email, phone, or visiting the manager during office hours.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MOTOR VEHICLE REPAIRS</strong></span>: No vehicles may be repaired, including oil changes, on university property. Repair or storage of automobiles, bicycles, motorcycles/parts, or similar mechanical devices is not permitted in the apartment, room, or complex.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OCCUPANCY</strong></span>: Apartments and rooms will not be ready for occupancy before the first day of the contract. If arriving late for semester/block check-in, please contact the manager to make arrangements. Accommodations may be made for university sponsored programs such as Get Connected, etc. Students should sleep in the bed that they contracted.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERNIGHT TRIPS</strong></span>: Students must notify their manager if they will be gone from the complex overnight for any reason. This is strictly a safety measure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>PARKING</strong></span>: Students bringing cars must purchase a BYU-Idaho student parking decal from Parking Services located in Kimball 150. Students need to fill out a Vehicle Registration Card from the manager's office and take the completed card, along with their registration, to Parking Services. This allows overnight parking in the Pioneer lot for residents of Perkins, Kerr, Barnes, Ricks, Lamprecht, and Chapman Halls. (Rexburg City ordinance 1030 does not allow overnight parking on city streets from December 15 to March 1.)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ROOFS</strong></span>: Students are not permitted on the roofs of the complex.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SECURITY</strong></span>: All entrances to complexes are locked for security during specified evening hours. Students are counseled to lock doors to their apartments or rooms to protect personal belongings and to provide additional security. It is essential that each student take responsibility for complex security, such as seeing that doors and gates are properly secured and not propped open.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SOUND EQUIPMENT</strong></span>: Students are discouraged from bringing powerful or bulky sound equipment such as large stereos, radios, televisions, speakers, etc., because the noise is a disturbance to other students and space is limited.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>STORAGE</strong></span>: There are storage areas in each complex where luggage can be stored while attending BYU-Idaho. Students leaving for a block or semester should take all their personal belongings with them if they are not returning. Students storing items in an on-campus complex hereby waive all claims against BYU-Idaho for loss of or damage to clothing, valuables, or other personal property. Students may store items in an on-campus complex free of charge if they have purchased an on-campus housing contract for the next continuing semester. Students must store their items in plastic boxes/totes. Each container must be clearly marked with a label provided by the manager. Students may not store computers, stereos, or any other valuables. Storage is available on a first come, first served basis and is limited to one, 13 foot cubby storage area per student.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>TELEPHONES</strong></span>: BYU-Idaho does not provide a telephone in the apartment. A public telephone is available in the main lounge of each complex. Calling cards are required to make long distance phone calls. A card can be obtained from the Bursar's Office.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>UPPER LOUNGES</strong></span>: Members of the opposite sex are only allowed in the upper lounges of Perkins, Kerr, Barnes, and Ricks Halls with the permission of the manager. Chapman and Lamprecht Halls are open to guests during the same hours that the main lounge is open.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>WELCOME AND OTHER MEETINGS</strong></span>: At the beginning and end of each semester, mandatory meetings are held to explain expectations and procedures that are critical for the student to know. Additional meetings may also be held at other times during the year as directed by the manager. All students will be held accountable for any information discussed or distributed in the meeting, whether or not they attend.</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9764" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9287" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
