<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x63801" Name="Off-Campus Parking" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Off-Campus Parking Appeals</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The H&amp;SL Office Adminstrators are available to assist students with towing and booting concerns at Approved Housing complexes. Click to learn more.</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110411T06:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3>Towing and Booting at Approved Housing Complexes</h3>
<p>Students who claim they were wrongly booted or towed in an approved housing unit will be allowed to submit an appeal to the Housing &amp; Student Living Office within 10 days of the violation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Parents and other visitors are not eligible to appeal, but a student may appeal on their behalf.  Some preliminary questions the student should address:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li> Were you legally parked?  Describe where you were parked.</li>
<li>Did you have a permit properly displayed allowing you to park in this lot?  Can you provide proof of this permit?</li>
<li>Why do you feel you should not be required to pay the booting/towing fee?</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A student submits an appeal and will meet with a Housing &amp; Student Living administrator to discuss the situation. The student should bring all documentation (parking permits, copy of the violation receipt, etc.) when meeting with the Housing &amp; Student Living administrator. To set up an appointment to discuss your off-campus parking appeal, please contact the Housing &amp; Student Living Office at (208) 496-9220.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Mediation &amp; Arbitration</h3>
<p>To resolve parking concerns, students take part in the Housing &amp; Student Living Mediation and Arbitration process. Throughout the course of the process the apartment manager and towing/booting company may be contacted for additional information.  If a resolution cannot be reached through mediation, the matter will be evaluated in the arbitration process.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The arbitration panel will consist of an impartial student without connection to the case, a university administrator, and an approved housing landlord to ensure a balanced perspective. Those present at the hearing will include the student in question, the towing company, and a representative from the housing unit in/from which the vehicle was booted/towed. Hearings may occur on a monthly basis, or as needed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is anticipated that one of the following judgments would be rendered at the conclusion of the hearing:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li> Parking violation stands, no further action required.</li>
<li>Towing company acted outside of the established parameters and is ordered to reimburse the collected fine.</li>
<li>Towing company acted appropriately, but housing unit did not meet requirements established under city ordinance 911. Housing unit would be ordered to reimburse the student for a paid fine.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other judgments may be considered according to the panel's discretion.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x9287" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
