<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x63931" Name="BYU-Idaho Honor Code Statement for Employees" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho Honor Code Statement for Employees</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho Honor Code Statement for Employees</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookToken type="string" label="Access_Token" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookToken><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div>
<p><br /><strong>BYU-Idaho Honor Code Statement for Employees</strong><br /><br /><em>We believe in being honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, and in doing good to all men.... If there is anything virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy, we seek after these things. (Thirteenth Article of Faith).</em><br /><br />As a matter of personal commitment, the faculty, administration, staff, and students of Brigham Young University, Brigham Young University-Hawaii, Brigham Young University-Idaho, and LDS Business College seek to demonstrate in daily living on and off-campus those moral virtues encompassed in the gospel of Jesus Christ and will:<br /><br />1. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Abide by the standards of Christian living taught by The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints</span>. This includes graciousness and consideration for others and the observance of high principles of honor, integrity, and morality.<br /><br />2. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Be honest in all behavior</span>. This means to refrain from cheating, plagiarizing, or knowingly giving false information.<br /><br />3. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Live a chaste and virtuous life</span>. This includes abstinence from all sexual relations outside the bonds of marriage.<br /><br />4. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Obey, honor, and sustain the law</span>.<br /><br />5. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Comply with all of the employing unit's regulations</span>. This includes compliance with rules relating to campus organizations and to the use of the employing unit or off-campus housing or other facilities.<br /><br />6. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Use clean language</span>.<br /><br />7. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Respect others</span>. This includes:<br /><br />Not physically or verbally abusing any person and not engaging in conduct which threatens or endangers the health or safety of others; and<br /><br />Not obstructing or disrupting the study of others, the performance of official duties by officers or employees, the teaching, research, disciplinary, administrative or other functions of the university or other authorized activities on the premises of the university. <br /><br />8. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Respect property rights</span>. This includes refraining from theft, concealment, damage, or misuse of the property of others.<br /><br />9. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Abstain from alcoholic beverages, tobacco, tea, coffee, and substance abuse</span>. This includes refraining from the possession, use, or distribution of any narcotic or dangerous drug (as defined by applicable law), except as prescribed by a licensed medical practitioner.<br /><br />10. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Participate regularly in church services</span>.<br /><br />11. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Observe BYU-Idaho standards of dress and grooming</span>. See dress and grooming standards below.<br /><br />12. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Observe high standards of taste and decency</span>. This includes refraining from disorderly, lewd, indecent, or obscene conduct or expression.<br /><br />13. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Help others to fulfill their responsibilities under this Code</span>.<br /><br />Specific policies embodied in the Honor Code include the continuing employee and student ecclesiastical endorsement requirements (refer to these policies for more detailed information).<br /><br /><br /><strong>BYU-Idaho Dress and Grooming Standards for Employees</strong><br /><br />Employees occupy a position of role model for students at BYU-Idaho. As role models, a higher and more formal dress and grooming standard is expected of employees when on campus than is expected of students. Specifically:<br /><br />1. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Male employees</span> are expected to wear a shirt and tie with dress slacks. Jeans are not appropriate professional attire.<strong> </strong>In areas where shirts, ties, and dress slacks are not suitable for the work environment, the department chair or director, in consultation with the vice president, will determine satisfactory attire, including the wearing of uniforms where appropriate. Extreme or immodest clothing styles are also unacceptable.<br /><br />Male employees are expected to maintain a clean and well-cared-for appearance. Hairstyles should be neat, avoiding extreme styles or colors, and trimmed above the collar and the ear. Sideburns should not extend below the earlobe or onto the cheek. Men are expected to be clean shaven; beards are not acceptable. Mustaches, if worn, should be neatly trimmed and may not extend beyond or below the corners of the mouth. Earrings and other body piercing are unacceptable. Shoes should be worn in all public campus areas.<br /><br />2. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Female employees</span> are expected to wear modest professional business office attire (dresses, skirts, dressy blouses and sweaters, pant suits). In areas where dresses or pant suits are not suitable for the work environment, the department chair or director, in consultation with the vice president, will determine satisfactory attire, including the wearing of uniforms where appropriate.<br /><br />Dresses or skirts above the knee or those with slits above the knee, as well as extreme or immodest clothing styles are inappropriate. Women should wear appropriate hosiery. Casual slacks, blouses, and sweaters, as well as jeans of any color or fabric, are not appropriate professional attire.<br /><br />Excessive ear piercing (more than one per ear) and other body piercing are not acceptable. Shoes should be worn in all public campus areas.<br /><br />3. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Safety Clothing</span>. In situations where dress standards may require modification for safety reasons, e.g. working with machinery or chemicals, the department should follow OSHA's approved safety clothing guidelines. Where specific safety clothing or uniforms are required by management, such clothing will be provided by the department in question.<br /><br />4. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Dress and Grooming Compliance</span>. Supervisors are held accountable to ensure employees under their direction understand and apply these dress and grooming standards.<br /><br />While dress outside the work environment may not necessarily be at the standard described below, the grooming standards should always be followed. Dress outside the work environment should always be modest, appropriate for the occasion, and consistent with the dignity of a representative of BYU-Idaho and The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.<br /><br /></p>
<p>
<p> </p>
</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x26193" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
