<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64194" Name="Faculty Voices: Experts and Specialists—Two Versions of the Jigsaw" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty Voices: Experts and Specialists—Two Versions of the Jigsaw</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The combination of students helping each other create the lesson plan, and still keeping individual accountability has been the key.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090425T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Eric d’Evegnee and Paul Johanson</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong><span><br /></span></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The Specialist Jigsaw</strong><strong> &mdash; </strong><strong>Eric d&rsquo;Evegnee</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img align="left" alt="Eric d'Evegnee" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/DevegneeE.JPG" style="margin: 15px;" />
<p><strong>The Problem&mdash;Ineffective Student Presentations</strong></p>
<p>In an effort to have my students critically engage the literature we read in class, I set them up in small groups and assigned them to read and present on a professional example of literary criticism. These presentations were like most student presentations. They were uneven in quality and rarely involved the other students. After two semesters, I realized I had to either throw out the idea or completely revise this method of student presentation. I honestly felt that the added depth of the outside material was critical for the students&rsquo; understanding of the literature we covered in a shortened semester.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Maximizing Benefits and Eliminating Negatives</strong></p>
<p>In a moment between semesters, I analyzed the model of student presentations I was using. The most significant benefit of this old model was that students analyzed an outside reading together and formulated a way to present the material to the rest of the class. However, I felt that the method of presentation lent itself to dry recitations of quotes and questions that merely summarized the text. The new model I wanted to use would maximize the benefit and eliminate the negative presentation style. With these goals in mind, I decided to take a group of five students and make them the &ldquo;specialist&rdquo; group. This group of students would still get together and create a handout that would have significant quotes from the text they studied together, but they would use these quotes to create analytical questions that would foster a small group discussion with other students. On the day designated in the syllabus, these five &ldquo;specialists&rdquo; would bring the handout that they worked on together and each of them would take a fifth of the students to another corner of the room or to another empty classroom in the building and lead a discussion of the assigned class reading and its connection to the &ldquo;specialist&rdquo; reading.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Fantastic Results</strong></p>
<p>The results have been fantastic. I haven&rsquo;t seen so many different kinds of students do so well before. This method still has the benefit of many students putting their heads together without the negative effects of the front of the classroom delivery. The combination of students helping each other create the lesson plan, and still keeping individual accountability has been the key. Each student has taken the specialist jigsaw seriously; I think because they are responsible for a small group of their peers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The most integral part of making this method successful is ensuring that the students feel like they are not just talking but are moving toward meaning. The instructor must integrate the groups&rsquo; discussions into a focused conclusion. Students should never feel like their comments in their groups don&rsquo;t contribute to what they learn that day. During the small group time, I walk around to the different groups and write down the great comments I hear and use them to create questions when the groups are done with their discussion. I integrate what I hear from students and their comments into my thoughts at the end of class. I always tie together the strands of thought into some kind of tangible lesson that the students can take with them. Integrating comments I haven&rsquo;t heard before can be risky, but I love the exhilaration of thinking critically on my feet and guiding a discussion as I listen.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Paul Johanson&mdash;My  Version of the Jigsaw</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img align="left" alt="Paul Johanson" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/JohansonP.JPG" style="margin: 15px;" />
<p><strong>Eight Functions and Four Representations</strong></p>
<p>In college algebra we want students to be able to identify eight functions when given in each of four representations.&nbsp; Those functions can be represented as data values, graphs, equations, and applications.&nbsp; Traditionally, an instructor shows the four representations of each function to the students and points out their key features.&nbsp; Rather than relying on this teaching by telling approach, we believe that there is power in helping&nbsp; students to investigate and discover these features for themselves.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Becoming Experts</strong></p>
<p>To do this we have prepared a spreadsheet exploration and lab activity for each function.&nbsp; Both the spreadsheet exploration and the lab activity come with guiding questions to help students identify the key features of each function in each of the four representations.&nbsp; There are also questions to help them make connections between the four representations.&nbsp; Unfortunately, carefully and thoroughly completing a spreadsheet activity and lab activity for a given function can be rather time consuming.&nbsp; So, instead of having every student do this for all eight functions, we ask each student to become the &ldquo;expert&rdquo; for two functions and then teach others about these functions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I organize the jigsaw this way:</p>
<ul>
<li>I divide the class into 8 groups.</li>
<li>I assign each group two functions. Importantly, two groups will work on identical pairs of functions.</li>
<li>For homework, individuals begin the spreadsheet exploration and lab activity for the first function.</li>
<li>In class, the groups work together to compile their findings from their individual investigations.</li>
<li>For homework, groups complete the spreadsheet exploration and lab activity for the second function.</li>
<li>During the next class period, the pairs of groups with the same set of functions compare their findings and plan how to best teach those functions to their classmates.</li>
<li>For homework, groups write a short lesson for each of their two functions and post it on a wiki set-up for their functions.</li>
<li>I assign each group member to a new group of 8 students composed of one representative from each of the original groups.</li>
<li>I ask each person to teach about one of their two functions. The counter-part from the matching groups gives assistance when needed.</li>
<li>Students record what they are taught on a function summary table.</li>
<li>Students return to their original function expert groups to compare what they were taught about the other six functions in the jigsaw groups.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>A Deeper Learning Experience</strong></p>
<p>My findings are that the investigations provide a deeper learning experience than the students have when a teacher points out key features.&nbsp;Asking two groups to work on the same functions provides a safety net to prevent the spread of misinformation. Returning to the original group to compare what you were taught compensates for variation in teaching skill. Posting the lessons on a wiki allows the instructor to review them for accuracy and provides a permanent record of the key features for each function.&nbsp; Having the class work in this way creates an atmosphere of cooperation and responsibility to teach one another.&nbsp; Finally, having become an expert on two functions, students understand the process and are much better able to study other functions independently.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Related Tools</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=31">Jigsaw</a><br /> <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=35">Instructor Role in Teach One Another</a><br /> <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=53">Learning in Groups</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
