<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64178" Name="My Experience with Discussion Boards in FDHUM 103" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">My Experience with Discussion Boards in FDHUM 103</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Perhaps the best thing about the discussion boards is the way they encourage a culture of learning within the class.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20081204T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Jon Linford</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times; font-size: small;"><br /></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><img align="left" alt="Jon Linford" height="146" hspace="8" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/LINFORDJ.JPG" style="width: 112px; height: 146px;" width="112" /> <span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif;">&nbsp;</span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">In the beginning I was skeptical about the Learning Model. I knew that faith was a principle of action and power, and that the Spirit was the true teacher. I also knew it was possible to invoke the Spirit in class, and discuss many seeming non-spiritual things in the light of the restored gospel. But I wasn&rsquo;t convinced that it would be possible to get students to truly prepare for a meaningful discussion on topics in which they previously had little interest. I wasn&rsquo;t sure that yielding class time to lengthy discussions would amount to more than &ldquo;sharing ignorance,&rdquo; and feared that without lectures the students simply wouldn&rsquo;t get the information they needed to be &ldquo;culturally literate.&rdquo; Furthermore, I was concerned that going into too much depth on a specific topic (in my case twentieth-century political art) would rob the course of sufficient breadth, and worried how I was going to give the students the necessary background in art, music, literature, theater, and dance for them to understand the cultural significance of the art works we would study.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">Part of the answer, we knew, lay in the preparation of effective study materials. Our team set up our course so that there was specific background reading and other artistic experiences posted online for each class period. For instance, in the lesson for World War One we posted a short introduction to the war, a chapter from Erich Maria Remarque&rsquo;s&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">All Quiet on the Western Front</em></span>, the poem&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Dulce et decorum est&nbsp;</em></span>by Wilfred Owen, three different versions of the German National Anthem, and a series of British war propaganda posters. At the end of each chapter we attached a series of questions, followed by a creative activity. For this chapter the students were asked to discuss why&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">All Quiet&nbsp;</em></span>was considered one of the great anti-war novels, and what devices Remarque had used to capture the horrors of war. They were asked to describe the differing ideals in each version of the German National Anthem, and how they were affected by Germany&rsquo;s changing political fortune.&nbsp;For the war posters, they were asked to evaluate each, both as a work of art and of political persuasion, and to discuss the specific aims of each poster. For the creative activity, the students were asked to design a propaganda poster advocating some aspect of the BYU-Idaho honor code, appealing to the emotions of the audience to persuade them to do something that they would not do naturally.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">All of this is very well, but how could we assure that the students would not merely gloss over the material and pay little heed to the questions, or worse, never look at the material at all and show up expecting to be spoon-fed? Twenty years of teaching experience told me that that is what would happen. So we required the students to study the lesson material, then log in on an online discussion board and discuss it&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">before&nbsp;</em></span>they come to class.&nbsp;For each lesson the students give themselves an assessment grade of 0-3: 0, a failing grade, means that they did not study the material; 1, a C, means that they studied the material but didn&rsquo;t talk to anyone about it;<span> </span>2, a B, means that they studied the material, engaged in a meaningful discussion online, and then came to class and continued that discussion; and 3, an A, means that they did all of these things, plus posted online their creative activity for the day. The discussion board makes it easy for me to check their self-assessed grade against what they have really been doing and make adjustments if necessary.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">From the start I have been overwhelmed by the depth and breadth of the discussions on the discussion board. So often I have seen students wandering away from the topic and have been tempted to step in and intervene, only to see another student bring the discussion back on track. It has been marvelous to watch the evolving consciousness of the class, both in the knowledge necessary for cultural literacy, and in the development of the students&rsquo; aesthetic sensitivity.&nbsp;Even better have been the discussions in class following these online explorations. Lecturing has nearly disappeared from my teaching&mdash;I do little more than guide the conversation, occasionally inserting a &ldquo;Scoutmaster minute&rdquo; where a little more background is needed. For our discussion of Shostakovich&rsquo;s&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Leningrad&nbsp;</em></span>Symphony, for instance, I took a few minutes to remind the students of sonata form the way Mozart and Beethoven had used it&mdash;this material had been presented earlier in the semester as part of a general introduction to music, but the students needed a refresher. Then I asked them to compare Mozart&rsquo;s form with how Shostakovich used it. The students were quick to point out the differences, and soon were using those differences to discover Shostakovich&rsquo;s intent with the symphony and how it was descriptive of the composer&rsquo;s own experience with the Second World War and Soviet Russia.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 0in;"><span style="font-family: 'times new roman', times, serif; font-size: small;">Perhaps the best thing about the discussion boards is the way they encourage a culture of learning within the class. Throughout my teaching career I have grappled with the problem of teaching to the bottom of the class; I believe every good teacher has the natural gift to look into the eyes of the students, see who is falling behind, and adjust the pace of the lecture accordingly. The problem with this is that the class never reaches critical mass because the gifted students are never sufficiently challenged. But time and again I have seen a student log into our discussion board and say that they don&rsquo;t get some concept, only to have it explained by another student who does. This not only saves time in class, but allows the gifted student the opportunity to reinforce and amplify a concept by teaching it to someone else. All of this makes our in-class discussions exceptionally vigorous, and one by one the weak, the hesitant, and the downright resistant have been pulled into the current of learning. Many of those who were &ldquo;behind the curve&rdquo; at the beginning of the semester are now among the class&rsquo;s most eager and informed participants. We certainly do not lack for discussion material in class&mdash;in fact we usually run out of time long before we run out of material, and the students then leave class and log onto the discussion board for follow-up discussion. Surely this is every professor&rsquo;s dream, to have the students discussing a lesson long after the class is over.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;</span></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
