<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64197" Name="Teaching Students How You Use the Learning Model" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Teaching Students How You Use the Learning Model</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">After being expected to apply the same learning principles in science, religion, and art classes, for example, students begin to get the picture.  The constant exposure to these principles over the course of their studies encourages students to take more responsibility for their learning.  Our collective efforts to teach “what the Learning Model is” and “how we use it” is a powerful means to developing disciple-leaders at BYU-Idaho.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090415T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brian Schmidt</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Many students do not recognize faculty members&rsquo; efforts to help them learn.&nbsp;&nbsp; While some students come to an &ldquo;aha&rdquo; realization of how the course activities fit together, others come away less satisfied&mdash;even when they have learned all that was intended.&nbsp;&nbsp; Helping students understand why a course was designed in a particular way seems paramount to bringing them to this awareness.&nbsp; The language of Learning Model can be helpful in communicating not only the rationale behind a course design, but why you have selected particular instructional strategies for a course.</p>
<br />
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Student Understanding</span></p>
<br /> <img alt="class" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/04-2009/teachlearningmodel/class.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 15px;" />
<p>Student understanding of the Learning Model is increasing.&nbsp; A survey winter semester found that 55% of the student body know the principles and process steps of the Learning Model (up from 38% in the fall).&nbsp; Student knowledge of the Learning Model will continue to increase as students are exposed to it through their courses and institutional messaging.</p>
<br />
<p>Yet even when students know the principles and process steps of the Learning Model, they often do not understand when it is being applied in their courses.&nbsp; This suggests that faculty should not only teach what the Learning Model is, but how it is being applied in their courses.&nbsp;&nbsp; The start of the semester is an opportune time to explain these connections with the course introduction and syllabus.</p>
<br />
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Resources to Teach Students</span></p>
<br />
<p>Numerous approaches have been developed to discuss the Learning Model.&nbsp; For ideas, consider visiting with colleagues or look at the examples and resources on <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=26">Teaching Your Class About the Learning Model</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp; Additionally the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/learningmodel/src/default.htm">Learning Model Website</a> is another resource that has video clips, explanations, and a discussion forum.&nbsp; Some faculty members have chosen to assign their students to take an <a href="http://www.byui.edu/learningmodel/selfassessment/lmquiz_1a.htm">online self assessment</a> or <a href="http://www.byui.edu/LearningModel/selfassessment/lmquiz_3.htm">test</a> to improve their knowledge of the Learning Model.&nbsp; Since these resources are online, students who do not know much about the model can be directed to learn more outside of classroom time.</p>
<br />
<p>Faculty can also use these resources to help resolve misconceptions about the Learning Model&mdash;particularly the notion that the faculty play a diminished role in the classroom.&nbsp; Designing and managing learning experiences that more deeply engage student involvement and accountability elevates a faculty member&rsquo;s responsibility.&nbsp; It may be helpful to explain your role in selecting collaborative learning activities and how you will monitor progress and intervene as necessary to correct and clarify.</p>
<br />
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Moving&nbsp; From &ldquo;What It Is&rdquo; To &ldquo;How We Use It&rdquo;</span></p>
<br />
<p>While it is helpful for students understand the Learning Model on a general level, it will not become significant until the students can see how principles are applied specifically in your course.&nbsp; Some examples and ideas are listed below:</p>
<br /> 
<ul>
<li>After reading an article by Elder Bednar on &ldquo;Learning by Faith&rdquo; students in a math class discuss ways in which students will be expected to &ldquo;exercise faith,&rdquo; &ldquo;act for themselves,&rdquo; and &ldquo;teach one another&rdquo; in your course.&nbsp; The instructor then points out that collaborative board work, team games, and jigsaws are not intended to lighten the instructor&rsquo;s workload, but rather to deepen student learning.&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">The syllabus of a Foundations course shows how the process through the steps of&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Prepare, Teach One Another,&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">and&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Ponder/Prove&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">are reflected in the course rhythm.&nbsp;&nbsp; Such cycles can easily be demonstrated to help students understand the learning patterns involved in class sessions or larger course units (see <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=26">Course Architecture</a>).&nbsp; To clarity the importance of the processes some instructors identify what percentages of their grades are tied&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">to Prepare, Teach One Another,&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">and&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Ponder/Prove&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">activities in the syllabus.&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;">A business professor finds opportunities to address why he is using instructional methods throughout the duration of his course.&nbsp; He explains how these periodic reminders help students step back from&nbsp;</span></em></span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">what&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">they are learning to see&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">how&nbsp;</em></span><span style="display: inline;">they are learning it.&nbsp; Another idea is to point out instances of Learning Model behavior as they happen.&nbsp; For example, if a student uses a scripture, commend him/her for using the principle of &ldquo;laying hold of the word of God.&rdquo;&nbsp; Consistently demonstrating examples helps student make connections between principles and practice&mdash;ultimately helping them learn how to learn better.</span></li>
</ul>
<br />
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Leverage The Language Of The Learning Model.</span></p>
<br />
<p>As President Clark has explained, &ldquo;The Learning Model provides a common framework for learning and teaching that extends across every discipline, course, and learning experience.&nbsp; All will be grounded in a shared approach.&rdquo;&nbsp; By tapping into this common language you can help students better understand why you are using particular teaching methods in a course.</p>
<br />
<p>Furthermore, there is a cumulative payoff in explaining and applying the Learning Model.&nbsp; After being expected to apply the same learning principles in science, religion, and art classes, for example, students begin to get the picture.&nbsp; The constant exposure to these principles over the course of their studies encourages students to take more responsibility for their learning.&nbsp; Our collective efforts to teach &ldquo;what the Learning Model is&rdquo; and &ldquo;how we use it&rdquo; is a powerful means to developing disciple-leaders at BYU-Idaho.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
