<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64190" Name="Faculty Voices: Principle Five" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty Voices: Principle Five</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">I learned that a culture of trust is a difficult thing that must be cultivated at every turn.
Ryan Nielson - Physics</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090226T07:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brian Schmidt</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Steve Hunsaker" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/02-2009/FacultyVoicesPrincipleFive/hunsaker.jpg" vspace="8" />
<p>The Faculty Development Committee recently sponsored two panel discussions on the fifth principle of the Learning Model: &ldquo;Learners and teachers at BYU-Idaho love, serve, and teach one another.&rdquo;  Afterwards participants were asked to reflect on what they learned.  I have summarized these reflections around major themes.  Three of these themes are included in this article.  Additional comments about the panel discussions will be included in subsequent Faculty Voices articles.</p>
<p><em>Steve Hunsaker </em></p>
<br />
<p><strong>The Savior</strong></p>
<br />
<p>It is a natural tendency to fool ourselves into thinking that it is better for the students to listen to me, to listen to what I know, to see what I can see.  Certainly a teacher can &lsquo;disseminate&rsquo; more information if he/she doesn&rsquo;t stop for student input.  Like the Savior, wise teachers realize that less is more (see 3 Nephi 33: 1, 14).  Sure, the students may not &lsquo;get&rsquo; as much information, but what they &lsquo;get&rsquo; they will own and it will actually change their minds and hearts.  That&rsquo;s the kind of teacher I want to be when I grow up.</p>
<p><em>Robert Wahlquist &mdash; Religion </em></p>
<br />
<p>I valued the comment about the power that can bring a class together in a spirit of trust emanating from a teacher who comes before the students as &ldquo;a disciple of Jesus Christ&rdquo; (3 Nephi 5:13). Disciples of Christ (students and teachers) can create an environment of learning that welcomes the comments of all and deepens the desire to serve each other in the class.</p>
<p><em>Jeffery G. Chapman &mdash; Religion </em></p>
<br /> <img align="right" alt="Eric D'Evegnee" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/02-2009/FacultyVoicesPrincipleFive/devegnee.jpg" vspace="8" />
<p>While we strive to help our students engage in the learning process on their own, we need to structure our course so our students have to stretch but not so much that they snap. The assurances we can provide our students in their learning process are vital to them wanting to learn throughout their lives. We should try to work with our students as God works with us. True, He places in mortality to learn on our own, but He also gives us help and assurance as we work out our spiritual learning &ldquo;with fear and trembling&rdquo;.</p>
<p><em>Eric D&rsquo;Evegnee &mdash; English </em></p>
<br />
<p><strong>Trust and Safe Learning Environments</strong></p>
<br />
<p>I learned (1) that being open and vulnerable with my students helps to build trust, (2) that some of my best students are the ones who don&rsquo;t quite trust me completely (i.e., &ldquo;prove me now herewith&rdquo;), and (3) that it is okay to feel that sense of loss at the end of the semester where my students who have finally learned to trust me are now gone (very similar to parenting our own children).</p>
<p><em>Jason Earl &mdash; Business </em></p>
<br />
<p>If you ask for trust, then you need to trust. Be willing to let the student arrive at correct principles at their own pace. Don&rsquo;t hurry the learning process. Don&rsquo;t be impatient.  Trust in the student and their thought process.  The learning environment is a living breathing entity that needs to be carefully and constantly managed. Student feedback through quick, anonymous evaluation helps to determine where your students really are and what they are thinking.</p>
<p><em>Mark Orchard &mdash; Ag Business, Plant and Animal Sciences </em></p>
<br /> <img align="right" alt="Ryan Nielson" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/02-2009/FacultyVoicesPrincipleFive/nielson.jpg" vspace="8" />
<p>I learned that a culture of trust is a difficult thing that must be cultivated at every turn.</p>
<p><em>Ryan Nielson - Physics </em></p>
<br />
<p>It was apparent that developing a rapport with the students&ndash; knowing their names, gaining their trust &ndash; requires a significant amount of time and effort from teachers, as well as, effective classroom presentation. These may be as important, if not more so, than being prepared with adequate content information.</p>
<p><em>Larry Thurgood - Religion </em></p>
<br />
<p>It appears faculty are still too new at the learning model to really share failures. We just want to talk about what works, successes. Perhaps we ought to practice what we expect our students to practice: learning and teaching one another in a spirit of love. Still too much posturing for trust in a workshop like that.</p>
<p><em>Anonymous </em></p>
<br />
<p>I was impressed by the variety of methods that teachers use to foster a classroom environment conducive to using the learning model. I have been having challenges with a class this semester, and I think the brown bag helped me become more aware of the situation and how it is affecting the class.</p>
<p><em>Michael Paul &mdash; Foreign Languages and Literatures </em></p>
<br />
<p>Small and simple acts of kindness are vital to the creation of a nurturing environment. Taking a personal interest in each student, learning their names, learning about their individual lives, laughing and joking with the students, and demonstrating charity in small ways are among the little things that help to establish a culture of trust. As I think about the fifth principle of the learning model, Doctrine and Covenants 64:33 comes to mind: &ldquo;Wherefore, be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. And out of small things proceedeth that which is great.&rdquo;</p>
<p><em>Kevin Galbraith &mdash; Home and Family </em></p>
<br />
<p><strong>Freedom and the Learning Model</strong></p>
<br />
<p>A colleague and I decided that we&rsquo;re glad that, so far, the Learning Model leaves room for personal interpretation and adaptation.  We are entitled to personal inspiration for our classes and can still be ourselves.</p>
<p><em>Brad Garner - Mathematics </em></p>
<br />
<p>There is&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><strong style="display: inline !important;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">not&nbsp;</span></strong></span>&ldquo;one right way.&rdquo; The best ways will be given to us by the spirit.</p>
<p><em>Dean Cloward &mdash; Teacher Education </em></p>
<br />
<p>It is interesting to note that as we develop more trust with our students as far as the Learning Model goes, the students seem to rise to the occasion.  The spirit prompts us to go in a certain direction, and we learn to listen and follow these promptings for the benefit of all.</p>
<p><em>Barbara Baiamonte &mdash; Teacher Education </em></p>
<br /> <img align="right" alt="Kendall Grant" hspace="8" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/02-2009/FacultyVoicesPrincipleFive/grant.jpg" vspace="8" />
<p>I thought we started to approach the learning model as we talked. I&rsquo;ve looked toward the day when we could have an atmosphere of true trust&mdash;I think that it is starting to develop.</p>
<p><em>Kendall Grant - English </em></p>
<br />
<p>I often think that teaching foreign languages is different from other subjects and does not lend itself to many of the innovative principles of the Learning Model.  My perspective was changed as I heard the creative ways in which instructors from a wide range of disciplines have adapted new teaching and learning methods to their disciplines.</p>
<p><em>Kirk A. Widdison&mdash;Foreign Languages and Literatures </em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
