<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64193" Name="The Impact of Learning Model Application on Student Course Evaluations" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Impact of Learning Model Application on Student Course Evaluations</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The greater the presence of a Learning Model trait in a class, the higher the overall instructor rating and the higher the level of perceived learning.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090311T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Scott Bergstrom, Institutional Research</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Scott Bergstrom" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/BergstromS.JPG" style="margin: 25px;" />
<p align="center">&nbsp;</p>
<p>We are  aware that some instructors are concerned that their course evaluations might  be adversely affected by incorporating elements of the Learning Model into  their teaching.&nbsp; The <a href="../../LearningAndTeaching/post/2008/12/Updating-Course-Evaluation-at-BYU-Idaho.aspx">new course evaluation instrument</a>, which has a strong Learning Model orientation, gives  us some preliminary information that might allay this concern.&nbsp; Using questions from the course evaluation  instrument, I created five scales to correspond to the <a href="../../learningandteaching/default.aspx">five elements of  the Learning Model architecture</a> &ndash; Outcomes, Architecture, Prepare, Teach  One Another, and Ponder/Prove.&nbsp;&nbsp; Space  does not permit me to describe each of these scales so I will use the Teach One  Another scale as an example.&nbsp; Student  responses to seven questions from the instrument were used to create the Teach One Another scale:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><em>I was an active participant in online or face-to-face class discussions.</em></li>
<li><em>I sought opportunities to share my learning with others outside of class.</em></li>
<li><em>I feel that I made important contributions to the learning and growth of fellow classmates.</em></li>
<li><em>The course provided opportunities to learn from and teach other students.</em></li>
<li><em>Group work, if assigned, was beneficial and meaningful.</em></li>
<li><em>Students were actively involved in this class through discussions, group work, and teaching.</em></li>
<li><em>The instructor provided appropriate opportunities to be an active participant in the class.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The  scale score derived from these seven questions serves as an indicator of the  extent to which this element of the Learning Model is present in a course.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Using the scores on the Teach One Another scale, I divided all courses that were evaluated in Fall 2008 into four quartiles  representing the degree to which the Teach One Another element of the Learning  Model was present in the course.&nbsp; The  first quartile represents courses in the lowest 25% of the Teach One Another scores,  the second represents the next 25% of courses, and so on.&nbsp; I computed the average overall instructor  rating1 and the average level of perceived learning2 for  each quartile group of courses.&nbsp; The  results of this analysis are in Figures 1 and 2.</p>
<div align="center"><img alt="Instructor Rating" border="2" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/03-2009/impact/instructorRating.jpg" style="margin: 10px;" />
<p>Figure 1.  The average overall instructor rating for each quartile of the Teach One Another scale.</p>
<img alt="Level of Perceived Learning" border="2" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/03-2009/impact/levelOfLearning.jpg" style="margin: 10px;" />
<p>Figure 2.  The average level of perceived learning for each quartile of the Teach One Another scale.</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As shown in Figure 1, the overall instructor rating rises steadily from the 1st to the 4th quartile.  The difference between the bottom and top quartiles is 1.34 points, a rather large (and statistically significant) difference.  As shown in Figure 2, the level of perceived learning rises sharply from the 1st to the 2nd quartile and then steadily upward thereafter.  The top quartile average level of perceived learning is more than three times larger than the bottom quartile average!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The pattern seems clear for both measures.&nbsp;  The higher the presence of the Teach One Another element in a course,  the higher the overall instructor rating and the greater the level of perceived  learning.&nbsp; My analysis showed that this same  pattern holds true for all five elements of the Learning Model:&nbsp; <strong>the  greater the presence of a Learning Model trait in a class, the higher the  overall instructor rating and the higher the level of perceived learning<span style="font-weight: normal; display: inline;">.</span></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is a very preliminary analysis and more work needs to be done before we can draw  firm conclusions.&nbsp; In the first place,  this a correlational analysis.&nbsp; We do not  know if there is a causal relationship at work.&nbsp;  Do Learning Model activities make effective teachers or are effective  teachers more likely to use Learning Model activities?&nbsp; Second, there may be other factors and traits  that are more influential on the overall instructor rating or on the level of  perceived learning.&nbsp; Is there a halo  effect in play here wherein teachers who are popular and courses that are well-liked  yield high scores on all questions no matter what?&nbsp; We simply do not know from this preliminary  analysis how influential Learning Model traits are on these selected measures.&nbsp; The presence of such a pronounced effect connected  with Learning Model practices compels further examination.&nbsp; Third, the power of the indicators being used  remains to be determined.&nbsp; For example,  do the seven items that make up the Teach One Another scale really provide a  good measure of the presence of that trait in a class?&nbsp; Are there better indicators of the Teach One  Another trait?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the  spirit of the scholarship of teaching and learning, I am hopeful that some instructors  will experiment with a well-defined learning model practice and see if there are  any changes in the course evaluations or, more importantly, in overall student  learning and growth.&nbsp; For example,  several members of the Physics faculty have conducted pre- and post-test  student assessments comparing the impact of different peer- and problem-based  teaching innovations.&nbsp; Such experiments  may provide us with compelling evidence of Learning Model effects, beyond what  we can derive from course evaluation data.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the very least, it is exciting that this  first empirical look at Learning Model practices implies a positive relationship  with the overall instructor rating and the level of perceived learning.&nbsp; It also suggests that, in general, teachers will  not be penalized by students for using elements of the Learning Model in their  classes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><sup>1&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 14px; display: inline;">The overall instructor rating is derived from the item which asks</span></sup><em>What is your overall  rating of this&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;"><strong style="display: inline !important;">instructor?</strong></em></span><span style="display: inline;">Responses are on the following 7-point scale:&nbsp;</span></em><em>very  poor (1), poor (2), fair (3), good (4), very good (5), excellent (6), and  exceptional (7).</em></p>
<p><sup>2&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 14px; display: inline;">The level of perceived learning is derived from the item which asks</span></sup><em>Compared to other college courses you have  taken, would you say that you have learned<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;"><strong style="display: inline !important;">:&nbsp;</strong></em></span>a great deal less (-2), a little less (-1),  about the same (0), a little more (1), and a great deal more (2).</em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
