<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64196" Name="Physics Professor Tracks Action Research Results" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Physics Professor Tracks Action Research Results</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">While the diagnostic tool was not designed specifically to measure the effectiveness of changes I make in the classroom, it does provide a nice cross-check of the comprehensive classroom experience which I can compare with my own observations from my daily interactions with the students.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090415T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brian Schmidt</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<img align="left" alt="Evan Hansen" height="170" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/HansenEv.JPG" style="margin: 25px;" width="120" />
<p>Physics professor Evan Hansen is a driven person &ndash; data-driven that is.&nbsp; Like many of us, Evan has been experimenting with small changes to his instructional assumptions and methods over the past several years as the college has sought to promote ever-increasing instructional excellence.&nbsp; And, like many of us, Evan wondered what, if anything, the initiatives around instructional development would mean for him in his courses.&nbsp;&nbsp; As both a scientist and an already popular and successful teacher, it made little sense to Evan to simply change for change&rsquo;s sake.&nbsp; Evan&rsquo;s mantra that &ldquo;We must revise our working models when confronted with new data, but would be wise not to prematurely reject them&rdquo; seemed to apply in this case, and so he set about to gather some data.</p>
<br />
<p>Even though Evan was already aware of much of the research and data driving the ideas that the Learning Model seeks to promote, he wondered how a conscious focus on these ideas might change student learning in&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">his&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">classes.&nbsp; So he did what most of us have thought about, but only few have actually done: Action Research.&nbsp; Action research is an idea that emerged from the literature around&nbsp;</span></em></span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">The Scholarship of Learning and Teaching</em></span><span style="display: inline;">, which urges professors to apply the research skills they honed during graduate work to their current work as professional educators.</span></p>
<br />
<p>Using a well-designed (normed and tested for reliability and validity) national diagnostic exam of physics concepts, Evan obtained baseline data on his courses by pre-testing students, and then assessing them again at the end of the semester with the same instrument.&nbsp; He began to track pre- and post- student performance on this instrument, semester by semester as he implemented a series of changes in the classroom.&nbsp; By only introducing one independent variable at a time, Evan was able to track changes in student performance against the baseline with some level of assurance that any changes noted could be, in large part or at least attributed to, the introduction of the new variable.&nbsp; The data was analyzed against the original baseline data, but also as a trend line comparing each semester performance on the test to the following semester.</p>
<br />
<p>The first change introduced to the Basic Physics course involved the adoption of&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;"><a href="../../learningandteaching/tools/tool.aspx?ToolID=40">concept tests</a>&nbsp;</em></span>where the lecture is regularly interrupted by posing a conceptual problem for students based on the material just covered (Eric Mazur.&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Peer Instruction</em></span>, 1997, Prentice Hall).&nbsp; Students are asked to choose a solution to the problem from a multiple choice list and then defend their selection to their neighbor trying either to convince the neighbor of the correctness of the choice, or to find the faulty thinking in their own decision.&nbsp; This process lasts 3-5 minutes and is repeated for every 10-15 minutes of lecture.</p>
<br />
<p>After several semesters, Evan next introduced some&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">structural changes&nbsp;</em></span>to his course and course assignments based on <a href="../../learningandteaching/tools/tool.aspx?ToolID=2">Learning Model Architecture</a>.&nbsp; The changes focused around more clearly defining&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Prepare&nbsp;</em></span>expectations and assignments for students, and around creating more collaborative learning, or&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Teach One Another&nbsp;</em></span>opportunities for students, both within the class and out.</p>
<br />
<p>Finally, Evan integrated the use of peer facilitators into his syllabus.&nbsp; Using peer facilitators involves using upper level physics education majors or physics majors to help facilitate small group activities.&nbsp; The activities are drawn from a series called&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Tutorials in Introductory Physics</em></span>, by Lillian C. McDermott and Peter S. Shaffer designed to address well-known student misconceptions in introductory physics.</p>
<br />
<p>The data flowing from six semesters of Action Research are below:</p>
<br />
<div align="center"><img alt="Graph 1" height="304" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/04-2009/physicsprofessor/graph1.JPG" style="margin: 7px; border: initial solid initial;" width="526" /> <br /> <img alt="Graph 2" height="294" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/04-2009/physicsprofessor/graph2.JPG" style="margin: 7px; border: initial solid initial;" width="526" /></div>
<br />
<p>While action research, by its very nature, is limited because of the number of students involved in a course and by the difficulty of controlling for all variables and possible covariance, results like these are encouraging even with all the caveats.&nbsp; Notwithstanding the limitations of the data, Evan values the very concrete measure that the diagnostic gives of the success experienced by individual students as they master the concepts of physics. Of the data he&rsquo;s collected so far, Evan says:</p>
<br />
<blockquote>While the diagnostic tool was not designed specifically to measure the effectiveness of changes I make in the classroom, it does provide a nice cross-check of the comprehensive classroom experience which I can compare with my own observations from my daily interactions with the students.</blockquote>
<br />
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">I recognize learning is very complex and that in addition to using this data, I must look beyond the numbers.&nbsp; And, I have seen benefits of the changes I&rsquo;ve made that are not measured by the test, namely an increased ability [on the part of the students] to step out beyond their current knowledge and skill level.</p>
</blockquote>
<br />
<p>We look forward to hearing more from Evan in the future as he continues tweaking his course and looking for ways to test the results.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
