<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64175" Name="Appropriate group meeting" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Appropriate Group Meeting</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">News articles</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="76" Height="53" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">instructional-development/090604Students-laptop_39(0)1.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20110610T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brian Schmidt</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Amy Hanks recalls a chemistry student who complained because he was assigned to a female lab partner.&nbsp; "He told me that working with women violated his temple covenants to his wife.&nbsp; I gently suggested he try working with this fellow student for a few weeks and if he still had issues to talk to me.&nbsp; He never came back to me-so I think it worked out."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Collaborative group work will not go away when students leave BYU-Idaho.&nbsp; To be successful in their careers, students must to learn how to navigate professional relationships.&nbsp; "Teach One Another" learning activities at BYU-Idaho can help students develop good habits that will assist them in the workforce.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If some of your assignments involve group work, consider discussing the implications of different meeting locations.&nbsp; Clearly some places are better than others.&nbsp; For example, apartments, homes, and secluded rooms on campus can create awkward situations-especially when students of the opposite sex are paired.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When balancing the need for undisturbed work space with openness, our campus has many options ranging from the 1,200 seat Crossroads Food Court to over forty group study rooms available in the McKay Library or Manwaring Center.&nbsp; Students are welcome to walk-in and use any unscheduled study room on a first-come first-served basis in these two buildings.&nbsp; To schedule a room (up to two days in advance), students can visit this website at the&nbsp; <a href="http://host4.evanced.info/byui/evanced/roomrequest.asp?mm=1">Mckay Library</a> or register with the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/eventservices/">Scheduling Office</a> to schedule space in the Manwaring Center.&nbsp; Additionally, learning commons and open labs are situated in several buildings throughout campus.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If one member of a student group can't meet physically with the rest of the group, that student can join virtually.&nbsp; A few common virtual conferencing tools are: <br /> <br /></p>
<p>&middot;<a href="http://www.skype.com/intl/en-us/home">Skype</a>.&nbsp; Pros: Free (for the basic service).&nbsp; Simple to use.&nbsp; Cons: Requires all users to have Skype accounts.&nbsp; Software must be downloaded and installed.&nbsp; Allows only 2-way connection.</p>
<p>&middot;<a href="http://www.google.com/support/chat/bin/answer.py?answer=159499">Google Video Chat</a>.&nbsp; Pros: Free. Small learning curve.&nbsp; Cons: Users must have a Google account and be listed in contacts.&nbsp; Plug-in needs to be downloaded and installed.&nbsp; Allows only 2-way connection.</p>
<p>&middot;<a href="http://www.learncentral.org/user/vroomreg">Elluminate vRoom</a>.&nbsp; Similar to the two above, but it allows 3 users to be connected.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our campus also has a license for <a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/adobeconnect.html">Adobe Connect</a>&nbsp; which allows larger groups of students to meet with additional features.&nbsp; This is most commonly used with Online Courses, but if needed, <a href="http://www.byui.edu/onlinelearning/create/connect_req.htm">group meetings</a> can be scheduled for campus courses if situations warrant.&nbsp; The <a href="http://www.byui.edu/ATS/training.htm">Faculty Technology Center</a> in the Library can answer questions about this technology and additional options.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho has numerous options available for student meetings.&nbsp; As students collaborate with group projects or activities, we can help them choose appropriate meeting locations to foster learning and prepare them for professional relationships in their careers.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
