<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64198" Name="Real Issues: Concerns Surfaced in Recent Student Survey" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Real Issues: Concerns Surfaced in Recent Student Survey</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Student understanding of the Learning Model is increasing. A winter semester survey found that 55% of the student body could identify the principles and process steps of the Learning Model (up from 38% in the fall).</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090507T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Brian Schmidt and Clark Gilbert</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Hand Over the Class</strong></p>
<img align="left" alt="Brian Schmidt" height="170" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/SchmidtB.jpg" style="margin: 15px;" width="120" /> <img align="left" alt="Clark Gilbert" height="170" src="http://pictures.byui.edu/EmpPix/GilbertC.jpg" style="margin: 15px;" width="120" />
<p><strong><br /></strong></p>
<br />
<p>With the advent of the Learning Model we have sent messages encouraging faculty to have students take more responsibility in the classroom through the use of collaborative learning activities. But with that encouragement we have also cautioned that&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Teach One Another&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">does not entail handing the class over to students. A recent student survey found that while most students report positive perceptions towards the Learning Model, many are concerned about the role of the instructor. This article shares some additional data from this student survey and addresses the importance of structuring Teach One Another activities.</span></em></span></p>
<br /> <img alt="Graph" border="1" height="322" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/05-2009/class/graph.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 10px;" width="255" />
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Students Are Catching the Vision</span></strong></p>
<br />
<p>Student understanding of the Learning Model is increasing. A winter semester survey found that 55% of the student body could identify the principles and process steps of the Learning Model (up from 38% in the fall). Additionally, students reported learning more in courses where principles of the Learning Model are practiced. They commented that the Learning Model helps them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Come to class better prepared</li>
<li>Feel more responsible</li>
<li>Be more engaged</li>
<li>Remember more</li>
</ul>
<br />
<p>The following statement was typical: &ldquo;Coming prepared to class every day helps me better understand the principles that are being taught, and taking an active role in teaching enables me to keep information in my mind longer.&rdquo; Not surprisingly, positive student evaluations tended to correlate with courses in which students recognized Learning Model implementation.</p>
<br />
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Don&rsquo;t Hand Over the Class</span></strong></p>
<br />
<p>Student enthusiasm for the Learning Model, however, was tempered by several concerns. Chief among them is a fear that some faculty will completely relinquish the instructional role to the students. As one student commented, &ldquo;I think that the Learning Model is a great idea, but I worry about how it is sometimes being implemented. There are some classes where I am sent on a wild adventure to find my own curriculum&hellip;there could be more structure.&rdquo; These student concerns center around the role of the instructor&mdash;or the perceived lack of it. Most students recognize that they need to take responsibility to more deeply engage and participate in their learning. Most recognize that collaborative learning activities are one way to foster that engagement. Students, however, do not want faculty to disappear from the learning process. As experts in the material, instructors need to design&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Teach One Another&nbsp;</em></span>activities in ways that allow monitoring, involvement, and redirection.</p>
<br />
<p>Other concerns appearing frequently in the student survey include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Overdependence on Student Presentations.</strong> Students feel that some classes are based almost entirely upon student presentations. As one student explained, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m only getting information from presentations which I could easily learn by myself on Wikipedia.&rdquo; Another student echoed, &ldquo;With so many presentations (to give everyone an opportunity to participate over the semester), we never had time to ask or discuss questions&mdash;this was especially frustrating after 30 &lsquo;un-insightful&rsquo; presentations.&rdquo; Simply replacing all faculty lectures with student presentations does not deepen learning. The purpose of Teach One Another activities is not to replace a qualified professor with an unqualified student as the source of information. Rather, it is to allow students to more actively engage the material, to articulate it in their own terms, and verbalize their understanding to others. The judicious use of student presentations can have very positive results if the material is focused with faculty feedback prior to the presentation.</li>
<li><strong>Unstructured Group Work.</strong> Student conversation does not necessarily lead to learning. As one student explained, &ldquo;group work can be ineffective because they (the students) are not easily focused. Most of the time only one or two students do all the work. Some feel that it is the perfect time to flirt and talk.&rdquo; Most students see the value in group work but struggle to keep the dialogue focused. They need the instructor to structure collaborative activities with specific processes and outcomes. The <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=53">Learning in Groups</a> tool offers ideas on how to structure roles, accountability, and evaluation to address student concerns about unproductive use of time.</li>
<li><strong>Lack of Intervention or Redirection.</strong> Finally an underlying theme in student comments relates to faculty supervision and feedback. Students worry that as they teach one another, &ldquo;the teacher [will] not feel that they need to teach anything.&rdquo; Addressing this issue brings up a difficult tension. Sometimes ambiguity is specifically designed into the learning experience to foster student discovery. On the other hand, if the learning process is so ambiguous that students get off track and become lost, they don&rsquo;t learn anything. Instructors need to be willing and ready to intervene, correct and guide students in a productive fashion. The <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=35">role of faculty</a> is critical in establishing clear boundaries and outcomes that lead to successful collaborative activities.</li>
</ul>
<br />
<p>While students have raised concerns around the practice of some Learning Model principles, their overall feedback is positive. Both faculty and students are learning how to better apply Learning Model principles in BYU-Idaho classes as they clarify their respective roles and mutual responsibilities in the learning process. As one student explained &ldquo;I am more prepared in my classes and I really feel like I am learning not just because I am in school, but because I am doing the action of learning myself. It isn't thrust upon me... I have been more prepared &hellip; and I am more confident in giving answers to questions that come up in class. I am a better learner because of the Learning Model.&rdquo;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
