<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64213" Name="“Pastures of Learning”" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">“Pastures of Learning”</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A pasture is an adept analogy to guide us as we plan and structure our instruction.  Several BYU-Idaho faculty members have adopted the analog of pastures as a means for structuring their lesson plans.  Some of their comments can be viewed by clicking on the picture/video link below.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20091007T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Devan Barker</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[In the early eighteenth century, the poet and essayist Joseph Addison, drawing on imagery taken from the 23<span style="font-size: 8px; display: inline;">rd &nbsp;</span>psalm, wrote a text comparing the Lord's interactions with us to a shepherd preparing a pasture.&nbsp; The text to this poem has become a beloved Christian hymn, but as a study in preparing an environment for learning and growth, it offers a remarkably apt analogy for thinking about instructional planning.&nbsp;
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0" width="483">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p>The Lord my pasture shall prepare<br /> And feed me with a shepherd's   care;<br /> His presence shall my wants supply<br /> And guard me with a watchful eye;<br /> My noonday walks He shall attend<br /> And all my midnight hours defend.</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Though in the paths of death I   tread,<br /> With gloomy horrors overspread,<br /> My steadfast heart shall fear no ill,<br /> For Thou, O Lord, art with me still;<br /> Thy friendly crook shall give me aid<br /> And guide me through the dreadful shade.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When in the sultry glebe I faint<br /> Or on the thirsty mountain pant,<br /> To fertile vales and dewy meads<br /> My weary, wandering steps He leads,<br /> Where peaceful rivers, soft and slow,<br /> Amid the verdant landscape flow.</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Though in a bare and rugged way,<br /> Through devious lonely wilds, I stray,<br /> Thy bounty shall my pains beguile;<br /> The barren wilderness shall smile,<br /> With sudden greens and herbage crowned,<br /> And streams shall murmur all around.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p align="left">A pasture is an adept analogy to guide us as we plan and structure our instruction.&nbsp; Several BYU-Idaho faculty members have adopted the analog of pastures as a means for structuring their lesson plans.&nbsp; Some of their comments can be viewed by clicking on the picture/video link below.</p>
<p align="left">&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/resources/video/pastures1/pastnew.html"><img align="left" alt=" " height="289" hspace="15" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/09-2009/picture1.png" style="padding-right: 5px;" title=" " width="323" /></a></p>
<p>Pastures are used by herdsmen to allow their animals to graze while restricting them to a particular area. Fences keep the animals from wandering and give them a protected place to gain nourishment. Once the best foliage is exhausted within the enclosure, the animals are transitioned to a new pasture to avoid overgrazing of the field.<br /> <br /></p>
<p>Like a shepherd who knows the best pastures for his sheep, instructors accompany and guide students through carefully chosen fields of inquiry.&nbsp;Some insights about lesson planning gleaned from this analogy are as follows:<br /> <br /></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Choose and Fence the pasture:</strong> When you determine your pastures, consider the      following:&nbsp; Is the pasture aligned with the learning objectives of      the course? Will it provide learning that will build upon student      preparation? Are key ideas, key questions and key problems clearly      structuring the inquiry?&nbsp;&nbsp;Explain the focus and parameters of      your dialogue. Assign boundaries to the conversation so it has logical      structure and a natural flow and momentum.<br /> <br /> <br /> </li>
<li><strong>Find the gate:</strong> Just as important as defining what pasture to engage, is the decision of      your approach.&nbsp; Finding the gate means determining what question you      want to answer as a result of your engagement with the material.&nbsp;      What is the problem you wish to resolve?&nbsp; What polemic frames your      approach to the new material? A book could be good material in a thousand      different contexts; which context defines your reason for choosing the      book or the topic? Is there a better approach to helping students capture      these ideas? <br /> <br /> <br /> </li>
<li><strong>Graze on what's green:</strong> It's easy to over-discuss or over-graze a topic. Don't      graze one spot bare while leaving the rest of the green pasture      untouched.&nbsp; Encourage students to explore the key concepts of the      whole pasture and then discuss the ideas from different angles and      perspectives.<br /> <br /> <br /> <strong> </strong> <ol>
<li><strong>Allow freedom within the boundaries:</strong> Provide people reasonable room to explore and deepen       their understanding within the topic while at the same time structuring       their experience within the pasture.&nbsp; Random wandering is no better       for real engagement than is a lock-step march through new material.       Provide students both structure and freedom.<br /> <br /> <br /> </li>
<li><strong>Bring back the strays: </strong>When people wander out of boundaries with tangential       comments or questions, guide them back with questions that redirect the       conversation.&nbsp; For those who insist upon walking the fence-line,       remind them of the ideas or questions central to the inquiry.<br /> <br /> <br /> </li>
<li><strong>&nbsp;Move on when the nourishment is exhausted:</strong> At a given point, the learning value of an activity       becomes greatly diminished. Recognize this point of diminishing returns.       Rather than pursuing every detail and loose end, close the gate behind       you and discuss how the ideas explored in that pasture prepare students       for the next pasture.<br /> <br /> <br /> </li>
</ol> </li>
<li><strong>Transition between pastures:</strong> The relationship between the ideas in one pasture and      those of the next is often just as important as the ideas within each pasture.&nbsp;      Be sure to lead the students from one learning pasture to the next in a      way that emphasizes how the two are related. Sequence your pastures in a      way that builds a logical momentum into your exploration. Below are      several resource links for lesson planning using&nbsp;pastures.<br /> <br /> </li>
</ul>
<p><br /> <a href="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/resources/Lesson%20Plan%20with%20pastures%202.doc"> Lesson Plan Template Incorporating Pastures #1</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/resources/lessontemplatewithpastures.doc"> Lesson Plan Template Incorporating Pastures #2</a></p>
<p><a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=24"> Learning and Teaching Website Tool on Lesson Planning</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
