<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64203" Name="Faculty Voices: Todd Lines" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Faculty Voices: Todd Lines</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Mercy or Sanity? Managing Student Late Work</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090604T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Todd Lines</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><img alt="Todd Lines" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/authorpics/linest.jpg" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" /><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Mercy or Sanity?</strong><br /> <strong>Managing Student Late Work</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In  my second year teaching at BYU-Idaho I ran into a dilemma.</p>
<p><br /> The pre-med students that I teach  need to take the Medical College Admissions Test (MCAT) early in their  undergraduate experience so that they can meet medical school application  deadlines.&nbsp; This means that pre-med students  regularly carry large credit hour loads in order to complete all of their  science classes as well as their major courses.&nbsp;  It&rsquo;s a difficult situation -- requiring students to take three or four  rigorous science classes each semester for several years.&nbsp; These individuals tend to be good students,  but they are very busy so getting behind is almost inevitable for some.<br /> <br /> How I initially dealt with the  situation was a fantastic failure.&nbsp; I was  faced with students who were bright, but overscheduled.&nbsp; I knew they  needed experience with the material to pass the MCAT, so I wanted to be flexible  with due dates. I thought of this as applying the principle of mercy to my  teaching.&nbsp; I made the mistake of letting  a few students turn in assignments late. The trickle turned to a flood and soon  the situation was out of control.&nbsp; I found myself unable to handle the  grading load of these late assignments because I was required to review each of  them individually instead of being able to correct the work in class as groups.  Additionally, students did not receive feedback in time to benefit them for the  exams.&nbsp; I was on campus at all hours of  the day and night working on correcting assignments.&nbsp; My family never saw me, and my health and  church service suffered as well. &nbsp;My  attempt to be merciful on due dates wasn&rsquo;t really helping them learn, and it  was making my life miserable.&nbsp; No one was  happy with the situation.<br /> One semester of this experience was  enough to convince me that something had to change. I still wanted to be understanding  of the students&rsquo; situation, and merciful towards them when possible regarding  due dates, but not at the expense of my health or the students&rsquo;  education.&nbsp; I needed a new approach. <br /> <br /> As I mulled over the dilemma, I set  three criteria for the new method:</p>
<ul>
<li>I wanted to  be able to show mercy, but not at the expense of my family and church calling  time. </li>
<li>I also  wanted to be able to talk one-on-on to the students so they could learn something  positive from the negative experience of having fallen behind in their work. </li>
<li>Finally, I  wanted them to identify and fix the cause of the problem so they did not repeat  the mistake.</li>
</ul>
For an answer, I decided to draw on  my past experience as a manager of many freshly minted engineers.<br /> <br /> It wasn&rsquo;t unusual for new engineering  employees to find themselves getting behind on their first projects. Their  method of dealing with this was almost always to hide from their project  manager until the project due date, when they just could not avoid the issue any  longer. When confronted by their project manager, they generally would admit  that they were very behind but would not offer a revised schedule or articulate  any plan for getting the project back on track.<br /> <br /> It took a bit of coaching to help  them see that a much better approach was to notify the project manager well in  advance of the due date that there was likely a schedule problem.&nbsp; At the  same time they identified the potential problem, they needed to approach the  project manager with a plan for how to accomplish the required work and with an  estimate of what additional resources (more time, help from other employees,  better tools, etc.) would be required.<br /> <br /> This method offered the supervisor a  choice between several options:   
<ul>
<li>Come up with  his/her own plan</li>
<li>Find someone  else to do the job and start over</li>
<li>Accept the  employee&rsquo;s plan</li>
</ul>
Generally if the employee had  analyzed the situation well, s/he had some idea what it would take to do the  job. The project manager rarely had extra people that could be asked to take  the project and start from scratch, nor did s/he usually want to come up with  his/her own plan, so the project manager was highly motivated to accept a  reasonable proposal. Working with the employee&rsquo;s proposed revisions for the job  was usually the best way to get the job done.<br /> <br /> In the case of those new engineers  who followed this procedure, I observed several important improvements:  
<ul>
<li>The job got done </li>
<li>The employee  suffered less personal cost</li>
<li>Both the  supervisor and the employee were happier at performance review time</li>
</ul>
I thought I might be able to apply a  similar strategy to my problem with students getting behind. My hope was that  if successful, this would not only solve my problem with late assignments, but  would also teach a strategy to the students for use in similar situations they  might face later in life. My hope was that these students would not have to  learn this lesson as new, young employees when their family&rsquo;s livelihood might  depend on the outcome.<br /> <br /> So here&rsquo;s what I tried: I developed a  one-page contract that my students can fill out and present to me when they get  behind. The contract requires the student to state what work they will do, set  a due date, and assign a percentage of the original grade that will be applied  to the late work. This must be done <em>before</em> they approach me about the problem. The contract also requires the student to  build a plan for changing their behavior so they will not get behind in the  future.&nbsp; Because I want them to form this plan, I don&rsquo;t accept late  homework without the contract, and I generally don&rsquo;t accept the contract if the  student has already done the late work. &nbsp;(There is already a standard penalty for late  work in my syllabus that covers situations where the student just turns in  something late without talking to me in advance. It is a 50% reduction in value  per lecture day.)<br /> The student brings their draft  contract to me and we discuss it. Generally I end up sending them away to revise  the contract because they have given little thought to how they will change so  the lateness problem does not recur. I don&rsquo;t want them saving their grade in my  class at the expense of another class, so a good plan is important if the student&rsquo;s  underlying problem is to be resolved. By the time students develop and propose  a plan in the contract, and come to my office to talk with me about it, the  process has defined a way for me to show some mercy to students in a difficult  situation, but at the same time insure that the student will not need more  mercy in the future.<br /> So far this has been much more  successful than my first attempt.&nbsp; There are still details to work out in the  system. For example, I have learned that allowing a student to negotiate too  high a percentage for the late work is not good, but too little is not  motivating enough to convince them to go through the difficult process of  planning how to catch up and stay on top of their assignments.&nbsp; Only time  will tell if this approach is successful in preparing students for their future  careers, but so far I have been much happier, less stressed, and my family no  longer comments on how much I&rsquo;ve changed since they last saw me.<br /> <br /> Below is an example of the form I&rsquo;m  currently using: <br /> <img alt="Recovery Pass" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/06-2009/RecoveryPass.jpg" style="margin: 15px;" />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
