<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64215" Name="Principles, Processes and Practices of the BYU-Idaho Learning Model" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Principles, Processes and Practices of the BYU-Idaho Learning Model</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">How do instructors become better teachers? In like manner to the students, they seek to implement Learning Model principles.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20091022T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Daniel Baird and Devan Barker</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p align="center">&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There's been a good bit of discussion on campus recently about whether the techniques associated with the Learning Model have come to overshadow its underlying principles. Stated another way, what should be the relationship between the principles, processes and practices of the learning Model? It's a good question and deserves some significant thought. Elder Scott counsels us that the distinction between principles and attendant processes and practices, is an important one to make.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>As you seek spiritual knowledge, search for principles. Carefully separate them from the detail used to explain them. Principles are concentrated truth, packaged for application to a wide variety of circumstances. A true principle makes decisions clear even under the most confusing and compelling circumstances. It is worth great effort to organize the truth we gather to simple statements</em> of principle.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Richard G. Scott</p>
<p align="right">&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Learning Model articulates 5 principles that set a BYU-Idaho education apart and help us, as a university, define success in learning and teaching. They are that learners and teachers at BYU-Idaho:</p>
<p>1) &nbsp;Exercise faith in the Lord Jesus Christ as a principle of action and power.</p>
<p>2) &nbsp;Understand that true teaching is done by and with the Holy Ghost</p>
<p>3) &nbsp;Lay hold upon the word of God - as found in the Holy Scriptures and in the words of the prophets - in all disciplines.</p>
<p>4) &nbsp;Act for themselves and accept responsibility for learning and teaching</p>
<p>5) &nbsp;Love, serve and teach one another.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Since, as Elder Scott indicates, the principles are the foundation of everything, then why worry about specific applications, teaching methods or set processes? If the principles list the necessary conditions for successful learning and teaching at BYU-Idaho, aren't they also sufficient? Is there need for anything else?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>An analogy from the scriptures might be useful at this point. Matthew 22:40 teaches us that all the laws and the gospel hang on two relatively simple principles of loving God and loving one's neighbor as one's self. Yet Christ himself gave us a multitude of secondary principles, specific commandments, inspired processes and even detailed practices that make up gospel living. The principles are clearly the foundation to the rest, but the rest offer us a supporting structure built on that foundation to aid and guide us in our attempts to live according to the principles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The situation is not dissimilar from the Learning Model. In addition to the Learning Model principles, certain processes and practices have been defined to help us achieve the learning and teaching we seek. These are not a replacement for, but an extension to and a support for the implementation of the principles. The principles define the necessary foundation. The secondary principles, processes and practices build the support structure sufficient to help insure good learning and teaching.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How do students become better learners? Clearly they seek to apply the 5 Learning Model principles. In practice, however, that could mean countless different things. As they search for ways to implement the principles, many students find it helpful to have a <em>process</em> which gives them a framework and guide. The process steps of <em>Prepare, Teach One Another, and Ponder and Prove</em> offer students the most rudimentary of frameworks in which they can begin to "love, serve and teach," or "lay hold on the word of God." etc. Once they become more skilled at connecting the principles to individual learning situations, the process steps become either automatic or superfluous.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How do instructors become better teachers? In like manner to the students, they seek to implement Learning Model principles. Along the way, however, they think systematically about design and purpose and the student experience. For instructors, therefore, the Learning Model includes two steps -- <em>Outcomes and Architecture - </em>to the three which describe the student experience. In this way, the principles and processes defined by the Learning Model act as a framework and guide for deciding what to do when instructing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The principles and processes of the Learning Model have been articulated institutionally so that they serve as a shared language and point of reference for the entire campus community. How the principles and processes are applied in real-time, however, is left largely to the judgment and expertise of the individual instructor. While the Learning Model certainly leans in certain directions, <em>it does not mandate any particular instructional practice</em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img align="middle" alt="Table comparing Principles, Processes and Practices of the Learning Model" height="311" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/10-2009/principlesmodel.png" style="width: 551px; height: 311px;" title="Table comparing Principles, Processes and Practices of the Learning Model" width="551" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The power of the principle is never completely captured by the process. The potential of a process is never fully realized by the practice. But, we get to the practical implementation end of things by some means other than trial and error while remaining true to the principles. Let's take a closer look...</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Principles, by definition, do not carry with them instructions for implementation. They are not directions or recipes. The idea that we should love one another is a foundational principle. Yet even with the strength and truth of that principle, it takes most of us a lifetime to really get good at implementation. In the case of our families, most of us eventually figure out what to say, what not to say, which gifts will be appreciated and which won't, etc. There are several things that help us so that learning to implement the principle isn't completely a process of trial and error. The first is individual and hopefully inspired judgement or wisdom. We look at a situation and do our best to find wise ways to implement the principle of love. The next way is that we rely on processes. We copy good patterns we've seen in other families. We schedule regular date nights. We count to ten. We use occasions like birthdays and anniversaries to prompt us when our natural ingenuity doesn't stretch quite far enough. Inspiration, Judgement and Processes help us bridge the gap from principle to practice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center"><em>Inspiration, Judgement, and Process</em> connect and relate <em>Principle</em> and <em>Practice</em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So what's the upshot of all this?</p>
<p>1)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Learning Model <em>Principles</em> are the foundation of the inspired learning and teaching we desire as a campus community.</p>
<p>2)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Individual instructional <em>practices</em> are of no value if used willy-nilly without understanding what they're trying to accomplish. (Teamwork may or may not be appropriate depending on what we're hoping to accomplish. The same is true of case studies, student presentations or class discussion.) We therefore have the need of principled guidance in our choice of practices.</p>
<p>3)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Personal inspiration and wise judgement born of experience are required as we try to implement good gospel and instructional principles in a multitude of different situations and contexts. This is the art of teaching.</p>
<p>4)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Recourse to well-developed <em>processes</em> can help guide us in determining how to best apply principles or when to use specific practices. This is particularly true if the processes are based on what's been learned from master teachers and those who study the art of teaching.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>All the important power lies in the <em>principles</em> and to a lesser degree, the applied <em>practices</em>. The <em>processes</em> which bridge them are extremely useful, but eventually destined to be internalized or replaced with wisdom accumulated through experience. The 5 principles of the Learning Model define the <em>necessary</em> conditions for successful BYU-Idaho learning and teaching experience, but by themselves, they do not provide a <em>sufficient</em> support structure for such learning. Secondary principles of good pedagogy, sound processes and tried-and-true practices have a role to play as well when built upon firm, first principles. And there will ever be a role for inspiration and individual judgement.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
