<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x64201" Name="New Tools to Fill the Gap" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">New Tools to Fill the Gap</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">In an attempt to offer the ‘big picture’ for two foundational process steps of the Learning Model, we’re introducing two new tools: The Process for Defining Outcomes, and A Course Architecture Process.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="80" Height="80" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">new_image_structure/FPO_Images/FPO_Small_Thumbnail.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" Width="" Height="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment=""/></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20090529T06:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Your Name</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever felt like the Learning Model gives you a destination but no map? Or maybe it&rsquo;s felt like puzzle pieces with no picture on the box? None of us has time to take dozens of instructional puzzle pieces and attempt to put them together into a coherent picture for teaching without further help.&nbsp; We need the picture on the box which tells us what pieces we&rsquo;re looking for and how they might fit into the whole.&nbsp; Or, to return to the first analogy, we need the map.<br /> <br /> Over the past several months, we&rsquo;ve been reviewing the tools currently on the <a href="../../learningandteaching/default.aspx">Learning and Teaching website</a> to make corrections and incorporate faculty suggestions.&nbsp; In doing this, it became apparent that while the overview tools provide an introduction to concepts and a discussion of general principles, and while other tools provide specific instructions for particular techniques, there was a conspicuous lack of tools that showed how it all fit together. &nbsp;We were missing the map to the whole.&nbsp; This was especially true of the two process steps that most involve faculty planning: <em>Outcomes&nbsp;<span style="display: inline;">and&nbsp;</span><span style="display: inline;"><em style="display: inline !important;">Architecture</em></span><span style="display: inline;">. &nbsp;</span></em> <br /> In an attempt to offer the &lsquo;big picture&rsquo; for two foundational process steps of the Learning Model, we&rsquo;re introducing two new tools: <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=54">The Process for Defining Outcomes</a>, and <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=62">A Course Architecture Process</a>.&nbsp; These tools offer little new information about outcomes or about course architecture.&nbsp; What they do offer, however, is an answer to the question, &ldquo;so how do I actually do this?&rdquo;&nbsp; Each tool offers a step by step, how-to guide that faculty can follow as they begin to actually integrate the principles of defining outcomes or architecting their course.<br /> <br /> <img alt="The Process for Defining Outcomes" height="208" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/05-2009/process_tools/defining_outcomes.JPG" style="float: left; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-right: 15px;" width="150" />The first tool, <strong><em><a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=54">The Process for Defining Outcomes</a></em></strong>provides an overview of the steps necessary in getting your goals for your class out of your mind and onto paper in such a way that they become powerful guides to all subsequent planning and assessment.&nbsp; The tool begins by showing an instructor how to contextualize instructional aims within the framework of program, departmental and institutional outcomes.&nbsp; It describes ways to organize all of the different kinds of outcomes into categories and priorities that make sense in the real world of classroom instruction. Next, the tool walks the instructor through the process of articulating outcomes using a four-part statement to insure that the outcomes are more than simple descriptions of wishful thinking, but that they become the structure upon which everything else can be built. The tool ends with multiple good examples of written objectives at both the course and the lesson levels.<br /> <br /> <img alt="A Course Architecture Process" height="208" src="http://www.byui.edu/learningandteaching/images/stories/05-2009/process_tools/architecture.JPG" style="float: right; margin-bottom: 15px; margin-left: 15px;" width="150" />The second tool, <a href="http://web.byui.edu/learningandteaching/tools/Tool.aspx?ToolID=62"><strong><em>A Course Architecture Process</em></strong></a>clarifies the assumptions made by the Learning Model about how a whole course is conceived and structured.&nbsp; It walks the reader step by step through the process of designing a course from the bottom up.&nbsp; One current faculty member who was recently trained in the process described in this tool called it &ldquo;the best professional development [he&rsquo;d] ever had.&rdquo;&nbsp; While few of us will actually be completely rewriting our courses in the near future, the process described in this tool is also helpful as we think about just tweaking and polishing our syllabus before the fall semester begins.&nbsp; The tool shows how the Learning Model is based on assumptions similar to a course design process called, &ldquo;Backward Design.&rdquo;&nbsp; As an instructor begins to architect a course around a chosen set of outcomes, the tool shows how to align assessments with the outcomes, how to design the student learning experience, how to determine content that students can master on their own and how to create in-class experiences that are truly formative to a student&rsquo;s learning.&nbsp; This is no castle-in-the-sky design process, however, as it ends with building a course calendar which fits the various outcomes, activities and content into the very limited span of a 14-week semester.<br /> <br /> These are only 2-page tools, so they can&rsquo;t do the thinking for you, but these suggestions can certainly get you on the right road and point you in the right direction.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x19084" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
