<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EventsDetail ID="x64280" Name="Faculty Conference Excursions" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Event Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Fall Faculty Conference Excursions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">2012 Fall Faculty Conference Excursion choices and workshop information.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Event Details" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Different to this year's conference will be faculty excursions. Starting at 1:00 pm, you will have the opportunity to participate in activities that include a Rafting Trip, an Art Gallery Tour, or a Teton Dam Flood Excursion. If you cannot attend an excursion, there will be a campus visit by DMBA VP/Treasurer and Chief Investment Officer, Kent Misener. His presentation will be from 3:00 pm to 4:00 pm in the MC Little Theater.</p>
<p>All schedules are tentative and subject to change.&nbsp;To register for an excursion and a lunch, follow <a href="https://byui.qualtrics.com/ControlPanel/?T=2mxreZ#SV_1BQES6XzHprVEi1">this link</a>&nbsp;by Thursday, August 30th. If you have questions, please contact Maria Nate at natem@byui.edu. Spaces are limited and will be filled on a "first-come, first-served" basis.</p>
<p><strong>Teton Dam Excursion&nbsp;</strong><br /> <br /> The Teton Dam failed on June 25, 1976, destroying hundreds of homes and thousands of acres of farmland and flooding Rexburg in 6 to 9 feet of debris-laden water. It was the largest dam ever to file in the history of the world.</p>
<p>We will visit the dam site and discuss the geological, engineering, and managerial reasons it failed and the local and national response. The dam's failure is used in training programs around the country under the topic of "how NOT to run a large project." We will also visit the Teton Dam museum and hear from some who experienced this life, and community, changing event.</p>
<p>Bring your camera, water, and weather-appropriate clothing.</p>
<p>Schedule:<br />1:00 - Get lunches<br />1:30 - Depart on a bus from the BYUI-Center traffic circle<br />3:30 - Return to departure point</p>
<p><strong>Jackson Hole Art Gallery Tour&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>James Johnson, adjunct Art Department faculty, will spearhead this excursion.</p>
<p>James Johnson graduated from Brigham Young University-Idaho with a BFA in Illustration, and is completing an MFA in Illustration from the Academy of Art University. He has studied with Leon and Del Parson, Walter Rane, Morgan Weistling, Bjorn Thorkelson, and others. He has also spent time in Israel, Egypt, and Jordan, gathering reference and inspiration for his Biblical paintings. Along with freelancing as an illustrator for LDS Church Magazines and other publications, he enjoys bringing the scriptures to life through paint, and has completed several religious painting commissions. He is currently completing a series of fine art paintings in preparation for a more extensive gallery career, while teaching as an adjunct faculty member of the BYU-Idaho Art Department in Rexburg, Idaho.</p>
<p>Please wear weather-appropriate clothing and comfortable walking shoes.</p>
<p>Schedule:<br /> 1:00 - Get box lunches and load van<br /> 1:30-3:00 - Journey to Jackson Hole<br /> 3:00-5:00 - James will lead our group through various galleries in Jackson Hole, fielding questions, explaining how one gets their work accepted/exhibited etc.<br /> 5:00-6:00 - Dinner (each participant will be responsible for paying for themselves)<br /> 6:00-7:00 - Free time to browse downtown shops<br /> 7:00-8:30 - Journey back to Rexburg</p>
<p><strong>Rafting Excursion</strong></p>
<p>Enjoy one last getaway on a calm-water float trip in Box Canyon, through old growth Douglas fir forest. Phil Murdock (from the Department of English), outdoorsman and 'resident' fly fishing instructor at BYU-I, will guide this trip.</p>
<p>Wear weather-appropriate clothing. Bring sunscreen and bottled water. We do not anticipate getting wet, but be prepared for water.</p>
<p>Schedule:<br /> 1:00 - Get box lunches and load vans<br />1:15 - Depart for launch point<br />2:15 - Arrive at launch point<br />4:00 - Load vans and head back to Rexburg<br />5:00 - Arrive home</p>
<p><strong>Ropes Course&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Climb to new heights and visit with colleagues at our own BYU-Idaho ropes course just west of the temple.</p>
<p>Schedule:<br />1:00 - Eat Lunch<br />1:30-3:30 - Ropes Course</p>
<p><strong>DMBA Investment Talk</strong></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho Human Resources is&nbsp;pleased to announce that DMBA VP/Treasurer and Chief Investment Officer, Brother Kent Misener, will be on campus Wednesday, September 5th to present "Investing in Turbulent Times".&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kent is an investment manager/economist - with a personality! He directs all CES institution retirement funds. Kent's investment performance constantly beats peers in funds that exist in the same investment categories that Deseret Mutual invests in.</p>
<p>He is one of Deseret Mutual's best presenters.&nbsp;Don't miss this rare opportunity. There is no need to register for this workshop.</p>
<p>Schedule:<br /> 3:00-4:00 pm - MC 372 Little Theatre&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="Semesters" label="Available Semesters" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><AvailableFall type="boolean" label="Available Fall" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</AvailableFall><AvailableWinter type="boolean" label="Available Winter" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</AvailableWinter><AvailableSpring type="boolean" label="Available Spring" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</AvailableSpring><AvailableSummer type="boolean" label="Available Summer" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</AvailableSummer><xPower Type="List" List="Date" Name="DateElements" label="Dates" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" display="localdateshort" Expanded="true"><Date type="date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" display="localdateshort" Expanded="false" UTC="true">20120807T18:00:00</Date></xPower><AdditionalInformation type="dhtml" label="Additional Information" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[]]></AdditionalInformation></xPower><EventImage type="imagefile" label="Event Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" Width="230" Height="332" Alignment="" Border="" Expanded="true" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">instructional-development/050708Gardens_3284em.jpg</EventImage><xPower Type="List" List="Images" Name="Images" label="Gallery Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="false" Height=""><Images type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace=""></Images></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35693" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x19084" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></EventsDetail>
