<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x64558" Name="What if a Pathway student feels like the course is too easy and they already speak English pretty well?"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">What if a Pathway student feels like the course is too easy and they already speak English pretty well?</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[Some of our Pathway International students do have excellent English already. Keep in mind, though, that they chose to participate in this program. For some, it may be that they wanted further exposure and experience with English, perhaps in preparation for taking college courses at an English-speaking university or college. For others, it may be that they have found that the Pathway program is a way to return to their education, but they may not necessarily need as much practice with their English.&nbsp;Find a way to discover what has attracted your partner to the program, and use that as a stepping-stone for your conversations. <br /><br />Speaking Partner meetings can help each Pathway student have a challenging, positive experience. If your student has great English already, then remember that conversing with you will keep up their language, and their opportunities to practice listening to and speaking English in real-time may be limited without you. It may take more effort, but look for ways to help them reach higher levels in their English language skills. For example, instead of using closed-ended or simple questions (e.g., &ldquo;Are you doing well today?&rdquo; or &ldquo;What is your name?&rdquo;), ask open-ended questions that will require them to think at a high level as they answer (e.g., &ldquo;What is your favorite thing about math?&rdquo; or &ldquo;What is the biggest problem you&rsquo;re having as you write this paper?&rdquo;). Similarly,&nbsp;if the Pathway student knows all of the listed vocabulary words, you might share more challenging (but useful) vocabulary.<br /><br />If your student already has native or near-native proficiency in English, then you should spend more time discussing the course content with them. Find ways to apply the materials to your lives, and seek opportunities to dig even deeper into the meaning and application of the principles they are learning.<br /><br />As with anything in life, we should also seek the inspiration of the Spirit of the Lord as we work in this program. If we seek the Lord&rsquo;s guidance, we can expect to find a way to help every student, even if it is not in the way you originally anticipated.]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
