<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x64537" Name="ENG 106L: Lesson 6" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ENG 106L: Lesson 6</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ENG 106L: Lesson 6</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h3></h3>
<div style="float: right;">
<div style="width: 175px; margin-left: 10px; border: #000 1px dotted; padding: 20px 10px;">
<h3>Vocabulary</h3>
<strong>Transition Words That Show Order </strong>
<ul>
<li>to begin with</li>
<li>at the same time</li>
<li>for now</li>
<li>the next step</li>
<li>later on</li>
<li>next</li>
<li>then</li>
<li>soon</li>
<li>later</li>
<li>while</li>
<li>earlier</li>
<li>afterward</li>
</ul>
<strong>Transition Words That Show Purpose or Reason</strong>
<ul>
<li>so</li>
<li>so that</li>
<li>for this reason</li>
<li>therefore</li>
</ul>
<strong>Transition Words That Show Result </strong>
<ul>
<li>as a result</li>
<li>therefore</li>
<li>thus</li>
<li>consequently</li>
</ul>
<strong>Transition Words That Give Example </strong>
<ul>
<li>for example</li>
<li>for instance</li>
<li>specifically</li>
</ul>
<strong>Adjectives </strong>
<ul>
<li>bored, boring</li>
<li>burned, burning</li>
<li>interested, interesting</li>
<li>excited, exciting</li>
<li>frightened, frightening</li>
<li>broken, breaking</li>
<li>confused, confusing</li>
<li>winning</li>
<li>running</li>
<li>annoyed, annoying</li>
<li>neat</li>
<li>lucky</li>
<li>adequate</li>
<li>gentle</li>
<li>common</li>
<li>sad</li>
</ul>
<strong>Words from Readings / Sample Stories </strong>
<ul>
<li>to achieve (v)</li>
<li>adequate (adj)</li>
<li>to communicate (v)</li>
<li>conference (n)</li>
<li>definitely (adv)</li>
<li>to evaluate (v)</li>
<li>goal (n)</li>
<li>mechanism (n)</li>
<li>motive (n)</li>
<li>military (n)</li>
<li>to occupy (v)</li>
<li>orientation (n)</li>
<li>to require (v)</li>
</ul>
<strong>Grammar Words </strong>
<ul>
<li>participle</li>
<li>past participle</li>
<li>present participle</li>
<li>modifier</li>
<li>adjective</li>
<li>adverb</li>
<li>object</li>
<li>simple sentence</li>
<li>compound sentence</li>
<li>clause</li>
<li>coordinating conjunction</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<h3><strong>Visit 1: Your Goals and Priorities<br /></strong></h3>
<p class="border"><img alt="Youg adults painting the side of a building" height="113" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Speaking Partners/images/120425_1234_Mexico-Pathway.png" style="border: 1px solid black;" width="241" /></p>
<p><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/ENG 106L Lesson 6.pdf">ENG 106L Lesson 6 PDF</a></p>
<p>During this speaking partner session, you will practice listening for information while your Speaking Partner reads to you. You will also discuss different topics related to the unit content, which the Speaking Partner will choose.</p>
<p><strong>Reading and Speaking Practice</strong></p>
<p>Read the <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/Priesthood Lesson.pdf">text</a> from a Priesthood lesson to your speaking partner about setting personal and family goals. Notice the "master plan" sentence, key words, and transitions in the text. Your speaking partner can help you with any pronunciation issues or vocabulary that you do not know.</p>
<p>Discuss the reading with your speaking partner. You may discuss some of the questions or topics below:</p>
<ol>
<li>According to this reading, our first step in selecting a goal is to decide how we want to improve the way we live. When you think about your life and how you want to improve, do you become overwhelmed? If so, why do you become overwhelmed?</li>
<li>The reading gave you a list of questions to ask yourself, discuss why these questions are important to consider when setting goals.</li>
<li>The reading also lists other areas that are applicable to our progress, such as our education. How are these areas important?</li>
<li>Why do you think it is important to focus on one or two goals at a time instead of all of our goals at the same time when we need to improve in all of these areas?</li>
<li>List different examples of personal goals and some examples of family goals.</li>
<li>How should you decide what family goals you need to improve on?</li>
<li>How does the last sentence in this reading relate to SMART goals, which you learned about in the Life Skills and English course? Why is it important to think about and decide "how we want to do" the goal and "when we want to finish it"?</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Writing Practice</strong></p>
<p>This week, your "Writing Skill" assignment is about cohesion. In this practice, you learned about writing and using a master plan to organize your writing. You will do a timed writing practice using a writing prompt or master plan sentence that your speaking partner will give you, which is related to goals. You will do the following steps for this exercise:</p>
<p>For the Speaking Partner: Give this sentence to the student.<br /> Master Plan/Topic Sentence: <em>"Completing a degree will give me the opportunity to work to sustain myself and my family, and to better serve in the church and in the community." </em></p>
<ol>
<li>Type the sentence that your speaking partner reads to you in a word document. This is your "master plan."</li>
<li>On another page in your word document or on a piece of paper, write down key words and phrases that represent the ideas that follow the "master plan." Think about how you will organize these ideas. (2 minutes timed)</li>
<li>At the end of the 2 minutes, use your master plan to write about this topic. Use the key words you wrote and transition words to organize your writing and to explain the steps you will take to achieve this goal. (8 minutes timed)</li>
<li>At the end of the 8 minute time limit, edit your writing for two minutes. For example, you may want to move sentences or add or change transition words to make your writing more coherent. (2 minutes timed)</li>
<li>Then, read your writing out loud to your partner. Reading aloud will help you to notice some other possible errors. Fix anything else you notice.</li>
<li>Finally, your partner will help you with any remaining organization errors.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>More Speaking Practice</strong></p>
<p>Your speaking partner will select one or more of the topics from the <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/Topic List Week 6.pdf">topic list</a>, which the two of you can discuss. After you are done, your speaking partner will help you with any issues they notice with grammar, vocabulary, or pronunciation issues.</p>
<h3><strong>Visit 2: Discussing and Reading about Goals<br /></strong></h3>
<p class="border"><img alt="Young man praying with hands clasped" height="113" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Speaking Partners/090508StudentPassAlong_007.jpg" style="border: 1px solid black;" width="240" /></p>
<p><strong> </strong>Read the <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/Julie B Beck.pdf">text</a> of a talk by Julie B. Beck, which was given in the General Young Women Meeting in April 2004. Take turns by reading one paragraph, your speaking partner reading the next, and so on until you read all of the text.</p>
<p>After you have read all of the article, discuss any new vocabulary or phrases that you did not understand. Your speaking can also help with any pronunciation issues that you may have.</p>
<p>Then, discuss the article as it relates to goals. You may discuss the following questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>What advice did Sister Beck's mother-in-law give her about learning to make rolls? How did she relate this to a habit of daily scripture study?</li>
<li>What did Sister Beck say was the "key" to developing the habit?</li>
<li>What did she say was the "key to unlocking important knowledge"?</li>
<li>How do these "keys" relate to other goals or good habits?</li>
</ol>
<p>After you have read and discussed the article, go through the blue highlighted words in the article and tell your speaking partner whether each word is an adjective or an adverb. Discuss any questions you have about the words.</p>
<p><strong>Writing</strong></p>
<p>During this session, you will do a timed writing assignment. You will write a short paragraph. It will be related to the content in the unit. Your speaking Partner will give you the topic. You will have to plan and write a short paragraph.</p>
<ol>
<li>Open a new, blank document in Microsoft Word.</li>
<li>Plan your writing (1-3 minutes).</li>
<li>Write your paragraph (6-10 minutes).</li>
<li>Edit your writing (1-3 minutes).</li>
<li>Save your writing.</li>
<li>Copy and paste your writing into the instant message area on Skype. Your Speaking Partner will read it and give you feedback during your tutor session. Think of at least one question you can ask your Speaking Partner, about something that will help you improve your paragraph.</li>
<li>If you wish, revise your writing. Use the feedback your Speaking Partner discussed with you. Save your writing again.</li>
<li>After your session, answer the questions above. Then copy and paste your paragraph into the box as well. Your instructor will read through it and may also give you some feedback.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/Topic List Week 6.pdf">Follow this link to see the Timed Writing Topics</a><em><br /> </em></p>
<p><strong>Speaking Partner Discussion</strong></p>
<p>Talk with your speaking partner about the first draft of your writing assignment. Do you have questions you want to ask?</p>
<p><strong>If you have time ...</strong></p>
<p>Discuss the vocabulary words for this week. You can practice using these words in complete sentences with your speaking partner.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<center></center>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x18360" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17147" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
