<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x64534" Name="ENG 106L: Lesson 3" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ENG 106L: Lesson 3</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">ENG 106L: Lesson 3</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h3></h3>
<div style="float: right;">
<div style="width: 175px; margin-left: 10px; border: #000 1px dotted; padding: 20px 10px;">
<h3>Vocabulary</h3>
<strong>Sound Adjectives </strong>
<ul>
<li>loud (adj)</li>
<li>noisy (adj)</li>
<li>whispering (adj)</li>
<li>blaring (adj)</li>
<li>silent (adj)</li>
<li>quiet (adj)</li>
<li>soft (adj)</li>
</ul>
<strong>Taste Adjectives </strong>
<ul>
<li>sweet (adj)</li>
<li>delicious (adj)</li>
<li>hot (adj)</li>
<li>spicy (adj)</li>
<li>salty (adj)</li>
<li>sour (adj)</li>
<li>fresh (adj)</li>
<li>tasty (adj)</li>
<li>bitter (adj)</li>
<li>tasteless (adj)</li>
<li>icy (adj)</li>
<li>burnt (adj)</li>
</ul>
<strong>Touch Adjectives</strong>
<ul>
<li>hard (adj)</li>
<li>smooth (adj)</li>
<li>soft (adj)</li>
<li>sharp (adj)</li>
<li>rough (adj)</li>
<li>wet (adj)</li>
<li>loose (adj)</li>
<li>hot (adj)</li>
<li>icy (adj)</li>
<li>light (adj)</li>
<li>heavy (adj)</li>
</ul>
<strong>Smell Adjectives</strong>
<ul>
<li>burnt (adj)</li>
<li>smelly (adj)</li>
<li>perfumed (adj)</li>
<li>scented (adj)</li>
<li>sweet-smelling (adj)</li>
<li>fresh (adj)</li>
<li>dusty (adj)</li>
</ul>
<strong>Sight Adjectives</strong>
<ul>
<li>dark (adj)</li>
<li>bright (adj)</li>
<li>dusty (adj)</li>
<li>light (adj)</li>
<li>big (adj)</li>
<li>small (adj)</li>
<li>little (adj)</li>
<li>long (adj)</li>
<li>wide (adj)</li>
<li>low (adj)</li>
<li>narrow (adj)</li>
<li>beautiful (adj)</li>
<li>shallow (adj)</li>
<li>(all colors)</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<h3><strong>Visit 1: Reading About and Describing Dreams and Places<br /></strong></h3>
<p class="border"><img alt="Youg adults painting the side of a building" height="113" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Speaking Partners/images/lehisdream.png" style="border: 1px solid black;" width="240" /></p>
<p></p>
<p><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/ENG 106L Lesson 3.pdf">ENG 106L Lesson 3 PDF</a></p>
<p>During this Speaking Partner session, you will read and discuss a chapter from the scriptures. You will also discuss different topics related to the unit content, which the Speaking Partner will choose.</p>
<p><strong>Reading Practice and Discussion</strong></p>
<p>Open and read <a href="http://lds.org/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8?lang=eng"> 1 Nephi 8</a> out loud together. Take turns by each reading one verse and then switching. While you read, look for all of the different words and phrases that Lehi uses to describe the different parts of his dream. Both the student and the Speaking Partner should pause whenever you notice these descriptions, and write down or type the words and phrases he uses. After reading, discuss any of the English words or phrases that you are not familiar with. If you wish to read more about the meaning of these symbols, you can find the interpretations that the Spirit gave to Nephi in <a href="http://lds.org/scriptures/bofm/1-ne?lang=eng">1 Nephi 11-12</a> or that Nephi gave to his brothers in <a href="http://lds.org/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/15?lang=eng">1 Nephi 15</a>.</p>
<p>After reading and discussing these descriptions, talk about or do the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Discuss how Lehi's words and Nephi's writings help you to visualize Lehi's dream when you read.</li>
<li>Your Speaking Partner will describe a dream that they have had. Ask any questions you have about their dream or any words or phrases that you don't understand.</li>
<li>Describe a dream that you remember to your Speaking Partner. Describe the different things you remember seeing or feeling during or after you had this dream.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Speaking Practice</strong></p>
<p>Your speaking partner will select one of the topics from the <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/Topic List Week 3.pdf">topic list</a> for Week 3 and describe a place to you. After they are done, ask questions about the place they have described.</p>
<p>Then, you will describe a place to your Speaking Partner. Your Speaking Partner will choose the topic for you from the topic list. When you describe this place, make sure you include details and descriptive words. After you describe this place, your Speaking Partner will ask you questions about it. They will also help you with any issues they notice with unclear details. You will also discuss any grammar, vocabulary, or pronunciation issues.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>Visit 2: Timed Writing Practice<br /></strong></h3>
<p class="border"><img alt="Young man praying with hands clasped" height="113" src="Images/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Speaking Partners/images/places.png" style="border: 1px solid black;" width="240" /></p>
<p></p>
<p>During this session, you will do a timed writing assignment. You will write a short paragraph. It will be related to the content in the unit. Your speaking Partner will give you the topic. You will have to plan and write a short paragraph.</p>
<p><strong>Timed Writing Practice (20-40 minutes)</strong></p>
<p>During this session, you will do a timed writing assignment. You will write a short paragraph. It will be related to the content in the unit. Your speaking Partner will give you the topic. You will have to plan and write a short paragraph.</p>
<p>The Pathway student will follow the steps below:</p>
<ol>
<li>Open a new, blank document in Microsoft Word.</li>
<li>Plan your writing (1-3 minutes).</li>
<li>Write your paragraph (6-10 minutes).</li>
<li>Edit your writing (1-3 minutes).</li>
<li>Save your writing.</li>
<li>Copy and paste your writing into the instant message area on Skype. Your Speaking Partner will read it and give you feedback during your tutor session. Think of at least one question you can ask your Speaking Partner, about something that will help you improve your paragraph.</li>
<li>If you wish, revise your writing. Use the feedback your Speaking Partner discussed with you. Save your writing again.</li>
<li>After your session, answer the questions above. Then copy and paste your paragraph into the box as well. Your instructor will read through it and may also give you some feedback.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Online Learning/Online Instruction/Speaking Partner ENG/Topic List Week 3.pdf">Click here to see the Timed Writing Topics.</a></p>
<p><strong>Discussion topic:</strong> Each Speaking Partner appointment is the opportunity for you to discuss ideas that you can use in your writing assignment. Discuss with your Speaking Partner a special place that you have visited or always wanted to visit.</p>
<ol>
<li>Where is this place located? Is it large? Small? Is it easy or difficult to get to?</li>
<li>Is there anything special about this place? Is it special to certain people? If so, who?</li>
<li>What do people do there? Is this place for playing? Sleeping? Worshiping?</li>
<li>Have you been there or is this a place that someone told you about?</li>
<li>Does anyone live there? What does this tell you about the people who live there?</li>
<li>If you have visited this place, then discuss what it looks like.</li>
<li>Discuss things that you can see, touch, hear, taste, and smell.</li>
<li>Explain how you feel when you are at this special place.</li>
<li>Ask your Speaking Partner questions about his/her favorite place.</li>
</ol>
<p>As you talk with your Speaking Partner, remember to keep notes of the different descriptive words that you use to describe this special place. What you discuss will help you with your writing assignment.</p>
<p><strong>Reading out Loud</strong></p>
<p>If there is time, your speaking partner will ask you to read the paragraphs "Hukilau Beach" and "Long Tan Mountain." You will practice reading out loud until you can read it smoothly. Discuss with your Speaking Partner the specific words and phrases that describe these places.</p>
<table border="1" style="border-color: #000000; border-width: 1px; width: 800px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p align="center"><strong>Long Tan Mountain </strong></p>
<p><em>There is a mountain in my city called Long Tan Mountain. That is the place where my family went every weekend. Before I came here to Hawaii, my parents and I always spent a couple of hours climbing the mountain and observing the beauty of nature. It is a beautiful place. Every time we went there I would observe the trees; they are all tall and full of leaves. I call them the natural sunshade. The air in the forest makes me feel relaxed and refreshed. My parents would point at different plants and tell me what kind of plant it is. They would tell me stories about their childhood. Time seemed to stop in those moments. Once we got to the top of the mountain, we could see the whole city. It was the most wonderful experience. I loved to spend time with my parents in such a beautiful place.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="1" style="border: 1px solid #000000; width: 800px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p align="center"><strong>Hukilau Beach </strong></p>
<p><em>Hukilau Beach is a beautiful place. When I am at Hukilau Beach, I like to walk on the sand. The sand always feels soft between my toes. I also like to swim in the water when I'm hot because the water feels cool on my skin. Hukilau beach is different on rainy days and sunny days. On rainy days, the air smells fresh and new. The rain removes all the bad smells from yesterday. On sunny days, lots of people bring food for a picnic on the beach. I think food tastes more delicious at the beach. My favorite time to visit the beach is when no one is there. The silence makes me calm and helps me to think. This is why Hukilau beach is one of my favorite places to visit.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<center></center>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x18360" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17147" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
