<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x64690" Name="Pathway Acceleration" Layout="general_Policy.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Pathway Acceleration</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Pathway Acceleration</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20121106T19:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong></p>
The purpose of Acceleration is to allow an academically prepared student who plans to matriculate the opportunity to take a course in addition to the prescribed Pathway courses. This will allow the accelerating student to make progress toward a degree prior to matriculating. The Acceleration process is not intended for all Pathway students and is not to be advertised or otherwise publicized; it is expected that a student will initiate the process by making a request to take additional classes. The request is to be made to the student's Peer Advisor. <br /><br /><br /><strong>Suitability:</strong> A Peer Advisor, upon receiving a request from a student to accelerate, will carefully determine the student's suitability for Acceleration. In order to be suitable for acceleration a student must meet the following criteria: <br />&nbsp;<br /><strong>Financial:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>No outstanding financial balance or past-due holds</li>
<li>Must indicate an ability to pay for the additional course</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Academic: <br /></strong>
<ul>
<li>Must be earning either an "A" or an "A-" in their present Pathway course(s) o&nbsp;&nbsp; A Lead Student or Advising Coordinator must verify the student's grades</li>
<li>A student who wishes to accelerate a second time must have received at least an "A-" in their last accelerated course</li>
</ul>
<strong>Other:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>Must submit a calendar showing they have adequate time for the additional course</li>
<li>Consideration will be given to instances when students have struggled in past courses as indicated on transcripts. This is not a disqualifying factor but should be taken into consideration when deciding whether a student is appropriate for acceleration.</li>
<li>The Peer Advisor will be cognizant of other "red flags" that indicate a student may not be successful in Acceleration</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>Things to Consider:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>A student is only permitted to accelerate one course per semester.</li>
<li>The grades a student receives while accelerating will be considered in their admission decision when the time comes for a student to matriculate. A student who receives a poor grade in a course under Acceleration may experience difficulty being admitted to the University to seek a degree.&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">A student who fails a course under Acceleration may be prevented from matriculation based on their GPA.</span></li>
<li>A student who wishes to accelerate a second time must follow the same process; there is no automatic acceleration for students who previously accelerated.</li>
<li>The course a student takes while accelerating must be degree-relevant.&nbsp; An accelerating student must take one of the following as their accelerated course:</li>
</ul>
&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;o&nbsp;&nbsp; A Foundations course <br />&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;o&nbsp;&nbsp; Foundations Capstone <br />&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;o&nbsp;&nbsp; An introduction course to an intended major <strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</strong><br /><strong><br />Peer Advisors:</strong> <br />When a student expresses a desire to accelerate a Peer Advisor will do the following: <br />
<ul>
<li>Ensure the suitability criteria are met</li>
<li>Assist the student in selecting an approved course</li>
<li>When the student is approved by a Peer Advisor for acceleration they must notify the Advising Coordinator who will issue the final approval and forward the information to the Online Support Center for authorization to take a course.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
