<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x64691" Name="Pathway Matriculation Options" Layout="general_Policy.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Pathway Matriculation Options</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Pathway Matriculation Options</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20121019T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong></strong>Pathway students that do not meet the 3.0 cumulative GPA need to retake an academic start class to raise their GPA.&nbsp; Pathway student cannot matriculate with having less than a 3.0 cumulative GPA but obtaining a 16 on their ACT.&nbsp; If a Pathway student would like to come to campus, they must fulfill all the requirements and they will forfeit their Pathway tuition. In order for a Pathway student to apply for campus they should select that they are a transfer student with less than 24 credits (in most cases). &nbsp; <br /><br /><strong>Justification Email</strong> <br /><strong><em>From:</em></strong><em> Justesen, Bryan <br /> <strong>Sent:</strong> Wednesday, August 22, 2012 9:08 PM<br /> <strong>To:</strong> Hales, Brad<br /> <strong>Subject:</strong> RE: Matriculating Students 3.0 exception</em> <em>Thanks for the reminder. Yes, the team unanimously felt that we should hold tight to the 3.0 standard. Even Lynne agreed which is undeniable proof that we made the right decision.&nbsp;<br /><br /></em><strong><em>From:</em></strong><em> Hales, Brad <br /> <strong>Sent:</strong> Monday, August 20, 2012 4:26 PM<br /> <strong>To:</strong> Justesen, Bryan<br /> <strong>Subject:</strong> Matriculating Students 3.0 exception</em> <em>Bryan,</em> <em>I also wanted to make sure that Karl added to his policy database that he is creating the decision that we made last Monday with the Pathway Managers about how we do not want to make exceptions for students that come close to the 3.0 Pathway academic start matriculation standard. Can you reply and confirm that decision and if there are any other details that I need to add. Then I will make sure that Karl documents this policy in his database.</em> <br /><em>Thanks,<br /> Brad</em> <br /><em>Pathway Program Support Coordinator</em> <br /><em>Phone: (208)496-1845</em> <br /><em>Email: </em><a href="mailto:halesb@byui.edu"><em>halesb@byui.edu</em></a><em> <br /> <br /> </em> <strong>Online Only Retake</strong> <br /><strong><em>From:</em></strong><em> Hales, Brad <br /> <strong>Sent:</strong> Friday, October 19, 2012 11:48 AM<br /> <strong>To:</strong> Karstad, Karl<br /> <strong>Cc:</strong> Landon, Lynne<br /> <strong>Subject:</strong> Online Only Retake Policy Revision<br /> </em>Karl,<br /> I talked to J.D. today about one additional question we had in regards to the Online Only Retake policy for Pathway students. We decided that students can take the online only version as a retake or the gathering version if they want. We will give them the option but not require them to gather even if the gathering is a possibility for them. We felt like it would create too much work to require them to gather for the retake if it is a possibility. Can you add this to the policy?<em></em> <br />Thanks,<br /> <em>Brad</em> <br /><em>Pathway Program Support Coordinator</em> <br /><em>Phone: (208)496-1845</em> <br /><em>Email: </em><a href="mailto:halesb@byui.edu"><em>halesb@byui.edu</em></a><em></em> <br /><br /><strong>Online Only Course Eligibility &amp; Attendance</strong> <br /><strong><em>From:</em></strong><em> Plank, Christina <br /> <strong>Sent:</strong> Thursday, October 18, 2012 8:17 AM<br /> <strong>Subject:</strong> Online Only Pathway Course Eligibility and Attendance Policy<br /> </em>Hello everyone,<em><br /> </em>As a follow up to Tuesday's POP meeting, here is the current information regarding eligibility for the Online Only versions of Pathway courses and the updated Attendance Policy.&nbsp; The Attendance Policy will remain as is for the remainder of the Fall semester, and the updated version will be effective Winter 2013.<em> </em>Thank you to everyone for your input as we discussed these important policies.<em></em> <br />Have a great day,<br /> Christina Plank<br /> Pathway Support Specialist for Course Experience<br /> Phone: 208-496-1847, Fax: 208-496-5847, Email: <a href="mailto:plankc@byui.edu">plankc@byui.edu</a> <br /><br /><strong>Pathway Attendance Winter 2013</strong> <br />In addition to the spiritually and socially empowering experiences available on Thursday evenings, meeting together each week during the first year also satisfies the university's residency requirement. This will allow students to apply to the BYU-Idaho Online Degree program after Academic Start. <br /><br />Pathway students are expected to attend all gatherings during the semester. They should plan their schedule accordingly and make any necessary arrangements to attend the Thursday gatherings. <br /><br />If students do not attend a gathering, they will lose attendance points in the course. The other online course assignments related to that week's lesson activities can still be submitted through I-Learn as usual.&nbsp; <br /><br />In addition to losing attendance points, additional penalties will apply if absence becomes a habit. If students miss four gatherings during the semester, their final grade will be reduced by one full letter grade. If students miss five or more gatherings during the semester, they will fail the course. <br /><br />In very rare instances, Pathway missionaries may cancel a gathering due to extreme weather or other unsafe situations. If such a situation occurs, this will not count against a student as an absence, but they will need to notify their online instructors. Any other attendance related questions should be directed to students' online instructors.]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
