<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x64680" Name="OSC Pipeline Strategy" Layout="general_Policy.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">OSC Pipeline Strategy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">OSC Pipeline Strategy</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120525T18:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>On Call OIS:&nbsp;</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The OSC will maintain two On Call OIS (<em>Online Information Specialists</em>) student employees.&nbsp; These employees will work minimal scheduled hours and will be used to maintain coverage during regular OIS absence due illness or vacation.&nbsp;</li>
<li>On Call OIS students will be trained and then observed to see if they can move up to be a regular OIS in the future. When possible the On Call OISs will be the pipeline of the OSC.</li>
<li>Recruiting for On Call OIS students will be on the BYU-Idaho job board.</li>
</ul>
<br /><strong>OIS Trainees:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>During periods of rapid growth, a trainee program may be implemented. Several student employees will be hired to be regular OIS one or two months before the semester that we will need them. These students will work two to four hours a week and will be fully trained by the time we need them.&nbsp;</li>
<li>The trainee program may also be implemented when several students are leaving (i.e. graduating or not invited to return) and there are insufficient returning students.</li>
<li>Trainees can also be On Call OIS or be used as an On Call OIS. Trainees after basic training can be used in coverage of the OSC. This is if they are working with an experienced OIS.</li>
<li>Recruiting for trainees can be on the BYU-Idaho job board or through a booth at the MC.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<strong><br />Returning Students:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>Those students that have done a good job working for the OSC and who need to leave for a semester or two will be considered in the planning for staffing the OSC.</li>
<li>When possible these students will return to their original positions.</li>
<li>Returning students will need to be rehired. <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>
<strong><br />Off Track Exception:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>The OSC has approval for one 20 hour off track exception.&nbsp;</li>
<li>If a student is off track and would like to use this exception, this might be a good solution for OSC staffing needs.</li>
<li>HR must be contacted (via email) to approve an Off Track Exception.</li>
</ul>
<strong><br />*New* Off Track Employment Option:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>Off track students can continue to work their on campus jobs while off track with as little as no credits.</li>
<li>This is up to 20 hours without an exception.</li>
<li>Contact Beth Baldwin for more details.</li>
</ul>
<strong><br />Continuous Recruitment:</strong> <br />
<ul>
<li>An OIS job posting will remain open throughout the year. This will hopefully provide a pool of applicants.&nbsp; If a student applies that meets all of the OIS's qualifications and is a high quality recruit, that student may fit future trainee or on call roles.</li>
<li>This job posting will be on the BYU-Idaho student job board.</li>
</ul>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="x18360" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17147" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
