<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<HiddenText ID="x64624" Name="Do I need an ecclesiastical endorsement?"><showText type="boolean" label="Enable to feature this question." readonly="false" required="false" hidden="false">false</showText><OpenningText type="string" label="Question Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">Do I need an ecclesiastical endorsement?</OpenningText><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Answer Text" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, all BYU-Idaho Online Degree students need an ecclesiastical endorsement.</p>
<p><a href="http://www2.byui.edu/StudentHonor/documents/Continuing%20Student%20Commitment%20and%20Ecclesiastical%20Endorsement%20Complete.pdf">Ecclesiastical Endorsement Form</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www2.byui.edu/StudentHonor/EndorsementFAQ2.htm">General Ecclesiastical Endorsement FAQs</a></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Pathway Students</span></p>
<p>During the Academic Start program, Pathway students are encouraged to begin preparing to live the BYU-Idaho Honor Code. Once students apply to BYU-Idaho as a degree-seeking student, they are expected to commit to live by the BYU-Idaho Honor Code and submit a continuing ecclesiastical endorsement at the beginning of each year.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Inactive Members</span></p>
<p>An ecclesiastical endorsement for inactive members is conducted the same way as it would be for active members. They must meet with their local bishop and stake presidency and be worthy and willing to live the honor code.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Non-Members</span></p>
<p>A non-member applying for the Online Degree program must still receive their ecclesiastical endorsement in order to complete their application.&nbsp;They will meet with their local bishop and then call the university chaplain as a substitute for the stake leader.&nbsp;Currently the university chaplain is <a href="http://web.byui.edu/Directory/Employee/belnapt">Timothy Belnap</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Taking Semesters Off</span></p>
<p>If the student plans on taking off more than two semesters, they must re-apply (update their application) through the admissions office since they will need a new ecclesiastical endorsement.</p>]]></BodyCopy></HiddenText>
