<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x65864" Name="Gateway Foundations" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Gateway Foundations Registration for Spring 2013</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Freshman priority</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>
<script src="http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.8.3/jquery.min.js" type="text/javascript">

</script>
<script type="text/javascript">
$(document).ready(function(){
    $('a[div#breadcrumbs href$=".xml"]').css("display","none");
});
</script>
</p>
<p>Freshman now have priority when registering for the following Gateway Foundations courses.</p>
<ul>
<li>FDAMF 101</li>
<li>FDENG 101</li>
<li>FDMAT 108</li>
<li>FDSCI 101</li>
</ul>
<p>The registration schedule for these courses will be as follows.</p>
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>March 18-20</td>
<td>First semester Freshman can register for up to 2 Gateway Foundations courses.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>March 25</td>
<td>Second semester Freshman can register for up to 2 Gateway Foundations courses.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>March 28</td>
<td>All non-freshman students can register for up to 2 Gateway Foundations courses.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>April 1</td>
<td>All students can register for up to 4 Gateway Foundations courses.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<ul></ul>
<h3>Frequently Asked Questions</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#faq1">How will Spring 2013 registration change?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq2">What is the purpose of this change?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq3">Why is this change being implemented now?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq4">What courses are impacted by this change in registration?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq5">Is there a limit to the number of Foundations Gateway sections for which I can register?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq6">How do I know if I qualify as a new or second-semester freshman?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq7">I am a second-semester freshman and registration opens for me prior to March 25. Why can't I add these classes on my first priority registration date?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq8">I am not a freshman but still need to take these classes. What do I do now?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq9">I am a transfer student; does this change apply to me?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq10">I am an online student; how does this change impact me?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq11">Can an instructor authorize me to add more than two of these Gateway Foundations courses?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq12">How important is it that I take these Gateway Foundations courses as a freshman?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq13">Can I add myself to a waitlist for these courses?</a></li>
<li><a href="#faq14">Is there someone I can contact if I have any further question?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a name="faq1"></a>How will Spring 2013 registration change?</strong></p>
<p>Priority registration for Spring Semester 2013 will generally be unchanged from past semesters.&nbsp; The most significant change involves reserving the DAY sections of the four Gateway Foundations courses for freshmen and initially limiting registration into these DAY sections to two.</p>
<p>New freshmen will be eligible to register for these courses on their scheduled registration day.&nbsp; Beginning Monday, March 25, all remaining freshmen will gain access to two Gateway Foundations courses. &nbsp;On Thursday, March 28, all non-freshmen will be given access to any two sections in these Gateway Foundations DAY sections.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq2"></a>What is the purpose of this change?</strong></p>
<p>It is an effort to facilitate a smoother transition for new freshmen into BYU&minus;Idaho and into the four required Gateway Foundations courses.&nbsp; This change will give new BYU&minus;Idaho freshmen priority in registering for these courses for Spring 2013 semester.&nbsp; It will also give second priority to second semester freshmen.</p>
<p>The focus on helping freshmen get seats in these courses is due to the fact that these courses have been designed and intended for freshmen students.&nbsp; If a freshman doesn't complete these courses early in their academic experience, it can impact the sequencing of their subsequent time at BYU&minus;Idaho.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq3"></a>Why is this change being implemented now?</strong></p>
<p>BYU&minus;Idaho has experienced, and expects to continue experiencing, significant growth in our enrollments.&nbsp; This growth has put significant pressure on the demand for these Gateway Foundations sections.&nbsp; Therefore, because these courses have been designed and intended for freshmen, we have recognized the need to help freshmen get these courses during their freshman semesters.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq4"></a>What courses are impacted by this change in registration?</strong></p>
<p>Spring 2013 registration will change for the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">DAY sections</span> only of the four Gateway Foundations courses:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>FDAMF 101</li>
<li>FDENG 101</li>
<li>FDMAT 108</li>
<li>FDSCI 101</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a name="faq5"></a>Is there a limit to the number of Foundations Gateway sections for which I can register?</strong></p>
<p>Yes.&nbsp; From March 18 through March 31, all students will be limited to registration in only two DAY sections of these courses, but will have unlimited access to online sections of these courses. &nbsp;Beginning Monday, April 1, the registration limit of two will be lifted, and students will be able to register in the DAY sections of all four courses if needed and if seats are available.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq6"></a>How do I know if I qualify as a new or second-semester freshman?</strong></p>
<p>New freshmen have been identified as students for whom Spring 2013 will be their first semester of enrollment at BYU&minus;Idaho and who have earned less than 30 college credits, including transfer credit accepted at BYU&minus;Idaho.</p>
<p>Second-semester freshmen have been identified as students who have attempted less than 21 credits at BYU&minus;Idaho and who have earned less than 30 college credits, including transfer credit accepted at BYU&minus;Idaho. &nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq7"></a>I am a second-semester freshman and registration opens for me prior to March 25.&nbsp; Why can't I add these classes on my first priority registration date?</strong></p>
<p>For the same reasons stated previously, they will not be available to second-semester freshman until March 25.&nbsp; Second-semester freshmen will be able to register for all other courses on their first eligible registration date.&nbsp; However, DAY sections of these four Gateway Foundations courses will not be available until March 25, when all have simultaneous access to them. &nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq8"></a>I am not a freshman but still need to take these classes.&nbsp; What do I do now?</strong></p>
<p>Non-freshmen who have not yet completed one or more of the Gateway Foundations courses will have unlimited priority access to online sections of these courses.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Beginning Thursday, March 28, non-freshmen will be given access to register for a maximum of two Day sections of the Gateway Foundations courses.&nbsp; Additionally, on April 1, the registration limit of two courses will be lifted, and all students will be able to add additional DAY sections of these courses, if available.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq9"></a>I am a transfer student; does this change apply to me?</strong></p>
<p>Yes.&nbsp; If Spring 2013 is the first semester you will be attending BYU&minus;Idaho and you are transferring in less than 30 college credits (including AP or IB), you will be considered a new freshman and will be eligible to register for two DAY sections of the Gateway Foundations courses beginning the day you are eligible to register for all other courses.&nbsp; However, if you transfer in more than 30 college credits, you will be eligible to register with the other non-freshmen on the dates indicated.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq10"></a>I am an online student; how does this change impact me?</strong></p>
<p>Online students will not be impacted by this change because they register for ONLN sections of the Gateway Foundations courses.&nbsp; The change applies only to DAY sections, for which online students are not eligible.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq11"></a>Can an instructor authorize me to add more than two of these Gateway Foundations courses?</strong></p>
<p>No.&nbsp; Instructors cannot override the registration limit of Gateway Foundations courses, nor can they authorize you to register before your assigned registration date.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong><a name="faq12"></a>How important is it that I take these Gateway Foundations courses as a freshman?</strong></p>
<p>It is very important for freshmen to take the four Gateway Foundations courses in their first few semesters in order for the sequencing of subsequent semesters to not be impacted negatively. Therefore, freshmen are strongly encouraged to take advantage of their ability to register for these courses before other students on campus have access to them.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq13"></a>Can I add myself to a waitlist for these courses?</strong></p>
<p>Yes.&nbsp; The waitlist for the Gateway Foundations courses will function the same as the waitlist for any other course. However, students may only be registered and waitlisted for a maximum of two Gateway Foundations courses at any time.&nbsp; For example, students may register for one and waitlist one Gateway Foundations section, but may not register for two sections <em>and</em> waitlist a third.</p>
<p><strong><a name="faq14"></a>Is there someone I can contact if I have any further question?</strong> &nbsp;</p>
<p>Yes.&nbsp; Please email any questions you may have to <a href="https://sn2prd0102.outlook.com/owa/redir.aspx?C=RtvYOThe_02_1d1t3MhqN9-GFhwph88I3bV53aG-PuY67Il4cpbWFMRrL4fga80zq40KJZJu2bQ.&amp;URL=mailto%3aregistration%40byui.edu" target="_blank">registration@byui.edu</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x44655" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
