<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x65936" Name="Instruction &amp; Curriculum" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Instruction &amp; Curriculum</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Instruction &amp; Curriculum</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Instruction &amp; Curriculum (IC): </strong>This function pertains to departmental duties over curriculum, education, training, and instruction. <strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Academic Program Administration" title="Academic Program Administration">Academic Program Administration</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Commencement" title="Commencement">Commencement</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Curriculum Delivery" title="Curriculum Delivery">Curriculum Delivery </a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Curriculum Planning &amp; Development" title="Curriculum Planning &amp; Development">Curriculum Planning &amp; Development</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Independent Study" title="Independent Study">Independent Study</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Program Development &amp; Review" title="Program Development &amp; Review">Program Development &amp; Review</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Scheduling" title="Scheduling">Scheduling</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Special Academic Programs" title="Special Academic Programs">Special Academic Programs</a></li>
<li><a class="anchorLink" href="#Student Handbooks" title="Student Handbooks">Student Handbooks</a></li>
</ul>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Academic Program Administration"></a>Academic Program Administration </strong></p>
<p>Records document the daily and routine administration of academic programs of the department or college. Records may include registration reports, add-drop analyses and reports, course enrollment summaries by class, graduation summaries, majors by class level, international activities, cooperative ventures, placement information, convenience copies of reports prepared by admissions, registrar's, budgets and planning, and other offices memos, working papers, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Superseded</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>2 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Commencement"></a>Commencement</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with commencement activities as they apply to students. Records may include commencement attendance forms, planning records created by commencement committees or other planning groups, and related documentation and correspondence; mailing addresses for diplomas, fees paid, and student listings; work sheets, transcripts, and transfer course evaluations.</p>
<p><em>Transfer one official copy of printed programs distributed at commencement ceremonies to Special Collections.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy (see above)</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Curriculum Delivery"></a>Curriculum Delivery</strong></p>
<p>Records document departmental course offerings and individual course contents. Records may include syllabi, course descriptions, course outlines, course summaries, course requests and proposals, curriculum approval lists, lists of classes by term, bibliographies, reading lists, course announcements, handout materials, lecture notes, exams, textbook orders, course packets; and related documentation and correspondence. File by course.</p>
<p><em>Official copies of syllabi should be transferred to Special Collections; remaining material should be destroyed after being replaced or superseded by other materials. Consult with the archivist when determining if other records warrant archival retention.</em></p>
<p><em>Faculty, colleges, and departments may want to keep some course materials longer for tracking courses and should follow what works efficiently and effectively for their own course records. </em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Superseded</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy (see above)</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Curriculum Planning &amp; Development"></a>Curriculum Planning &amp; Development</strong></p>
<p>Records materials created or used in the update and development of courses and that document course name changes and dropped courses. Records may include course proposals, course revisions, curriculum changes, course requests, curriculum committee meeting minutes, curriculum proposals, reports on curriculum design, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Offices should permanently retain committee meeting minutes and curriculum proposal reports; all other records should be destroyed after 3 years.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy (see above)</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Independent Study"></a>Independent Study</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with departmental approval for students to enroll in independent study courses. Records may include permission sheets with students' names, course names, number of credits, and faculty signatures.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Program Development &amp; Review"></a>Program Development &amp; Review</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with planning and implementation of new degree programs and any major reorganizations or changes to established programs. Records may include final reports, working papers, letters of support, review agendas, faculty status reports, reviews of individual degree programs by campus and off-campus sources, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
<p><em>Transfer the record copy of final reports and reviews of individual degree programs by on and off-campus sources to the University Archives after 5 years; destroy remaining records after retention period.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>5 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy (see above)</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Scheduling"></a>Scheduling</strong></p>
<p>Records document the formation of class schedules by academic departments for inclusion in the institutional catalog and schedule of classes, and the scheduling of rooms for classes. Records may include the final edition of the schedule of classes, requests from departments for class offerings, deviation from schedule forms, course schedule maintenance forms, requests for class changes, working papers, and related documentation and correspondence. Room scheduling records may include room assignment lists and related documentation, class room technology requests, and course catalogs.</p>
<p><em>One official copy of the master Course Schedule and/or the course catalog should be transferred to the archives upon publication; remaining records should be destroyed after one year of retention.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Superseded</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1 year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy (see above)</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Special Academic Programs"></a>Special Academic Programs</strong></p>
<p>Records associated with special academic programs serving and aiding institution students. Programs documented by this series range from special requirement and certification programs to programs aimed at assisting and encouraging target groups of institution students. Records may include policy and program planning and development, explanatory materials, evaluations, support services, program course outlines, program participation and aid selection records, activity accounting records, reports, and related documentation and correspondence.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Inactive</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>7 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong><a name="Student Handbooks"></a>Student Handbooks</strong></p>
<p>Records document the requirements, policies, and offerings of specific instructional units for use by current or potential students. Records contain information or policies on fields of study, faculty, academic requirements, the evaluation process, and the research proposal process.</p>
<p><em>Transfer only one official record copy to Special Collections; destroy supporting materials after superseded.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Superseded</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>0</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Permanent Holdings</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x45982" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
