<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x65931" Name="Campus Retention Schedule" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Campus Retention Schedule</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Campus Retention Schedule</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Campus Retention Schedule for Departments</strong></h1>
<hr />
<p><strong>About the Campus Retention Schedule (CRS)</strong></p>
<p>The CRS contains common departmental functions to help offices identify recordkeeping requirements. That is, records are grouped by their purpose rather than under a department or office. This allows for multiple offices to gather the information they need from one source, and to standardize disposition actions across campus.&nbsp;&nbsp;Regardless of where the records are or who maintains them, records containing the same kind of information and retention periods fall into the same category. Understanding that your department's records are spread throughout the schedule by function will help you in understanding how to navigate the CRS. See below for instructions on <a class="anchorLink" href="#How to use the crs" title="How to use the CRS">How to Use the CRS</a>.</p>
<p>Use the CRS to help you organize and file your records. Follow the categories in your grouping of records in physical files and in electronic systems. Keeping records in the categories listed will help you in retaining records and in disposition of records. The records categories listed in the schedule are generalized so as to help multiple campus departments; not every office will hold some of the records listed. Only use the categories that are applicable to your office.</p>
<p>The CRS is subject to change and revision as recordkeeping practices change, record categories are revised, and offices that manage records are reorganized. To create your own retention schedule, download a blank <a href="Documents/records-retention/BYUI_Records_Retention_Schedule.xls" title="Records Retention Schedule">records retention schedule</a>. </p>
<p><strong><a name="How to use the crs"></a>How to Use the CRS</strong></p>
<p>The CRS is organized into eight main <a class="intLink" href="x46260.xml" title="Functions">functions</a>. Each function is an aggregate grouping of common activities within which an office might engage. The eight functions are high-level key words to describe an office's overall responsibilities.</p>
<p>Within each function are several record categories (also referred to as series) grouped together based on similarity in type and use and by retention period. Each record category has a brief description of the type of records that fall into the category and several examples of those records. Categories also include a description of when retention begins, how long that records should be kept in office once retention begins, and a final disposition. &nbsp;If you cannot find your record in a category, please <a class="intLink" href="x46348.xml" title="Contacts">contact the records manager</a>. Do not feel you need to include every category as you review your records; instead, use only the categories that apply to your office's recordkeeping duties.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong>Record Category (Series)</strong></p>
<p>Description of the category along with examples of common record types that fall within this category.</p>
<p><em>Specific retention instructions or notes.</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Event for when retention begins</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Number of years/months to retain records after the event/preferred retention period</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Disposal action through destruction or transfer</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>If I have a department's meeting minutes and I consider them routine and not important, I would identify that record as something that would fall under the function of&nbsp;<em>Administrative</em>, I would then scroll through the records categories to locate the category&nbsp;wherein the minutes fit. In this case it would fall into the category:&nbsp;<em>Administrative Support, Routine</em>.</p>
<table border="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">
<p><strong>Administrative Support, Routine</strong></p>
<p>Records of routine work performed by University offices. Records may include announcements, calendars, schedules, communication logs, mailing lists, memorandum, and pending action files, routine minutes, and other series of records that support routine operations within the University system.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>End of Calendar Year</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Destroy</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I might group the minutes with other routine operations that fit the description, then at the end of the calendar year I would consider all those records as in the retention period of three years. Once three years are up, I would then securely shred the records associated with routine administrative support. Electronic as well as hard copy records should follow this retention schedule and be destroyed accordingly.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="true"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x46352" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x46451" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x45982" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
