<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Content ID="x66011" Name="Policies" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">University Policies and Procedures</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Policies and Procedures</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<h1><a name="Top"></a>Frequent Policy Links</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#fund_raising"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></a><a href="#1-1">Fund Raising(1-1) </a></li>
<li><a href="#guest_speaker"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Guest Speakers(1-4)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#surveys"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Surveys &amp; Questionnaires(1-5)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-6"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Candidates for Public Office (1-6)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-8"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></a><a href="#1-8">Fraud Policy (1-8)</a></li>
<li><a href="#1-10"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Relationship with the News Media (1-10)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-16"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Public Expression and Demonstration Policy (1-16)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-17"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Electronic Mail (1-17)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-18"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Campus Scheduling Policy: University Sponsored Events (1-18)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-19"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Campus Scheduling Policy(1-19)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#publicity"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">On-Campus Publicity, Advertising, and Solicitations Policy(1-23)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#video"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Video/Audio Production and Distribution(1-26)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-27"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Building Access Policy ( 1-27)</span></a></li>
<li><a href="#1-28"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Information Privacy (1-28)</span></a></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="#1-29">Approval Policy for Gifts-in-Kind Received on Campus (1-29)</a></span></li>
<li><a href="http://www.byui.edu/copyright">Copyright Policy</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul></ul>
<p><strong><a name="1-1"></a>Fund Raising (1-1)</strong></p>
<p>I. PURPOSE<br /> To coordinate and control all solicitations of gifts of all kinds to the University so as to avoid multiplicity of appeals. This policy is not intended to curtail solicitations of gifts. All faculty members are encouraged to obtain proper gifts, wherever possible, on approval from the Development Office.&nbsp;<br /> II. DEFINITIONS<br /> Gift, for the purpose of this policy, will mean any money or contribution for which there is not a specific contract.</p>
<p><br /> III. POLICY<br /> A. The BYU-Idaho Development Office is established to coordinate and control all solicitations of gifts to the University. Division and department heads and individual faculty and staff members planning to solicit gifts of any kind should first obtain approval for a specific gift, or for a category or type of gift, from the Director of Development and their respective vice president.<br /> <br /> B. All gifts to the University of money, stocks, bonds, or gifts-in-kind are to be channeled through the Development Office.<br /> <br /> C. Letters of appreciation for all major gifts and receipts are sent to donors by the Development Office.<br /> <br /> D. Whenever a gift is restricted for specific purposes by the donor, a memorandum is prepared by the Director of Development and sent to the department concerned advising them of the receipt of the gift and the full details of the stipulations of the donor.<br /> <br /> E. From the legal point of view, the Development Office is the only department authorized to issue receipts indicating a charitable tax deductible contribution valid for I.R.S. claims.<br /> <br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="guest_speaker"></a><strong>Guest Speaker (1-4)</strong></p>
<p>If you'd like to have a guest speaker visit your societies, please fill out the form (steps 1-3) and bring to Kimball 210.</p>
<p><a href="http://www2.byui.edu/PR/SpkrRqst.pdf" target="_blank">Speaker Request Form</a> for University Events.</p>
<p>(Approved March 2005 by the President's Council)<br /> (To view "Speaker Request Forms" please see the BYU-Idaho Online Forms Index)</p>
<p>I. PURPOSE<br /> To state the policy and the procedure to follow when inviting a speaker or other presenters to the BYU-Idaho campus.</p>
<p>II. POLICY<br /> Any individual must be approved before he or she is invited to speak on campus. Potential speakers are not to be contacted until official approval has been received. The intended audience determines who approves the potential speaker and how that speaker is approved.</p>
<p>A classroom audience must be approved by the Department Chairman.</p>
<p>A department audience must be approved by the Department Chairman and the Dean.</p>
<p>An academic college audience must be approved by the Dean and the Academic Vice President who will determine whether the request should be reviewed by President's Council.</p>
<p>An Activities Program audience must be approved by the Student Activities Council and the Director of Student Activities.</p>
<p>An Activities Program event intended for a campus-wide audience must be approved by the Director of Student Activities and the Advancement Vice President who will determine whether the request should be taken to President's Council.</p>
<p>A. Any individual speaking to a campus-wide audience and sponsored by the Institution (Devotionals, Forum, etc.) must be approved by the BYU-Idaho President's Council, Executive Committee, and the Board of Trustees. These requests must be submitted up to one year in advance of the event for General Authorities and six months in advance for all others. Clearance is valid for two years.<br /> <br /> B. Other potential speakers to campus audiences must be sponsored by Academics, Student Activities, or a University Department. Speakers for any program must be evaluated and approved, as detailed above, before they are contacted.<br /> <br /> C. Advertising and Promotion<br /> A speaker approved for:</p>
<p>A classroom audience may be advertised to the members of that specific class.</p>
<p>a department audience may be advertised to students and faculty of that department. Posters may be hung in or near the college/department offices and classrooms.</p>
<p>An academic college audience may be advertised to the students and faculty of that college. Posters and announcements may be hung in or near the college offices and classrooms.</p>
<p>An approved Academic or Activity event may be promoted campus-wide and advertised through Institutional media (Web Page, Campus Updates, etc.) if the speaker was sponsored by BYU-Idaho as an institutional speaker and approved by Salt Lake.</p>
<p>When the Academic or Activity event is approved for campus-wide promotion, but the speaker is not sponsored by BYU-Idaho as an Institutional speaker and is not approved by Salt Lake, then the event may be advertised through Institutional media. The speaker may be mentioned by name, but the advertising and promotion centers on the event and not the speaker.</p>
<p>III. PROCEDURE<br /> A. Approval of guest speakers must be submitted through the appropriate channels before any invitation may be extended. Speaker requests must be submitted on official speaker request forms.</p>
<p>Requests for speakers, other than General Authority and/or Campus-wide speaker requests, should be submitted at least one month in advance of the proposed event's date.</p>
<p>The following information must be included on all requests:</p>
<p>Education, training, or experience that qualifies the speaker to address a university audience</p>
<p>Excerpts or summaries of previous addresses, if available</p>
<p>Speaker's present position</p>
<p>Significant background information or the speaker's public record</p>
<p>Signature of the faculty sponsor</p>
<p>Recommendation of a faculty member</p>
<p>B. Request for speakers to a campus-wide audience are first submitted (at least six months in advance) to the appropriate Vice President who will consider initial approval of the speaker. If the Vice President grants initial approval:</p>
<p>The Public Relations office will seek an ecclesiastical endorsement for the individual.</p>
<p>Once the endorsement is received, the appropriate Vice President will take the request to President's Council.</p>
<p>If approved by President's Council, the speaker name will be submitted to the Executive Committee.</p>
<p>C. Because of their demanding schedules, General Church Officers should not normally be requested for campus speaking assignments. If there is a justified request, it should be submitted to President's Council through the appropriate Vice President.<br /> <br /> D. Failure to obtain proper approval prior to invitation of the speaker may result in cancellation of the event and loss of scheduling privileges.<br /> <br /> E. The sponsoring organization is responsible for arranging the program and coordinating the care of the speaker with the Public Relations Office. It is a matter of courtesy that a written follow-up of confirmation be sent to the speaker finalizing all necessary detail, including topic and length of speech, travel and lodging information, and guest standards.<br /> <br /> F. Criteria for Selection of Speakers</p>
<p>The speaker must be qualified by education, training, or experience to discuss the topic chosen for presentation.</p>
<p>After receiving official approval and invitation, any person who has qualified as a candidate for the nomination of a major political party for the office of president of the United States may address general assemblies or large gatherings of students and faculty at BYU-Idaho. Any other person who has qualified as a candidate for major political office or who is a representative of a major political party may be invited to address the student body, faculty, staff, class, or organization within the University after receiving official approval and invitation.</p>
<p>The speaker must not advocate or be directly affiliated with organizations which advocate (by insurrection, civil riot, mob rule, or any other violent or illegal way) the overthrow of the government of the United States or of its constituent units by force, or in any way violate restrictions imposed for the public safety.</p>
<p>In the presentation, the speaker must not advocate ideas in opposition to a belief in a Divine Creator, nor take advantage of this forum in any way to demean The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints or its principles. Furthermore, the speaker must not be antagonistic to the Church or its standards.</p>
<p>Speakers must be made aware of Latter-day Saint standards of personal conduct which they are expected to maintain while on campus. The speaker's public reputation for integrity and observance of the moral values inherent in the Honor Code and embraced by the Church should reflect favorably upon the speaker and BYU-Idaho. Speaker should be sought whose personal lives provide an appropriate model for our students.</p>
<p>The actions and deportment of guest speakers while on campus will be the direct responsibility of the sponsoring faculty member, department head, or administrator. Speakers invited by student groups will be the responsibility of the Director of Student Activities and staff.</p>
<p>No fund raising activity for private enterprise or for political parties or candidates is allowed.</p>
<p>Once the speaker is approved through the appropriate channels, the Public Relations office will obtain the ecclesiastical clearance where required.</p>
<p>The BYU-Idaho Honor Code requires that participants in approved programs and events be treated with courtesy and respect. University policy, including the Honor Code, prohibits the obstruction or disruption of any authorized activity on the BYU-Idaho campus. Banners, placards, handouts, unusual dress, shorts, or any other actions that attempt to disrupt, avert, or harass the participants in an event are not allowed.<br /> <br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="surveys"></a><strong>Surveys and Questionnaires (1-5)</strong></p>
<p>I. PURPOSE<br /> To explain the guideline to be followed in the use of surveys and questionnaires at BYU-Idaho.<br /> <br /> II. POLICY<br /> <br /> A. All surveys, questionnaires, questions for oral interviews, etc. must be approved before they are used at BYU-Idaho. This policy applies to instruments used by students, teachers, administrators, or staff members and to instruments being used on or off campus. Regular classroom tests or examinations are exempt from the policy.<br /> <br /> B. The intent of this policy is not to restrict legitimate research, but to make certain that inappropriate questions are avoided. In general, those designing surveys should not delve into private affairs nor into matters which should be discussed only with one's parents or Church leaders. Questions which invite criticism of the Church, its policies, or its doctrines should also be avoided.<br /> <br /> III. IMPLEMENTATION<br /> A. The Director of Institutional Research is at present the person on campus assigned to approve surveys and questionnaires.<br /> <br /> B. University personnel desiring approval of survey instruments should discuss their ideas with the Director of Institutional Research or preferably submit a rough draft of their proposed survey.<br /> <br /> C. After approval is obtained, the instrument may be reproduced or otherwise used as desired.</p>
<p>D. One copy of the approved questionnaire or survey should be delivered or sent to the Director of Institutional Research to be kept on file.<br /> <br /> E. Questionable cases may be referred to the President for possible consideration by the Commissioner's Office and the Church Questionnaire Committee.<br /> <br /> F. Additionally, the Director of Institutional Research is to offer his services to university personnel - especially students - in the design and formatting of surveys to improve their quality.</p>
<p><br /> <a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><strong><a name="1-6"></a>Candidates for Public Office (1-6)</strong></p>
<p><br /> (Revised policy approved 7 August 2006 by President's Council)<br /> I. PURPOSE<br /> To outline the requirements for BYU-Idaho employees to run for public office.<br /> II. POLICY<br /> It is permissible for BYU-Idaho personnel to run for public office if campaigning does not interfere with their employment duties and if they receive appropriate approval prior to making the commitment to run.<br /> Candidates for office are not to use the resources of BYU-Idaho to obtain lists of names, or any information (except for library research), to use in a political campaign. Additionally, the mail system of the employing unit is not to be used to distribute campaign literature or to promote votes. Overall, supplies, equipment, and personnel are not to be used in connection with the political activities of the candidate.<br /> III. APPROVAL FOR RUNNING FOR OFFICE<br /> Before an employee agrees to become a candidate for public office - whether local, state, or national - the employee must first obtain permission in writing from their immediate supervisor, then through each successively higher supervisor - ending with the respective vice president.<br /> If authorization is granted to run for public office, it should be understood that campaigning shall not interfere with the individual's employment duties. If it does, the approval may be revoked.<br /> IV. IF ELECTED TO OFFICE<br /> If a person is elected to a public office, then the following will apply:<br /> A. If the office is full-time, the employee should resign before taking office.<br /> B. If the office is only part-time (or full-time for a limited number of months), such as the State Legislature, the handling of compensation will be as follows:<br /> 1. Faculty<br /> If the elected person is a member of the faculty on a regular contractual basis, the contract will be adjusted to adequately reflect the appropriate pay for responsibilities performed at BYU-Idaho during the time he/she is in public office.<br /> 2. Administrative and Staff Employees<br /> If the elected person is an employee classified as Administrative or Staff and is on a twelve-month, year-round basis, the employee should use vacation time and/or "leave without pay" for time away from work. Administrative employees must use "leave without pay" in full-day increments.<br /> V. CONTINUING ACTIVITIES ON COMMITTEES<br /> When the elected person is involved in continuing activity on committees or other assignments beyond those which are regularly assumed, such as a legislative session in the case of legislators, it is expected that these other activities will be so arranged that the employee's regular working schedule will not be interrupted. If this is not possible, additional arrangements must be made for participation in these activities through the same procedure required for obtaining permission to run for office.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="1-7"></a><a name="1-8"></a><strong>Fraud Policy (1-8)</strong></p>
<p></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho has adopted the Honor Code which applies to students, faculty, staff, and administrators. All who, through their employment or enrollment, represent BYU-Idaho are required to maintain the highest standards of honor, integrity, morality, and consideration of others in personal behavior. Fraudulent activity at the University constitutes a serious violation of the Honor Code and will not be tolerated. This policy defines fraud as theft or the conversion of University resources for personal gain. Resources may include, but are not limited to: cash, tangible property, and information. Employees have a fiduciary responsibility to appropriately use University resources of which they have been entrusted.<br /> Fraud deterrence at BYU-Idaho is the responsibility of all members of the campus community, particularly administrative management. To effectively fulfill this charge depends on adherence to established policies, procedures, and internal controls. Periodic audits, system reviews, and other special analyses can assist management in fulfilling its responsibility. The Internal Audit Department and Campus Police are available to perform special audits or investigations. However, these resources should not be expected to substitute for line controls which should be in place to verify the integrity of day-to-day activities.<br /> Anyone having knowledge of misuse or misappropriation of University resources has an obligation to report misconduct to appropriate University officials. Normally, reporting would be through line management. If there is a known or suspected fraud involvement by person(s) in line management, reporting should be through the Director of Personnel Services, Internal Audit, Campus Police, or an administrative level manager above the known or suspected level of involvement.<br /> A department should handle one-time or very immaterial cases of fraud with appropriate prudence and restraint. Personnel Services along with the appropriate vice president(s) will handle more substantial cases of fraud involving damages to the University, repetitive acts, or serious violations of University policy. When deemed necessary, allegations may be verified through audit or other investigative procedures. Persons conducting an investigation will keep source information confidential.<br /> All instances, whether one-time/immaterial or more serious cases, must be reported in writing to the Director of Personnel Services.<br /> Normally, fraudulent activities will result in termination of University employment, legal prosecution, and restitution. After considering all available information, the President's Staff, in consultation with line management, will determine final disciplinary action.<br /> (See also Policy 3-6: Reporting of Fraudulent Activity)</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="1-10"></a><strong>Relationship with the News Media (1-10)</strong></p>
<p><br /> I. PURPOSE<br /> To outline and clarify the guidelines that have been established at BYU-Idaho for dealing with the news media. These guidelines include measures to follow when approached by representatives from the media as well as steps to take in submitting appropriate news material to the media.<br /> II. POLICY<br /> A. It is BYU-Idaho's desire to maintain an attitude of openness with the news media.<br /> 1. Personnel in each department or area should feel free to respond to questions by the media concerning their department or area. If they are concerned about the response, they are welcome to contact Media Relations for assistance.<br /> 2. Questions raised by the news media about an area other than the one an employee represents or about the university in general should be referred to that area or to Media Relations for comment.<br /> 3. In order to avoid confusion or duplication, and to assist the university in building strong relationships with news media, please notify Media Relations of contacts or interviews with media representatives.<br /> B. To release material to the media, the proper procedure is to do so through Media Relations.<br /> III. PROCEDURES<br /> A. When approached by a representative from the news media, the following guidelines are suggested:<br /> 1. If the issue relates to one's own area, one should feel free to respond. (It is assumed that the planetarium director knows most about the planetarium, the ag chairman most about the ag program, etc.) As a courtesy and to ensure successful communications, the appropriate department head and Media Relations should be notified before an information, if possible.<br /> 2. If questions are raised regarding issues about which one is not informed, it is acceptable to simply state, "I don't know." It is important that any information given should be accurate and that one be able to substantiate whatever statements are made. One should carefully consider if he wants to make a statement and may choose to respond simply by stating, "No comment."<br /> 3. If issues are raised about areas other than what one represents or about the university in general, the media should be referred to that department or to Media Relations for comment.<br /> 4. Issues of a sensitive or controversial nature might best be answered with a statement prepared in cooperation with the Public Relations Office and Media Relations and the department involved, subject to appropriate review by the appropriate supervisor. Such a method of response provides the opportunity to thoroughly think through the issue and its ramifications and to respond accordingly. Such a statement should be anticipated and prepared in advance of any contact with the media, or the media should be informed that a formal statement is forthcoming.<br /> 5. When caught off guard by a reporter, any response can be difficult and frightening. One should be aware that:<br /> a. Anything said could be quoted.<br /> b. When called by telephone unexpectedly, one can ask for time to prepare, i.e., "let me check my notes; I will call you right back."<br /> c. If asked in advance for an interview, one should feel free to ask what questions he will be expected to answer.<br /> B. When a person or department desires to release information to the media, the proper procedure is to do so through the Media Relations. Qualified personnel, familiar with university policy and having the contacts and organization to effectively get news to the public, are available. Using Media Relations helps to ensure that information going to the public will portray a positive and accurate image of BYU-Idaho.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="1-16"></a><strong>Public Expression and Demonstration (1-16)</strong></p>
<p><br /> I. APPLICATION FOR PUBLIC FORUM<br /> The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints sponsors BYU-Idaho to provide a university education in a wholesome atmosphere that nurtures spiritual growth and a strong testimony of the divinity of Jesus Christ. This atmosphere is preserved through commitment to conduct that reflects the ideals and principles of the Church.<br /> The BYU-Idaho campus is not a public forum. However, as part of its intellectual climate, BYU-Idaho permits responsible public expression, events, and speakers. In order that such activities do not become disruptive of or in opposition to the purposes and uses of the university campus, all public expression events and speakers must be organized and approved in accordance with established University policy. All speakers on campus must comply with the BYU-Idaho Guest Speaker Policy (No. 1-4). All BYU-Idaho affiliated individuals and groups desiring to sponsor open public expression, such as rallies or gatherings, with or without preselected speakers, for the purpose of protest or demonstration on the BYU-Idaho campus must meet with a duly designated representative of the Public Relations Office and complete a Request for Public Expression or Demonstration form. Information required includes the date, time, and place; who is in charge of the event; who will attend the event; the purpose and planned content of the expression(s); and copies of all literature and other materials intended for display or distribution during the event.<br /> II. APPROVAL OF REQUESTS<br /> The request will be reviewed by the Public Relations Office and the applicant will be informed of approval, approval with conditions, or disapproval within five (5) working days. (Requests that require approval by the Executive Committee and the Board of Trustees must be submitted at least two months prior to the event. This includes any speaker whose program is designed for campus-wide consumption or any event not covered by existing institutional policy.) Upon explanation of exigent circumstances, the Public Relations Office may, at its sole discretion, shorten the time period for review.<br /> The Public Relations Office will consider the following public expression standards in reviewing public expression requests:<br /> 1. Time, Place, and Manner Standards<br /> The event or expressions may not prevent or disrupt the effective operation of university functions or approved activities, such as classes, meetings, ceremonies, or other public events and the conduct of university business in university offices.<br /> The event or expressions may not obstruct the legitimate movement of any person about the campus, movement within any campus building, or access to any campus building (including residence halls).<br /> The event or expression may not be violent, a threat to individual or public safety, or destructive of university or personal property.<br /> The requested time and place must be available, adequate, and appropriate for the type of event planned.<br /> Only one event may be held in a specific location at one time. Events scheduled for the same time must be located at least 100 yards apart.<br /> The event must conform to the size of the location in which it is placed.<br /> 2. Content Standards<br /> The event or expressions may not contradict, be in opposition to, or attack or deride the teachings, doctrine, authority, or practices of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, or be in opposition to its general Church leaders.<br /> The event or expressions may not denigrate, defame, degrade, or be discourteous to individual persons.<br /> The event or expressions must strictly adhere to the Honor Code and must not be dishonest, illegal, unchaste, profane, or unduly disrespectful of others.<br /> Once approval is granted, the event must occur on the date, in the time, place, and manner approved, and in accordance with the public expression standards. If a request is denied, the reason(s) for disapproval will be in writing and available to the applicant. Disapproved requests may be resubmitted in amended form. Appeals for denied requests may be submitted to the Advancement Vice President.<br /> III. NON-BYU-Idaho ORGANIZATIONS AND SPEAKERS<br /> For organizations, participants, and speakers not affiliated with BYU-Idaho, access to the activities for public expression is by formal, authorized invitation only. (See BYU-Idaho Guest Speaker Policy No. 1-4). Individuals or groups affiliated with BYU-Idaho desiring to invite a non-BYU-Idaho individual or organization to come on campus for public expression must meet with a representative of the Public Relations Office and must complete a Request for Public Expression or Demonstration form. Necessary information includes the information requested in the Request for Public Expression or Demonstration form; the name and status of the sponsored group or individual; and the speaker's or organization's general purpose, background, and activities.<br /> The request for a non-BYU-Idaho speaker or organization will be received by the Public Relations Office and the applicant will be informed of approval, approval with conditions, or disapproval within five (5) working days. (Requests which require approval by the Executive Committee and the Board of Trustees must be submitted at least two months prior to the event.) Upon explanation of exigent circumstances, the Public Relations Office may, at its sole discretion, shorten the time period for review.<br /> The Public Relations Office will consider the public expression standards above, plus the following standard in considering whether or not to extend an invitation:<br /> The general purposes and past activities of the proposed invited organization, participant, or speaker may not be contrary or in opposition to the teachings, doctrine, authority, or practices of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, or in opposition to general Church leaders.<br /> Once approval is granted, the organization, participant, or speaker must be formally invited and the event must occur on the date, in the time, place, and manner approved, and in accordance with the public expression standards and, for speakers, the BYU-Idaho Guest Speaker Policy. If a request is denied, the reason(s) for disapproval will be in writing and available to the applicant. Disapproved requests may be resubmitted in amended form. Appeals for denied request may be submitted to the Advancement Vice President.<br /> IV. ENFORCEMENT<br /> Approved events and speakers may be monitored for compliance by the Campus Police. Any videotapes made of the event, participants, or speaker will only be used for law and public expression standards enforcement purposes. If the public expression standards are violated, the event may be terminated by the University and the University may take appropriate and lawful action. Costs of damages or litter collection as a result of an event will be borne by the sponsoring organization or individuals. Students or faculty violating the BYU-Idaho Honor Code may be disciplined according to the Honor Code Procedures. Persons violating state law or local ordinances may be subject to arrest or prosecution.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="1-17"></a><strong>Electronic Mail (1-17)</strong></p>
<p><br /> (Revised March 4, 2004)</p>
<p>I. PURPOSE<br /> To establish the policy for use of electronic mail on the BYU-Idaho campus.</p>
<p>II. POLICY<br /> A. Official university messages to all employees and students may be sent through BYU-Idaho e-mail. Employees and students are expected to regularly check their e-mail accounts for official information. This policy is to assure that important BYU-Idaho communication is received in a timely and consistent manner.<br /> All students and employees are responsible to check their BYU-Idaho e-mail accounts frequently.<br /> BYU-Idaho e-mail is an official method of communicating with all students and employees.<br /> Some official university information may no longer be sent through ground mail.<br /> Students can choose to forward university information to another preferred e-mail account, but remain responsible for reading BYU-Idaho e-mail messages.<br /> B. Acceptable use of electronic mail (e-mail) is based on the Honor Code, common sense, common decency, and civility. BYU-Idaho has provided e-mail to employees and students as a tool to further the mission of BYU-Idaho.<br /> C. BYU-Idaho e-mail helps support instructional, service, and administrative functions and should never be used in any way that does not respect the mission, image, and reputation of BYU-Idaho. All users of the e-mail system provided by BYU-Idaho should understand that:<br /> They agree to accept and adhere to this policy as part of the Honor Code.<br /> The use of e-mail is a privilege and not a right. As owner of the BYU-Idaho e-mail system, BYU-Idaho has the right to remove e-mail accounts for any reason it deems necessary.<br /> BYU-Idaho does not guarantee the privacy or confidentiality of e-mail messages. All messages are considered campus records.<br /> BYU-Idaho reserves the right to monitor, inspect, copy, store, and disclose the contents of e-mail messages when it believes it is appropriate to prevent or correct improper use, satisfy a legal obligation, or insure proper operation of the e-mail facilities.<br /> E-mail is not intended to serve as a repository for records of permanence or lasting value. Users should keep their e-mail cleaned up by archiving, saving, or purging messages older than four months. Messages older than six months are subject to automatic deletion.<br /> Broadcasting messages sent via e-mail to all employees or all students are sent by permission of Public Relations. Broadcast e-mail messages are first sent to Internal Communications within Public Relations. These messages are screened before being sent campus wide to ensure approved content. (See Section III, Procedure.)<br /> Failure to adhere to the minimum standards set forth by this document can result in disciplinary action and/or loss of e-mail privileges.<br /> D. Unacceptable uses of e-mail include, but are not limited to the following:<br /> Using e-mail for any purpose which violates federal or state laws.<br /> Using e-mail for individual commercial gain, political purposes, and excessive or frivolous personal use.<br /> Accessing, reading, or tampering with someone else's e-mail without permission.<br /> Misrepresenting your identity or affiliation in e-mail communications.<br /> Sending harassing, intimidating, abusive, or offensive material to or about others.<br /> Intercepting, disrupting, or altering electronic communications.<br /> Using someone else's identity and password or letting someone else use your identity and password.<br /> Broadcasting messages to large lists of individuals without proper authority.<br /> Excessive amounts of shared data stored in the e-mail post office.<br /> Initiation or propagation of chain mail messages.<br /> E. For specific policies and procedures regarding advertising through campus email, please see Policy 1-23.</p>
<p>III. PROCEDURE<br /> The BYU-Idaho gray branding bar will distinguish official and executive campus e-mail from all others.<br /> Official BYU-Idaho e-mail will be sent within one of the following categories:<br /> Daily Update<br /> A daily all-employee publication of general news and information assembled in one e-mail and sent at 4:45 p.m. M-F.<br /> Important<br /> "Important" messages are sent alone, separate from the Daily Update. They can be sent immediately or at the end of the day.<br /> Examples of e-mails marked "important" could include:<br /> Messages from the president<br /> Messages from President=s Council<br /> Immediate Physical Plant notices<br /> Time-sensitive schedule changes<br /> Deaths<br /> Emergency<br /> "Emergency" messages are sent alone, separate from the Daily Update. They can be sent immediately and could include:<br /> Messages from the president<br /> Messages from President=s Council<br /> Weather warnings<br /> Disasters and catastrophes<br /> Evacuation notices<br /> E-mail by groups<br /> On campus e-mail lists are built and managed through the Server Management Department in Information Technology and Internal Communications within Public Relations. These lists provide specific information to targeted audiences.<br /> Student Update<br /> Four Student Updates are sent as follows:<br /> Student Associations &amp; Societies - Sent Monday at 4:40p.m. (Focuses on Association and Society messages)<br /> Student Activities Update- Sent Tuesday at 4:40 p.m. (Focuses on Student Activities program)<br /> Student Update - Sent Wednesday at 4:40 p.m. (General information for students)<br /> Important - Sent as needed and containing official university notification or information that must be read.<br /> Caution should be exercised when sending large attachments, particularly to students who have a 25 MB limit imposed on their mailboxes. Emails distributed simultaneously to large numbers of people, including those distributed through University Communications, should not exceed a maximum size of 100K, including attachments. Attachments larger than 100K should be converted to HTML format, stored in a public location, such as a web server, and accessed via a hypertext link in the email message.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="1-18"></a><strong>Campus Scheduling Policy: University Sponsored Events (1-18)</strong></p>
<p><br /> (Approved January 31, 2003; updated April 16, 2004)</p>
<p>Purpose<br /> To provide campus groups the procedure, priority, and standards for using University facilities.</p>
<p>Guiding Principles<br /> University events must benefit the students and relate to the institutional mission. Events must have a clear, defined purpose.<br /> Most campus space is considered multi-use space and will be scheduled to meet institutional priorities. Campus space policies will be practical, consistent, and will be communicated to all constituents.</p>
<p>Policies<br /> Event space will be allocated on a priority basis as follows:<br /> a. Students (academic classes and activities).<br /> b. University wards and stakes (on Sundays and Monday evenings from 7:00 PM to 9:00 PM).<br /> c. University departments.<br /> d. Institutional needs.<br /> e. Community needs.<br /> Monday evenings from 7:00 PM to 9:00 PM are reserved for family home evenings. Any exception to this policy will need prior approval by President's Council.<br /> Tuesday evenings are no longer solely reserved for ward and stake activities. Classrooms may now be reserved for other purposes on Tuesday nights. However, bishops and stake presidents will continue to have first priority to their assigned offices on Tuesday evenings after 5:30 PM for the purpose of conducting interviews, etc.<br /> Events must consider risks, liability, students' time, and impact on employee supervision.<br /> Events must be budgeted to avoid undue financial burden.<br /> Events must be affordable to all students. Fees charged must be reasonable, consistent, and protect the institution's tax-exempt status.<br /> Events must comply with all University safety regulations.<br /> Events must be compatible with all University objectives and standards.<br /> Events are not allowed to promote private enterprise or products.<br /> The appropriate vice president or designee will evaluate and authorize events.<br /> Departments who seek to co-sponsor University events with non-university entities must complete an Event Request Form and have the event approved by the Events Council.<br /> Event sponsors will ensure that institutional policies and procedures are followed.<br /> Policies for event scheduling, and regulations that control the care of space and equipment will be posted on the University web site.<br /> Events must be scheduled in accordance with institutional priorities.<br /> a. All events are scheduled and calendared through Campus Scheduling.<br /> b. Major University sponsored events are coordinated at a scheduling meeting<br /> held three times a year at the beginning of each semester.<br /> c. Individuals are not authorized to sponsor campus wide programs and activities.<br /> d. Event sponsors are responsible to schedule and calendar events.<br /> e. Event sponsors must use and schedule campus support services (Custodial,&nbsp;<br /> Media Services (lights and sound), University Police, Ticket Office).<br /> Professionally catered dinners, luncheons, banquets, and other food-related events must be scheduled and provided through University Food Service Catering. Professional catering will not be allowed on campus.<br /> a. Commercial food or personally prepared food can be brought on campus<br /> by the user for scheduled events except in the Manwaring Center.<br /> b. Campus Scheduling will provide the food policies for each facility. These&nbsp;<br /> policies are to be followed.<br /> The BYU-Idaho Ticket Office must manage ticket sales and money collection.<br /> The Events Council will evaluate events to ensure appropriate control and service.</p>
<p>Procedures<br /> Assure event has a student or institutional purpose.<br /> Assure event follows event guidelines and principles.<br /> Have vice president or his designee approve the event.<br /> Schedule the event, event set-up, and take-down with Campus Scheduling, 496-2248.<br /> Campus Scheduling will send the event sponsor an event confirmation.<br /> Event sponsor must make arrangements with Custodial, Media Services, University Police, and Food Services if services are required.<br /> Sponsor must have an event coordinator present to properly oversee and supervise the event.<br /> All health and safety EMERGENCIES should be phoned into University Police, 496-3000.<br /> Microphone set-ups are routinely taken care of by Media Services, responding to a schedule from Campus Scheduling. Other set-ups must be scheduled through Campus Scheduling. Generally, more elaborate sound will involve a fee.<br /> Office furniture, chairs, pianos, etc. cannot be moved to other rooms. When a standard room set up is changed, all items must be returned to the original set up at the end of the event.<br /> User must follow any special regulation for care use and cleaning of space used.<br /> Fill out an evaluation form to provide feedback and suggestions.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="scheduling"></a><a name="1-19"></a><strong>Campus Scheduling Policy: University Sponsored Events (1-19)</strong></p>
<p>(Approved January 31, 2003; updated April 16, 2004)</p>
<p>Purpose<br /> To provide campus groups the procedure, priority, and standards for using University facilities.</p>
<p>Guiding Principles<br /> University events must benefit the students and relate to the institutional mission. Events must have a clear, defined purpose.<br /> Most campus space is considered multi-use space and will be scheduled to meet institutional priorities. Campus space policies will be practical, consistent, and will be communicated to all constituents.</p>
<p>Policies<br /> <br /> Event space will be allocated on a priority basis as follows:<br /> a. Students (academic classes and activities).<br /> b. University wards and stakes (on Sundays and Monday evenings from 7:00 PM to 9:00 PM).<br /> c. University departments.<br /> d. Institutional needs.<br /> e. Community needs.</p>
<p>Monday evenings from 7:00 PM to 9:00 PM are reserved for family home evenings. Any exception to this policy will need prior approval by President's Council.</p>
<p>Tuesday evenings are no longer solely reserved for ward and stake activities. Classrooms may now be reserved for other purposes on Tuesday nights. However, bishops and stake presidents will continue to have first priority to their assigned offices on Tuesday evenings after 5:30 PM for the purpose of conducting interviews, etc.</p>
<p>Events must consider risks, liability, students' time, and impact on employee supervision.</p>
<p>Events must be budgeted to avoid undue financial burden.</p>
<p>Events must be affordable to all students. Fees charged must be reasonable, consistent, and protect the institution's tax-exempt status.</p>
<p>Events must comply with all University safety regulations.</p>
<p>Events must be compatible with all University objectives and standards.</p>
<p>Events are not allowed to promote private enterprise or products.</p>
<p>The appropriate vice president or designee will evaluate and authorize events.</p>
<p>Departments who seek to co-sponsor University events with non-university entities must complete an Event Request Form and have the event approved by the Events Council.</p>
<p>Event sponsors will ensure that institutional policies and procedures are followed.</p>
<p>Policies for event scheduling, and regulations that control the care of space and equipment will be posted on the University web site.</p>
<p>Events must be scheduled in accordance with institutional priorities.</p>
<p>a. All events are scheduled and calendared through Campus Scheduling.<br /> b. Major University sponsored events are coordinated at a scheduling meeting<br /> held three times a year at the beginning of each semester.<br /> c. Individuals are not authorized to sponsor campus wide programs and activities.<br /> d. Event sponsors are responsible to schedule and calendar events.<br /> e. Event sponsors must use and schedule campus support services (Custodial,&nbsp;<br /> Media Services (lights and sound), University Police, Ticket Office).<br /> <br /> Professionally catered dinners, luncheons, banquets, and other food-related events must be scheduled and provided through University Food Service Catering. Professional catering will not be allowed on campus.<br /> a. Commercial food or personally prepared food can be brought on campus<br /> by the user for scheduled events except in the Manwaring Center.<br /> b. Campus Scheduling will provide the food policies for each facility. These&nbsp;<br /> policies are to be followed.<br /> The BYU-Idaho Ticket Office must manage ticket sales and money collection.<br /> The Events Council will evaluate events to ensure appropriate control and service.</p>
<p>Procedures</p>
<p>Assure event has a student or institutional purpose.</p>
<p>Assure event follows event guidelines and principles.</p>
<p>Have vice president or his designee approve the event.</p>
<p>Schedule the event, event set-up, and take-down with Campus Scheduling, 496-2248.</p>
<p>Campus Scheduling will send the event sponsor an event confirmation.</p>
<p>Event sponsor must make arrangements with Custodial, Media Services, University Police, and Food Services if services are required.</p>
<p>Sponsor must have an event coordinator present to properly oversee and supervise the event.</p>
<p>All health and safety EMERGENCIES should be phoned into University Police, 496-3000.</p>
<p>Microphone set-ups are routinely taken care of by Media Services, responding to a schedule from Campus Scheduling. Other set-ups must be scheduled through Campus Scheduling. Generally, more elaborate sound will involve a fee.</p>
<p>Office furniture, chairs, pianos, etc. cannot be moved to other rooms. When a standard room set up is changed, all items must be returned to the original set up at the end of the event.</p>
<p>User must follow any special regulation for care use and cleaning of space used.</p>
<p>Fill out an evaluation form to provide feedback and suggestions.<br /> <br /> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="publicity"></a><strong>On-Campus Publicity, Advertising, and Solicitations Policy (1-23)</strong></p>
<p>(Approved June 16, 2003; revised August 2005)</p>
<p>This policy is intended to: (1) preserve the integrity of the Mission of BYU-Idaho, (2) secure the rights of students and faculty, and (3) safeguard the moral values and principles of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. All solicitations, publicity, and advertising must be conducted in a manner in harmony with the standards and mission of BYU-Idaho.<br /> To go beyond the guidelines stated in this policy, present a detailed proposal to University Communications for consideration.<br /> BYU-Idaho University Communications reserves the right to reject any publicity, advertising, solicitation, or communication not deemed appropriate.</p>
<p>Commercial Solicitations and Advertising<br /> Selling or soliciting by outside businesses, agencies, individuals, for-profit or not-for-profit organizations is prohibited on campus. BYU-Idaho does NOT allow advertising by outside entities on campus except as noted below:<br /> SCROLL: The Scroll is the official newspaper serving the BYU-Idaho campus and will accept appropriate advertising from the private business sector that is in harmony with university standards.<br /> SUMMIT MAGAZINE: Summit Magazine is the official alumni publication of BYU-Idaho and accepts appropriate advertising from the private sector through the office of Public Relations.<br /> NEWS &amp; NOTES: News &amp; Notes is the weekly employee newsletter and DOES NOT publish commercial advertising. A small want-ads section allows retirees and present employees to sell private items.<br /> COUPON BOOKS/CARDS: Non-campus coupon books or cards offering discounts MAY NOT be distributed on campus. However, BYU-Idaho student coupon books offering discounts on products and services may be distributed on campus by or with approval of the Advancement Office.<br /> EVENT PROGRAMS: No commercial advertising is allowed on event programs or the back of tickets. At the invitation of the institution, written recognition may be given.<br /> SPONSORSHIPS: Financial sponsorship or advertising by private business is not allowed on campus.<br /> I-MAGAZINE: i-magazine is a publication created by students for students serving the BYU-Idaho campus and will accept appropriate advertising from the private business sector that is in harmony with university standards.<br /> TELEPHONE DIRECTORY: The BYU-Idaho Telephone Directory will accept appropriate advertising from the private business sector that is in harmony with university standards.<br /> Students participating in an academic course requiring the creation of a business entity are permitted to advertise and sell on campus subject to academic guidelines, signage policy, and the BYU-Idaho Style Guide. (Campus includes all university property and buildings including men's and women's residence halls.)</p>
<p>Publicity and Promotions<br /> This policy contains guidelines for students and employees regarding on-campus publicity of university programs. All publications, collateral, and promotions must comply with this policy and receive authorization before being placed or communicated on campus.<br /> The McKay Library allows publicity and promotions as specified in the guidelines attached to this document.<br /> POLICIES REGARDING HANGING POSTERS, MAKING VIDEOS, AND SIMILAR ACTIVITIES IN THE MCKAY LIBRARY<br /> An important part of the mission of the David O. McKay Library is to maintain an atmosphere conducive to learning "even by study and also by faith." Some activities occasionally attempted by individual students or campus organizations seriously interfere with this and are therefore not permitted. These include but are not necessarily limited to the following.<br /> None of these activities may take place in the Library without specific permission from the Library Director or his designee. Some activities require permission from other university offices as well, as indicated. Failure to secure permission(s) may result in campus disciplinary action being taken.<br /> 1. Displaying posters, flyers, or any other form of printed advertisements. Bring these to the Library Administrative Office. If deemed acceptable, posters will be put up (and taken down) by Library staff. Generally, flyers are not permitted. Flyers found on tables, desks, workstations, etc. will be discarded.<br /> 2. Making video or audio recordings, or taking still photographs. These are extremely disruptive to study and learning. They also may violate an individual's right not to be filmed, recorded, or photographed without having given permission.</p>
<p>Students: Authorization for such activities that are part of a class assignment must be negotiated between your instructor and the Library Director. Be certain to discuss this at the time the assignment is given. If you wait until the last minute, it may not be possible to secure permission. "The work is due tomorrow" will not be sufficient reason for making an exception.<br /> 3. Conducting surveys or interviews (whether recorded or not). Permission MUST be secured from appropriate campus administrators [e.g., dean or department chair and the Director of Institutional Research] before proceeding. A written statement of such permission must be presented when seeking authorization from the Library Director. Surveys approved by the Director of Institutional Research may be conducted in the plaza outside the Library without additional approval from the Library Director, but they may NOT be done inside the building without his consent.<br /> 4. Making announcements or otherwise drawing attention to yourself for the purpose of promoting an event. These are extremely disruptive to study and learning and will not be tolerated. If an emergency page is necessary, contact a worker at the circulation counter.</p>
<p>In rare instances it may be necessary to involve campus security personnel to disperse unauthorized activities. Sanction for such will be reserved to the Library Director or his designee. Neither library patrons nor student employees should initiate such involvement unless they feel an immediate danger to life or property.</p>
<p>Posters<br /> Posters are a common medium for campus promotion.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> STANDARDS: Must be on poster-quality paper.<br /> SIZE: May be no larger than 14" x 22" and no smaller than 11" x 17".<br /> QUANTITY: No more than two posters per event per hallway are allowed.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL: MC Information Desk, Hart 264, Snow 219, MC 394, Activities Communications Team.<br /> LOCATION: Attached to bulletin boards and/or wall railings by pins or clasps-no tape.<br /> 1. Austin: No poster rails. Bulletin board in main hallway.<br /> 2. Benson: Poster rails on first and second floors. Bulletin board on second floor.<br /> 3. Clarke: Poster rails on all three floors. Bulletin board, first floor, southwest entrance.<br /> 4. Hart: Poster rails on second floor only. Bulletin board in east hall, second floor.<br /> 5. Hinckley: Poster rails in first floor hallway.<br /> 6. Kimball: Poster rails on first and second floors, south end of building. Bulletin boards are assigned.<br /> 7. Kirkham: No poster rails. Bulletin boards at south entrance, first and second floor in west hallway.<br /> 8. Manwaring: Poster rails near Galley. Bulletin boards near ticket office and bowling alley.<br /> 9. McKay: Requires approval of Library Administrative Office.<br /> 10. Ricks: Poster rails on all floors. Bulletin boards are assigned.<br /> 11. Romney: Poster rails on all three floors. Some open bulletin boards on first and second floors.<br /> 12. Smith: Poster rails on all floors. Bulletin boards are assigned.<br /> 13. Snow: Poster rails in halls on first and second floors. Bulletin boards are assigned.<br /> 14. Spori: Rails are reserved for artwork. Bulletin boards in south entrance and stairways.<br /> 15. Taylor: Poster rails in first floor halls only. Bulletin board at southeast entrance.<br /> 16. Res. Halls: Bulletin board near offices.</p>
<p>Easels<br /> Easels display larger posters for higher profile events.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: Posters displayed on easels must be 11" x 17" minimum, 24" x 36" maximum.<br /> LOCATION: Scheduled and placed by SCA. Total easels in a building: Austin (4), Benson (4), Hart (10), Hinckley (4), Kimball (4), Kirkham (4), Romney (3), Snow (10), Taylor (2), Manwaring Center (10). TAYLOR BLDG: May only announce Devotionals and/or Forums.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL: MC Information Desk, Hart 264, Snow 219, MC 394, Activities Communications Team.</p>
<p>Flyers/Handbills<br /> Small, printed flyers and handbills may be used as promotion hand outs.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: May be no larger than 8.5" x 11".<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL: MC Information Desk, Hart 264, Snow 219, MC 394, Activities Communications Team.<br /> LOCATION: May be distributed hand-to-hand from information desks, offices, inside the Manwaring Center and outside its north entrances, the McKay Library outdoor quad, and inside the Hart Building. Flyers/handbills may be distributed hand-to-hand to off-campus housing units as approved by each apartment complex manager. Flyers/handbills may not be placed on cars.</p>
<p>E-Mail<br /> Official university messages to all employees and students will be sent through BYU-Idaho e-mail. BYU-Idaho employees and students should regularly check their e-mail accounts for official information. This policy is to assure that important BYU-Idaho messages are communicated in a timely and consistent manner. E-mail messages, including text attachments, should be limited to a maximum size of 100K.<br /> All-employee and all-student e-mails are first sent to Internal Communications within Public Relations. The messages are reviewed for content and appropriateness before being sent campus wide.<br /> Official BYU-Idaho e-mail will be sent within one of the following categories:<br /> A. Daily Update. A daily all-employee publication of general news and information assembled in one e-mail and sent at 4:45 PM M-F. The BYU-Idaho gray branding bar will distinguish official and executive campus e-mail from all others.<br /> B. Important. 'Important' messages are sent alone, separate from the Daily Update. They can be sent immediately or at the end of the day. Examples of e-mails marked 'important' could include:<br /> 1. Messages from the president.<br /> 2. Messages from President's Council.<br /> 3. Immediate Physical Plant notices.<br /> 4. Time-sensitive schedule changes.<br /> 5. Deaths.<br /> C. Emergency. 'Emergency' messages are sent alone, separate from the Daily Update. They can be sent immediately and could include:<br /> 1. Messages from the president.<br /> 2. Messages from President's Council.<br /> 3. Weather warnings.<br /> 4. Disasters and catastrophes.<br /> 5. Evacuation notices.<br /> D. E-mail by groups. On campus e-mail lists are built and managed through Todd Smith in Information Technology and Bryce Rydalch in Internal Communications. These lists provide specific information to targeted audiences.<br /> E. Student Update. Three Student Updates are sent as follows:<br /> 1. Student Associations and Societies. Sent Monday at 4:40 PM. (Focuses on Association and Society messages.)<br /> 2. Student Activities Update. Sent Tuesday at 4:40 PM. (Focuses on Student Activities program.)<br /> 3. Student Update. Sent Wednesday at 4:40 PM. (General information for students.)<br /> 4. Important. Sent as needed and containing official university notifications or information that must be read.<br /> The BYU-Idaho brand (gray bar) will banner the Student Update.</p>
<p>E-mail Posters<br /> Electronic posters sent to targeted mail lists.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide and carry the appropriate logo. www.byui.edu/style.<br /> SIZE: Optimum file size for easiest downloading.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> BREADTH: Targeted lists provided by clients. Not for mass distribution.<br /> APPROVAL/DISTRIBUTION: Internal Communications.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho Homepage News and Promotion Blocks and Highlights<br /> Areas on BYU-Idaho web site open for promotion and news distribution.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide and carry the appropriate logo. www.byui.edu/style.<br /> LOCATIONS: BYU-Idaho home page.<br /> REQUIREMENTS: JPG image size 100w x 75h resolution (all in pixels). Hyperlink to info web page.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL/PLACEMENT: University Communications.</p>
<p>My.byui.edu Web Page Promotion Banner<br /> Area on my.byui.edu web site open for promotion of student events.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> LOCATIONS: My.byui.edu student log-in page.<br /> REQUIREMENTS: JPG image size 384w x 85h, resolution 72 (all in pixels). Hyperlink to info web page.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL/PLACEMENT: Internal Communications.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho Online Bulletin Board<br /> 1. Advertisers are limited to BYU-Idaho students and employees and must supply a BYU-Idaho email address in order to use service (except housing contracts and retirees).<br /> 2. All advertising must be consistent with the standards of decency and good taste espoused by BYU-Idaho.<br /> 3. Items for sale must be the advertiser's personal property.<br /> 4. No commercial businesses.<br /> a. Advertisers may post ads to offer an individual service (typing, mending, ski waxing, etc.), but advertising a business to earn a substantial portion of your living is not the purpose of this service.<br /> b. Repetitive selling of the same item or product is considered a commercial business and will not be approved.<br /> c. Disguised or veiled advertising by students or employees for commercial businesses is prohibited.<br /> 5. The Housing link on BYU-Idaho Home Page must be used to advertise housing contracts. They can be posted for 30 days.<br /> 6. The classified ads (other than housing contracts) will remain posted for two weeks.<br /> 7. The Ride Board category can only be used by someone entering a valid BYU-Idaho username and password.<br /> 8. BYU Idaho is not responsible for any items or services offered or purchased using this web site. It is the sole responsibility of the individual purchasing an item or service to verify its validity, value, and appropriateness. Special precautions should be taken in offering or obtaining rides from any individual.<br /> 9. Online classified advertising may also be placed in the Scroll online newspaper.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.</p>
<p>Student Ads<br /> Student personal ads may be displayed on note cards posted on bulletin boards.<br /> STYLE: Student personal ads must be done in good taste and dated.<br /> SIZE: Student personal ads must be on 3" x 5" note cards.<br /> PLACEMENT/LOCATION: Student personal ads are displayed only on approved bulletin boards in the Austin, Hart east hall, Manwaring Center 1st floor, and Snow 2nd floor near elevator. Students are responsible for placing and removing their own ad cards.<br /> APPROVAL: MC Information Desk, Hart 264, Snow 219.</p>
<p>Ground Signs<br /> Weatherproof signs that are placed around campus on a temporary basis.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: Ground signs may be no larger than 14" x 22" and stand no taller than 3', unless otherwise approved.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL/PLACEMENT: Pre-approval by Internal Communications.</p>
<p>Table Tents<br /> Table tents are advertisements displayed three dimensionally on tables and counters.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: Must be no larger than 8.5" x 11".<br /> QUANTITY: One table tent per table or counter top may be displayed in designated campus buildings.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL/PLACEMENT: Pre-approval by Internal Communications.<br /> LOCATION: Tables and countertops in Kimball, Smith, Taylor and Manwaring Center. Manwaring Center food services tables require the approval of the Director of Food Services.</p>
<p>Banners<br /> Flexible, weatherproof signs for display inside or outside that hang freely without frames.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: Pre-approved on a case-by-case basis.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Self directed.<br /> APPROVAL/PLACEMENT: Pre-approval by Internal Communications.</p>
<p>Kiosks<br /> Outdoor weather-protected kiosks displaying large format advertisements.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: Kiosks will hold posters 44.5" x 45" (1), 22" x 45" (2), or 22" x 22" (4).<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: University Communications.<br /> One panel of each kiosk (four total panels) may be assigned to approved participants.<br /> Occasionally, University Communications may need to access and utilize panels assigned to other participants for key institutional messages. In these cases, notification and coordination will be provided at the earliest possible date.<br /> Each panel is to be maintained by the assigned participant including the placement and removal of information.<br /> The approved participant must ensure that all information promoted in their panel is appropriate and follows branding and terminology guidelines. University Communications will monitor all kiosk panels as occasion dictates and reserves the right to remove unacceptable materials without prior notice.<br /> A key will be distributed through University Communications to the assigned responsible party. No duplicate keys are to be made and all keys should be returned to University Communications.<br /> Scheduling of panels will be controlled by the assigned participant.<br /> The University Communications panel may be reserved for one week per campaign. Additional days/weeks may be added if no other reservations have been made.<br /> LOCATIONS:<br /> Location 1: South side of Manwaring Center.<br /> Location 2: Sidewalk intersection east of Hart Building.<br /> Location 3: McKay Library quad.<br /> Location 4: Northwest of the Hinckley Building.</p>
<p>Large Format Signs<br /> Large format signs such as indoor kiosks, movie posters, vertical framed banners (Olympic banners), and 4' x 8' billboard type signs.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> SIZE: Pre-approved on a case-by-case basis.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: University Communications.<br /> LOCATIONS: Approved by University Communications.</p>
<p>Multimedia<br /> Multimedia promotions, video commercials, and a news magazine.<br /> STYLE: Any communication or promotional material sponsored by BYU-Idaho must incorporate the official BYU-Idaho Style Guide (www.byui.edu/style) and carry the appropriate logo.<br /> PROJECT MANAGEMENT: University Communications.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="video"></a><strong>Video/Audio Production and Distribution (1-26)</strong></p>
<p>(Approved by President's Council on May 27, 2005)</p>
<p>Statement of Purpose<br /> This policy covers two issues concerning video/audio production and distribution.</p>
<p>Video/audio productions created both on- and off-campus by academic and administrative departments (colleges, classes, faculty, employees, and students).</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho recordings (both video and/or audio) of speeches and programs involving the University President and all University programs: devotionals, forums, dedications, employee meetings, President Club programs, etc.</p>
<p>Policy and Procedure<br /> Video/audio productions created by academic and administrative departments (colleges, classes, faculty, employees, and students).</p>
<p>In general, BYU-Idaho will not produce or release video/audio presentations for wide-scale distribution.</p>
<p>Any media creation produced on campus or by University employees or students which is intended for use on- or off-campus (other than class assignments) may not be distributed, reproduced, broadcast, or provided to any off-campus entity for the purpose of viewing, distributing, reproducing, or broadcasting without prior approval from President's Council.</p>
<p>President's Council approval is required in order to manage the release or distribution of approved productions. This protects the University's legal rights, ensures appropriate quality and content, and preserves the University's brand identity.</p>
<p>Where approval is sought, the video presentation must be submitted in sufficient time for review prior to release. To facilitate approval, a description of the project, its use and distribution, must also be provided. Along with video or media production, all legal rights concerning the content, including copyright releases, personal appearance releases, or music clearances, must be obtained. All personal appearance releases must be obtained by the Public Relations Office.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho video/audio recordings of University programs.</p>
<p>Except for approved institutional purposes, BYU-Idaho will not release or distribute video/audio recordings of University programs, employee meetings, special events, dedications, devotionals, forums, or other activities occurring on- or off-campus on a wide-scale basis.</p>
<p>A request to record for the intent to release such programs can only be secured through President's Council. To the extent that such events are recorded, their use, release, or distribution, in whole or in part, may only be approved by President's Council.</p>
<p>President's Council reserves the right to withhold the release of any program. Some programs will not be released under any circumstance.</p>
<p>All recordings will be archived by Media Services. Access to and availability of these recording is defined by the following:</p>
<p>Secured recordings:&nbsp;Certain of these recordings are not released under any circumstance. Others are not released to the general public, but are intended for specific university audiences: faculty, employees, and students or in some cases all three. These recordings are archived in Media Services and can be accessed upon request by the approved audiences. The Library will control these recordings and will load them on equipment for viewing or listening.<br /> Limited use recordings:&nbsp;These recordings are released for University use. They may be checked out by employees and faculty for educational purposes and played to campus audiences: employees, faculty and students. These recordings are not to be copied, distributed, or removed from campus for general audience viewing.<br /> General recordings:&nbsp;These recordings are released for general use. They are available on KBYI/KBYR FM, KBYU-TV and BYU-TV etc., and can be checked out, viewed, and shown as desired.</p>
<p><br /> <a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><strong><a name="1-27"></a>Building Access Policy (1-27)</strong></p>
<p><em>(Approved November 1, 2004 by President's Council)</em></p>
<p>I. Purpose<br /> The purpose of this policy is to establish guidelines for after-hours access to campus buildings; to promote the safety of employees, students, and others; and to provide security for university property.<br /> II. Philosophy<br /> Employees and students should have access to campus facilities after hours as needed for legitimate purposes. Policies should be in place to provide for the safety of those entering the buildings after hours and for the security of university property.<br /> III. Policy<br /> Building Access<br /> <img alt="Campus Building Schedule" height="282" src="Images/societies/Building_Schedule.jpg" width="651" /><br /> *Academic building lockup will begin at 11:30 p.m. and be completed by 12:30 a.m.<br /> <br /> All campus buildings will be open from 6 a.m. to 10 p.m. on Sundays unless otherwise posted. Academic buildings will not be open on holidays unless specifically scheduled.<br /> Buildings are considered secured before and after the times noted and may be accessed only by authorized employees after hours and on weekends and holidays.<br /> Employees are authorized to access assigned offices or workstations 24 hours per day.<br /> Employees are not authorized to access areas outside their assigned work areas after buildings are secured.<br /> Employee dependants are not authorized to be in buildings after normal business hours unless accompanied by an authorized employee.<br /> Employees are not authorized to use facilities such as the swimming pool, bowling alley, gyms, ballrooms, woodshop, auto lab, welding lab, manufacturing lab, agriculture labs, and/or computer labs for their personal or family activities after buildings have been secured.<br /> Students<br /> Once buildings are secured, students (including student employees) are only allowed access if they have an appropriate pass as per university policy 4-5.<br /> Ecclesiastical Use<br /> Generally, campus buildings are open for ecclesiastical access from 6 a.m. to 10 p.m. Sundays and 6 p.m. to 10 p.m. on Tuesdays. In emergencies ecclesiastical leaders with keys to the buildings may access buildings at other times.<br /> IV. Assignment of Keys<br /> Keys are issued in accordance with university policy 7-4.<br /> V. Police<br /> University Police have the responsibility to secure buildings in the evening and investigate when people are found in buildings after they are secured. University Police provide emergency access to buildings in case of fire or natural disaster. They also unlock doors when keys are accidentally locked in or provide escorts into locked areas to retrieve personal property.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><strong><a name="1-28"></a>Information Privacy (1-28)</strong></p>
<p><em>(Approved by President's Council, January 2005)</em></p>
<p>Purpose<br /> To promote the privacy of certain confidential university, employee, student and third party records collected and used at BYU-Idaho.<br /> Policy<br /> Reasonable measures shall be taken to protect and secure private and confidential information collected and used at the University. The University shall comply with applicable federal and state privacy laws including FERPA, the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA), and HIPAA.<br /> Implementation<br /> Employees of the University shall receive training regarding institutional information privacy policies and procedures. They shall agree to abide by such policies by signing an Information Usage Agreement that outlines their responsibility to maintain the security and confidentiality of protected information. This protected information includes:<br /> Academic records of students as detailed in University policy 4-4.<br /> Financial records of students and third parties as detailed in University policy 3-7.<br /> Health records of patrons of the University Student Health Center as detailed in the "Notice of BYU-Idaho Student Health Center Privacy Practices" (See <a href="http://www.byui.edu/health-center/insurance">INSURANCE</a>)<br /> Other information deemed private or confidential by the University such as social security numbers and personal financial information.<br /> Employees are expected to:<br /> Abide by the BYU-Idaho Computer Security and Use Policy, including prevention of unauthorized access to or use of any information in electronic data files maintained, stored or processed by BYU-Idaho by using safe password protocol, by protecting passwords, and by locking or logging out of computer systems when leaving work areas.<br /> Understand that all information made available to them, irrespective of the medium, may contain sensitive and confidential information that should be disclosed only to those authorized to receive it.<br /> Respect the privacy and rules governing the use of private information by utilizing, exhibiting, and divulging the content of any record or report only as required for the fulfillment of work assignments in accordance with BYU-Idaho policy.<br /> Insure that any printed material containing private information is handled, stored and disposed of appropriately.<br /> Report any violations of security policies or attempted unauthorized access of protected information to an institutional compliance officer or other designated agent of BYU-Idaho.<br /> Secure electronic data in accordance with Information Technology policy.<br /> Ensure that third party contractors who are given access to any private records agree to abide by similar privacy and security standards and policies as required by GLBA.</p>
<p>For training on information privacy, please review the following PowerPoint presentation:<br /> Information Privacy and Compliance Training</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p><a name="1-29"></a><strong>Approval Policy for Gifts-in-Kind Received on Campus (1-29)</strong></p>
<p><em>(Approved by President's Council, March 2005. Revised and approved by President's Council on December 19, 2005)</em></p>
<p>Purpose<br /> The purpose of this policy is to ensure that non-cash gifts/gifts-in-kind (GIK) are not accepted by the University if they may result in costs or obligations that the University does not wish to bear. This policy does not apply to gifts that come through the Church's gift review committee.<br /> (Gifts solicited by groups from multiple local vendors for specific events will be excluded from this policy, i.e. donations used for such things as door prizes. However, a description of the event, the use of the gifts solicited and specific restrictions on the types of gifts to be accepted must be approved in writing by the appropriate vice president prior to solicitation. LDS Foundation must also approve the gift raising activity and will provide a list of local businesses that may not be solicited.)<br /> Policy and Procedure<br /> Any employee with a valid NetID may initiate a GIK approval request. Prior to acceptance, all GIK must be approved by the vice president over the department in which the GIK is intended to be used or his designee. A web based process has been designed to facilitate the approval process (http://web.byui.edu/giftrequest/). Any potentially hazardous material (chemicals, solvents, lubricants, radio active materials, fuels, flammables, explosives etc.) must be evaluated in writing by the Safety Office prior to initiating a request for GIK approval. A copy of the written evaluation must be submitted to the appropriate vice president prior to the initiation of this procedure.<br /> The web-based process requires submission of the following information for each GIK.<br /> Donor name and address<br /> Any relevant corporate affiliation and title<br /> Donor telephone number<br /> The gift available date<br /> A description of the gift<br /> The estimated value of the gift<br /> An explanation of how the gift will be benefit the University<br /> Any expected costs of installation<br /> A description of space required to store, install, or display the gift<br /> Any security requirements associated with the gift<br /> Other associated cost of the gift (transfer fees, taxes, repair costs, etc.)<br /> The general ledger account number of the department who will be the recipient of the gift<br /> The estimated disposal date of the gift (optional)<br /> NetID of the individual making the request<br /> Date request submitted<br /> The e-mail address of the responsible vice president<br /> This information will be submitted via a campus web page and stored. In addition an e-mail will be submitted to the appropriate vice president notifying him that a document awaits review along with the web link to the approval site.<br /> The Vice president will access and review the information via the web and either approve or deny the gift based upon the following criteria.<br /> 1. GIK is immediately useful to the institution<br /> 2. GIK can be sold and there are no restrictions that would prevent the university from disposing of the GIK for cash<br /> If a GIK does not meet at least one of the above criteria or if the GIK requires resources or new or reconfigured space to store or display or use the gift, the GIK request can only be approved by president's council. The general policy of the school is that unless a GIK is useful to the university, it will be sold immediately.<br /> If the gift is approved by the vice president, a record will be created for the request. This record of approved GIK will be sent to the director of Financial Services for institutional review. After review, if no problems are identified, the originator and Philanthropies will be notified on the decision of the GIK request. A history file of all approved GIK will be maintained and may be accessed on the web. The file may be sorted by the approval number, originator, donor name, approval/denial or recipient department.</p>
<p><a href="#Top"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Back to top</span></a></p>
<hr align="center" noshade="noshade" size="2" width="100%" />
<p>&copy; BYU-Idaho<br /> Rexburg, Idaho</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" GroupStart=""><xPower Type="List" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="Facebook;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/><!--071613 xpowercomponent_Optional to xPower--></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x36149" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x17645" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
