<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x66116" Name="By-Laws" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">By-Laws</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">By-Laws</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>BY LAWS of the Education Society </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article I Official Name &amp; Membership</strong></p>
<p>Section 1: The name of the Society shall be Brigham Young University-Idaho Education Society, hereinafter referred to as the Education Society.</p>
<p>Section 2: Membership in the Education Society will be determined according to the following requirements:</p>
<p>&bull;-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; An accepted student of Brigham Young University- Idaho.</p>
<p>&bull;-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A declared Education Major or of some major or minor affiliated with Education.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article II Purposes &amp; Goals</strong></p>
<p>Section 1: At least one monthly activity will be planned to promote networking and professional development within the Teacher Education Department.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article III Structure and Leadership</strong></p>
<p>Section 1: The Education Society will be led by a President appointed by the society advisor.</p>
<p>Section 2: The society will create committees as needed and invite an individual to serve as committee leader. Committees will include; logistics, publicity, newsletter, and activities.</p>
<p>Section 2: New committees may be formed on a need basis.&nbsp; The Education Society President and advisor will approve all new committees before they are formed.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article IV Appointments and Invitations</strong></p>
<p>Section 1: Advisors of the Society will appoint The President of the Education Society.&nbsp; The President will be released of his/her appointment by advisors depending on availability. A society president will not serve more than one year.</p>
<p>Section 2: Students who show involvement and are taking a proactive role to improve professional development may be invited by the President or advisor to be a committee leader or a committee member.</p>
<p>Section 3: Committee Leaders may invite Society members to be committee members of their specific committee under the direction of the President and advisor.</p>
<p>Section 4: Invitations to committees will be ongoing during the semester according to the needs of the Education Society.</p>
<p>Section 3: Students off-track are able to participate in society functions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article V: Leadership Responsibilities</strong></p>
<p>Section 1: The President is to head up and run the Education Society under the direction of the advisor, department head, and College Dean of Education.&nbsp; They will report to the advisor about society events.&nbsp; The President will oversee the Committee Leaders in assisting in the needs of the Education Society.&nbsp; He/she will supervise the committees.&nbsp; He/she will conduct or delegate to Committee Leaders within the Education Society.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>Section 2: The Logistics Committee Leader is to oversee all activity in the Logistics Committee.&nbsp;&nbsp; The Logistics Committee Leader is to work with their designated committee members and other Committee Leaders in the Education Society under the direction of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean of Education.&nbsp; Meeting minutes, accounting of funds provided by the University, and a semester budget will be recorded by the Logistics Committee Leader.</p>
<p>Section 3: The Publicity Committee Leader is to oversee all activity in the Publicity Committee.&nbsp; The Publicity Committee Leader is to work with their designated committee members and other Committee Leaders in the Education Society under to direction of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean of Education.&nbsp; Emails to be sent out for activities will be created and sent to the advisors for review.&nbsp; The advisors will be responsible for distributing the emails.&nbsp; Posters and other publicity will be part of the responsibilities (school requirements will be followed).</p>
<p>Section 4: The Newsletter Committee Leader is to oversee all activity in the Newsletter Committee.&nbsp; The Newsletter Committee Leader is to work with their designated committee members and other Committee Leaders in the Education Society under to direction of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean of Education.&nbsp; The Newsletter Committee Leader is responsible for the design and structure of the Education Society Newsletter and BYU-Idaho Education Society webpage.&nbsp; The Newsletter Committee Leader will be responsible for finding out current information about announcements, programs, activities, and endorsements offered by the Education Society, Education Department, and other professionals in the field of Education.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Section 5: The Activities Committee Leader is to oversee all activity in the Activities Committee.&nbsp; The Activities Committee Leader is to work with their designated committee members and other Committee Leaders in the Education Society under to direction of the President, Advisor, Department Head, and College Dean of Education.&nbsp; The Activities Committee Leader will be responsible for arranging events such as forums, trips, and discussion groups for all society members.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Section 6: Responsibilities of all Committee Leaders will be met by working with their designated committee members.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Article VI: Committee Leaders and Responsibilities (Financial rules, meetings, and governing policies)</strong></p>
<p>Section 1: The Committee Leaders and President will meet twice a month and report on their job and responsibilities and inform committee leaders of occurrences in their committees.</p>
<p>&bull;-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President and the advisor will assign the specific meeting time and place.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&bull;-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Meeting times and location will be announced to concerned parties at least one week in advance.</p>
<p>&bull;-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Advisors will be informed of committee leader meetings, but are not required to come.&nbsp; Details of committee leader meetings will be reported to the advisor after they are held if the advisor is not present.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Section 2: One monthly activity will be planned to promote networking and professional development within the Teacher Education Department: The committee leaders and members will plan and execute the activities while staying within the budget.</p>
<p>Sections 3: Committees may be formed as needed.&nbsp; Responsibilities within the new committee will be clearly stated and approved by the advisor before the committee is able to act as part of the Education Society.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35993" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x30782" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
