<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.88 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x66192" Name="FAQs" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQs</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQs</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Frequently Asked Questions</strong></h3>
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong>How do I join the society?<strong> </strong></strong></p>
<p>You can join the society by sending your name, email and I-number to byuidental@gmail.com. Once we recieve your information, your student account will be charged $10, you will be added to our email list and you will be given access to our I-Learn group (I-Learn coming soon).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Why should I join the society?</strong></p>
<p>Being a member of the society comes with a number of benefits. You will be able to have access to all of our tips, hints and resources in our I-Learn group (coming soon). You will be able to hear from our guest speakers that come to visit us such as dentists, dental students and admissions committees. You will have support from those who are on the same path as you and much more. Come meet us at one of our meetings or email us at byuidental@gmail.com for more information. We meet on campus in room 270 in the Benson building every Thursday at 7pm.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Why am I charged $10 to be a member?</strong></p>
<p>Being a member of the society is a great opportunity to gain experience and be provided with opportunities to increase your skills and increase your chances of being accepted to dental school. Although we would love to be able to provide this for free, some of our activities require materials or services that cost money. Paying the low $10 cost allows us to make these activities and services availiable to you and are a lot cheaper than at other universities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Why dentistry?</strong></p>
<p>The dental profession offers a wide range of benefits. Aside from monetary compensation, dentists are able to provide a service for the community that gives them extreme satisfaction. They are well respected members of society that do all they can to uphold the responsibility that comes with the profession. Dentistry is a dynamic and stable profession that can offer security as well as the opportunity to continually advance in education as well as technique. It is also very flexible and gives you the opportunity to not only provide for a family, but support them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>How do I know which dental schools to apply to?</strong></p>
<p>Choosing a dental school is not always easy. There are a number of different things to take into account when trying to choose where to apply. Things to look at are tuition costs, equipment costs, residency, length of program and scholarships offered. Not only should you take into consideration the cost of the program and the means by which you will pay for it, but also location, the school's philosophy and teaching style, instructor to student ratio as well as the focus of the program (clinical, research, etc). The search for a dental school can be a lengthy process, but the best way to get a feel for what you like in a dental school is to research each school by going to their website as well as talk with those dentists you have shadowed to see what they liked about the school they attended.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>What major should I choose?</strong></p>
<p>According to most dental schools, they have no preference as to which major you choose. Most of them will say they encourage a diversity of majors, as long as all pre-requisite classes are taken. It is important to choose a major with which you are genuinely interested in and that can be a back-up profession should you not recieve admission into a dental school.</p>
<p>Having said that, it is important to plan early and take into account the policies that BYU-Idaho enforces. Things to take into account are the 120-credit limit and the fact that you must petition to change your major if you have over 60 credits. Meet with an advisor at the Ag/Life Science Academic Discovery Center in BEN 240 to make sure you have planned correctly. There are also resources available at the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/health-professions" title="Health Professions Website">Health Professions website</a> that will aid you in class planning and major selection.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x30835" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
