<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.65 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x66304" Name="History of Ricks" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">History of Ricks</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">History</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p><img alt="Old Gym" src="http://contentdm.lib.byu.edu/utils/ajaxhelper/?CISOROOT=BYUICampus&amp;CISOPTR=385&amp;action=2&amp;DMSCALE=90&amp;DMWIDTH=512&amp;DMHEIGHT=383&amp;DMX=0&amp;DMY=0&amp;DMTEXT=old&amp;DMROTATE=0" style="float: right;" title="Old Gym" /></p>
<p>This is a brief history of Ricks College from a chapter of Arthur Porter Jr.'s history written by David L. Crowder.</p>
<p>Arthur Porter Jr. Reading Room is the name of the room that Special Collections is now located. Arthur Porter was&nbsp;a family man who was one of the first professors at Ricks Academy and Ricks College. He was&nbsp;a religious leader and&nbsp;a businessman. He was involved in the Commercial Club, Chamber of Commerce, and Rotary Club.&nbsp;He was a part of the County Fair&nbsp;Associations, Boy Scouts, and Hospital Advisory Board. He was City Councilman in 1913-1919 and then was Mayor of Rexburg from 1929-1935. He later was in the House of Representatives from 1943-1946 and after that was the County Superintendent of Schools from 1949-1953.</p>
<p><strong>Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College</strong></p>
<p>In September 1902, Arthur Porter, Jr., commenced teaching at Ricks Academy. For that purpose he had moved from Preston and his teaching position at Oneida Stake Academy. Porter's tenure at Ricks Academy would see many changes, but the physical plant in 1902 must have been disheartening. The academy was housed in the old ZCMI building on East Main Street. The building was a two-story brick building with an addition on the east side. Because the building could not accommodate all the students, the first ward church was used for classrooms during the week. (The first ward church at that time was located south of Main Street on Second East.) The foundation for a building had been laid where the present campus is located although there was some criticism concerning the distance one needed to travel &nbsp;to get there from downtown.</p>
<p>&nbsp;The academy offered seventh and eighth grades as well as the first two years of high school. There was a public grade school in Rexburg at the time but no high school. Many Students were "considerably older than students in corresponding grades today," explained Porter, "due to pioneer conditions." The academy name had been changed earlier in 1902 from Fremont Stake Academy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;(Page 48 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>&nbsp;When Porter was hired, he joined five other faculty members. Ezra Christiansen (name was changed to Dalby in 1907) was principal and taught theology, pedagogy, history, and science. Hannah Grover taught English, drawing, and needlework. Ellen Clark taught elocution, reading, orthography, and physical culture. Thomas Jones taught preparatory classes, physiology, and penmanship. Edgar O. T. Reid taught the business course. Porter's courses rounded out the curriculum. He was assigned to teach mathematics, geography, and vocal music. His music credentials seemed to be a good singing voice and some facility on the mandolin. Only Christiansen and Porter held college degrees. Teachers often had no more than an eighth grade education. Porter explained that "an eighth grade graduate could get a contract to teach. In some country districts, the matter of cost was a qualification of importance. A low salary might be offered, and you got the job if you exhibited a fair education although not a graduate from a high school or college. Nevertheless," he continued, "I do not wish to disparage the work of teachers. Their opportunities were limited by pioneer conditions and lack of facilities. The great men and women that arose out of these schools testify to the great value of the teaching done and the dedication of these teachers to the profession/*</p>
<p>The academy had started in 1888 as Bannock Stake Academy. In 1898, Bannock Stake was divided and the school received a new name to reflect the new stake - Fremont Stake Academy. That lasted until January 7 25, 1902, when the Fremont, Bingham, and Teton Stakes were combined into one district for educational purposes. That necessitated another name change. There was some debate about a new name and the local board recommended the name "Smith Academy/' honoring the Prophet Joseph Smith and the then current, president of the Church, Joseph F. Smith. "Smith Academy" lasted until March 5, 1902, when, upon recommendation of the Church Board of Education, the name was changed to Ricks Academy honoring Thomas E. Ricks, founder of Rexburg. Ricks had died a few months earlier on September 28, 1901.</p>
<p>When Porter began teaching at the academy, the school was under the jurisdiction of the General Church Board of Education of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and a local board. The local board was composed of the presidencies of the three stakes in the</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 49)</p>
<p>education district Thomas E. Bassett, president of Fremont Stake (Rexburg Stake did not come into existence until June 23, 1935), was president of the board. About two hundred students attended the academy during the 1902-03 school year.</p>
<p>The students were able to leave the ZCM1 and first ward buildings for the 1903-04 school year. The new building had been completed in time for classes to be held in the fourteen classrooms of the new three- story stone building. Also in the building were four office rooms, a library, an auditorium and laboratory rooms.</p>
<p>During the 1904-05 school year, Porter taught only mathematics classes. By this time the faculty had increased to eleven and was more specialized although eight of the eleven did not have college degrees. Porter seriously considered writing a mathematics textbook, but he never got that project underway.</p>
<p>For the 1905-06 school year, Porter was assigned to teach science. That meant he taught physics, chemistry, physiology, geology, and botany. He collected a number of various bugs to use for illustration in his classes. Some faculty committees were established to aid the students in their academic and social pursuits. Porter was assigned to the athletic and amusements committees along with Alfred Bond, Oscar A. Kirkham, and Retta Snow. Porter's name appeared in print in the student publication Student Rays for the first time in February 1906 in the joke section:</p>
<p>Amy (in physics class): The air has other properties besides the ones mentioned. Because when cooking you cannot use the recipes for low climates when up in the mountains as it does not require as much material - sugar for instance. The higher up the less material.</p>
<p>Instructor Porter: If you can prove that. Miss Amy, I shall have my kitchen moved upstairs immediately.</p>
<p>On April 10, 1906, Gertrude Elizabeth Porter died leaving her husband and three little girls. The students and faculty of Ricks Academy attended the funeral and extended resolutions and letters of condolence to die bereaved The students and faculty also joined the cortege to the I where the family hoarded the train tor the ride to Logan where Mrs. Porter was to be buried. Porter returned from Logan</p>
<p>(Page 50 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>on April 21. He resumed his teaching responsibilities at the academy on April 23.</p>
<p>During the 1906-07 school year, Porter again taught science classes. The year was interrupted with the Founder's Day program on November 12. Aposde John Henry Smith dedicated the new building (it had taken almost three years for all encumbrances against the building to be paid). A quartet composed of Porter, David Smith, Alta Watson, and a Miss Harris sang as part of the dedicatory ceremony.</p>
<p>Early in December 1907, several people representing the ward mutuals, the militia, and the academy met in Dr. George E. Hyde's office to discuss organization of a city athletic association to benefit young people. A committee was formed with Dr. Hyde, chairman; Porter, secretary; and Robert Tempest, treasurer. Another committee on membership was appointed by the chairman. Woodvine Hall was available four nights a week and equipment was purchased to set up a gymnasium there. A membership fee of seventy-five cents a month was charged to pay expenses. It was a grand scheme to entertain the young people, but the developers soon found that the young people were more interested in other forms of entertainment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;Porter is credited in the May 1907 Student Rays with having the following interchange with a student:</p>
<p>&nbsp;Instructor Porter in botany: Every green plant contains chlorophyll.</p>
<p>Fayette: Goodness! Then there must be lots of chlorophyll in this class.</p>
<p>Porter rested from the school year and began preparation for the next one by attending a summer school session at University of Utah in Salt Lake City to do some graduate study. He left in June and returned to Rexburg a few days before classes started in the fall.</p>
<p>Porter's teaching load was increased for the 1907-08 school year. For the first time, classes in languages appear in the catalog, and Porter, with his background in German, was assigned two classes along with his science classes. Additionally, Principal Dalby (by this time he had changed his last name) decided that students, faculty, and anyone interested from the community would be invited to attend a "Free Lecture Course" to be held each Wednesday night. Dalby had the whole year scheduled. Porter was assigned to lecture on the subject of</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 51)</p>
<p>"Evolution" on December 11, 1907, and on "Travels in Europe" on March 17, 1908. His scientific background fit him for the first lecture and his missionary background fit him for the second.</p>
<p>In February 1908 the Student Rays carried a "Roast to the Faculty":</p>
<p>Arthur Porter, we like the name,</p>
<p>We know a lady who likes the same. [Nelle Child]</p>
<p>He teaches German with care and skill,</p>
<p>Puts us through the language mill.</p>
<p>Sober and serious all the time,</p>
<p>Whate'er he teaches is good, sublime.</p>
<p>We'll learn the lessons he presents,</p>
<p>And extend to him our compliments.</p>
<p>In March 1908 Student Rays under "General Locals" carried this</p>
<p>interchange:</p>
<p>John: Brother Porter, what course does Effie Evans take?</p>
<p>Porter: She takes devotional and noon hour.</p>
<p>Instructor Porter: If a bear went in a dry goods store, what would it want 7</p>
<p>Spencer: It would want muslin.</p>
<p>An annual chore of academy students and faculty was April clean- up day. In 1908, it was Porter's turn, along with Oscar Steele and Ezekial Holman, to see that assignments were made and the work done. After the work was finished, Porter attended city council meeting on May 4 and, "in behalf of the Ricks Academy, petitioned the council for a refund of $5 for work done by them on the street east of the academy grounds last Friday, the work having been necessary for drainage of waste waters from the grounds. The matter was referred to the road and bridge committee to investigate and report at die next session." The council decided no payment was necessary.</p>
<p>In April, a writer for Student Rays observed that "Miss Nelle Child, instructor of music at the academy last year, was a visitor at the school recently." She may have visited the school generally, but there was no doubt whom she visited specifically. The courtship of Arthur and Nelle was by no means a well-kept secret. In fact, rather than attend summer</p>
<p>(Page 52 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>school in June and July, Arthur and Nelle were married June 24, 1908, in the Salt Lake Temple. Cards were sent to announce the wedding. The couple honeymooned for several days, returning to Rexburg on July 15.</p>
<p>Earlier, on June 15, Porter had been asked to speak at a funeral of one of his students, Mary Robb. He "spoke in highest praise of her character and vigorous scholarship pointing out that, though young, she had lived a long and successful life." Mary, from Wilford, Idaho, was twenty years old. She died suddenly and unexpectedly from blood poisoning " superinduced by appendicitis," according to an article in the Current- Journal.</p>
<p>During the 1908-09 school year, Porter was assigned to teach science and German again. The "Free Lecture Course" had not worked out well and was dropped for the year. The Student Rays for November, under the heading "Fizzers," poked a little fun at Porter's chemistry class:</p>
<p>Brother Porter: Students, please taste Experiment 32.</p>
<p>In the fall, 1908, Porter taught a zoology class. "Professor Porter's class in zoology is doing some extremely interesting work in the laboratory this week. The students bring to class live crayfish and frogs which are dissected and studied minutely."</p>
<p>The Christmas issue, 1908, of Student Rays again noted a dialogue from Porter's chemistry class:</p>
<p>Martha: Mr. Porter, is a liter of dark brown gas visible to the eye?</p>
<p>Brother Porter: Yes, unless you're asleep.</p>
<p>The January 1 909 issue noted the following advice:</p>
<p>Brother Porter: Students, do not delay performing this experiment any longer as it will be necessary for you to become suffocated while doing it.</p>
<p>The March issue carried this sage advice:</p>
<p>Porter: You should have a pleasant smile for your visitors. That's the way my wife got me.</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 53)</p>
<p>Observing Arbor Day in April 1909 provided the impetus for faculty and students of the academy to clean up the grounds. Porter had done such a good job directing the 1908 effort that he and H. H. Hale were assigned to direct the effort in 1909. "Arbor Day was celebrated at the Ricks Academy with enthusiasm and school loyalty. The students all came out in their working clothes and, provided with shovels and other implements, spent the day in working to improve the surroundings. They were encouraged and directed by their teachers and Principal Dalby who worked side by side with them all day," noted an observer for the Current-Journal U A splendid embankment ten feet wide at the top was thrown up on the lower side of the ditch behind the building. This was graded as a promenade and sown with white clover and a row of Carolina poplars planted along the ditch side. In time this will form a beautiful background, shutting out whatever is behind it It will also protect the grounds from floods and erosion."</p>
<p>The Student Rays was published as a "Commencement Number" in May 1909. Each faculty member received some attention. "Porter," the issue noted, "has charge of science and German. Quiet and unassuming, he is not one who wastes valuable energy in useless pursuits but wisely holds it in reserve until the opportune moment for expression arrives. His devotional talks are on current science or on foreign travel, dealing chiefly with Deutschland and Switzerland. It is reported that he is very considerate o^ students' feelings, taking revenge only during examination periods. He has been with us for seven years and will continue his work next year."</p>
<p>Although the academy catalog noted that Porter would be teaching science and German during the 1909-10 school year, he also taught Book of Mormon classes and a class entided "Deportment" - these in addition to his usual chemistry, German I and II, physiology, geology, and botany classes. Porter notes in the margin of his grade book ("The Teachers Improved Class Book") the names of the students who used profanity, broke the Word of Wisdom, went to the pool hall, and/or missed Sunday services. Either he was especially observant, or he had a good system of informants.</p>
<p>Porter had a new extracurricular assignment during the 1909-10 year. He was to aid in finding housing for students. He advertised in the Current- Journal for anyone with a room to rent to contact him. He</p>
<p>(Page 54 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>noted that some students, in addition to paying rent, would be willing to work for board.</p>
<p>The Friday theology hour was to follow a new format during the winter o( 1909-10. One Friday would be a devotional and testimony meeting; the next would be "group meetings." The two types of meetings would alternate through the winter, presumably to maintain an interest level in both. "The groups already arranged for were announced by Principal Dalby as follows: dramatics, consisting chiefly of a series o( readings from our best dramatists; a biography group under the direction of O. C. Dalby will devote their attention to the lives of famous men and women; Arthur Porter, Jr., will conduct a science group, the purpose of which is to investigate the newest achievements in the scientific world."</p>
<p>Porter spoke to students on November 9 about "common Indian corn or maize." He explained how the corn was used in the manufacture of several products, and he had several products with him for illustration purposes. That satisfied the scientific part of his assignment. For the religious part he spoke in devotional on Friday, December 3. "He read from Isaiah, 'How beautiful upon the mountain are the feet of him who bringeth good tidings, who publisheth peace, who bringeth tidings of good cheer.' The value of cheer and good will was emphasized and the students were enjoined to speak well of one another or not speak at all."</p>
<p>By April 1910, in time for the annual clean-up, Porter's noted ability to make grounds look nice was institutionalized with his appointment as chairman of the academy grounds committee. He directed the clean-up and the planting of 350 trees on the academy grounds for Arbor Day.</p>
<p>For the 1910-1 1 school year, Porter was assigned to teach geometry in addition to science and German. For the next three years, all he taught was German. The commencement issue of Student Rays in May 1912 noted that Porter was "one o{ Ricksie's oldest instructors, editor of the county's official newspaper, and superintendent of Sunday School. Previously, he gave most of his efforts to aiding us in the great cause of 'accumulating savvy,' but, during the last year, he has been able to spare us only enough of his time to instruct our classes in German." The February 1914 issue noted:</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 55)</p>
<p>Porter (in German class): Will you decline "ein glas bier"?</p>
<p>Student I never have yet.</p>
<p>The end of the 1913-14 school year marked a rather radical change in the faculty of Ricks Academy. For about two years, a sentiment had been developing that the faculty at the academy was becoming too liberal. That meant that they seemed to be accepting, if not teaching, "evolution" and "higher criticism." The board of education decided to replace Dalby and most of the faculty. Of fourteen teachers, only Porter, Howard M. Sundberg, and Ray L Ormsby were retained under the new principal A. B. Christenson. He hired another eleven teachers.</p>
<p>The 1914-15 school year got off to a good start as far as the faculty were concerned. A social was held so all new teachers could become acquainted with each other and the new principal. After visiting and eating, they were treated to the lovely singing of Nelle Porter.</p>
<p>Porter taught mathematics, German, and theology during the 1914- 15 year. He received the following note from one of his theology students dated October 29, 1914: "Dear Teacher, Please excuse me from theology yesterday because 1 had a misfortune with my glasses and was unable to study and had a headache. Your student, Stephen Meikle."</p>
<p>Porter taught only German again in 1915-16. He resigned at the end of the 1916 school year from teaching at the academy, but his involvement with the school would continue in many capacities, including printing many materials for the school such as Student Rays and later the Rixida. He also printed the Ricks College Catalogue for many years and was a part-time teacher on occasion.</p>
<p>As a member of the Rexburg City Council in 1916, Porter was involved in building College Avenue. Many anticipated that opening that street would facilitate and accelerate building of the newly autho- rized gymnasium building on campus. Porter encouraged the project in his newspaper and in casual and formal conversation with members of the local board of education. Early in 1918, the building was completed enough to use. It would not be dedicated until November 22, 1919, under the direction of Apostle George A. Smith. Prior to that date, however, the new principal, George S. Romnev, announced that</p>
<p>(Page 56 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>henceforth the school would be known as Ricks College rather than Ricks Academy.</p>
<p>On May 28, 1920, Ricks College alumni gathered in Rexburg for an annual reunion. "Members of former classes of the college gathered to participate in the annual banquet and ball and renew their fealty to their alma mater. Nearly two hundred were seated at the banquet tables and twice as many met at the dance. A special feature of this year's meeting was the reunion of the entire graduating class of 1910, this being just ten years since their graduation, and they were carrying out a plan agreed upon when they graduated. Every member was present." There were twelve members of the class, two boys and ten girls. Porter was on the program and told the story of the class of 1910 and his memories of the class.</p>
<p>Porter taught French in 1924 at the college. In 1925 he taught German. Both classes were taught on a part-time basis.</p>
<p>With Porter's calling to the Fremont Stake Presidency in 1925, his affiliation with Ricks College took on another dimension. Members of the stake presidency were called to serve on the local board of education of the college. His appointment came in 1926. One of his first assignments in the capacity of a member of the board was to travel, in company with Peter J. Ricks, to the small communities surrounding Rexburg to recruit for the college. Increasing the number of students at the college was important because the Church authorities had "under consideration plans for expanding the college provided there is sufficient support to justify this development. The present effort is to make a survey of the district and learn the number of students who would attend. The committee has found enthusiastic support of the institution in the sections visited. It stands in high favor and there is a general desire to see it grow. Many young people are planning to attend."</p>
<p>The October 29, 1926, board meeting was important for organiza- tional purposes. The Church Board of Education had decided that Ricks College would be the official Church school in Idaho and that each stake president would be called to serve on the local board. The response to that was favorable as it seemed to signal permanency for the college. An executive committee was appointed with John W. Hart, president; Albert Choules, vice-president; George H. Lowe and Porter.</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 57)</p>
<p>Porter would serve on the committee during its entire existence. President Romney would be an ex-officio member of the executive committee and all other sub-committees. Porter was also appointed to the finance standing committee.</p>
<p>At the November 5, 1926, board of education meeting, some changes were authorized in the college auditorium located in the gymnasium building. It had been poorly designed with a small stage, a flat floor so those seated toward the back could not see a performance very well, and had several wooden pillars which supported the gym floor above but cut off the view of the stage. Porter wrote about the remodeling and the result- President Romney was very anxious to have this auditorium improved but the Church indicated they would not participate in the expense. The matter was considered by the board but the cost seemed prohibitive. Oswald Christensen outlined a cheap plan that would have two posts. I went to Idaho Falls to see my friend Howard Sundberg the architect. He was a former teacher at Ricks and was interested and proposed replacing the posts with great steel I-beams. He drew a plan and estimated the job to cost $6,000. He offered to supervise the installation and join us in a donation of his services.</p>
<p>The executive board discussed the matter at a special session. The president thought $1,000 could be spared out of the year's budget. [IJ proposed raising $500 or more by installing an advertising curtain across the front of the stage. It was estimated we could raise $1,500 or more in labor contributed. Also, some money could be raised by entertainment. So the board decided to go ahead.</p>
<p>In due course, the job was completed and the auditorium was more enjoyable; the stage was enlarged; the advertising netted approximately $700. It Ithe advertising curtain] remained a year or more before it was removed and was replaced by a decorative curtain.</p>
<p>The architect assured us the I-beams were strong enough to carry a freight train, but, when I saw the great crowds that danced up there, I wondered how the walls would be affected by the vibration caused by some of the dances such as the Berlin Polka. I realized how unwise it was to build a large and popular dance hall in the top of the building. Also, the exit down the stairway from this was a firerrap. Most of the young people, especially teenagers from the surrounding area, danced there. Also, one evening when I went up to the building the hall was filled to overflowing with scouts and scourers. When seated, not only were all the tiers of benches around the hall occupied, bill hundreds were lifting on the fiooi In fact, most of the hall was thus occupied. It was a sight CO tee. But I could</p>
<p>(Page 58 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>not enjoy it and regretted that I had been so active in promoting this improvement in such a badly constructed building.</p>
<p>My sons were in that overcrowded scout meeting. My sons and daughters danced there. I worried a lot but did not feel justified in making public my concern and thereby putting a "wet blanket" on this public enterprise. It was a genuine relief to me when I heard that the city fire department had declared the dance hall and exit as a fire hazard and limited its use for large crowds.</p>
<p>After the November 5 meeting of the board of education, Porter participated in the festivities o{ the annual Founder's Day program. Sporting activities, a parade, and a commemoration at the tabernacle recalled the history of the college. A " grand ball" climaxed the program.</p>
<p>On Monday night, February 7, 1927, a special ceremony took place on campus. A big bonfire rally was held to celebrate completion o{ the remodeling project in the gymnasium building. Many speeches were made intended to arouse increased loyalty to the school. At least one of the wooden pillars was burned on the fire. Members of the executive board were very much evident with gratitude shown for their leadership in providing for the remodeling.</p>
<p>The executive committee's next major project was to arrange for the installation of a gas heating plant to heat the laboratories. Porter was especially pleased with the development as he had spent several years in the laboratories and knew how uncomfortable they were, especially in winter.</p>
<p>Late in 1927 the executive committee approved plans for the college to purchase adjoining land for an athletic field. The Chamber of Commerce pledged its members to raise $8,000 for the undertaking. However, there was some strong opposition from those who felt the city park, where the college had held sporting events for some time, was adequate. They argued that the city was not large enough to support two sporting fields. Regardless of arguments to the contrary, plans were pushed along to establish a building fund for a college field. It would be some time before the plans were fulfilled.</p>
<p>The Ricks College Board of Education approved the following resolution at its March 14, 1928, meeting:</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 59)</p>
<p>Whereas, the board of education of the Ricks College has received official information that the Madison High School is prepared to establish third-year high school work and desires to do so the coming year.</p>
<p>Therefore, in view of these facts, the Ricks College will readjust its curriculum featuring hereafter college courses and fourth-year high school course. Courses will still be offered for students lacking three years of high school work</p>
<p>In 1928, Porter had become affiliated again with Ricks College in a teaching capacity. "In the morning I teach two classes in French at the college," Porter noted. "The second year class meets at 7:30 a.m. and the first year at 8:20 to 9:05. I have twelve to fifteen in each class and am giving heavy courses. I have all written work read by Stanford Blaylock, a student."</p>
<p>During the latter months of 1929 and into early 1930, as the national and state financial picture became more and more gloomy, rumors were passed along that the Church Board of Education was going to close Ricks College. Despite the rumors, the local board decided at their March 18, 1930, meeting to allow a summer school to operate in June and July.</p>
<p>The rumors of closing persisted. To get direct information, about twenty men from the community representing the board of education, Chamber of Commerce, and other organizations traveled to Salt Lake City for an arranged meeting with President Heber J. Grant and his counselors along with Joseph F. Merrill, commissioner of Church education. The meeting was held in President Grant's office on April 8.</p>
<p>President John W. Hart explained how the rumors that the college was to be closed had circulated through the Upper Snake River Valley and had a "detrimental effect on attendance at the college." The Rexburg representatives, as reported in the Rexburg Journal, were assured "that at no time had any date been considered by the Church Board of Education for closing Ricks College. On the contrary, they said, there were four Church schools in Utah and only one in Idaho. and we could be assured that, if any more Church schools were closed,</p>
<p>Ricks College would be among the last. They had felt personally that there should be a Church school in Idaho it the funds of the Church were sufficient to continue these schools. They also assured the</p>
<p>(Page 60 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>committee that any other action with reference to the continuance of Ricks College would be communicated direct[ly] to the board and that no attention should be given to any other reports and rumors."</p>
<p>To further appease those in the Upper Snake River Valley, President Hart announced that the appropriation for another school year had been made. President Romney was authorized to hire teachers, including a football coach, and a recruiting campaign to increase student numbers got underway. Everyone was optimistic about the future of the college. A newspaper reported that "it is indeed gratifying to hear the rejoicing on all sides from all quarters at the glad word that the dear old Ricks is to remain. From every part of the Upper Snake River Valley the sounds of joy are heard."</p>
<p>The Ricks College Board of Education called a special meeting on Monday, July 21, to appoint an acting president for the college. President Romney had been granted a leave of absence to commence September 1. The board appointed Hyrum Manwaring as acting president. At the meeting, President Romney gave an optimistic report on the condition of the college.</p>
<p>On August 15, the Porters had a dinner party in their home to honor President Romney and his wife. The affair was well attended and the Romney' s were pleased with the consideration shown.</p>
<p>On September 1, 1930, the executive committee met pursuant to a call of President Hart. President Manwaring met with the board for the first time as an ex-officio member. A decision was finalized to proceed with the purchase of "a plot of ground west of the college for an athletic field and a committee was appointed to make negotiations immediately with a view of acquiring this property."</p>
<p>The college opened for its forty-third year on September 22. Faculty and students gathered at the opening assembly to hear Porter, on behalf of the board of education, give "an enthusiastic address. He complimented the students present on their attendance at this fine Idaho institution. He spoke in very complimentary terms of President Hyrum Manwaring and his corps of able teachers. He was very optimistic in his assurance to the students that Ricks College would be permanently maintained and continue to wield a mighty influence for good among the people of the great Snake River Valley." It was a</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 61)</p>
<p>prophetic message that would be sorely tried several times in ensuing years.</p>
<p>The board of education further implemented a program of improvements to the physical plant of the college by completing the purchase of a new heating system in November 1930. Installation began immediately.</p>
<p>By November 1930, there was not much doubt that the continuance of the college was tenuous indeed. The Church Board of Education had recommended that the college be presented to the state of Idaho for inclusion in the state education system. President Hart agreed that that was a viable solution rather than simply closing the school. Hart, well known in state Republican political circles, and</p>
<p>Porter (now mayor of Rexburg), well known in state Democratic</p>
<p>political circles, spent much time in Boise lobbying for the state to assume control of the school. On January 16, 1931, the Idaho Senate began debate on the bill transferring Ricks College to the state. The House passed the bill; the Senate defeated it. Hart made a quick trip to Salt Lake City and received assurance that the school would be funded to operate until the state legislature met in 1933 when another attempt would be made to give it to the state.</p>
<p>Hyrum Manwaring was confirmed by the Church Board of Education as president of Ricks College on May 6, 1931. Romney would not be returning to the school; he was called to preside over the Northern States Mission in Chicago. President Manwaring had one overriding goal - save Ricks College.</p>
<p>On September 9, 1931 , a large group met at the Idamont Hotel to discuss again the merits of buying land for a college athletic field, especially if it was just to be given to the state. Porter gave a "spirited talk" in favor of the acquisition as did others. Agreement was reached and donations in the amount of $565 were made at the end of the meeting with Porter setting the example. A committee had been appointed to raise additional funds. The field was finally purchased and an athletic field was soon available and used during the school year.</p>
<p>On September 16, 1932, at nine o'clock in the morning, the Ricks College faculty met in the opening session of a three day institute to prepare for the opening of school. They discussed the problems facing</p>
<p>(Page 62 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>the school and possible solutions. Porter attended the opening meeting and "gave them the greetings and advice of the board of education."</p>
<p>Hart and Porter attended the opening of the legislative session in January 1933, again to lobby legislators to take Ricks College into the state education system. A ringing declaration had been issued by the Rexburg Journal: "It may be problematic whether Ricks College should be continued under church or state auspices, but it is not a question whether it should be maintained. The school must go on, and it is our job to find the plan and put it through. This is not a one-man job either. Every citizen of the upper valley and all of southeastern Idaho should be enthusiastic to preserve this educational asset and lend every influence to promote its further growth and usefulness. Every man, woman, and child should be ready to bear the Ricks College banner, shout her slogan, and vigorously fight for a definite plan that will ensure its perpetuity and future usefulness. Let us unfurl and fling this slogan to the Idaho breeze: 'Ricks College - Ours - Now and Forever!'" Despite the declaration and the personal lobbying effort, the state again refused the gift of Ricks College.</p>
<p>The board of education issued a call for a mass meeting at the tabernacle on Sunday afternoon, March 19, at four o'clock. A large number attended to discuss a central issue: What should be done about Ricks College? The Church had determined to discontinue its junior colleges. The state did not want the school. The only thing to do was operate with local financial support if it was to be operated at all. The sentiment was overwhelming in favor of continued operation. Committees were established to aid the board of education which effectively assumed control and administration of the school. Porter agreed to serve on the finance committee along with J. E. Graham, chairman; Deibert G. Taylor, P. C. Craven, and J. E. Jensen. Other committees were enrollment and publicity. A central committee with Peter J. Ricks, chairman, had overall jurisdiction.</p>
<p>The board of education journeyed again to Salt Lake City and met with the First Presidency and Commissioner Merrill to see if the Church could possibly aid the school again. The board explained their plans to see to the continued operation of the college and the extent of local support. The Church leaders were impressed with the</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 63)</p>
<p>determination shown and agreed to allow the college to operate under the local board with some Church financial support.</p>
<p>Several important decisions were made at the May 1 5 meeting of the board. The faculty were to be hired and the budget for the year was approved. They decided to increase the number of board members by appointing two local men. The central committee was to make recommendations and the president of the board would make the appointment.</p>
<p>On August 23, 1933, the board met to go over plans with President Manwaring for the ensuing school year. Everything seemed to be ready, and the board was confident that Ricks would have a great year. Community support, in the face of a deepening financial depression, was gratifying.</p>
<p>The board met on March 15, 1934, to assess the past year when the college had been under their direct control. They were pleased with the way the college had been administered by President Manwaring but concerned about the next term. They decided they had no recourse but to proceed as if everything would work out They made plans for improving the physical facilities as well as maintaining the financial integrity o{ the institution. When school started in the fall, enrollment had dramatically increased, much to everyone's delight.</p>
<p>In January 1935, Porter again went to Boise, lobbied legislators to accept Ricks, but again was disappointed. However, he and other members of the board followed the established pattern of seeking, successfully, for Church and community financial support. The college "got by" another year. In March 1936, the executive board met with President Manwaring and heard his report on the school. They agreed "that the outlook for Ricks College is brighter than for a number of years past."</p>
<p>A change in the executive committee of the board of education took place in April 1936. President Hart died, and Peter J. Ricks became president of the committee.</p>
<p>In April 1936, the board was pleased with the announcement that the North Western Association of Secondary and Higher Schools had granted full accreditation to Ricks College. They seemed to vindicate all the sacrifices made to maintain a quality program.</p>
<p>(Page 64 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>In January 1937, Porter returned to Boise. By this time he must have felt like a veteran lobbyist The state turned down the offer to take Ricks College again. The Church and community again helped and the executive committee of the board had direct control of the college for another year.</p>
<p>The Church assumed control of the college again in 1938. The executive committee was discontinued before the 1 938-39 school year, but the local board was retained with Porter still a member. He recognized that the local board was just a figurehead board during the school year, but neither he nor the others minded a bit. President Hyrum Manwaring had written a letter to each board member on November 17, 1938, thanking them for their service, expressing confidence in the reorganized Church educational structure, and asking for "future loyalty even though you may no longer be an administrative officer." The local board was disbanded before the beginning of the 193940 school year. The crisis, apparently, had passed.</p>
<p>The Ricks College seventeenth annual "Leadership Week" was held February 14, 15, and 16, 1939. The last several had been held under circumstances leaving people wondering if each one would be the last By 1939, the future of the college and "Leadership Week" seemed assured. The theme illustrated the optimistic attitude - "Self reliant and charged with new ideas, strong, ambitious, and fervent faith, we press forward, asking no favors, but opportunity to work." Porter was in charge of the Church welfare department which met each day from 10:00 to 10:50 a.m. Speakers included David A. Smith, president of the Idaho Falls Stake, and Presiding Bishop LeGrand Richards. Porter made introductions and conducted the sessions.</p>
<p>Not only had Porter been involved with the seventeenth "Leadership Week," but he had undoubtedly attended the previous sixteen. He would continue to support that kind of educational activity until near the end of his life.</p>
<p>Ricks College would have some stability during the 1 940s although the world war would disrupt the male-female ratio. A four-year curriculum was commenced with the third year added for the 1948-49 school year and the fourth the following year. In 1954, school administrators were notified that the school would revert to a junior college again. The last baccalaureate degrees were awarded in August</p>
<p>(Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College Page 65)</p>
<p>1956. Then rumors started that the school was to be closed altogether or moved to Idaho Falls. The move to Idaho Falls rumor proved to be true. Porter was very much involved emotionally and intellectually with the controversy created by the announced move to Idaho Falls. But he was satisfied to encourage his sons to leadership in the anti-move crusade, a crusade that spanned a few years chronologically, but a millennia emotionally. Success attended the efforts of those who argued so well for retention of the college in Rexburg and, to the date of this publication, there has been no further discussion of removal of the college.</p>
<p>Porter, writing in 1957, summarized his relationship to Ricks College: "I have participated in every crisis that the school has passed through in the past fifty-five years." Indeed he had, and by his participation had helped ameliorate each crisis.</p>
<p>Porter was a special guest of honor at the Ricks College com- mencement ceremony on Thursday, May 24, 1962. He was presented a Distinguished Service Award by President John L Clarke. He was only the fourth in the seventy-four year history of the college to be so honored. His commendation noted his extensive service to the college, the city, county, and state. Earlier in the day Porter had joined the Class of 1912 in their fifty-year reunion. He was honored by the six members of the class and enjoyed participating in discussing experiences of fifty years before. The six present were: Lorenzo Parker, Cleone E. Dalby, J. Orval Ellsworth, Cyral A. Watson, J. Henry Hansen, and Edward C. Phillips.</p>
<p>Ground was broken in June 1962 with appropriate ceremony for a new library on the college campus. On December 11, 1963, the library was dedicated by Elder Marion G. Romney and named the David O. McKay Library. Porter was again honored by the college by having the beautiful 1 92-seat lecture room on the second floor named the Arthur Porter Lecture Room. The citation sent to the Church Board of Education noted that Porter "has always been an ardent supporter of Ricks College and of numerous good causes. Now in his eighty-sixth year, he is widely and rightly considered one of the great characters of the Upper Snake River Valley." The Porter Room was the setting for a reception after the dedicatory program was completed. Several members of Porter's family were present to add their</p>
<p>(Page 66 Ricks Academy &amp; Ricks College)</p>
<p>congratulations. The tribute that the lecture room in the library be associated with Porter was especially fitting. He had, for a good many years, approached the problems associated with public service as an academic.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x47636" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
