<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_FullWidth ID="x66572" Name="Surplus FAQ" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">FAQ</Abstract><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<dl style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"> <dt><strong>Who is responsible for determining the value of an item?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">The budget steward has ultimate responsibility.  Sometimes the person who knows the value of the item is the person who uses it or is responsible for it.</dd> <dt><strong>How do I know if the item has a value of less than $25?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">Common sense for most items will tell you, especially if you paid less than $25 for it originally.  Doing a quick search online may let you see how much an item sells for new and used.  Electronics will usually draw a higher value than other items.  You can also ask others their opinion.  If you still can't decide, contact the Surplus Specialist.</dd> <dt><strong>Who do I tell we have low value surplus items?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">Enter a Relief of Accountability (ROA), but only input one line item with the description of "Low Value Surplus Item" and input the quantity.  Your account number will only be used to help us with reporting and training.</dd> <dt><strong>Why do I need to enter a Relief of Accountability?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">Entering an ROA notifies someone to provide tags for marking and arrangements for pickup and proper removal.</dd> <dt><strong>Why are tags needed for these items?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">This allows us to pick them up and track them so there is appropriate accountability.</dd> <dt><strong>What if I know the item has a value more than $25 but I don't know how much it's worth?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">Just enter your best estimate and feel free to add a comment in the ROA providing instructions to help us sell the item.</dd> <dt><strong>Will I still be able to purchase items at the bi-monthly Surplus Sale?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">Yes, although the process will be changing in the near future.  Notification of these changes will be sent out and posted to the website.</dd> <dt><strong>Why was this change made, don't these items still bring value back to the University by selling them?</strong></dt> <dd style="padding-left: 10px;">Yes, and we are confident by spending our time and resources on items valued at more than $25 we can bring additional value back to the University as a whole.</dd> </dl> <br /> <br />
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><em>If you have further questions, please call 496-2312.</em></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_FullWidth>
