<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.82 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<PolicyPage ID="x66571" Name="Surplus Policies and Procedures" Layout="general_Policy.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Policy Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Surplus Policies and Procedures</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Policy Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Surplus Policies and Procedures</Abstract><Date type="date" label="Revision Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20111219T19:00:00</Date><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Policy</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">All items which are no longer of use to the University are to be disposed of according to this policy. Items with asset tags or items valued at more than $25 require a "Relief of Accountability" to account for sale, disposal or donation. When an item is sold, the net proceeds will be returned to an authorized fund of the department submitting the item. Items valued over $25 which are not sold after two (2) surplus sales may be reduced in price, donated or discarded at the discretion of Surplus Operations personnel. <strong style="display: inline;">Improper disposal of BYU-Idaho items may result in disciplinary action.</strong></p>
<p></p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Definitions</h4>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong style="display: inline;">Surplus Items</strong> - Items that no longer have value to BYU-Idaho but have a BYU-Idaho asset tag and/or over $25 value to other entities or individuals. This category may also include large quantities of a low value item that may be sold together.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong style="display: inline;">Low Value Surplus Items</strong> - Items determined under the direction of the budget account steward to have value of less than $25.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;"><strong style="display: inline;">Disposal Surplus</strong> - These are non-capital asset items which are broken or have completed their useful life and do not have value to other entities or persons.</p>
<p></p>
<h4 style="font-weight: bold;">Procedures</h4>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 15px;">
<li><strong style="display: inline;">Surplus Items</strong>
<ul style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; list-style-type: circle; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>These items require a "Relief of Accountability" (ROA) form, found at <a href="https://web.byui.edu/Surplus/">https://web.byui.edu/Surplus/</a></li>
<li>After completion, the ROA will be sent to the budget steward for approval. If approved, the ROA is sent to the Surplus Office.</li>
<li>A sticker will be sent to the steward to tag the item for easy identification.</li>
<li>Once tagged, call the Surplus Sales Office (extension 2615). They will notify the moving crew to pick up the items.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">Low-Value Surplus</strong>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Rather than devote resources to the sale of these low-value items where proceeds might do little more than offset expenses, BYU-Idaho will donate them to Deseret Industries for sale or for distribution to other Church entities. All furnishings will be considered for possible reissue. Exception requests for Surplus Operations to sell low value items should be sent to the Surplus Operations Specialist.</p>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">For Low-Value Surplus items, follow the same procedure as outlined for 1 above. In the description field record "low value surplus items" (input furniture, if applicable) and list the total quantity of items. No other information is needed. The stickers will be different than those used to surplus items. These items will be picked up weekly. These items are still considered to have value and may not be taken by employees, students or others for their own use.</p>
</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">Disposable Surplus</strong>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Disposable surplus must be discarded and may not be given to employees or others.</p>
</li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">Donations</strong>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Requests may come from various entities for donations of surplus items. The following guidelines address these requests:</p>
<ol style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif; padding-left: 30px;">
<li>The first option for surplus items is to provide value for the University or other Church entities. Items can be donated to other entities if they are not sold after two (2) surplus sales.</li>
<li>The University does not make donations to For-Profit entities.</li>
<li>Donation requests from Public Schools or Government entities takes precedence over requests from non-profit entities.</li>
<li>Donation approval will be provided through the Donation Advisory Committee comprised of representatives from Financial Services, Internal Audit, Public Relations, Information Technology and Purchasing.</li>
</ol></li>
<li><strong style="display: inline;">Retiring Employees</strong>
<p style="font-family: Verdana, Arial, sans-serif;">Only items that are scheduled for surplus can be sold to retirees without going through the normal surplus procedures. For these items, the valuation of the product will go through the same process as all surplus items. Computers will be re-imaged according to University guidelines. Vice President's approval is required for items being sold to retiring employees if exception to this policy and procedure is required.</p>
</li>
</ol>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Policy" label="Policy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="PolicyNavigationComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></PolicyPage>
