<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsDetail ID="x66519" Name="New Student Body Vice President" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Article Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">New Student Body Vice President</Title><subTitle type="string" label="Sub-Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">BYU-Idaho has a new Student Body Vice President, Niccol Hahn. The SRC also introduced new coordinators, and and a new elections team for the Spring 2012 Semester.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" GroupStart=""><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"/><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0">0.5</Priority></xPower><ThumbnailImage type="imagefile" label="Thumbnail Image" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Width="150" Height="150" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">student-support/SRC/Student-Body-Officers.jpg</ThumbnailImage><xPower Type="List" Name="ArticleImages" label="Article Images" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="" List=""><Image type="imagefile" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Width="230" Border="" Alignment="" Expanded="true" Height="144" AlternateText="" HSpace="" VSpace="">student-support/SRC/SRC-Coordinators(0).jpg</Image></xPower><Date type="date" label="Date" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" display="localdateshort" UTC="true">20120514T18:00:00</Date><Author type="string" label="Author's Name" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Kevin Orton, SRC Program Assistant</Author><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>The Student Representative Council (SRC) announced a new Student Body Vice President, Coordinators, and the brand new Elections team. SRC is the only student organization at Brigham Young University-Idaho (BYU-Idaho) led by a Student Body President and Vice President elected at-large by students for 2 semesters, and is under the stewardship of Student Support Director Allen Jones and Student Support Coordinator Joanna Relken. "I am extremely pumped for this semester! Our team is solid and we will accomplish great things! We are thrilled for the new people that have joined our SRC team, especially Niccol and our amazing coordinators. We have a team full of skills, dedication, and heart!" said current Student Body President Rodrigo Stabio a Junior from Eden, Utah studying Business Management.</p>
<p>The SRC takes a different approach to Student Government with a focus on addressing student concerns. It is organized into four areas with two Coordinators leading each area and overseen by the Student Body President and Student Body Vice President. "This semester a new area was created to assist with Elections. Having an elections team in SRC will make it possible for us to not slow down and keep a steady momentum on our current projects, "says Stabio</p>
<p>Last semester with the graduation of former Vice President Justin Aquino, the Elections Council selected Niccol Hahn, a Senior from Centerville, Utah studying Sociology, who ran against Stabio to fill the Vice President position for the remainder of the Spring semester. "I am grateful I have been given a chance to serve in this position for the semester. It is a great opportunity to serve the school and the students that attend here. I am also grateful for the opportunity I have to learn from the council members we have chosen as well as from Rodrigo. It is going to be a wonderful semester" said Hahn.</p>
<p>Additionally, seven new coordinators have been selected to lead the different areas. Wendy Smith, a Senior studying Elementary Education from Roswell, New Mexico and Landon Welch, a Junior studying Business Management from Kent, Washington as Council Coordinators; Kristen Cagle a Sophomore studying Communications from San Diego, California and Kenny Stanfield, a Sophomore studying Social Work from Idaho Falls, Idaho as Research Coordinators; and Cassidy Oldham, a Junior studying Communications from Orem, Utah and Shaun Belliston a Junior studying Humanities &amp; Philosophy from West Richland, Washington as Student Voice Coordinators.  Also Rebecca Thompson, a Senior studying Communications from Kennewick, Washington has been selected to lead the new Elections area this semester.</p>
<p>Student Body Officers are elected for two semester terms and the next election will be held this semester at the end of June. Students interested on running can find requirements on the official SRC website (www.byui.edu/student-representative-council), also if any student is interested in participating in the SRC there are still opportunities available.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x36320" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Name="News" label="News" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="x36269" CompTypes="NewsNavigationComponent"/><xPower Type="List" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="Component" Name="xPower" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes=""/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" Navigation="Ancestors" GenerationOrder="down" StartPage="x5" MaxNodes="" MaxDepth="" Query=""/><xPower Type="Component" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Component="x36315" CompTypes="SiteControl"/></NewsDetail>
