<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x66914" Name="Produce Materials" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">How Do I Produce Communication Materials?</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">How Do I Produce Communication Materials?</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x15474" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/><fbookTop type="boolean" label="Put facebook at top of page" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</fbookTop><fbookStatus type="string" label="Facebook ID#" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></fbookStatus><fbookDisplayed type="string" label="Number of facebook messages to display" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">1</fbookDisplayed></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style><!--
.article-bookmarks { border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: .5em; padding-top: 1.2em; padding-bottom: 0;  width: 180px; float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em; font-size: .8em;}
.article-bookmarks h3 { text-align: center; font-size: 1.6em;}
.article-bookmarks li { margin-left: 1em; font-family: "Helvetica", arial, sans-serif; }
.blue {color: #056CB6;}
a h2 {text-decoration: none !important;}
--></style>
<div class="article-bookmarks">
<h3>Marketing Options</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#bk-posters">Posters and Table Tents</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-overposters">Oversized Posters</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-kiosks">Kiosks</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-banners">Olympic Banners</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-fliers">Fliers and Brochures</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-mywebbanner">My.Byui Banners</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-email">Emails</a></li>
<li><a href="#bk-other">Other Marketing Options</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><em>All</em> marketing materials on campus need to be approved by the University Communications Marketing Managers before they are put up. You can email them your designs at ucidentity@byui.edu for approval before anything is printed.</p>
<p>Below is a list of all the pre-approved marketing materials that you can use on the BYU-Idaho campus. Each one includes a step-by-step guide to producing and then getting approved the respective option. Simply refer to whichever option you are using and follow the instructions.</p>
<p>If you have questions, you can always contact the Marketing Managers at 208-496-2028 or ucidentity@byui.edu.</p>
<p><em>Note:</em> If you are an IBC company, these instructions will be slightly different. Please contact a Marketing Manager for specific directions.</p>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-posters"></a>Posters and Table Tents</h2>
<p>Posters are 11x17 or 13x20 and are hung on the walls in buildings across campus in pre-approved locations. Table tents may be put on any flat table or counter on campus.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the <a href="x10775.xml">poster template</a> or the <a href="x10516.xml">table tent template</a>.</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Finish the rest of the designing.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to ucidentity@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Managers will email you back within 2 business hours.</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters or table tents. You will then bring them to Kimball 215, where the Marketing Managers will stamp them.</li>
<li>Put them up in the designated places. If you'd like to put table tents in the Crossroads, you'll need to first bring them to the MC Info Desk.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-overposters"></a>Oversized Posters</h2>
<p>Oversized posters are the 22x28 posters in the MC in the frames with rounded fronts.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the <a href="x10520.xml">oversized poster template</a>.</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Finish the rest of the designing.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to ucidentity@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Managers will email you back within 2 business hours. Oversized posters also need to be scheduled for specific spots in the MC, so be sure to speak with a Marketing Manager so they can get you a spot.</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters. You will then take them directly to the MC Info Desk&mdash;they will put them up for you. Be sure to take with you the email from a Marketing Manager that says which spots they are scheduled for.</li>
<li>Oversized posters can be up for a maximum of two weeks. If you would like to keep the poster after it has been up, be sure to go back to the Info Desk to retrieve it.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-kiosks"></a>Kiosks</h2>
<p>Kiosks are the 43.75x45 posters in the three-sided covered stands in several different outdoor locations.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the <a href="x10518.xml">kiosk template</a>.</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Finish the rest of the designing.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to ucidentity@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Managers will email you back within 2 business hours. Kiosks also need to be scheduled for specific spots in the MC, so be sure to speak with a Marketing Manager so they can get you a spot.</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print out the posters. You will then take them to the Marketing Managers at Kimball 215&mdash;they will put them up for you.</li>
<li>Kiosks can be up for a maximum of three weeks. If you would like to keep the poster after it has been up, be sure to tell that to the Marketing Managers and go back to Kimball 215 to retrieve it when the time is up.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-banners"></a>Olympic Banners</h2>
<p>Olympic banners are the 30x60 or 30x72 banners that hang on the white frame in outdoor locations.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the <a href="x10517.xml">olympic banner template</a>.</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Finish the rest of the designing.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to ucidentity@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Managers will email you back within 2 business hours.</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print the posters. You will then take them to the Marketing Managers at Kimball 215, where you will get the frame and zip ties so that you can put them up. You will also be in charge of bringing back the frames when the time is up.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-fliers"></a>Fliers and Brochures</h2>
<p>Fliers and brochures come in several different sizes and can be handed out at booths in the MC, distributed via mail, or placed on a department countertop for people to take.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the <a href="x10519.xml">flyer template</a> or <a href="x10513.xml">brochure template</a>.</li>
<li>Download <a href="x16259.xml">your organization's logo</a> and place it in the respective spot on the template.</li>
<li>Finish the rest of the designing.</li>
<li>Once the design is finished, send a PDF copy to ucidentity@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Managers will email you back within 2 business hours.</li>
<li>Once you have your approval, you can print the materials out. These two particular types of marketing material do not need to be stamped. Distribute them in one of the above ways.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-mywebbanner"></a>My.byui Banners</h2>
<p>Campus message banners are the digitals ads that employees and students see on my.byui.edu.</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the <a href="x16330.xml">my.byui banner template</a> and pay attention to the details outlined on that page about how to design a my.byui ad.</li>
<li>Finish the designing.</li>
<li>Send a .jpg copy to ucidentity@byui.edu for approval. One of the Marketing Managers will email you back within 2 business hours.</li>
<li>Once the design is approved, send a Photoshop (.psd) file to newsdesk@byui.edu. Be sure to include how long you'd like the ad to be up (maximum of two weeks&mdash;two days per week), and what URL you'd like the banner to link to (required). Also specify which audience you're targeting with the ad (refer to the template page for more information on that).</li>
<li>News Desk will put it up for you. It may take 24 hours to appear and are given priority on the first-come, first-serve basis.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-email"></a>Emails</h2>
<p>University Communications sends an email to students and another to faculty on Tuesday and Thursday every week. The purpose of this email is to give organizations on campus the opportunity to send a message out via email (there is no other way for organizations to send an email out to everyone on campus besides this). Each office an send out one message per week (on either the Tuesday or the Thursday email).</p>
<ol>
<li>Write a headline that is up to 60 characters (including spaces) and two lines of text (up to 200 characters, including spaces). You may also include a URL that the message will link to from the email. This URL must be to a webpage on the BYU-Idaho website.</li>
<li>Send all of this information to newsdesk@byui.edu. All requests must be submitted to this email before 4:45pm on the day prior to being included in an email. Please visit <a href="x10748.xml">this page</a> for detailed information.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="blue"><a name="bk-other"></a>Other Marketing Options</h2>
<ul>
<li>The school newspaper, the <em>Scroll</em>, sells advertising space in the paper. You can call 208-496-3730 or email scrollads@byui.edu for more information.</li>
<li>If you have an idea that is different from the above options, contact a Marketing Manager to propose it. If it is significantly different it may need to be approved by Communication Council, which could take several weeks.</li>
<li>Posters on easels can only be used at events to specify the location of the event (for example, right at the entrance to the room where the event is going on). They <em>cannot</em> be used for any other marketing across campus.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any questions about the above marketing options, please feel free to contact a Marketing Manager at 208-496-2028 or ucidentity@byui.edu.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x10072" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
