<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67597" Name="Chemical Appendix 3" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Chemical Appendix 3</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Chemical Appendix 3</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Appendix 3 - Chemical Specific Hazards That May       Lead to Fires or Explosions </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The combination of certain compounds or classes of       compounds can result in a violent chemical reaction leading to an explosion or fire. Other       compounds pose explosion or fire hazards when exposed to heat, shock, or other conditions.       Listed below are some of the specific compounds and combinations of compounds that may       pose explosion or fire hazards and may be encountered in laboratories. This list is not       intended to be complete, and researchers should always be familiar with the flammability       and other properties of the chemicals involved in their research.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1. Acetylenic compounds </strong>are explosive in mixtures of 2.5-8.0% with air. At pressures of 2 or more atmospheres,       acetylene subjected to an electrical discharge or high temperature can decompose       explosively. Dry acetylides can detonate on receiving a slight shock. Many heavy metal       acetylides are sensitive explosives.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2. <strong>Aluminum chloride</strong> should be       considered a potentially dangerous material. If moisture is present, there may be       sufficient decomposition (generating HCL) to build up considerable pressure. If a bottle       is to be opened after long standing, it should be completely enclosed in a heavy towel.</p>
<p>3. <strong>Ammonia</strong> reacts with iodine       forming nitrogen triiodide, which is explosive, and with hypochlorites to give chlorine.       Mixtures of ammonia and organic halides sometimes react violently when heated under       pressure.</p>
<p>4. <strong>Dry benzoyl peroxide</strong> is easily       ignited and sensitive to shock and may decompose spontaneously at temperatures above 50o       C. It is reported to be desensitized by addition of 20 % water.</p>
<p>5. <strong>Carbon disulfide</strong> is both very       toxic and very flammable; mixed with air, its vapors can be ignited by a steam bath or       pipe, a hot plate, or a glowing light bulb.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Chlorine</strong> may react violently       with hydrogen or with hydrocarbons when exposed to sunlight.</p>
<p>7. <strong>Diazomethane</strong> and related       compounds should be treated with extreme caution. They are very toxic (potent       carcinogens), and the pure gases and liquids explode readily. Solutions in ether are safer       from this standpoint.</p>
<p>8. <strong>Dimethyl sulfoxide</strong> decomposes       violently on contact with a wide variety of active halogen compounds. Explosions from       contact with active metal hydrides have been reported.</p>
<p>9. <strong>Diethyl, diisopropyl, and other ethers </strong>(       particularly the branched-chain type) sometimes explode during heating or refluxing       because of the presence of peroxides. Ferrous salts or sodium bisulfite can by used to       decompose these peroxides, and passage over basic active alumina will remove most of the       peroxidic material. In general, however, old samples of ethers should be carefully and       properly disposed of.</p>
<p>10. <strong>Ethylene oxide</strong> has been known       to explode when heated in a closed vessel. Experiments using ethylene oxide under pressure       should be carried out behind suitable barricades.</p>
<p>11. <strong>Halogenated compounds</strong> such as       chloroform, carbon tetrachloride, and other halogenated solvents should not be dried with       sodium, potassium, or other active metals; violent explosions are usually the result of       such attempts.</p>
<p>12. <strong>Hydrogen peroxide</strong> stronger than       3% can be dangerous; in contact with the skin, it may cause severe burns. Thirty percent       hydrogen peroxide may decompose violently if contaminated with iron, copper, chromium, or       other metals or their salts.</p>
<p>13. <strong>Liquid-nitrogen</strong> cooled traps       open to the atmosphere rapidly condense liquid air. Then, when the coolant is removed, an       explosive pressure buildup occurs, usually with enough force to shatter glass equipment.       Hence, only sealed or evacuated equipment should be used.</p>
<p>14. <strong>Lithium aluminum hydride</strong> should       not be used to dry methyl ethers of tetrahydrofuran; fires from this are very common. The       products of its reaction with carbon dioxide have been reported to be explosive. Carbon       dioxide or bicarbonate extinguishers should not be used against lithium aluminum hydride       fires, which should be smothered with sand or some other inert substance.</p>
<p>15. <strong>Oxygen tanks</strong>: Serious       explosions have resulted from contact between oil and high-pressure oxygen. Oil should not       be used on connections to an oxygen cylinder.</p>
<p>16. <strong>Ozone</strong> is a highly reactive and       toxic gas. It is formed by the action of ultraviolet light on oxygen (air) and, therefore,       certain ultraviolet source may require venting to the exhaust hood. Liquid and solid ozone       are explosive substances.</p>
<p>17. <strong>Palladium or platinum on carbon,       platinum oxide</strong>, <strong>Raney nickel, and other catalysts </strong>should be       filtered from catalytic hydrogenation reaction mixtures carefully. The recovered catalyst       is usually saturated with hydrogen and highly reactive and, thus, will inflame       spontaneously on exposure to air. Particularly in large-scale reactions, the filter cake       should not be allowed to become dry. The funnel containing the still-moist catalyst filter       cake should be put into a water bath immediately after completion of the filtration.       Another hazard in working with such catalysts is the danger of explosion if additional       catalyst is added to a flask in which hydrogen is present.</p>
<p>18. <strong>Parr bombs</strong> used for       hydrogenations have been known to explode. They should be handled with care behind       shields, and the operator should wear goggles.</p>
<p>19. <strong>Perchlorates</strong>: The use of       perchlorates should be avoided whenever possible. Perchlorates should not be used as       drying agents if there is a possibility of contact with organic compounds, or in proximity       to a dehydrating acid strong enough to concentrate the perchloric acid to more than 70%       strength (e.g., in a drying train that has a bubble counter containing sulfuric acid).       Seventy percent perchloric acid can be boiled safely at approximately 200o C, but contact       of the boiling undiluted acid or the hot vapor with organic matter, or even easily       oxidized inorganic matter (such as compounds of trivalent antimony), will lead to serious       explosions. Oxidizable substances must never be allowed to contact perchloric acid. Beaker       tongs, rather than rubber gloves, should be used when handling fuming perchloric acid.       Perchloric acid evaporations should be done in a hood with adequate airflow and a built-in       water spray for the ductwork behind the baffle. Frequent (weekly) washing out of the hood       and ventilator ducts with water is necessary to avoid spontaneous combustion or explosion       if this acid is in common use.</p>
<p>20. <strong>Permanganates</strong> are explosive       when treated with sulfuric acid. When both compounds are used in an absorption train, an       empty trap should be placed between them.</p>
<p>21. <strong>Peroxides </strong>(inorganic): When       mixed with combustible materials, barium, sodium, and potassium peroxides form explosives       that ignite easily.</p>
<p>22. <strong>Phosphorus</strong> (red and white)       forms explosive mixtures with oxidizing agents. White P should be stored under water       because it is spontaneously flammable in air. The reaction of P with aqueous hydroxides       gives phosphine, which may ignite spontaneously in air or explode.&nbsp;</p>
<p>23. <strong>Phosphorus trichloride</strong> reacts       with water to form phosphorous acid which decomposes on heating to form phosphine, which       may ignite spontaneously or explode. Care should be taken in opening containers of       phosphorous trichloride, and samples that have been exposed to moisture should not be       heated without adequate shielding to protect the operator.</p>
<p>24. <strong>Potassium</strong> is in general more       reactive than sodium; it ignites quickly on exposure to humid air and, therefore, should       be handled under the surface of a hydrocarbon solvent such as mineral oil or toluene.       Oxidized coatings should be carefully scraped away before cutting the metal (explosions       can otherwise occur).</p>
<p>25. <strong>Residues from vacuum distillations</strong> have been known to explode when the still was vented to the air before the residue was       cool. Such explosions can be avoided by venting the still pot with nitrogen, by cooling it       before venting, or by restoring the pressure slowly.</p>
<p>26. <strong>Sodium</strong> should be stored in a       closed container under kerosene, toluene, or mineral oil. Scraps of Na of K should be       destroyed by reaction with n-butyl alcohol. Contact with water should be avoided because       Na reacts with water to form hydrogen with evolution of sufficient heat to cause ignition.       Carbon dioxide, bicarbonate, and carbon tetrachloride fire extinguishers should not be       used on alkali metal fires.</p>
<a href="x46454.xml">Chemical Hygiene Policy</a><br />]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
