<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67633" Name="Respitory Protection Program" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Respitory Protection Program</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Respitory Protection Program</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Reference: 29 CFR 1910.134</p>
<p><strong><a name="Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></strong><a href="#1.0 PURPOSE"><br /> Purpose</a><br /> <a href="#2.0 SCOPE">Scope</a><br /> <a href="#3.0 REFERENCES">References</a><br /> <a href="#4.0 Medical Evaluation">Medical Evaluation</a><br /> <a href="#5.0 Monitoring">Monitoring</a><br /> <a href="#6.0 Selection of Respirators">Selection of Respirators</a><br /> <a href="#7.0 Training">Training</a><br /> <a href="#8.0 Maintenance and Care of Respirators">Maintenance and Care of Respirators</a><br /> <a href="#9.0 Emergency Use Respirators">Emergency Use Respirators</a><br /> <a href="#10.0 Program Monitoring">Program Monitoring</a><br /> <a href="#11.0 Definitions">Definitions</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="1.0 PURPOSE">1.0 PURPOSE </a></strong></p>
<p>The primary objective of this program is  to prevent       respiratory injury due to atmospheric       contamination. As far as feasible this shall be accomplished by  accepted engineering       controls (i.e., enclosure, confinement, ventilation, and  substitution). When effective engineering controls are not feasible, or  while they are being       instituted, occupational&nbsp; respiratory injuries and illnesses  caused by breathing air contaminated with harmful dusts,       fogs, fumes, mists, gases, smokes sprays or vapors, will be  controlled by the use of       appropriate respiratory protection equipment. This program will  outline the training,       inspection, and utilization of respirators.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="2.0 SCOPE">2.0 SCOPE</a></strong></p>
<p>This program applies to all BYU-Idaho personnel that wear respiratory       protective devices as part of their routine assignment or in emergency or non-routine       situations.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="3.0 REFERENCES">3.0 REFERENCES </a></strong></p>
<p>29 CFR 1926.103 <br /> 29 CFR 1910.134 <br /> 29 CFR 1910.38 <br /> ANSI Z88.6 (Respirator Use -- Physical Qualifications for Personnel) <br /> ANSI Z88.2 (Standard Practices for Respiratory Protection) <br /> BYU-Idaho College Hazard Communication Program <br /> BYU-Idaho College Chemical Hygiene Program (Lab Standard) <br /> BYU-Idaho College Confined Space Entry Program</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents </a></p>
<p><strong><br /> <a name="4.0 Medical Evaluation">4.0 Medical Evaluation</a></strong></p>
<p>4.1 (Alternate) BYU-Idaho personnel will not be assigned to tasks       requiring use of respirators unless it has been determined that they are physically able       to perform the work and use the equipment. A BYU-Idaho physician shall determine what health       and physical conditions are pertinent. (This is the OSHA 29 CFR 1910.134)</p>
<p>4.1.1 A physician shall determine if employees are indeed         physically able to wear a respirator as part of their work assignment. (This is from ANSI         Z.88.6 a good idea but not mandated)</p>
<p>4.2 Frequency. This medical examination should be conducted every       five years up to age 35, every 2 years up to age 45, and annually thereafter. (This goes       with previous one)</p>
<p>4.3 Pulmonary Function Test. Spirometry will be used to screen       individuals that use respirators incidentally to their job performance. If the FVC (forced       vital capacity) is less than 80 percent or the FEV1 (forced expiratory volume - 1 second)       is less than 70 percent, restriction from respirator use will be considered.</p>
<p>4.4 Medical History. A medical history questionnaire will be       utilized to identify the following:</p>
<p>4.4.1 Previously diagnosed diseases, especially cardiovascular or         respiratory diseases</p>
<p>4.4.2 Psychological conditions that might effect respirator use         (claustrophobia)</p>
<p>4.4.3 Problems associated with breathing during normal work         activities</p>
<p>4.4.4 Past problems with respirator use</p>
<p>4.4.5 Past and current usage of medication</p>
<p>4.4.6 Known physical deformities or abnormalities which may         interfere with respirator use</p>
<p>4.4.7 Previous occupations</p>
<p>4.4.8 Susceptibility to tachycardia (rapid beating of the heart)         produced by breathing heated air.</p>
<p>4.5 A determination will be made by the examining physician into       which of three possible categories the respirator user falls:</p>
<p>Class 1 No restrictions</p>
<p>Class 2 Limited Restrictions (Specifically identified by the         physician)</p>
<p>Class 3 No respirator use allowed under any circumstances (This         goes with medical exam )</p>
<p>4.6 Corrective Lenses. Because of the potential of serious       fitting problems by individuals wearing corrective lenses, ONLY the BYU-Idaho       Safety       Department can authorize respirator use to these individuals.</p>
<p>4.6.1 The wearing of contact lenses in contaminated atmospheres         is not allowed.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="5.0 Monitoring">5.0</a></strong><a name="5.0 Monitoring"> <strong>Monitoring</strong></a><strong>. </strong></p>
<p>5.1 A representative of the BYU-Idaho Safety Office or other       competent person shall perform all required air monitoring.</p>
<p>5.2 The competent person shall make a reasonable determination as       to which substances to monitor and how frequently to monitor</p>
<p>5.3 Air sampling data are important in the selection of the       proper respirator and should include:</p>
<p>5.3.1 Identification of the contaminant</p>
<p>5.3.2 Nature of the hazard</p>
<p>5.3.3 Concentration in the breathing zone.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="6.0 Selection of Respirators">6.0 Selection of       Respirators</a>.</strong></p>
<p>6.1 The selection of the appropriate respirator will be made only       after considering a wide assortment of contaminant variables. Among them are the       following:</p>
<p>6.1.1 The physical state of the contaminant -- dust, mist, vapor,         fume, or gas</p>
<p>6.1.2 Its physical properties such as molecular weight, water         solubility and vapor pressure</p>
<p>6.1.3 Physiologic effects on the body, such as eye irritation,         skin adsorption or dulling of the sense of smell.</p>
<p>6.1.4 Measured concentrations compared to permissible exposure         level</p>
<p>6.1.5 Warning properties and odor thresholds.</p>
<p>6.2 Job and individual requirements shall be considered in the       selection of respirators. These include:</p>
<p>6.2.1 Length of time respirator will be worn</p>
<p>6.2.2 The activity of the wearer</p>
<p>6.2.3 Additional requirements of eye protection</p>
<p>6.2.4 Communication</p>
<p>6.2.5 Temperature</p>
<p>6.2.6 Personnel acceptance and face fit</p>
<p>6.3 Unusual factors should be anticipated in selecting       respirators. Some examples include:</p>
<p>6.3.1 Adsorption through or irritation of the skin</p>
<p>6.3.2 Radiation of the skin and whole body</p>
<p>6.4 Air Purifying Respirators</p>
<p>6.4.1 Air purifying respirators will not be worn in atmospheres         containing less than 19.5% oxygen by volume.</p>
<p>6.4.2 Air purifying respirators will not be used where the         contaminants are unknown.</p>
<p>6.4.3 Air purifying respirators will not be used where high or         moderate levels of exposure are expected.</p>
<p>6.4.4 Air purifying respirators will not be used when any of the         following contaminants are present:</p>
<p>carbon monoxide <br /> hydrogen cyanide <br /> hydrogen fluoride <br /> hydrogen sulfide <br /> methylene chloride <br /> nitrous oxides <br /> ozone <br /> Aisocyanates" <br /> vinyl chloride <br /> <em>(This list is not all inclusive) <br /> </em></p>
<p>6.4.5 Only NIOSH/MSHA -- certified respirators will be used.</p>
<p>6.4.6 The selection of respirators will be made by the         BYU-Idaho Safety department or its' qualified designee.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="7.0 Training">7.0 Training</a>.</strong></p>
<p>7.1 Minimum training shall include the following:</p>
<p>7.1.1 Instruction in the nature of the hazard and an appraisal of         what may happen if the respirator is not worn.</p>
<p>7.1.2 A discussion of the respirators capabilities and         limitations.</p>
<p>7.1.3 Every respirator wearer shall receive fitting instructions         including demonstrations and practice in how the respirator should be worn, how to adjust         it, and how to determine if it fits properly. (Respirators shall not be worn when         conditions such as facial hair, temple pieces on glasses, or absence of one or both         dentures, prevent a good face seal.)</p>
<p>7.1.4 Training shall provide individuals an opportunity to handle         the respirator, have it fitted properly, test its facepiece-to-face seal, wear it in         normal air for a long familiarity period, and, to wear it in a test atmosphere.</p>
<p>7.2 Fit Testing.</p>
<p>7.2.1 A qualitative fit test will be conducted initially and as         part of the regular medical evaluation.</p>
<p>7.2.2 A fit check will be conducted by employees each time they         don a respirator. This check can be performed in either of 2 ways:</p>
<p>7.2.2.1 Positive Pressure: the wearer covers the exhalation valve           and breathes out. If a slight positive pressure is felt inside the facepiece, the           respirator is adjusted properly.</p>
<p>7.2.2.2 Negative Pressure: The wearer covers both cartridges with           his hands and inhales. The test is deemed acceptable if the facepiece collapses slightly,           and stays collapsed while the wearer holds his breath.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of           Contents</a></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="8.0 Maintenance and Care of Respirators">8.0 Maintenance       and Care of Respirators</a>.</strong></p>
<p>8.1 Cleaning</p>
<p>8.1.1 Routinely used respirators shall be collected on a regular         basis and be cleaned and disinfected. (At least weekly)</p>
<p>8.1.2 Those respirators used by more than one worker shall be         thoroughly cleaned and disinfected after each use.</p>
<p>8.2 Inspection</p>
<p>8.2.1 All respirators shall be inspected routinely before and         after each use.</p>
<p>8.2.2 Respirators used routinely shall be inspected during         cleaning. Worn, deteriorated, or defective parts shall be immediately replaced.</p>
<p>8.2.3 Parts replacement or repairs should be done only by a         qualified individual.</p>
<p>8.3 Storage</p>
<p>8.3.1 Respirators must be stored to protect against dust,         sunlight, heat, extreme cold, excessive moisture, or damaging chemicals. Storage should be         in a self-sealing type container. (Zip-lock bags or cans with plastic lids)</p>
<p>8.3.2 Respirators should be packed or stored so that the         facepiece and exhalation valve will rest in a normal position and function will not be         impaired by the elastomer setting in an abnormal position</p>
<p>8.4 Repair</p>
<p>8.4.1 Replacements or repairs shall be done only by experienced         persons with parts designed for the respirator. No attempt shall be made to replace         components or to make adjustment or repairs beyond the manufacturer's recommendations</p>
<p>8.5 Air Quality. All breathing air shall meet or exceed the CGA       (Compressed Gas Association) G7.1 standard for Grade "D" air.<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>8.6 Use of Respirators.</p>
<p>8.6.1 Each respirator permanently assigned to an individual         should be durably marked to indicate to whom it was assigned and when the respirator was         issued.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="9.0 Emergency Use Respirators">9.0 Emergency Use       Respirators</a>.</strong></p>
<p>9.1 Training</p>
<p>9.2 Inspection. Emergency use SCBA or Air-line respirators must       be inspected monthly. This inspection will be made by the "using" department and       shall include as a minimum the following items:</p>
<p>9.2.1 The respirator is where it is supposed to be</p>
<p>9.2.2. The air cylinder(s) are fully charged</p>
<p>9.2.3. The low air-pressure warning alarm is working</p>
<p>9.2.4. The elastomeric parts are in good condition</p>
<p>9.2.5. The air cylinders are hydrostatically tested at least once         every 5 years. (Test date is stamped into cylinder neck)</p>
<p>9.3 A record shall be kept of inspection dates and findings for       respirators maintained for emergency use.</p>
<p>9.4 Cleaning. Respirators maintained for emergency use shall be       cleaned and disinfected after each use.</p>
<p>9.5 Storage. Instructions for proper storage of emergency use       respirators are found in "use and care" instructions usually mounted inside the       carrying case lid.</p>
<p>9.6 Use in Dangerous Atmospheres.</p>
<p>9.6.1 In areas where the wearer, with failure of the respirator,         could be overcome by a toxic or oxygen-deficient atmosphere, at least one additional         person shall be present. Communication shall be maintained, and planning shall be such         that one individual will be unaffected by any likely incident and that individual will         have the proper rescue equipment to be able to assist others in time of an emergency.</p>
<p>9.6.2 When self-contained or hose masks with blowers are used in         atmospheres immediately dangerous to life or health, standby men must be present with         suitable rescue equipment.</p>
<p>9.6.3 Individuals using air line respirators in atmospheres         immediately hazardous to life or health shall be equipped with safety harnesses and safety         lines for lifting or removing persons from hazardous atmospheres or, other and equivalent         provisions for rescue, shall be used. A standby rescuer with a SCBA shall be at the         nearest fresh air station.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="10.0 Program Monitoring">10.0 Program Monitoring</a></strong></p>
<p>10.1 The BYU-Idaho Safety Department will monitor the       "Respiratory Protection Program". Random inspections will be made to insure that       respirators are properly selected, used, cleaned and maintained.</p>
<p>10.2 Results of these inspections will be forwarded to department       supervisors, area directors and the Safety Office.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="11.0 Definitions">11.0 Definitions</a>. </strong></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Competent person</span>: One who is capable of identifying existing       and predictable hazards in the surroundings, and who has authorization to take prompt       corrective measures to eliminate them.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Fit testing</span>: Evaluation of the sealing characteristics and       performance of the respirator under controlled conditions.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Respirator</span>: A device designed to protect the wearer from       inhalation of harmful atmospheres. Types include:</p>
<p>1. Atmosphere-supplying respirators:</p>
<p>a. Self contained breathing apparatus (S.C.B.A.) <br /> b. Air-line <br /> c. Hose-mask <br /> d. Combination of self-contained and hose-mask or air-line</p>
<p>2. Air-purifying respirators:</p>
<p>a. Gas and vapor (gas mask and chemical cartridge) <br /> b. Particulate (dust, fog, fume, mist, smoke, and sprays) <br /> c. Combination gas, vapor, and particulate</p>
<p>3. Combination atmosphere-supplying and air-purifying:</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Qualified person</span>: A person who by reason of experience or       training is familiar with the operation to be performed and the hazards involved.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
