<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67649" Name="Bloodborne Pathogen Policy" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bloodborne Pathogen Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Bloodborne Pathogen Policy</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left"><a href="x46622.xml">Bloodborne       Summary</a><br /> <a href="x46624.xml">Hepatitis       B Vaccine Refusal Form</a></p>
<hr />
<strong>Bloodborne Pathogens Policy</strong><br /> Compliance with 29 CFR 1910.1030<br /> Drafted November 30, 1999 <br /><br /><strong><a name="Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><br /> </strong><a href="#1.0 Introduction">1.0 Introduction</a><br /><a href="#2.0 Definitions">2.0 Definitions</a><br /> <a href="#3. Department Exposure Control Plan.">3.0 College Departmental Responsibilities</a><br /> <a href="#4. Exposure determination.">4.0 Exposure determination</a><br /> <a href="#5. General Work Practices and Procedures.">5.0 General Work Practices and Procedures</a><br /> <a href="#6 Personal Protective Equipment.">6.0 Personal Protective Equipment</a><br /><a href="#7 Housekeeping.">7.0 Housekeeping</a><br /> <a href="#8 Regulated Waste.">8.0 Regulated Waste</a><br /> <a href="#9 Laundry.">9.0 Laundry</a><br /> <a href="#10 HIV and HBV Research Laboratories and Production Facilities.">10.0 HIV and HBV       Research Laboratories and Production Facilities</a><br /> <a href="#11 Hepatitis B vaccination and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up">11.0 Hepatitis       B vaccination and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up</a><br /> <a href="#12 Communication of Hazards to Employees.">12.0 Communication of Hazards to Employees</a><br /> <a href="#13 Record Keeping.">13.0 Recordkeeping</a>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Bloodborne Pathogens Exposure Control Plan</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="1.0 Introduction"></a><a href="#1.0 Introduction">1.0 Introduction</a></strong></p>
<p>The purpose of this Exposure Control Plan is to reduce the       probability of college employees<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>contracting serious illness due to pathogenic       microorganisms while working at BYU-Idaho or participating in academic or volunteer       programs associated with the university.</p>
<strong>
<p><a name="2.0 Definitions"></a><a href="#2.0 Definitions">2.0 Definitions</a></p>
</strong>
<p>2.1 <em>Blood</em> means human blood, human blood components,       and products made from human blood.</p>
<p>2.2 <em>Bloodborne Pathogens</em> means pathogenic microorganisms       that are present in human blood and can cause disease in humans. These pathogens include,       but are not limited to, hepatitis B virus (HBV) and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).</p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>2.3 <em>Clinical Laboratory</em> means a workplace where       diagnostic or other screening procedures are performed on blood or other potentially       infectious materials.</p>
<p>2.4 <em>Contaminated</em> means the presence or the reasonably       anticipated presence of blood or other potentially infectious materials on an item or       surface.</p>
<p>2.5 <em>Contaminated Laundry</em> means laundry which has been       soiled with blood or other potentially infectious materials or may contain sharps.</p>
<p>2.6 <em>Contaminated Sharps</em> means any contaminated object that       can penetrate the skin including, but not limited to, needles, scalpels, broken glass,       broken capillary tubes, and exposed ends of dental wires.</p>
<p>2.7 <em>Decontamination</em> means the use of physical or chemical       means to remove, inactivate, or destroy bloodborne pathogens on a surface or item to the       point where they are no longer capable of transmitting infectious particles and the       surface or item is rendered safe for handling, use, or disposal.</p>
<p>2.8 <em>Engineering Controls</em> means controls (e.g., sharps       disposal containers, self-sheathing needles) that isolate or remove the bloodborne       pathogens hazard from the workplace.</p>
<p>2.9 <em>Exposure Incident</em> means a specific eye, mouth, other       mucous membrane, non-intact skin, or parenteral contact with blood or other potentially       infectious materials that results from the performance of an employee's duties.</p>
<p>2.10 <em>Handwashing Facilities</em> means a facility providing an       adequate supply of running potable water, soap and single use towels or hot air drying       machines.</p>
<p>2.11 <em>Licensed Healthcare Professional</em> is a person whose       legally permitted scope of practice allows him or her to independently perform the       activities required by section 11 dealing with Hepatitis B Vaccination and Post-exposure       Evaluation and Follow-up.</p>
<p>2.12 <em>HBV</em> means hepatitis B virus.</p>
<p>2.13 <em>HIV</em> means human immunodeficiency virus.</p>
<p>2.14 <em>Occupational Exposure</em> means reasonably anticipated       skin, eye, mucous membrane, or parenteral contact with blood or other potentially       infectious materials that may result from the performance of an employee's duties.</p>
<p>2.15 <em>Other Potentially Infectious Materials means</em></p>
<p>2.15.1 The following human body fluids: semen, vaginal         secretions, cerebrospinal fluid, synovial fluid, pleural fluid, pericardial fluid,         peritoneal fluid, amniotic fluid, saliva in dental procedures, any body fluid that is         visibly contaminated with blood, and all body fluids in situations where it is difficult         or impossible to differentiate between body fluids;</p>
<p>2.15.2 Any unfixed tissue or organ (other than intact skin) from         a human (living or dead); and</p>
<p>2.15.3 HIV-containing cell or tissue cultures, organ cultures,         and HIV- or HBV-containing culture medium or other solutions; and blood, organs, or other         tissues from experimental animals infected with HIV or HBV.</p>
<p>2.16 <em>Parenteral</em> means piercing mucous membranes or the       skin barrier through such events as needlesticks, human bites, cuts, and abrasions.</p>
<p>2.17 <em>Personal Protective Equipment</em> is specialized clothing       or equipment worn by an employee for protection against a hazard. General work clothes       (e.g., uniforms, pants, shirts or blouses) not intended to function as protection against       a hazard are not considered to be personal protective equipment.</p>
<p>2.18 <em>Regulated Waste</em> means liquid or semi-liquid blood or       other potentially infectious materials; contaminated items that would release blood or       other potentially infectious materials in a liquid or semi-liquid state if compressed;       items that are caked with dried blood or other potentially infectious materials and are       capable of releasing these materials during handling; contaminated sharps; and       pathological and microbiological wastes containing blood or other potentially infectious       materials.</p>
<p>2.19 <em>Research Laboratory</em> means a laboratory producing or       using research-laboratory-scale amounts of HIV or HBV. Research laboratories may produce       high concentrations of HIV or HBV but not in the volume found in production facilities.</p>
<p>2.20 <em>Source Individual</em> means any individual, living or       dead, whose blood or other potentially infectious materials may be a source of       occupational exposure to the employee. Examples include, but are not limited to, hospital       and clinic patients; clients in institutions for the developmentally disabled; trauma       victims; clients of drug and alcohol treatment facilities; residents of hospices and       nursing homes; human remains; and individuals who donate or sell blood or blood       components.</p>
<p>2.21 <em>Sterilize</em> means the use of a physical or chemical       procedure to destroy all microbial life including highly resistant bacterial endospores.</p>
<p>2.22 <em>Universal Precautions</em> is an approach to infection       control. According to the concept of Universal Precautions, all human blood and certain       human body fluids are treated as if known to be infectious for HIV, HBV, and other       bloodborne pathogens.</p>
<p>2.23 <em>Work Practice Controls</em> means controls that reduce the       likelihood of exposure by altering the manner in which a task is performed (e.g.,       prohibiting recapping of needles by a two-handed technique).</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="3. Department Exposure Control Plan.">3.0 Department       Exposure Control Plan.</a></strong><a name="3. Department Exposure Control Plan."> </a></p>
<p>Each department or center at BYU-Idaho shall write and review       a supplementary safety policy for their area. This document, shall be titled the       A (Name of       Department or Center) Exposure Control Plan (for example, The College of Nursing Exposure       Control Plan). The Exposure Control Plan shall be reviewed and updated at least annually       and whenever necessary to reflect new or modified tasks and procedures which affect       occupational exposure and to reflect new or revised employee positions with occupational       exposure.</p>
<p>3.1 Exposure Control Plan.</p>
<p>Each department or center should write a former plan detailing       the proper protocols for handling potential occupational exposures or contamination       involving biohazardous substances for their individual area as well as provide training       for employees who are at risk for occupational exposure.</p>
<p>3.1.2 Protocol for handling biohazardous wastes.</p>
<p>3.1.2.1 The BYU-Idaho Health Center will oversee the shipping           of all biohazardous waste to the proper off-campus waste handling facilities. Each           department or center's protocol must include proper packaging, labeling, and delivery of           biohazardous wastes to the College Health Center.</p>
<p>3.1.2.1.1 Each department or center on campus which produces             biohazardous waste is required to deliver such waste for shipment to the campus Health             Center.</p>
<p>3.1.2.1.2 Each department or center will be charged a fee by the             health center for the purchase of biohazardous containers and for the shipping of those             containers to the necessary waste disposal facilities.</p>
<p>3.1.3 Provide Biohazard Exposure training for all employees whose         line of work may present risk of occupational exposure (see section 12 and 13).</p>
<p>3.1.4 Provide information on benefits and risks for Hepatitis B         vaccination shots (see section 11).</p>
<p>3.1.5 Include a copy of the department list from section 4.0 of         this document to the Campus Safety Office.</p>
<p>3.1.6 A copy of this policy shall be submitted to the Campus         Safety Office for documentation and review.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="4. Exposure determination.">4.0 Exposure determination</a></strong><a name="4. Exposure determination.">. </a></p>
<p>Each department with employee's who have occupational exposure       shall prepare an exposure determination. This exposure determination shall be made without       regard to the use of personal protective equipment and shall contain the following:</p>
<p>4.1 Job List Defined. A list of all job classifications in which       all employees in those job classifications have occupational exposure;</p>
<p>4.2 Job List(some exposure) Defined. A list of job       classifications in which some employees have occupational exposure, and</p>
<p>4.3 Task List Defined. A list of all tasks and procedures or       groups of closely related task and procedures in which occupational exposure occurs and       that are performed by employees in job classifications listed in accordance with the       provisions of items 4.1 and 4.2 of this standard.</p>
<p>4.4 List of job classifications in which all employees have       occupational exposure. (include list here)</p>
<p>4.5 List of job classifications in which some employees have       occupational exposure. (include list here)</p>
<p>4.6 List of tasks and procedures involving occupational exposure.       (including enclosed list)</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="5. General Work Practices and Procedures.">5.0 General       Work Practices and Procedures.</a></strong></p>
<p>5.1 Universal Precautions. Universal precautions shall be       observed to prevent contact with blood or other potentially infectious materials. Under       circumstances in which differentiation between body fluid types is difficult or       impossible, all body fluids shall be considered potentially infectious materials.</p>
<p>5.2 Engineering and work practice controls.</p>
<p>5.2.1 Use. Engineering and work practice controls shall be used         to eliminate or minimize employee exposure. Where occupational exposure remains after         institution of these controls, personal protective equipment shall also be used.</p>
<p>5.2.2 Maintenance. Engineering controls shall be examined and         maintained or replaced on a regular schedule to ensure their effectiveness.</p>
<p>5.3 Hand-washing. BYU-Idaho shall provide       hand-washing       facilities which are readily accessible to employees in jobs listed in 4.4 and 4.5 above.</p>
<p>5.3.1 Exception. When provision of hand-washing facilities is not         feasible, BYU-Idaho shall provide either an appropriate antiseptic hand cleanser in         conjunction with clean cloth/paper towels or antiseptic towelettes. When antiseptic hand         cleansers or towelettes are used, hands shall be washed with soap and running water as         soon as feasible after an exposure.</p>
<p>5.3.2 Removal of Gloves. Supervisors shall ensure that employees         wash their hands immediately or as soon as feasible after removal of gloves or other         personal protective equipment.</p>
<p>5.3.3 Contact with Infectious Materials. Supervisors shall ensure         that employees wash hands and any other skin with soap and water, or flush mucous         membranes with water immediately or as soon as feasible following contact of such body         areas with blood or other potentially infectious materials.</p>
<p>5.4 Eating in Contaminated Areas. Eating, drinking, applying       cosmetics or lip balm, and handling contact lenses are prohibited in work areas where       there is a reasonable likelihood of occupational exposure.</p>
<p>5.5 Food and Drink. Food and drink shall not be kept in       refrigerators, freezers, shelves, cabinets or on countertops or benchtops where blood or       other potentially infectious materials are present.</p>
<p>5.6 Aerosols. All procedures involving blood or other potentially       infectious materials shall be performed in such a manner as to minimize splashing,       spraying, spattering, and generation of droplets of these substances.</p>
<p>5.7 Pipetting. Mouth pipetting/suctioning of blood or other       potentially infectious materials is prohibited.</p>
<p>5.8 Containers. Specimens of blood or other potentially       infectious materials shall be placed in a container which prevents leakage during       collection, handling, processing, storage, transport, or shipping.</p>
<p>5.8.1 Labeling. The container for storage, transport, or shipping         shall be labeled or color-coded according to section 12.1 and closed prior to being         stored, transported, or shipped. If Universal Precautions are used in the handling of all         specimens, the labeling/color-coding of specimens is not necessary provided containers are         recognizable as containing specimens. This exemption only applies while such         specimens/containers remain within the facility using Universal Precautions. Labeling or         color-coding in accordance with section 12.1 is required when such specimens/containers         leave the facility.</p>
<p>5.8.2 Contaminated Primary Containers. If outside contamination         of the primary container occurs, the primary container shall be placed within a second         container which prevents leakage during handling, processing, storage, transport, or         shipping and is labeled or color-coded according to the requirements of this standard.</p>
<p>5.8.3 Puncture Resistance. If the specimen could puncture the         primary container, the primary container shall be placed within a secondary container         which is puncture- resistant in addition to the above characteristics.</p>
<p>5.9 Servicing and Shipping Equipment.</p>
<p>5.9.1 Decontamination. Equipment which may become contaminated         with blood or other potentially infectious materials shall be examined prior to servicing         or shipping and shall be decontaminated as necessary, unless the it can be demonstrated         that decontamination of such equipment or portions of such equipment is not feasible.</p>
<p>5.9.2 Labeling. A readily observable label in accordance with         section 12.1.5 shall be attached to the equipment stating which portions remain         contaminated.</p>
<p>5.9.3 Informing. The area supervisor shall ensure that         information concerning contaminated equipment is conveyed to all affected employees, the         servicing representative, and/or the manufacturer, as appropriate, prior to handling,         servicing, or shipping so that appropriate precautions will be taken.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="6 Personal Protective Equipment.">6.0 Personal       Protective Equipment. </a></strong></p>
<p>6.1 Availability. When there is occupational exposure,       BYU-Idaho shall provide, at no cost to the employee, appropriate personal protective       equipment such as, but not limited to, gloves, gowns, laboratory coats, face shields or       masks and eye protection, and mouthpieces, resuscitation bags, pocket masks, or other       ventilation devices. Personal protective equipment will be considered Aappropriate@ only       if it does not permit blood or other potentially infectious materials to pass through to       or reach the employee's work clothes, street clothes, undergarments, skin, eyes, mouth, or       other mucous membranes under normal conditions of use and for the duration of time which       the protective equipment will be used.</p>
<p>6.2 Use. Department supervisors shall ensure that College       personnel use appropriate personal protective equipment unless the supervisor shows that       the employee temporarily and briefly declined to use personal protective equipment when,       under rare and extraordinary circumstances, it was the employee's professional judgment       that in the specific instance its use would have prevented the delivery of health care or       public safety services or would have posed an increased hazard to the safety of the worker       or co-worker. When the employee makes this judgement, the circumstances shall be       investigated and documented in order to determine whether changes can be instituted to       prevent such occurrences in the future.</p>
<p>6.3 Accessibility. BYU-Idaho shall ensure that appropriate       personal protective equipment in the appropriate sizes is readily accessible at the       worksite or is issued to employees. Hypoallergenic gloves, glove liners, powderless       gloves, or other similar alternatives shall be readily accessible to those employees who       are allergic to the gloves normally provided.</p>
<p>6.4 Cleaning, Laundering, and Disposal. BYU-Idaho       shall       clean, launder, and dispose of personal protective equipment required by this plan at no       cost to the employee.</p>
<p>6.5 Repair and Replacement. BYU-Idaho shall repair or replace       personal protective equipment as needed to maintain its effectiveness, at no cost to the       employee.</p>
<p>6.6 Inner Contamination. If a garment(s) is penetrated by blood       or other potentially infectious materials, the garment(s) shall be removed immediately or       as soon as feasible.</p>
<p>6.7 Removal All personal protective equipment shall be removed       prior to leaving the work area.</p>
<p>6.7.1 Storage. When personal protective equipment is removed it         shall be placed in an appropriately designated area or container for storage, washing,         decontamination or disposal.</p>
<p>6.8 Gloves. Gloves shall be worn when it can be reasonably       anticipated that the employee may have hand contact with blood, other potentially       infectious materials, mucous membranes, and non-intact skin; when performing vascular       access procedures except as specified in paragraph section 6.8.4; and when handling or       touching contaminated items or surfaces.</p>
<p>6.8.1 Disposable Glove Replacement. Disposable (single use)         gloves such as surgical or examination gloves, shall be replaced as soon as practical when         contaminated or as soon as feasible if they are torn, punctured, or when their ability to         function as a barrier is compromised.</p>
<p>6.8.2 Disposable Glove Re-use. Disposable (single use) gloves         shall not be washed or decontaminated for re-use.</p>
<p>6.8.3 Utility Gloves. Utility gloves may be decontaminated for         re-use if the integrity of the glove is not compromised. However, they must be discarded         if they are cracked, peeling, torn, punctured, or exhibit other signs of deterioration or         when their ability to function as a barrier is compromised.</p>
<p>6.8.4 Phlebotomy. If a supervisor judges that routine gloving for         all phlebotomies is not necessary then the supervisor shall:</p>
<p>6.8.4.1 Periodically reevaluate this policy;</p>
<p>6.8.4.2 Make gloves available to all employees who wish to use           them for phlebotomy;</p>
<p>6.8.4.3 Not discourage the use of gloves for phlebotomy; and</p>
<p>6.8.4.4 Require that gloves be used for phlebotomy in the           following circumstances:</p>
<p>6.8.4.4.1 When the employee has cuts, scratches, or other breaks             in his or her skin;</p>
<p>6.8.4.4.2 When the employee judges that hand contamination with             blood may occur, for example, when performing phlebotomy on an uncooperative source             individual; and</p>
<p>6.8.4.4.3 When the employee is receiving training in phlebotomy.</p>
<p>6.9 Masks, Eye Protection, and Face Shields. Masks in combination       with eye protection devices, such as goggles or glasses with solid side shields, or       chin-length face shields, shall be worn whenever splashes, spray, spatter, or droplets of       blood or other potentially infectious materials may be generated and eye, nose, or mouth       contamination can be reasonably anticipated.</p>
<p>6.10 Gowns, Aprons, and Other Protective Body Clothing.       Appropriate protective clothing such as, but not limited to, gowns, aprons, lab coats,       clinic jackets, or similar outer garments shall be worn in occupational exposure       situations. The type and characteristics will depend upon the task and degree of exposure       anticipated.</p>
<p>6.10.1 Anticipated Gross Contamination. Surgical caps or hoods         and/or shoe covers or boots shall be worn in instances when gross contamination can         reasonably be anticipated (e.g., autopsies, orthopedic surgery).</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a name="7 Housekeeping."><strong>7.0 Housekeeping. </strong></a></p>
<p>Departments shall ensure that their work areas are maintained in       a clean and sanitary condition. The department shall determine and implement an       appropriate written schedule for cleaning and method of decontamination based upon the       location within the facility, type of surface to be cleaned, type of soil present, and       tasks or procedures being performed in the area.</p>
<p>7.1 Cleaning Schedule. (insert cleaning schedule here)</p>
<p>7.2 Cleaning Equipment, Disinfectants, and Equipment.(insert list       here)</p>
<p>7.3 Equipment and Working Surfaces. All equipment and       environmental and working surfaces shall be cleaned and decontaminated after contact with       blood or other potentially infectious materials.</p>
<p>Contaminated work surfaces shall be decontaminated with an       appropriate disinfectant after completion of procedures; immediately or as soon as       feasible when surfaces are overtly contaminated or after any spill of blood or other       potentially infectious materials; and at the end of the work shift if the surface may have       become contaminated since the last cleaning.</p>
<p>7.4 Disposable Protective Coverings. Protective coverings, such       as plastic wrap, aluminum foil, or imperviously-backed absorbent paper used to cover       equipment and environmental surfaces, shall be removed and replaced as soon as feasible       when they become overtly contaminated or at the end of the workshift if they may have       become contaminated during the shift.</p>
<p>7.5 Contaminated Bins, Pails, and Cans. All bins, pails, cans,       and similar receptacles intended for reuse which have a reasonable likelihood for becoming       contaminated with blood or other potentially infectious materials shall be inspected and       decontaminated on a regularly scheduled basis and cleaned and decontaminated immediately       or as soon as feasible upon visible contamination.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="8 Regulated Waste.">8.0 Regulated Waste.</a></strong><a name="8 Regulated Waste."> </a></p>
<p>8.1 Sharps.</p>
<p>8.1.1 Bending and Recapping. Contaminated needles and other         contaminated sharps shall not be bent, recapped, or removed except as noted in paragraphs         6.1.1 below. Shearing or breaking of contaminated needles is prohibited.</p>
<p>8.1.1.1 Contaminated needles and other contaminated sharps shall           not be recapped or removed unless the director or supervisor can demonstrate that no           alternative is feasible or that such action is required by a specific medical procedure.</p>
<p>Such recapping or needle removal must be accomplished through the           use of a mechanical device or a one-handed technique.</p>
<p>8.1.2 Contaminated Reusable Sharps. Immediately or as soon as         possible after use, contaminated reusable sharps shall be placed in appropriate containers         until properly reprocessed. These containers shall be</p>
<p>8.1.2.1 Puncture resistant</p>
<p>8.1.2.2 Labeled or color-coded</p>
<p>8.1.2.3 Leakproof on the sides and bottom</p>
<p>8.1.3 Reusable Sharps Storage. Reusable sharps that are       contaminated with blood or other potentially infectious materials shall not be stored or       processed in a manner that requires employees to reach by hand into the containers where       these sharps have been placed.</p>
<p>8.1.4 Broken glassware. Broken glassware which may be       contaminated shall not be picked up directly with the hands. It shall be cleaned up using       mechanical means, such as a brush and dust pan, tongs, or forceps.</p>
<p>8.1.5 Contaminated Sharps Discarding and Containment.</p>
<p>8.1.5.1 Contaminated sharps shall be discarded immediately or as         soon as feasible in containers that are:</p>
<p>8.1.5.1.1 Closable;</p>
<p>8.1.5.1.2 Puncture resistant;</p>
<p>8.1.5.1.3 Leakproof on sides and bottom; and</p>
<p>8.1.5.1.4 Labeled or color-coded in accordance section 12.1 of           this plan.</p>
<p>8.1.5.2 During use, containers for contaminated sharps shall be:</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.1 Easily accessible to personnel and located as close as           is feasible to the immediate area where sharps are used or can be reasonably anticipated           to be found (e.g., laundries);</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.2 Maintained upright throughout use; and</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.3 Replaced routinely and not be allowed to overfill.</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.4 When moving containers of contaminated sharps from the           area of use, the containers shall be:</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.5 Closed immediately prior to removal or replacement to           prevent spillage or protrusion of contents during handling, storage, transport, or           shipping;</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.6 Placed in a secondary container if leakage is possible.           The second container shall be:</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.6.1 Closeable;</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.6.2 Constructed to contain all contents and prevent             leakage during handling, storage, transport, or shipping; and</p>
<p>8.1.5.2.6.3 Labeled or color-coded according to section 12 of             this plan.</p>
<p>8.1.5.3 Reusable containers shall not be opened, emptied, or           cleaned manually or in any other manner which would expose employees to the risk of           percutaneous injury.</p>
<p>8.2 Other Regulated Waste Containment. Regulated waste shall be       placed in containers which are:</p>
<p>8.2.1 Closable;</p>
<p>8.2.2 Leakage. Constructed to contain all contents and prevent         leakage of fluids during handling, storage, transport or shipping;</p>
<p>8.2.3 Labeling. Labeled or color-coded in accordance with section         12.1 of this plan; and</p>
<p>8.2.4 Closing. Closed prior to removal to prevent spillage or         protrusion of contents during handling, storage, transport, or shipping.</p>
<p>8.3 Outside Contamination of Waste Container. If outside       contamination of the regulated waste container occurs, it shall be placed in a second       container. The second container shall be:</p>
<p>8.3.1 Closable;</p>
<p>8.3.2 Leakage. Constructed to contain all contents and prevent         leakage of fluids during handling, storage, transport or shipping;</p>
<p>8.3.3 Labeling. Labeled or color-coded in accordance with section         12.1 of this plan; and</p>
<p>8.3.4 Closing. Closed prior to removal to prevent spillage or         protrusion of contents during handling, storage, transport, or shipping.</p>
<p>8.4 Disposal. Disposal of all regulated waste shall be in       accordance with applicable regulations of the United States, States and Territories, and       political subdivisions of States and Territories.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="9 Laundry.">9.0 Laundry.</a></strong></p>
<p>9.1 Handling. Contaminated laundry shall be handled as little as       possible with a minimum of agitation. (1) Contaminated laundry shall be bagged or       containerized at the location where it was used and shall not be sorted or rinsed in the       location of use.</p>
<p>9.2 Containers. Contaminated laundry shall be placed and       transported in bags or containers labeled or color-coded in accordance with section 12.1       of this plan. When a facility utilizes Universal Precautions in the handling of all soiled       laundry, alternative labeling or color-coding is sufficient if it permits all employees to       recognize the containers as requiring compliance with Universal Precautions.</p>
<p>9.3 Wet Contaminated Laundry. Whenever contaminated laundry is       wet and presents a reasonable likelihood of soak-through of or leakage from the bag or       container, the laundry shall be placed and transported in bags or containers which prevent       soak-through and/or leakage of fluids to the exterior.</p>
<p>9.4 Personal Protective Equipment. The supervisor shall ensure       that employees who have contact with contaminated laundry wear protective gloves and other       appropriate personal protective equipment.</p>
<p>9.5 Labels and Marking. When contaminated laundry is sent to a       second facility which does not utilize Universal Precautions in the handling of all       laundry, the department generating the contaminated laundry must place such laundry in       bags or containers which are labeled or color-coded in accordance section 12 of this plan.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="10 HIV and HBV Research Laboratories and Production Facilities.">10 HIV and HBV Research Laboratories and Production Facilities.</a></strong><a name="10.0 HIV and HBV Research Laboratories and Production Facilities."> </a></p>
<p>This section applies to research laboratories and production       facilities engaged in the culture, production, concentration, experimentation, and       manipulation of HIV and HBV. It does not apply to clinical or diagnostic laboratories       engaged solely in the analysis of blood, tissues, or organs. These requirements apply in       addition to the other requirements of this plan.</p>
<p>Research laboratories and production facilities shall meet the       following criteria:</p>
<p>10.1 Standard microbiological practices. All regulated waste       shall either be incinerated or decontaminated by a method such as autoclaving known to       effectively destroy bloodborne pathogens.</p>
<p>10.2 Special practices.</p>
<p>10.2.1 Doors. Laboratory doors shall be kept closed when work         involving HIV or HBV is in progress.</p>
<p>10.2.2 Contaminated Materials. Contaminated materials that are to         be decontaminated at a site away from the work area shall be placed in a durable,         leakproof, labeled or color-coded container that is closed before being removed from the         work area.</p>
<p>10.2.3 Access. Access to the work area shall be limited to         authorized persons. Written policies and procedures shall be established whereby only         persons who have been advised of the potential biohazard, who meet any specific entry         requirements, and who comply with all entry and exit procedures shall be allowed to enter         the work areas and animal rooms.</p>
<p>10.2.4 Signs. When other potentially infectious materials or         infected animals are present in the work area or containment module, a hazard warning sign         incorporating the universal biohazard symbol shall be posted on all access doors. The         hazard warning sign shall comply with section 12.2 of this plan.</p>
<p>10.2.5 Use of Safety Cabinets. All activities involving other         potentially infectious materials shall be conducted in biological safety cabinets or other         physical-containment devices within the containment module. No work with these other         potentially infectious materials shall be conducted on the open bench.</p>
<p>10.2.6 Protective Clothing. Laboratory coats, gowns, smocks,         uniforms, or other appropriate protective clothing shall be used in the work area and         animal rooms. Protective clothing shall not be worn outside of the work area and shall be         decontaminated before being laundered.</p>
<p>10.2.7 Gloves. Special care shall be taken to avoid skin contact         with other potentially infectious materials. Gloves shall be worn when handling infected         animals and when making hand contact with other potentially infectious materials is         unavoidable.</p>
<p>10.2.8 Decontaminating Waste. Before disposal all waste from work         areas and from animal rooms shall either be incinerated or decontaminated by a method such         as autoclaving known to effectively destroy bloodborne pathogens.</p>
<p>10.2.9 Vacuum Lines. Vacuum lines shall be protected with liquid         disinfectant traps and high-efficiency particulate air (HEPA) filters or filters of         equivalent or superior efficiency and which are checked routinely and maintained or         replaced as necessary.</p>
<p>10.2.10 Needles. Hypodermic needles and syringes shall be used         only for parenteral injection and aspiration of fluids from laboratory animals and         diaphragm bottles. Only needle-locking syringes or disposable syringe-needle units (i.e.,         the needle is integral to the syringe) shall be used for the injection or aspiration of         other potentially infectious materials. Extreme caution shall be used when handling         needles and syringes. A needle shall not be bent, sheared, replaced in the sheath or         guard, or removed from the syringe following use. The needle and syringe shall be promptly         placed in a puncture-resistant container and autoclaved or decontaminated before reuse or         disposal.</p>
<p>10.2.11 Spills. All spills shall be immediately contained and         cleaned up by appropriate professional staff or others properly trained and equipped to         work with potentially concentrated infectious materials.</p>
<p>10.2.12 Accidental Exposures. A spill or accident that results in         an exposure incident shall be immediately reported to the laboratory director or other         responsible person.</p>
<p>10.2.13 Biosafety Manual. A biosafety manual shall be prepared or         adopted and periodically reviewed and updated at least annually or more often if         necessary. Personnel shall be advised of potential hazards, shall be required to read         instructions on practices and procedures, and shall be required to follow them.</p>
<p>10.3 Containment equipment. Certified biological safety cabinets       (Class I, II, or III) or other appropriate combinations of personal protection or physical       containment devices, such as special protective clothing, respirators, centrifuge safety       cups, sealed centrifuge rotors, and containment caging for animals, shall be used for all       activities with other potentially infectious materials that pose a threat of exposure to       droplets, splashes, spills, or aerosols.</p>
<p>10.3.1 Certification. Biological safety cabinets shall be         certified when installed, whenever they are moved and at least annually.</p>
<p>10.4 Facilities. HIV and HBV research laboratories shall meet the       following criteria:</p>
<p>10.4.1 Eye and Hand Wash. Each laboratory shall contain a         facility for hand washing and an eye wash facility which is readily available within the         work area.</p>
<p>10.4.2 Autoclave. An autoclave for decontamination of regulated         waste shall be available.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="11 Hepatitis B vaccination and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up">11.0 Hepatitis       B vaccination and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up</a>.</strong></p>
<p>11.1 Availability. BYU-Idaho shall make available the       hepatitis B vaccine and vaccination series to all employees who have occupational       exposure, and post-exposure evaluation and follow-up to all employees who have had an       exposure incident.</p>
<p>11.2 Procedure. BYU-Idaho shall ensure that all medical       evaluations and procedures including the hepatitis B vaccine and vaccination series and       post-exposure evaluation and follow-up, including prophylaxis, are:</p>
<p>11.2.1 Cost. Made available at no cost to the employee;</p>
<p>11.2.2 Convenience. Made available to the employee at a         reasonable time and place;</p>
<p>11.2.3 Performed By. Performed by or under the supervision of a         licensed physician or by or under the supervision of another licensed healthcare         professional; and</p>
<p>11.2.4 Protocol. Provided according to recommendations of the         U.S. Public Health Service current at the time these evaluations and procedures take         place, except as specified by section 11.4.</p>
<p>11.3 Laboratory Tests. BYU-Idaho shall ensure that all       laboratory tests are conducted by an accredited laboratory at no cost to the employee.</p>
<p>11.4 Hepatitis B Vaccination. Hepatitis B vaccination shall be       made available after the employee has received the training required in section 12.3 of       this plan and within 10 working days of initial assignment to all employees who have       occupational exposure unless the employee has previously received the complete hepatitis B       vaccination series, antibody testing has revealed that the employee is immune, or the       vaccine is contraindicated for medical reasons.</p>
<p>The participation in a prescreening program shall not be a       prerequisite for receiving hepatitis B vaccination.</p>
<p>11.4.1 Employee Refusal. If the employee initially declines         hepatitis B vaccination but at a later date while still covered under the standard decides         to accept the vaccination, BYU-Idaho shall make available hepatitis B vaccination at         that time.</p>
<p>The employees who decline to accept hepatitis B vaccination shall         sign the statement in appendix A.</p>
<p>11.4.2 Boosters. If a routine booster dose(s) of hepatitis B         vaccine is recommended by the U.S. Public Health Service at a future date, such booster         dose(s) shall be made available in accordance with section 11.2.</p>
<p>11.5 Post-exposure Evaluation and Follow-up. Following a report         of an exposure incident, BYU-Idaho shall make immediately available to the exposed         employee a confidential medical evaluation and follow-up, including at least the following         elements:</p>
<p>11.5.1 Documentation. Documentation of the route(s) of exposure,         and the circumstances under which the exposure incident occurred;</p>
<p>11.5.2 Identification of Source. Identification and documentation         of the source individual, unless it can be established that identification is infeasible         or prohibited by state or local law;</p>
<p>11.5.2.1 The source individual's blood shall be tested as soon as           feasible and after consent is obtained in order to determine HBV and HIV infectivity. If           consent is not obtained, BYU-Idaho shall establish that legally required consent           cannot be obtained. When the source individual's consent is not required by law, the           source individual's blood, if available, shall be tested and the results documented.</p>
<p>11.5.2.2 When the source individual is already known to be           infected with HBV or HIV, testing for the source individual's known HBV or HIV status need           not be repeated.</p>
<p>11.5.2.3 Results of the source individual's testing shall be made           available to the exposed employee, and the employee shall be informed of applicable laws           and regulations concerning disclosure of the identity and infectious status of the source           individual.</p>
<p>11.5.3 Employee Serology.</p>
<p>11.5.3.1 The exposed employee's blood shall be collected as soon           as feasible and tested after consent is obtained.</p>
<p>11.5.3.2 If the employee consents to baseline blood collection,           but does not give consent at that time for HIV serologic testing, the sample shall be           preserved for at least 90 days. If, within 90 days of the exposure incident, the employee           elects to have the baseline sample tested, such testing shall be done as soon as feasible.</p>
<p>11.5.4 Prophylaxis. Post-exposure prophylaxis, when medically         indicated, as recommended by the U.S. Public Health Service;</p>
<p>11.6 Counseling and Evaluation of Reported Illnesses.</p>
<p>11.6.1 Information Provided to the Healthcare Professional.         BYU-Idaho shall ensure that the healthcare professional responsible for the employee's         Hepatitis B vaccination is provided a copy of the Bloodborne Pathogen Standard.</p>
<p>In addition the healthcare professional evaluating an employee         after an exposure incident shall be provided with the following information:</p>
<p>11.6.1.1 A description of the exposed employee's duties as they           relate to the exposure incident;</p>
<p>11.6.1.2 Documentation of the route(s) of exposure and           circumstances under which exposure occurred;</p>
<p>11.6.1.3 Results of the source individual's blood testing, if           available; and</p>
<p>11.6.1.4 All medical records relevant to the appropriate           treatment of the employee including vaccination status which are the employer's           responsibility to maintain.</p>
<p>11.7 Healthcare Professional's Written Opinion.       BYU-Idaho shall obtain and provide the employee with a copy of the evaluating healthcare       professional's written opinion within 15 days of the completion of the evaluation.</p>
<p>11.7.1 Hepatitis B Vaccination. The healthcare professional's         written opinion for Hepatitis B vaccination shall be limited to whether Hepatitis B         vaccination is indicated for an employee, and if the employee has received such         vaccination.</p>
<p>11.7.2 Evaluation and Followup. The healthcare professional's         written opinion for post-exposure evaluation and follow-up shall be limited to the         following information:</p>
<p>11.7.2.1 That the employee has been informed of the results of           the evaluation; and</p>
<p>11.7.2.2 That the employee has been told about any medical           conditions resulting from exposure to blood or other potentially infectious materials           which require further evaluation or treatment. All other findings or diagnoses shall           remain confidential and shall not be included in the written report.</p>
<p>11.8 Medical recordkeeping. Medical records required by this plan       shall be maintained in accordance with section 13.1 of this plan.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="12 Communication of Hazards to Employees.">12.0       Communication of Hazards to Employees.</a></strong><a name="12 Communication of Hazards to Employees."> </a></p>
<p>12.1 Labels.</p>
<p>12.1.1 Required Labeling. Warning labels shall be affixed to         containers of regulated waste, refrigerators and freezers containing blood or other         potentially infectious material; and other containers used to store, transport or ship         blood or other potentially infectious materials, except as provided in sections 12.1.7         through 12.1.9.</p>
<p>12.1.2 Required Legend. Labels required by this section shall         include the legend as demonstrated in figure 1 in appendix 2.</p>
<p>12.1.3 Color. These labels shall be fluorescent orange or         orange-red or predominantly so, with lettering or symbols in a contrasting color.</p>
<p>12.1.4 Location and Attachment. Required labels shall be affixed         as close as feasible to the container by string, wire, adhesive, or other method that         prevents their loss or unintentional removal.</p>
<p>12.1.5 Contaminated Equipment. Labels required for contaminated         equipment shall be in accordance with this paragraph and shall also state which portions         of the equipment remain contaminated.</p>
<p>12.1.6 Color Coding In Place of Labels. Red bags or red         containers may be substituted for labels.</p>
<p>12.1.7 Exemption for Blood Products. Containers of blood, blood         components, or blood products that are labeled as to their contents and have been released         for transfusion or other clinical use are exempted from the these labeling requirements.</p>
<p>12.1.8 Exemption for Inner Packaging. Individual containers of         blood or other potentially infectious materials that are placed in a labeled container         during storage, transport, shipment or disposal are exempted from these labeling         requirements.</p>
<p>12.1.9 Exemption for Decontaminated Waste. Regulated waste that         has been decontaminated need not be labeled or color-coded.</p>
<p>12.2 Signs.</p>
<p>12.2.1 Location. Signs shall be posted at the entrance to HIV and         HBV Research Laboratory and Production Facilities, which shall bear the legend BIOHAZARD         (see figure 1 in appendix 2). In addition the following information shall be included on         the sign:</p>
<p>12.2.1.1 The name of the Infectious Agent</p>
<p>12.2.1.2 Special requirements for entering the area</p>
<p>12.2.1.3 The name and telephone number of the laboratory director           or other responsible person.</p>
<p>12.2.2 Color. These signs shall be fluorescent orange-red or         predominantly so, with lettering or symbols in a contrasting color.</p>
<p>12.3 Information and Training. All employees with occupational       exposure shall participate in a training program which must be provided at no cost to the       employee and during working hours.</p>
<p>Training shall be provided as follows:</p>
<p>12.3.1 When. At the time of initial assignment to tasks where         occupational exposure may take place; or within 90 days after the effective date of the         standard.</p>
<p>12.3.2 Refresher Training. Followup training shall be provided at         least annually.</p>
<p>12.3.3 New Tasks. Additional training shall be provided when         changes such as modification of tasks or procedures or institution of new tasks or         procedures affect the employee's occupational exposure. The additional training may be         limited to addressing the new exposures created.</p>
<p>12.3.4 Content. Material appropriate in content and vocabulary to         educational level, literacy, and language of employees shall be used. The training program         shall contain at a minimum the following elements:</p>
<p>12.3.4.1 An accessible copy of the regulatory text of the           Bloodborne Pathogen Standard and an explanation of its contents;</p>
<p>12.3.4.2 A general explanation of the epidemiology and symptoms           of bloodborne diseases;</p>
<p>12.3.4.3 An explanation of the modes of transmission of           bloodborne pathogens;</p>
<p>12.3.4.4 An explanation of the exposure control plan and the           means by which the employee can obtain a copy of the written plan;</p>
<p>12.3.4.5 An explanation of the appropriate methods for           recognizing tasks and other activities that may involve exposure to blood and other           potentially infectious materials;</p>
<p>12.3.4.6 An explanation of the use and limitations of methods           that will prevent or reduce exposure including appropriate engineering controls, work           practices, and personal protective equipment;</p>
<p>12.3.4.7 Information on the types, proper use, location, removal,           handling, decontamination and disposal of personal protective equipment;</p>
<p>12.3.4.8 An explanation of the basis for selection of personal           protective equipment;</p>
<p>12.3.4.9 Information on the hepatitis B vaccine, including           information on its efficacy, safety, method of administration, the benefits of being           vaccinated, and that the vaccine and vaccination will be offered free of charge;</p>
<p>12.3.4.10 Information on the appropriate actions to take and           persons to contact in an emergency involving blood or other potentially infectious           materials;</p>
<p>12.3.4.11 An explanation of the procedure to follow if an           exposure incident occurs, including the method of reporting the incident and the medical           follow-up that will be made available;</p>
<p>12.3.4.12 Information on the post-exposure evaluation and           follow-up that BYU-Idaho is required to provide for the employee following an exposure           incident;</p>
<p>12.3.4.13 An explanation of the signs and labels and/or color           coding used at Ricks;</p>
<p>12.3.4.14 An opportunity for interactive questions and answers           with the person conducting the training session.</p>
<p>12.3.5 Trainer. The person conducting the training shall be         knowledgeable in the subject matter covered by the elements contained in the training         program as it relates to the workplace that the training will address.</p>
<p>12.3.6 Additional Training in Research Laboratories. Additional         Initial Training for Employees in HIV and HBV Laboratories and Production Facilities.         Employees in HIV or HBV research laboratories and HIV or HBV production facilities shall         receive the following initial training in addition to the above training requirements.</p>
<p>12.3.6.1 BYU-Idaho shall assure that employees demonstrate           proficiency in standard microbiological practices and techniques and in the practices and           operations specific to the facility before being allowed to work with HIV or HBV.</p>
<p>12.3.6.2 BYU-Idaho shall assure that employees have prior           experience in the handling of human pathogens or tissue cultures before working with HIV           or HBV.</p>
<p>12.3.6.3 BYU-Idaho shall provide a training program to           employees who have no prior experience in handling human pathogens. Initial work           activities shall not include the handling of infectious agents. A progression of work           activities shall be assigned as techniques are learned and proficiency is developed. The           supervisor shall assure that employees participate in work activities involving infectious           agents only after proficiency has been demonstrated.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of           Contents</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a name="13 Record Keeping.">13.0 Record Keeping.</a></strong></p>
<p>13.1 Medical Records. BYU-Idaho shall establish and maintain       an accurate record for each employee with occupational exposure, in accordance with 29 CFR       1910.20. This record shall include:</p>
<p>13.1.1 Identification. The name and social security number of the         employee;</p>
<p>13.1.2 Vaccination Status. A copy of the employee's hepatitis B         vaccination status including the dates of all the hepatitis B vaccinations and any medical         records relative to the employee's ability to receive vaccination as indicated in 11.4;</p>
<p>13.1.3 Examinations. A copy of all results of examinations,         medical testing, and follow-up procedures as required by section 11;</p>
<p>13.1.4 Written Opinion. The employer's copy of the healthcare         professional's written opinion.</p>
<p>13.1.5 Information Provided to Health Care Professional. A copy         of the information provided to the healthcare professional as required by section 11.</p>
<p>13.1.6 Confidentiality. BYU-Idaho shall insure that Employee         medical records required by this section:</p>
<p>13.1.6.1 Are kept confidential; and</p>
<p>13.1.6.2 Are not disclosed or reported without the employee's           express written consent to any person within or outside the workplace except as required           by this section or as may be required by law.</p>
<p>13.1.7 Maintenance of Records. BYU-Idaho shall maintain the         records required by this section for at least the duration of employment plus 30 years in         accordance with 29 CFR 1910.20.</p>
<p>13.1.8 Availability. Employee medical records required by this         section shall be provided upon request for examination and copying to the subject         employee, and to anyone having written consent of the subject employee.</p>
<p>13.2 Training Records.</p>
<p>13.2.1 Required Information in Training Records. Training records         shall include the following information:</p>
<p>13.2.1.1 The dates of the training sessions;</p>
<p>13.2.1.2 The contents or a summary of the training sessions;</p>
<p>13.2.1.3 The names and qualifications of persons conducting the           training; and</p>
<p>13.2.1.4 The names and job titles of all persons attending the           training sessions.</p>
<p>13.2.2 Record Retention. Training records shall be maintained for         3 years from the date on which the training occurred.</p>
<p>13.2.3 Availability of Records. Employee training records         required by this section shall be provided upon request for examination and copying to         employees, to employee representatives, to the Director, and to the Assistant Secretary in         accordance with 29 CFR 1910.20.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
