<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67600" Name="Chemical Appendix 6" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Chemical Appendix 6</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Chemical Appendix 6</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left" style="text-align: center;"><strong>Appendix 6 - Handling Procedures for Some Common       Particularly Hazardous Substances </strong></p>
<p>This section outlines special handling procedures       for some specific particularly hazardous substances that may be used in Chemistry       Department laboratories. The information presented in this section is not meant to be       complete, and faculty should consult the appropriate literature and their laboratory       supervisor before working with these particularly hazardous substances.</p>
<p>(<strong>1) Acrylonitrile </strong><br /> Acrylonitrile is regulated as a human carcinogen by OSHA and also is listed as a substance       with a high degree of acute toxicity. The PEL (permissible exposure limit) is 2 ppm as an       8-hour time-weighted average or 10 ppm as averaged over any 15-min period. Dermal or eye       contact with liquid acrylonitrile is also prohibited. Work involving significant       quantities of acrylonitrile should be conducted using the general procedures outlined in       both Parts VI-C and VI-D. Laboratory hoods that have been demonstrated to provide       sufficient protection should be used, and closed systems are recommended for laboratory       operation.</p>
<p><strong>(2) Benzene </strong><br /> In humans, acute inhalation exposure to benzene can produce a picture of acute delirium,       characterized by excitement, euphoria, and restlessness and, if the exposure is       significantly high, the symptoms may progress to depression, drowsiness, stupor, and even       unconsciousness. The concentration required to produce this symptom complex is 1000 ppm or       higher. These concentrations will also produce irritation of the eye, nose, and       respiratory tract. Chronic inhalation exposure to 25-50 ppm of benzene can produce changes       in the blood picture that include macrocytosis, decrease in the total red blood count,       decrease in platelets, decrease in the hemoglobin concentration, or decrease in       leukocytes. Any or all of these hematologic effects may be seen in any individual.       Usually, the worker will be asymptomatic while these effects are observed in the blood       picture. Continued exposure at somewhat higher concentrations (probably more than 100 ppm)       can insidiously result in more severe blood disorders that include leukopenia or even       aplastic anemia, with symptoms of headaches, dizziness, loss of appetite, nervousness,       irritability, and perhaps bleeding manifestations, i.e., nosebleeds, easy bruisability, or       hematuria. Severe cases may have fatal outcomes. Recently, a number or reports have been       published that describe leukemia in workers who have had aplastic anemia. These cases have       been reported in Italy and Turkey in workers exposed to grossly high concentrations of       benzene. In addition, there is some indication that an excess of leukemia may occur       without a preceding picture of aplastic anemia in workers who have been repeatedly exposed       to benzene at concentrations of more than 100 ppm.</p>
<p>The current OSHA PEL for benzene is 1 ppm as an       8-hour time-weighted average (TWA), 25 ppm for a ceiling concentration for time period       such that the 8-hour TWA is not exceeded, and a peak above the ceiling at 50 ppm for no       more than 10 min. Benzene is a flammable liquid and should not be exposed to heat or       flame. An explosion hazard also exists when its vapors are exposed to flame. Benzene may       react vigorously with oxidizing agents such as bromine pentafluoride, chlorine, chromic       acid, nitryl perchlorate, oxygen, ozone, perchlorates, aluminum chloride plus fluorine       perchlorate, sulfuric acid plus permanganates, potassium peroxide, silver perchlorate plus       acetic acid, and sodium peroxide.</p>
<p>Experiments involving the use of benzene should be       conducted employing the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C; all operations in which       there is the possibility of the accidental release of harmful quantities of benzene should       be carried out in a designated area.</p>
<p><strong>(3) Bis(chloromethyl)ether (BCME),       Chloromethyl Methyl Ether, and Other Chloromethyl Ether Derivatives <br /> </strong>Because of the high volatility of bis(chloromethyl)ether (BCME), inhalation is       the route of exposure that presents the greatest hazard to humans. BCME vapor is severely       irritating to the skin and mucous membranes and can cause corneal damage that heals       slowly. The substance has caused lung cancer in humans. BCME is highly toxic to animals       via inhalation: LD50 (rats, 7-hour inhalation) = 7 ppm. It is moderately toxic via the       oral and skin routes:LD50 (rats, oral) =280 mg/kg; LD50 (rabbits, skin) =368 mg/kg. Its       vapors are strongly irritant to the eyes of rats. Rats and hamsters subjected to 10 or 30,       6-hour exposures of 1 ppm BCME showed evidence of tracheal and bronchial hyperplasia, as       well as effects on the central nervous system. BCME is carcinogenic to mice following       inhalation, skin application, or subcutaneous administration. In mice, it is carcinogenic       by inhalation and subcutaneous administration. BCME is a lung carcinogen in humans.</p>
<p>The TLV for BCME is 0.001 ppm (1 ppb; 5 mg/m3). The       substance is classified by ACGIH as a human carcinogen. OSHA has classified BCME as a       cancer-suspect agent and has stringent regulations (29 CFR 1910.1008) for its use if its       concentration in a material exceeds 0.1%. Work involving chloromethyl ether derivatives       must be carried out using the general procedures outlined in Parts VI-C and VI-D.</p>
<p><strong>(4) Carbon Monoxide <br /> </strong>Carbon Monoxide is a direct and cumulative poison. It combines with the       hemoglobin of the blood to form a relatively stable compound, carboxyhemoglobin, and       renders if useless as an oxygen carrier. When about one-third of the hemoglobin has       entered into such combination, the victim dies. The gas is a treacherous poison because of       its odorless character and insidious action. Exposure to 1500-2000 ppm CO in air for 1       hour is dangerous, and exposure to 4000 ppm is fatal in less than 1 hour. Headache and       dizziness are the usual symptoms of CO poisoning, but occasionally the first evidence of       poisoning is the collapse of the patient.</p>
<p>Carbon monoxide should be used only in areas that       have adequate ventilation employing the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C. A trap       or vacuum break should always be used to prevent impurities from being sucked back into a       CO cylinder.</p>
<p><strong>(5) Carbon Tetrachloride</strong> <br /> The current OSHA PEL for carbon tetrachloride is 2 ppm as an 8-hour time-weighted average.       The current TLV for carbon tetrachloride is 5 ppm. Carbon tetrachloride is suspected to       have carcinogenic potential in humans. ACGIH also states that skin contact may account for       a substantial part of toxic responses.</p>
<p>The carcinogenic potency of carbon tetrachloride is       low and in most of its uses in Chemistry Department laboratories it need not be treated as       a particularly hazardous substance. In cases where large quantities of carbon       tetrachloride are in frequent use, then the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C       should provide adequate protection. All operations should be carried out in a hood, not       only because of the carcinogenicity of the substance, but also because of its other toxic       effects and its volatility. Nitrile rubber is the recommended material for gloves and       other protective clothing.</p>
<p><strong>(6) Chlorine <br /> </strong>Chlorine is classified as a substance with a high degree of acute toxicity.       Humans can generally detect the odor of chlorine at about 0.3 ppm. Minimal irritation of       the throat and nose are noticed at about 2.6 ppm and painful irritation at about 3.0 ppm;       at a range of 2.6-41.0 ppm, a group of "trained industrial hygienists" noted       "strong irritation." The subjective response to chlorine is less pronounced with       prolonged exposure. Experimentally determined responses to chlorine by humans are not very       consistent. Throat irritation occurs at about 6.6-15 ppm. However, an exposure for medical       purposes of a large number of humans to 5-7 ppm for 1 hour did not result in serious or       long-term consequences. Exposure to about 17 ppm causes coughing, and levels as low as 10       ppm may cause lung edema. Chronic effects on humans from long-term low-level exposures       have been well documented. Animal exposures have indicated that prolonged exposure to       approximately 1.7 ppm for 1 hour per day may cause deterioration in the nutritional state,       blood alteration, and decreased resistance to disease. The TLV and the OSHA PEL are 0.5       ppm (1.5 mg/m) TWA over eight hours. NIOSH has recommended a ceiling limit of 0.5 ppm over       any 15-min period. The ACGIH 15-min exposure limit is 3 ppm.</p>
<p>Chlorine should be kept away from easily oxidized       materials. Chlorine reacts readily with many organic chemicals, sometimes with explosive       violence. Because of the high toxicity of chlorine, laboratory operations using it must be       carried out in a hood employing the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C.</p>
<p><strong>(7) Chloroform</strong></p>
<p>Inhalation exposure to chloroform at concentrations       greater than 1000 ppm can produce dizziness, nausea, and headaches. At higher       concentrations, there can be disorientation and delirium progressing to unconsciousness.       Such high exposure can also produce liver and possibly kidney damage. It is believed that       chloroform can sensitize the heart to adrenaline, causing cardiac arrhythmias and possibly       death. High concentrations of the vapor can produce conjunctivitis. Liquid chloroform in       the eyes will produce a painful corneal injury that usually heals in several days. Chronic       exposure to chloroform at concentrations of 100-200 ppm has been reported to produce large       livers. Continued contact with the skin can produce drying , fissuring, and inflammation.       In experimental studies, prolonged ingestion of high levels of chloroform by mice resulted       in liver cancers and by rats, kidney tumors.</p>
<p>Although the fire hazard of chloroform is slight,       exposure to heat or flame can result in generation of phosgene gas. Chloroform reacts       violently with acetone plus a base, aluminum, disilane, lithium, magnesium, nitrogen       tetroxide, potassium, perchloric acid plus phosphorus pentoxide, potassium hydroxide plus       methanol, potassium tert-butoxide, sodium, sodium hydroxide plus methanol, sodium       methylate, or sodium hydride.</p>
<p>The current OSHA PEL for chloroform is 2 ppm as an       8-hour time-weighted average. The ACGIH currently recommends that chloroform be treated as       a suspect human carcinogen and recommends an 8-hour time-weighted average exposure of 10       ppm. Although chloroform has caused tumors in animals, its potency is low. In most of its       uses in the Chemistry Department it need not be treated as a particularly hazardous       substance. In cases where significant quantities of chloroform are in frequent use, the       general procedures outlined in Part VI-C should provide adequate protection. The high       volatility of chloroform emphasizes the importance of a hood for such operations.       Polyvinyl alcohol gloves provide the best hand protection.</p>
<p><strong>(8) Dimethyl and Diethyl Sulfate<br /> </strong>Many cases of dimethyl sulfate poisoning have been reported. The common initial       symptoms are headache and giddiness, with burning of the eyes. The patient's condition may       worsen, with painful eyes, nose and throat irritation, loss of voice, coughing, difficult       in breathing and swallowing, vomiting, and diarrhea possible. The onset of the symptoms       may be delayed up to 10 hours. Skin contact causes blistering and necrosis, and DMS can be       absorbed through the skin in sufficient quantity to cause systemic intoxication. In the       worst cases, there is severe inflammation of the mucous membranes and pulmonary injury       that may be fatal; several deaths have occurred. For example, exposure to 97 ppm for 10       min was fatal. DMS is moderately toxic to animals via the oral route: LD50 (rats) = 440       mg/kg. Undiluted DMS produced moderate to severe irritation when applied to the skin of       guinea pigs; 1% DMS produced mild irritation. DMS does not cause skin sensitization in       animals. Undiluted DMS applied to rabbit eyes produced severe injury. Even a 1-hour       exposure to 58 ppm has resulted in permanent eye damage in rats. During a 4-hour exposure,       30 ppm DMS killed five out of six rats, but 15 ppm was not lethal.</p>
<p>DMS has been shown to be carcinogenic in the rat by       inhalation, subcutaneous injection, and following 1 hour per day exposures to 10 ppm DMS       for 130 days. The TLV for DMS is 0.1 ppm (0.5 mg/m3) as an 8-hour time-weighted average.       DMS is classified as being suspected of carcinogenic potential in humans by the ACGIH. The       OSHA PEL for DMS is 0.5 ppm. These limits include a warning of the potential contribution       of skin absorption to the overall exposure.</p>
<p>The general procedures outlined in Part VI-D should       be used when handling more than a few grams of DMS in view of its fairly high carcinogenic       potency in rats by inhalation and its ability to penetrate the skin. It is particularly       important to avoid skin contact by appropriate use of rubber gloves, a rubber apron, and       other protective apparel, and to avoid inhalation of even low concentrations of vapor by       working in a hood. Operations involving smaller quantities of DMS can be conducted using       the general procedures presented in Part VI-C.</p>
<p><strong>(9) Ethylene Dibromide (1,2-Dibromoethane)</strong> <br /> Ethylene dibromide (EDB) is classified as a compound with a high degree of acute toxicity;       the approximate oral lethal dose of EDB for humans is 5 ml. Skin absorption of EDB can       also cause death, and inhalation of the vapor can produce pulmonary edema. EDB can cause       severe irritation to all exposed tissues, respiratory tract, skin, and eye. Systemic       effects include central nervous system depression, kidney injury, and severe liver       necrosis. Ethylene dibromide is highly toxic to animals via inhalation.</p>
<p>The maximum survival exposure of rats to EDB vapors       in air are 3000 ppm for 6 min, 400 ppm for 30 min, and 200 ppm for 2 hours. It is       moderately toxic via the oral and skin routes: LD50 (rats, oral) = 140 mg/kg; LD50       (rabbits, skin) = 300 mg/kg. EDB is markedly irritating to skin, and a 10% solution has       caused serious but reversible corneal injury in rabbit eyes. Rats were repeatedly exposed       to 50 ppm EDB for 6 months. Half died from pneumonia and upper respiratory tract tumors       (squamous-cell carcinomas of the forestomach) in mice and rats following oral       administration. The 1979 TLV for EDB was 20 ppm (155 mg/m3) as an 8-hour time-weighted       average. The exposure limit is 30 ppm over any 15-min period. These limits include a       warning about the potential contribution of skin absorption to the overall exposure. In       1980, the ACGIH put EDB in category A 1b (human carcinogen). For this category, there is       no assigned TLV, but the ACGIH recommends that those working with A 1b carcinogens should       be properly equipped to ensure maximum peak is 50 ppm for 5 min in any 8-hour time period.</p>
<p>On the basis of the carcinogenicity data for EDB,       the procedures described in Part VI-D should be followed when handling more than a few       grams in the laboratory. Operations involving smaller quantities should be carried out       using the procedures outlined in Part VI-C. Serious skin injury can occur from direct       exposure to EDB. The substance can penetrate neoprene and several other types of plastic;       therefore, gloves and other protective apparel of these materials provide only temporary       protection if EDB spills on them.</p>
<p>(10) Hydrazine<br /> Hydrazine is classified as a compound with a high degree of acute toxicity; exposure to       its vapors can cause respiratory tract irritation, excitement, convulsion, cyanosis, and       decrease in blood pressure. The liquid can severely burn the eyes and skin. Hydrazine can       cause fatty degeneration of the liver, nephritis, and hemolysis. Hydrazine is moderately       toxic to animals via the inhalation, oral, and skin routes: LC50 (rats, 4-hour inhalation)       = 570 ppm; LD50 (rats, oral) = 60 mg/kg; LD50 (rabbits, skin) = 283 mg/kg (hydrazine       hydrate). It is a strong skin and mucous membrane irritant and a strong skin sensitizer.       Hydrazine hydrate produced moderately severe irritation when applied to rabbit eyes. After       repeated oral, skin, or injection exposure, the effects noted include weight loss,       weakness, vomiting, and convulsions. The chief histological finding is fatty degeneration       of the liver.</p>
<p>Among guinea pigs and dogs exposed to hydrazine in       the air 5-47 times, the dogs showed liver damage, with lesser damage to the kidneys and       lungs, while the guinea pigs had pneumonitis and partial lung collapse.</p>
<p>Hydrazine and hydrazine salts have been shown to be       carcinogenic in mice after oral and intraperitoneal administration and in rats following       oral dosing. By the oral route, effects were found at doses of 24-36 (mg/kg)/day in mice       and 20 (mg/kg)/day in rats. No tumors were observed in Syrian golden hamsters after oral       administration. The ACGIH has classified hydrazine as suspected of carcinogenic potential       in humans. The TLV for hydrazine is 0.1 ppm (0.1 mg/m3) and the OSHA PEL is 0.1 ppm (0.1       mg/m3) as 8-hour time-weighted averages. These limits include a warning about the       potential contribution of skin absorption to the overall exposure. The NIOSH has (1978)       recommended a ceiling limit of 0.03 ppm in any 2-hour period.</p>
<p>When more than a few grams of hydrazine are to be       used in the laboratory, the general procedures outlined in both Parts VI-C and VI-D should       be used because hydrazine is carcinogenic in animal tests, quite volatile, and readily       absorbed through the skin. Nitrile rubber is recommended for gloves and other protective       apparel. Prompt washing with water effectively removes hydrazine from skin that it has       splashed on. Hydrazine should not be used in the vicinity of a flame or under conditions       where sparks can occur, as an explosion or fire can result.</p>
<p><strong>(11) Hydrogen Bromide and Hydrogen Chloride<br /> </strong>Both hydrogen bromide (HBr) and hydrogen chloride (HCL) are toxic gases which are       severely irritating to the upper respiratory tract. The acids formed neutralize the alkali       of the tissues and can cause death as a result of edema or spasm of the larynx and       inflammation of the upper respiratory system. Concentrations of 0.13-0.2% are lethal for       human beings in exposures lasting a few minutes. However, because of their odor, usually       these gases provide adequate warning for prompt voluntary withdrawal from contaminated       atmospheres. These gases are also corrosive to the skin and mucous membranes and can cause       severe burns. Exposure to high concentrations may also result in dermatitis. Contact with       the eyes rapidly causes severe irritation of the eyes and eyelids.</p>
<p>Hydrogen bromide and hydrogen chloride are corrosive       gases that have pungent, irritating odors. Although both are colorless, they fume in moist       air because of their high solubility in water. In a cylinder under pressure, both exist in       the form of a gas over a liquid (under such conditions, the cylinder pressure is equal to       the vapor pressure of the substance contained; at 25o C, this is 4.22 MPa (613 lb/in.2 for       HCL and 2.20 MPa (320 lb/in.2 for HBr). As long as liquid is present in the cylinder, the       pressure will remain fairly constant. Although neither HBr nor HCl is combustible, both       react with common metals to form hydrogen, which may form explosive mixtures with air.</p>
<p>Operations involving significant quantities of       hydrogen bromide and hydrogen chloride should be conducted using the general procedures       outlined in Part VI-C. Laboratory workers should wear protective apparel, including rubber       gloves, suitable gas-tight chemical safety goggles, and clothing such as a rubber or       plastic apron. Proper respiratory equipment should be available. These gases should be       handled only in adequately ventilated areas. A check valve, vacuum break, or trap should       always be used to prevent foreign materials from being sucked back into the cylinder       because this can cause the development of dangerous pressures. Leaks of HBr and HCl will       be evident by the formation of dense white fumes on contact with the atmosphere. Small       leaks of HCl can be detected by holding an open bottle of concentrated ammonium hydroxide       near the site of the suspected leak; the formation of dense white fumes confirms the       existence of a leak. Cylinder-valve leaks can usually be corrected by tightening the valve       packing nut (by turning it clockwise as viewed from above).</p>
<p><strong>(12) Hydrogen Cyanide<br /> </strong>Prior approval from the Chemical Hygiene Committee is required before using       hydrogen cyanide (see Part VII).</p>
<p><strong>(13) Hydrofluoric Acid <br /> </strong>The use of anhydrous hydrogen fluoride requires prior approval from the Chemical       Hygiene Committee. All forms - dilute or concentrated solutions or the vapor - of       hydrofluoric acid (HF) cause severe burns. Inhalation of anhydrous HF or HF mist or vapors       can cause severe respiratory tract irritation that may be fatal. Death from pulmonary       edema occurred within 2 hours in three of six workers splashed with 70% HF solution       despite prompt showering with water. Anhydrous HF is a clear, colorless liquid that boils       at 19.5o C. Because of its low boiling point and high vapor pressure, anhydrous HF must be       stored in pressure containers. A 70% aqueous solution is a common form of HF. Hydrofluoric       acid is miscible with water in all proportions and forms an azeotrope (38.3% HF) that       boils at 112o C. Anhydrous or concentrated aqueous HF causes immediate and serious burns       to any part of the body. Dilute solutions (&lt;30%) and gaseous HF are also harmful,       although several hours may pass before redness or a burning sensation is noticed. These       burns may still by quite severe and progressively damaging to the skin and deeper tissues.       "Undissociated HF readily penetrates skin and deep tissue where the corrosive       fluoride ion can cause necrosis of soft tissues and decalcification of bone; the       destruction produced is excruciatingly painful. Fluoride ion also attacks enzymes (e.g. of       glycolysis) and cell membranes. The process of tissue destruction and neutralization of       the hydrofluoric acid is prolonged for days, unlike other acids that are rapidly       neutralized. Because of the insidious manner of penetration, a relatively mild or minor       exposure can cause a serious burn" [Proctor, N. H.; Hughes, J. P.; Fischman, M. L.       Chemical Hazards of the Workplace, J. B. Lippincott Co., Philadelphia, 1988, p.279].       Occasionally workers fail to recognize the importance of seeking medical attention for HF       before pain commences. By the time the victim is affected with progressively deep and more       painful throbbing and burning, serious damage may have taken place. Exposures under       fingernails can be a particularly painful problem if ignored. Wearing clothing (including       leather shoes and gloves) that has absorbed small amounts of HF can result in serious       delayed effects such as painful slow-healing skin ulcers.</p>
<p>When handling HF, it is crucial to ensure adequate       ventilation by working only in a hood so that safe levels (3 ppm) are not exceeded. All       contact of the vapor of the liquid with eyes, skin, respiratory system, or digestive       system must be avoided by using protective equipment such as a face shield and neoprene or       polyvinyl chloride gloves. The protective equipment should be washed after each use to       remove any HF on it. Safety showers and eyewash fountains should be nearby. Anyone working       with HF should have received prior instructions about its hazards and in proper protective       measures and should know the recommended procedure for treatment in the event of exposure       (Reinhardt, C.F&gt; et al.; Am. Ind. Hyg. Assn. J., 1966, 27, 166.)</p>
<p>Spills and leaks - The vapors of both anhydrous HF       and aqueous 70% HF produce visible fumes if they contact moist air. This characteristic       can be useful in detecting leaks but cannot be relied on because of atmospheric       variations. Spills of HF must be treated immediately to minimize the dangers of vapor       inhalation, body contact, corrosion of equipment, and possible generation of hazardous       gases. Spills should be contained and diluted with water. The resulting solution should be       neutralized with lime before disposal.</p>
<p>Waste disposal - Waste HF should be slowly added to       a larger volume of a stirred solution of slaked lime to precipitate calcium fluoride,       which is chemically inert and poses little toxic hazard (sodium fluoride is highly soluble       and toxic). Alternatively, hydrofluoric acid can be diluted to about 2% concentration with       cold water in a polyethylene vessel, neutralized with aqueous sodium hydroxide, and       treated with excess calcium chloride solution to precipitate calcium fluoride.</p>
<p>In the event of exposure - Anyone who knows or even       suspects that he or she has come into direct contact with HF should immediately flush the       exposed area with large quantities of cool water. Exposed clothing should be removed as       quickly as possible while flushing. Medical attention should be obtained promptly, even if       the injury appears slight. On the way to the physician, the burned area should be immersed       in a mixture of ice and water. If immersion is impractical, a compress made by inserting       ice cubes between layers of gauze should be used. Make sure that the physician understands       that the injury was cause by HF and requires treatment very different from other acid       burns. Even in the case of very small exposure, washing alone may not be sufficient to       completely prevent injury. For minor exposures such as small hole in glove, application of       a calcium glutaconate antidote gel can bind free fluoride ion not removed by washing.</p>
<p>If HF liquid or vapor has contacted the eyes, these       organs should be flushed with large quantities of clean water while the eyelids are held       apart. This flushing should be continued for 15 minutes. Medical attention should be       obtained promptly.</p>
<p>Anyone who has inhaled HF vapor should be removed       immediately to an uncontaminated atmosphere and kept warm. Medical help should be obtained       promptly. Anyone who has ingested HF should drink a large quantity of water as quickly as       possible. Do not induce vomiting. Again, medical help should be obtained promptly. After       the acid has been thoroughly diluted with water, if medical attention is delayed, the       person should be given milk or two fluid ounces of milk of magnesia to drink to sooth the       burning effect.</p>
<p><strong>(14) Hydrogen Sulfide <br /> </strong>Hydrogen sulfide is extremely dangerous. Human exposure to relatively low       concentrations of H2S has caused corneal damage, headache, sleep disturbances, nausea,       weight loss, and other symptoms suggestive of brain damage. Higher concentrations can       cause irritation of the lungs and respiratory passages and even pulmonary edema. Exposure       to 210 ppm for 20 min has caused unconsciousness, arm cramps, and low blood pressure. Coma       may occur within seconds after one or two breaths at high concentrations and be followed       rapidly by death. For example, workers exposed to 930 ppm H2S for less than 1 min died.       Hydrogen sulfide is moderately toxic to animals via the inhalation route: LC50 (mice, 1       hour) = 673 ppm; LC50 (mice, 7.5 hours) = 140 ppm. Exposure to 10-13 ppm for 4-7 hours has       caused eye irritation. Skin absorption of H2S is slight and not</p>
<p>considered significant. However, prolonged or       repeated skin contact might cause mild irritation. Guinea pigs that had 0.78 in2 of their       skin exposed to 100% H2S vapors for 1 hour experienced slight swelling. The TLV and PEL       for H2S is 10 ppm (14 mg/m3) as an 8-hour time-weighted average and 15 ppm as a short-term       exposure limit. NIOSH (1977) has recommended a 10-min ceiling of 10 ppm.</p>
<p>Partly because of the disagreeable odor of H2S, but       also because of its toxicity, laboratory operations with it should be carried out in a       hood. Use the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C when working with hydrogen sulfide.       Cylinders of it should not be stored in small, unventilated rooms, as deaths have resulted       from people entering such rooms containing a leaking cylinder.</p>
<p><strong>(15) Nickel Carbonyl</strong> <br /> The use of nickel carbonyl requires prior approval from the Chemistry Department Chemical       Hygiene Committee (see part VII).</p>
<p><strong>(16) Nitrogen Dioxide</strong><br /> Nitrogen dioxide (NO2) is classified as a highly acute toxin; it is a primary irritant,       acting primarily on the lungs and to a lesser extent on the upper respiratory tract. It is       certainly one of the most insidious of the gases. The inflammation of the lungs may cause       only slight pain, but the edema that results may easily cause death. One hundred ppm of       NO2 in air is a dangerous concentration for even a short exposure, and 200 ppm may be       fatal in a short time. Nitrogen dioxide is reddish brown, has an irritating odor, and must       be avoided by the use of an air-purifying respirator equipped with an acid-gas cartridge       or canister; at concentrations greater than 50 times the TLV, a positive-pressure       atmosphere-supplying respirator must be used and, in IDLH atmospheres, a pressure-demand       self-contained breathing apparatus or a positive-pressure air-line respirator that has       escape-cylinder provisions is required.</p>
<p>Nitrogen dioxide should be handled using the general       procedures outlined in Part VI-C. Nitrogen dioxide is a deadly poison, and no one should       work with a cylinder of this substance unless they are fully familiar with its handling       and its toxic effect. Ventilation is extremely important, and respiratory protective       equipment should always be available. Only stainless steel fittings should be used.</p>
<p><strong>(17) Mercury <br /> </strong>The element of mercury is a liquid metal with a vapor pressure of 0.00185 mm at       25o C. This corresponds to a saturation concentration of 20 mg of mercury per cubic meter       of air or 2.4 ppm of air. The American Conference of Governmental Industrial Hygienists       has established a threshold limit for mercury vapor of 0.05 mg of mercury per cubic meter       of air for continuous 40-hour per week exposure. Long term chronic exposure to mercury       vapor in excess of 0.05 mg of mercury per cubic meter of air may result in cumulative       poisoning. The use of mercury in laboratory amounts in well-ventilated areas is fairly       safe; however special precautions must be followed when working with large quantities of       mercury.</p>
<p>Mercury poisoning from exposure by chronic       inhalation produces a variety of symptoms. The characteristic effects are emotional       disturbances, unsteadiness, inflammation of the mouth and gums, general fatigue, memory       loss, and headaches. Kidney damage may result from poisoning by mercurial salts. In most       cases of exposure by chronic inhalation, the symptoms of poisoning gradually disappear       when the source of exposure is removed. However, improvement may be slow and complete       recovery may take years. Skin contact with mercury compounds produces irritation and       various degrees of corrosion. Soluble mercury salts can be absorbed through the intact       skin and produce poisoning.</p>
<p>The general procedures outlined in Part VI-C should       be followed when working with large quantities of liquid mercury. Every effort should be       made to prevent spills of metallic mercury because the substance is extremely difficult       and time consuming to pick up. Droplets get into cracks and crevices, under table legs,       and under and into equipment. If spills are frequent and Hg is added to the general air       level, the combined concentration may exceed the allowable limits.</p>
<p>Storage - Containers of large quantities of mercury       should be kept closed and stored in secondary containers in a well-ventilated area. When       breakage of instruments or apparatus containing mercury is a possibility, the equipment       should be placed in an enameled or plastic tray or pan that can be cleaned easily and is       large enough to contain the Hg. Transfers of Hg from one container to another should be       carried out in a hood and over a catch tray or pan to confine any spills.</p>
<p>Cleanup of spills - Pools of metallic Hg can be       collected by suction by using an aspirator bulb or a vacuum device made from a filtering       flask, a rubber stopper, and several pieces of flexible and glass tubing. Alternatively,       mercury-spill cleanup kits are available commercially. When a large spill, pressure system       rupture, or heating of mercury is involved, the College Safety Officer (356-2457) will       survey the area and advise on the degree of hazard which may exist and necessary       preventive measures to be undertaken. If Hg has spilled on the floor, the workers involved       in cleanup and decontamination activities should wear shoe covers. When the cleanup is       complete, the shoe covers should be disposed of and the workers should thoroughly wash       their hands, arms, and face several times.</p>
<p>Waste Disposal - Significant quantities of metallic       Hg from spills or broken thermometers or other equipment, and contaminated Hg from       laboratory activities should be collected in thick-walled high-density polyethylene       bottles for reclamation. Rags, sponges, shoe covers, and such used in cleanup activities,       and broken thermometers containing small amounts of residual mercury, should be placed in       a sealed plastic bag, labeled, and disposed of in a safe manner.</p>
<p>(<strong>18) N-Nitrosodialkylamines and Certain       Other N-Nitroso Compounds <br /> </strong>N-Nitrosodimethylamine is strongly hepatotoxic and can cause death from liver       insufficiency in experimental animals. It is carcinogenic in at least 10 animal species,       including subprimates. The main targets for its carcinogenic activity are the liver, lung,       esophagus, trachea, and nasal cavity. Although data are not available on the toxicity of       N-nitrosodiethylamine in humans, the closely related compound N-nitrosodimethylamine has       caused extensive liver damage as a consequence of ingestion, inhalation, or topical       application to the skin.</p>
<p>The general procedures outlined in Parts VI-C and       Part VI-D should be followed when working with N-nitrosodialkylamines. All work with       N-nitrosodialkylamines should be carried out in a well-ventilated hood or in a glove box       equipped with HEPA filter. To the extent possible, all vessels that contain       N-nitrosodialkylamines should be kept closed. All work should be carried out in an       apparatus that is contained in or mounted above unbreakable pans that will contain any       spill. All containers should bear a label such as the following: CANCER-SUSPECT AGENT. All       personnel who handle the material should wear plastic, latex, or neoprene gloves and a       fully buttoned laboratory coat.</p>
<p>Storage - All bottles of N-nitrosodialkylamines       should be stored and transported within an unbreakable outer container; storage should be       in a ventilated storage cabinet (or in a hood).</p>
<p>Cleanup of spills and waste disposal - Because       N-nitrosodialkylamines are chemically stable under usual conditions, disposal is best       carried out by incineration. Contact the Safety Office to arrange for the disposal of       waste and contaminated materials. For incineration of liquid wastes, solutions should be       neutralized if necessary, filtered to remove solids, and put in closed polyethylene       containers for transport. All equipment should be thoroughly rinsed with solvent, which       should then be added to the liquid waste for incineration. Great care should be exercised       to prevent contamination of the outside of the solvent container. If possible, solid       wastes should be incinerated; if this is not possible, solid wastes from reaction mixtures       that may contain N-nitrosodialkylamines should be extracted and the extracts added to the       liquid waste. Similarly, any rags, paper and such that may be contaminated should be       incinerated. Contaminated solid material should be enclosed in sealed plastic bags that       are labeled CANCER-SUSPECT AGENT and with the name and amount of the carcinogen. The bags       should be stored in a well-ventilated area until they are incinerated. Spills of       N-nitrosodialkylamines can be absorbed by Celite R or commercial spill absorbent. After       the absorbent containing the major share of the nitrosamine has been picked up (avoid       dusts; do not sweep), the surface should be thoroughly cleaned with a strong detergent       solution. If a major spill occurs outside of a ventilated area, the room should be       evacuated, the Campus Police (911) should be contacted, and the cleanup operation should       be carried out by trained persons equipped with self-contained respirators. Those involved       in this operation should wear rubber gloves, laboratory coats, and plastic aprons or       equivalent protective apparel.</p>
<p><strong>(19) Phosgene</strong> <br /> Phosgene is classified as a substance with a high degree of acute toxicity. In humans, the       symptoms of overexposure to phosgene are dryness or a burning sensation in the throat,       numbness, vomiting, and bronchitis. An airborne concentration of 5 ppm may cause eye       irritation and coughing in a few minutes. The substance can cause severe lung injury in       1-2 min at a level of 20 ppm. Exposure to concentrations above 50 ppm is likely to be       fatal. Phosgene is extremely toxic to animals via inhalation. Thus 74% of a group of rats       died from exposure to 55-100 ppm for only 10 min. Liquid phosgene is likely to cause       severe skin burns and eye irritation. Pulmonary edema, bronchiolitis, and emphysema were       found in cats and guinea pigs exposed to 2.5-6.25 ppm of phosgene/day for 2-41 days. A       variety of animals exposed to 0.2 or 1.1 ppm for 5 hours per day also had pulmonary edema.       The TLV and the OSHA PEL for phosgene are 0.1 ppm (0.4 mg/m3) as an 8-hour TWA. NIOSH has       recommended a limit of 0.2 ppm over any 15-min period.</p>
<p>Laboratory operations involving phosgene require the       use of the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C. Work with phosgene should always be       carried out with water or dilute alkali. Note that for many applications phosgene can be       replaced by the less hazardous diphosgene and triphosgene.</p>
<p><strong>(20) Sodium Cyanide (and other cyanide       salts) <br /> </strong>Inorganic cyanide salts are classified as substances with a high degree of acute       toxicity. Sodium cyanide is among the fastest acting of all known poisons. The lethal oral       dose for humans is 200 mg. The symptoms of cyanide overdose include weakness, headache,       confusion, and, occasionally, nausea and vomiting. Higher doses may be followed by almost       instantaneous death. Solutions are irritating to the skin, nose, eyes, and cyanide is       absorbed through the skin. Sodium cyanide is highly toxic to animals via the oral route:       LD50 (rats) = 6.4 mg/kg. It can be corrosive to the skin and the eyes, for it is highly       alkaline. Sodium cyanide can also produce toxic symptoms via skin absorption and       inhalation. The TLV and OSHA PEL for cyanide are both 5 mg/m3 as an 8-hour TWA. These       limits include a warning of the potential contribution of skin absorption to the overall       exposure. In 1976, NIOSH recommended that the 5 mg/m3 limit be retained but that its basis       be changed from an 8-hour TWA to a 10-min ceiling.</p>
<p>Proper gloves should be worn when handling dry       sodium cyanide. Rubber gloves and splash proof goggles should be worn when substantial       amounts of sodium cyanide solution are used. Hydrolysis of sodium cyanide (and other       cyanide salts) by water or acid generates HCN which is extremely hazardous. Consequently,       cyanide salts should always be handled using the general procedures outlined in Part VI-C.       All reaction equipment in which cyanides are used or produced should be placed in or over       shallow pans so that spills or leaks will be contained. In the event of spills of HCN or       cyanide solutions, the contaminated area should be evacuated promptly and it should be       determined immediately whether anyone had been exposed to cyanide vapors or liquid splash.       Consideration should be given to the need for evacuating other parts of the building or       notifying other occupants that the spill has occurred. In general, it is usually best not       to attempt to dilute or absorb such spills if they occur in well-ventilated areas.</p>
<p>Detection - Hydrogen cyanide has a characteristic       odor that resembles that of bitter almonds, however, many people cannot smell it in low       concentrations, and this method of detection should not be relied on. Vapor-detector tubes       sensitive to 1 ppm of HCN are available commercially. The presence of free cyanide ion in       aqueous solution may be detected by treating an aliquot of the sample with ferrous sulfate       and an excess of sulfuric acid. A precipitate of Prussian blue indicates that free cyanide       ion is present.</p>
<p>Storage - Sodium cyanide and acids should not be       stored or transported together. An open bottle of NaCN can generate HCN in humid air, and       HCN may be liberated from spills of sodium cyanide solutions.</p>
<p>Waste disposal - Waste solutions containing cyanides       should be sealed in clearly marked bottles. Contact the Safety Office to arrange disposal       of these containers.</p>
<p>In the event of exposure - Anyone who has been       exposed to HCN should be removed from the contaminated atmosphere immediately. Any       contaminated clothing should be removed and the affected area deluged with water.       Emergency medical attention should be obtained immediately.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="x46454.xml">Chemical Hygiene Policy</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
