<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67642" Name="Lockout/Tagout Policy" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Lockout/Tagout Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Lockout/Tagout Policy</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>Reference: <a href="Documents/Admin_Offices/Facilities Management/Security and Safety/29 CFR 1910-147 Control of Hazardous Energy.pdf" target="_blank"> 29 CFR 1910.147</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></strong><a href="#1.0 PURPOSE"><br /> 1.0 Purpose</a><br /> <a href="#2.0 SCOPE">2.0 Scope</a><br /> <a href="#3.0 REFERENCES">3.0 References</a><br /> <a href="#4.0 Procedure">4.0 Procedure</a><br /> <a href="#5.0 General Rules">5.0 General Rules</a><br /> <a href="#6.0 Definitions">6.0 Definitions</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="1.0 PURPOSE">1.0 PURPOSE</a> </strong></p>
<p>The purpose of the Lockout/Tagout program at BYU-Idaho       is to       ensure that no injury to personnel or property damage occurs if an energy source is       improperly or accidentally energized or opened. This program identifies the training       requirements of all affected personnel so that the proper Lockout/Tagout procedures are       applied to all energy isolating devices. By following the correct procedures, the person       performing the maintenance or installation ensures that all equipment and/or facilities       are inoperable and safe to repair, alter, clean, inspect, or disassemble. This program       will also correlate the "Lockout" programs of outside servicing personnel and       ensure that they are informed of the BYU-Idaho Lockout/Tagout program.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="2.0 SCOPE">2.0 SCOPE</a></strong></p>
<p>2.1 This procedure applies to all  energized systems that might       unexpectedly, improperly, or accidentally be energized and cause  injury or property damage.&nbsp;       Systems included in this program include but not limited to:  electrical, steam, hydraulic, chemical, compressed air or gas, stored       (kinetic) or other .</p>
<p>2.2 Exceptions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>2.2.1 New construction</p>
<p>2.2.3 Electrical distribution systems, including related         equipment for communication or metering</p>
</blockquote>
<p>2.3 Servicing and/or maintenance which takes place during normal       production operations, except when:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>2.3.1 A bypass, guard or other safety device is removed, or, (b)         an employee is required to place any part of his/her body into an area of a machine or         piece of equipment where work is actually performed upon the material being processed, or         where an associated danger zone exists during a machine operating cycle.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>2.4 Cord and plug connected equipment which is unplugged and       under the exclusive control of the person performing the servicing or maintenance.</p>
<p>2.5 "Hot Tap" operations involving transmission and       distribution systems (provided other precautions are taken).</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="3.0 REFERENCES">3.0 REFERENCES</a></strong></p>
<p>3.1 Control of Hazardous Energy (Lockout/Tagout) - CFR 1910.147</p>
<p>3.2 Construction - CFR 1926.417</p>
<p>3.3 Power Transmission and Distribution - 29 CFR 1926.950(d)       (De-energizing lines and equipment); 29 CFR 1926.954 (Grounding for protection of       employees).</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><a name="4.0 Procedure"><strong>4.0</strong> <strong>Procedure</strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p>4.1 Determine what equipment or machinery needs to be       "locked out".</p>
<p>4.2 A competent person should make a survey to locate and       identify all energy isolating devices to be certain that these devices apply to the       equipment to be "locked out".</p>
<p>4.3 Determine which personnel are affected if an energy source is       improperly or accidentally energized or opened.</p>
<p>4.4 If an energy isolating device is not capable of being locked       out, a tag only shall be used, and then other means shall be taken to ensure adequate       protection for affected personnel.</p>
<p>4.5 Sequence of Lockout/Tagout</p>
<blockquote>
<p>4.5.1 Notify all affected employees that a lockout/tagout is         going to be utilized.</p>
<p>4.5.2 If the machine or equipment is operating, shut it down by         the normal stopping procedure (depress stop button, open toggle switch, etc.).</p>
<p>4.5.3 Operate the switch, valve or other energy isolating         device(s) so that the equipment is isolated from its energy source(s). Stored energy must         be dissipated or restrained by methods such as repositioning, blocking, bleeding down etc.</p>
<p>4.5.4 Lockout and Tagout the energy isolating devices with         assigned individual lock(s) and tag(s).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>4.5.4.1 If more than one individual is working on a piece of           equipment, EACH individual shall place their own personal lock and tag on the energy           isolating devices.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>4.5.5 After ensuring that no personnel are exposed, and as a         check on having disconnected the energy sources, TRY the normal operating controls to make         certain the equipment will not operate. (CAUTION: Return operating controls to         "neutral" or "off" position after the test.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>4.6 Restoring Equipment to Normal Operation</p>
<blockquote>
<p>4.6.1 After servicing and/or maintenance is complete and         equipment is ready for normal operations, check the area around the equipment to ensure         that no one is exposed.</p>
<p>4.6.2 After all tools have been removed from the equipment,         guards have been re-installed and employees are in the clear, remove all         "lockout" and "tagout" devices.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>4.6.2.1 As each person no longer needs to maintain their           "lockout" protection, that person will remove their lock and tag from the energy           isolating device.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>4.6.3 Operate the energy isolating devices to restore energy to         the equipment.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><a name="5.0 General Rules">5.0 General Rules</a></strong></p>
<p>5.1 All maintenance personnel will be required to carry (or have       immediately available a lock(s), lockout device and tags during working hours.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>5.1.1 All "lockout" and "tagout" devices         shall identify the individual that applied the device.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>5.2 Never remove another person's lock or tag or operate, attempt       to operate or override equipment that is "locked" and/or "tagged" out.</p>
<p>WARNING: Any person who removes another person's lock and/or tag       (except as authorized herein) or attempts to operate, operates, or overrides equipment       that is "locked" and/or "tagged" out, is subject to the most extreme       measures as outlined in BYU-Idaho's "progressive discipline" policy.</p>
<p>5.3 When multiple locks and tags are used, the department/craft       that is responsible for servicing or repairs is to lockout and tagout first, i.e.;       electrical systems are first locked out by electricians. The first department/craft to       install locks and tags will be the last to remove their locks and tags.</p>
<p>5.4 The lockout device is under the exclusive control of the       authorized person performing the work.</p>
<p>5.5 The locks used for lockout shall be a "keyed" lock       of a 5 (five) tumbler design and have the person's identity affixed. The affected person       and the BYU-Idaho Key shop will have exclusive control of all keys to "Lockout"       locks.</p>
<p>5.6 NOTE: No keyed alike locks will be used for lockout.</p>
<p>5.7 The locks and tags used for Lockout/Tagout will not be used       for any other purpose.</p>
<p>5.8 Departments may use "department" locks and tags to       secure machinery or equipment from being operated, but these locks will not be used when       individuals are engaged in servicing or maintenance operations.</p>
<p>5.9 If the "Authorized" or "Affected"       personnel is/are not available to remove his/their lock(s) only the department supervisor       may authorize the removal of the locks and tags. This may be done only after every effort       has been made to contact the above persons.</p>
<p>5.10 For systems dealing with hazardous materials and/or       conditions which involve potentially critical personnel exposure; the department       supervisor or his next highest member of supervision shall review the system and determine       the appropriate "Lockout" procedure.</p>
<p>5.11 Where feasible on all valves and piping systems: (1) valves       will be locked and (2) "blinds" will be installed; on both sides of the area       being worked on.</p>
<p>5.12 All locks and tags will remain in place until the work is       completed unless with the exception that they may be removed temporarily to test or adjust       the system or equipment. The locks and tags will then be immediately replaced.</p>
<p>5.13 Whenever outside servicing or contractor personnel are to be       engaged in activities covered by the "Scope" of this program,       BYU-Idaho and the       outside employer shall inform each other of their respective "lockout"       procedures.</p>
<p>5.14 The BYU-Idaho Safety Department will train department       supervisors in the Lockout/Tagout program. The department supervisor will be responsible       for the training of all affected personnel. All affected personnel will be trained       initially and be retrained annually or as the situation warrants. New BYU-Idaho       personnel       affected by the lockout program will be trained as part of their initial orientation. A       training outline and training record will be maintained in departments, with copies       forwarded to the BYU-Idaho Risk Management and Safety Training Office.</p>
<p>5.15 The BYU-Idaho Safety Department will perform annual       audits of the Lockout/Tagout program. Results of this audit will be forwarded to       supervisors and department directors.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="6.0 Definitions">6.0 Definitions</a>. </strong></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Affected Personnel</span>: A person who is required to work on       machinery or equipment during installation (set up) or who performs maintenance,       servicing, or testing.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Authorized Person</span>: The person that initiates or implements       the Lockout/Tagout program.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Energized</span>: Connected to an energy source or containing       residual or stored energy.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Energy isolating device</span>: A mechanical device that       physically prevents the transmission or release of energy. It includes but is not limited       to the following: electrical circuit breakers, a disconnect switch, slide gate, a       "blind", or valve used to block or isolate energy.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Energy source</span>: Any source of electrical, mechanical,       hydraulic, pneumatic, steam, chemical, thermal, or other type of energy.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Lockout</span>: The placement of a lockout device on an energy       isolating device in accordance with established procedures, to ensure that the energy       isolating device and the equipment or system being controlled cannot be operated until the       lockout device is removed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Lockout Supervisor</span>: The department supervisor is in charge       of BYU-Idaho's Lockout/Tagout program for his department. Department supervisors will       coordinate the Lockout/Tagout programs when there is more than one group or department       working on specific equipment.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Tagout</span>: The placing of an approved tag on an energy       isolating device, in accordance with the established procedures.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Tagout device</span>: A prominent warning device, such as a tag       and its means of attachment, that is made of materials that will withstand all       environmental conditions, and be substantial enough to prevent inadvertent or accidental       removal. The Tagout device must be designed to that it can be securely fastened to an       energy isolating device. The equipment being controlled may not be operated until the       tagout device is removed. The means of attachment of a tagout device shall be of a       non-reusable type, self-locking, with a minimum unlocking strength of 50 pounds (nylon       cable tie).</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Try</span>: The act of an authorized person verifying that all       switches, valves, or other devices are in-fact correctly locked and tagged to ensure that       all energy sources have been isolated. All affected personnel should observe the       "try".</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Competent Person</span>: An individual who is capable, by       training and/or experience, of identifying existing and predictable hazards or working       conditions in the work place. This person is authorized to take prompt corrective measures       to eliminate the unsafe conditions. A "competent person" knows and understands       BYU Idaho's Lockout/Tagout Program.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
