<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67651" Name="Asbestos Summary" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Asbestos Summary</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Asbestos Summary</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left"><a href="x46600.xml"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">A</span></a><a href="x46600.xml">bestos       Policy</a><br /> <a href="x46602.xml">Asbestos       Appendix - Asbestos Inventory</a></p>
<hr />
<p align="left"><strong>Summary of&nbsp; the BYU-Idaho Abestos       Management Plan<br /> </strong>In compliance with 29 CFR 1926.1101<br /> Submitted November 3, 1999</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho is committed to providing a safe work place for all       individuals working in university facilities. The primary purpose of this plan is to ensure       that university employees, students, and visitors are protected from asbestos hazards,       and that applicable asbestos regulatory requirements are followed.</p>
<p>This plan applies to all BYU-Idaho personnel engaged in the removal,       inspection, disturbance, or maintenance of asbestos containing materials (ACM) or presumed       asbestos containing materials (PACM) in university facilities. Certain reporting       requirements also apply to non-university construction personnel working in       BYU-Idaho facilities. Item12 of this plan applies only touniversity personnel engaged in asbestos brake       and/or clutch repair, or custodial employees who are exposed to asbestos as part of their       cleaning or housekeeping duties.</p>
<p>1. <strong>Asbestos Inspection and Inventory.</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>The Safety Office will determine the presence, location, and       quantity of ACM and/or PACM in all university facilities. For more information see <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a class="anchorLink" href="x46600.xml#5.0 Asbestos Inspections and Inventory">section 5 of the Asbestos Management Policy.</a></span></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p>2. <strong>Requirements for Asbestos Work.</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>All asbestos assessment and abatement work shall be done in       accordance with state and federal regulatory requirements. University personnel do not perform <strong>Class       I, II, or III work</strong>. All Class I, II, and III asbestos work (abatement) shall be       performed by asbestos abatement contractors that are certified, licensed, bonded, and       insured to work in the state of Idaho. Non-university abatement contractors will be solely       responsible for the training, respiratory protection, exposure monitoring, and medical       surveillance of their own workers.</p>
<p>A. <strong>Supervisors should </strong>inform their employees of the         general requirements for working with asbestos containing materials. Refer to <a><span style="text-decoration: underline;"></span></a><a class="anchorLink" href="x46600.xml#6.0 Requirements for Asbestos Work"><strong>section 6.0 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></a>.</p>
<p>3. <strong>Requirements for Class IV Asbestos Work.</strong> Class IV       asbestos work consists of maintenance or custodial activities during which employees       contact but do not disturb ACM or cleanup waste and debris resulting from Class I through       III activities. Class IV work includes the following additional requirements:</p>
<p>A. When asbestos containing roofing material is removed, it shall         not be dropped or throne to the ground, but shall be hand carried to the ground or lowered         to the ground in a covered, dust-tight chute. Such material must be removed no later than         the end of the work shift.</p>
<p>4. <strong>Personal Protective Equipment.</strong> As BYU-Idaho       personnel do       not perform Class I, II, or III asbestos work, it is not expected that respirator use will       be required. Non-university workers who perform abatement work at BYU-Idaho       facilities will       be responsible for their own respiratory protection programs. Should it become necessary       for university personnel to wear respirators for asbestos concerns, the applicable portions of       the <a><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>BYU-Idaho       Respiratory Protection Program</strong></span></a> will be followed.</p>
<p>5. <strong>Training.</strong> Training will be provided to all       university employees engaged in Class IV asbestos work. See <a href="x46600.xml#9.0 Training"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>section 9 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></span></a> for training requirements.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Waste Disposal.</strong> ACM waste shall be collected and       disposed of in sealed, labeled, impermeable bags or other containers. Asbestos abatement       contractors shall dispose of the asbestos waste in accordance with all federal, state, and       local regulations. The university safety office shall ensure       that asbestos waste from BYU-Idaho facilities is disposed of properly.</p>
<p>7. <strong>Notification to Regulatory Agencies.</strong> Prior to any       demolition or renovation project, the university safety office will make a       determination of the total quantity of RACM that will be disturbed or removed during the       project. He will insure that proper notifications are sent (by himself or by the Asbestos       Abatement Contractor) to the Division of Air Quality should such notification be warranted       as specified in <a href="x46600.xml#11.0 Notification to Regulatory Agencies"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>section 11 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></span>.</a></p>
<p>8. <strong>Communication of Asbestos Hazards.</strong> Before any asbestos       work is begun, BYU-Idaho Safety Office personnel shall determine       the presence, location, and quantity of ACM or PACM and shall notify       pertinent individuals of       its presence, location, and quantity. See <strong><a href="x46600.xml#12.0 Communication of Asbestos Hazards"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">section 12 of the Asbestos Management Policy</span>.</a></strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p>9. <strong>Signs and Labels.</strong> All regulated areas shall be       posted with warning sign(s) in accordance with 29 CFR 1926.1101, section k. See <a href="x46600.xml#13.0 Signs and Labels"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>section 13 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></span></a> for more information.</p>
<p>10. <strong>Air Monitoring.</strong> Air sampling will be conducted for       university personnel engaged in asbestos work who have the potential to be exposed to       asbestos concentrations above the PEL. This exposure determination, as well as the actual       air sampling will be performed by the Safety Office. See <a href="x46600.xml#14.0 Air Monitoring"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>section 14 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></span></a> for more information.</p>
<p>11. <strong>Responsibilities.</strong> The duties of the       BYU-Idaho Safety Office in regards to asbestos are       outlined in <a href="x46600.xml#15.0 Responsibilities"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>section 15 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></span></a>.</p>
<p>12. <strong>Non-Construction Asbestos Activities</strong>. Those who are       engaged in asbestos brake and/or clutch repair or custodial employees whose housekeeping       or cleaning duties entail exposure to asbestos containing material need to be assessed by       the Safety Office to determine if such personnel exposed to       asbestos in non-construction activities are exposed above the PELs.</p>
<p>A. If employees are exposed at or above the PELs, then an air         monitoring program, respiratory protection program, and several additional controls as         specified in 29 CFR 1910.1001 will be implemented.</p>
<p>B. Employees engaged in ACM brake and/or clutch repair shall         receive asbestos training. This training will include the specific requirements found in         29 CFR 1910.1001, Appendix F. These requirements are also found in the appendix of the         BYU-Idaho Asbestos Management Plan.</p>
<p>13. <strong>Housekeeping duties.</strong> Employees who perform       housekeeping duties in areas which contain ACM or PACM should be familiar with and abide       by the following requirements as listed in <a href="x46600.xml#16.0 Non-Construction Asbestos Activities"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Section 16.3 of the Asbestos Management Policy</strong></span>.</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
