<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67646" Name="Confined Space Entry Policy" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Confined Space Entry Policy</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Confined Space Entry Policy</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p align="left"><a href="x46627.xml">Confined Spaces       Summary</a><br /> <a href="x46628.xml">Permit Required Confined Spaces Entry Guidelines</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>BYU-Idaho Permit-Required Confined Space Entry Policy</strong></p>
<p><strong><a name="Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></strong><a href="#0.0 BASIS/JUSTIFICATION"><br /> Basis/Justification</a><br /> <a href="#1.0 PURPOSE">1.0 Purpose</a><br /> <a href="#2.0 SCOPE">2.0 Scope</a><br /> <a href="#3.0 REFERENCES">3.0 References</a><br /> <a href="#4.0 GENERAL RULES">4.0 General Rules</a><br /> <a href="#5.0 TRAINING">5.0 Training</a><br /> <a href="#6.0 CONFINED SPACE ENTRY PERMIT">6.0 Confined Space Entry Permit</a><br /> <a href="#7.0 ISOLATING AND CONTROLLING HAZARDOUS ENERGY">7.0 Isolating and Controlling       Hazardous Energy</a><br /> <a href="#8.0 CLEANING AND PURGING EQUIPMENT">8.0 Cleaning and Purging Equipment</a><br /> <a href="#9.0 VENTILATING THE CONFINED SPACE">9.0 Ventilating the Confined Space</a><br /> <a href="#10.0 GAS TESTING THE CONFINED SPACE ATMOSPHERE">10.0 Gas Testing the Confined Space       Atmosphere</a><br /> <a href="#11.0 IDENTIFYING PHYSICAL HAZARDS">11.0 Identifying Physical Hazards</a><br /> <a href="#12.0 DUTIES OF SUPERVISOR, ATTENDANT AND ENTRANT">12.0 Duties of       Supervisors/Attendant/Entrant</a><br /> <a href="#13.0 RESCUE/RETRIEVAL AND EMERGENCY SERVICES">13.0 Rescue, Retrieval, and Emergency       Services</a><br /> <a href="#14.0 RESPIRATORY PROTECTION">14.0 Respiratory Protection</a><br /> <a href="#15.0 OUTSIDE SERVICING OR CONTRACTOR PERSONNEL">15.0 Outside Servicing or Contractor       Personnel</a><br /> <a href="#16.0 ANNUAL AUDITS">16.0 Annual Audits</a><br /> <a href="#17.0 DEFINITIONS">17.0 Definitions</a></p>
<p><a name="0.0 BASIS/JUSTIFICATION"><strong>0.0 BASIS/JUSTIFICATION </strong></a></p>
<p>The administration of BYU-Idaho recognizes that       "Confined Spaces" can be dangerous, even potentially lethal work areas.       Personnel can be exposed to a wide range of atmospheric, chemical, explosion, mechanical,       and electrical hazards. And in the event of an accident, rescue may be both difficult and       dangerous. Because of a commitment to provide a safe and healthful work place, and to       comply with OSHA safety standards, the Permit Required Confined Space Entry (PRCSE)       program, described hereafter, is implemented as institutional policy.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="1.0 PURPOSE">1.0 PURPOSE </a></strong></p>
<p>The purpose of the "Permit-Required Confined Space       Entry" (PRCSE) program is to establish a working standard at BYU-Idaho       which       includes the following elements:</p>
<p>1.1 Establish a program for minimizing permit space hazards and       for regulating employee entry into permit spaces.</p>
<p>1.2 Evaluation of all workplaces to determine what spaces are       subject to PRCSE rules.</p>
<p>1.3 Inform all university employees and/or contractor personnel who       may be exposed to the hazards of PRCSE, and of the existence and location of these spaces.</p>
<p>1.4 Train "qualified" employees as "Entry       Supervisors", "Authorized Entrants", "Attendants", and the       "Permit-Required Confined Space Rescue Team".</p>
<p>1.5 Establish a PRCSE permit system specifying, in writing, the       location and type of work to be done, personnel who will be entering the PRCSE work area,       certifying that all existing hazards have been evaluated by a qualified person, and that       necessary protective measures have been taken to insure the safety of each individual.</p>
<p>1.6 Provide the necessary equipment to work in PRCSE areas, and       if required, to rescue employees during a contingency in any of these areas.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="2.0 SCOPE">2.0 SCOPE</a> </strong></p>
<p>BYU-Idaho facilities which may be categorized as PRCSE       include, but are not limited to, the following areas:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(a) Service tunnel system <br /> (b) Boilers, ducts, flues, and coal bunkers at the Heating Plant <br /> (c) Transformer vaults. <br /> (d) Manholes, other vaults (Sewer, Water and Electrical) <br /> (e) Granaries, silos, dust collection tanks <br /> (f) Swimming pool chlorination system tanks, surge tanks and sand tanks. <br /> (g) Air handling plenums, ducts and any space with a limited access, or open topped space,         more than four (4) feet deep, i.e., trench, tank, or duct.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="3.0 REFERENCES">3.0 REFERENCES</a></strong><a name="3.0 REFERENCES"> </a></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">OSHA General Industry</span><br /> 29 CFR 1910.146 Permit-Required Confined Spaces <br /> 29 CFR 1910.120(b)(4)(ii) ("HAZWOPER") <br /> 29 CFR 1910.134 (Respiratory Protection) <br /> 29 CFR 1910.147 (Lockout/Tagout) <br /> 29 CFR 1910.252(a)(4) (Welding in Confined Space) <br /> 29 CFR 1910.252(c)(2) (Welding) <br /> 29 CFR 1910.252(c)(9) &amp; (10) (Welding)</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">OSHA Construction </span><br /> 29 CFR 1926.21(b)(6)(I) (Training ,Protective Equipment) <br /> 29 CFR 1926.352(g) (Welding) <br /> 29 CFR 1926.353(b)(1) &amp; (2) (Welding-Ventilation)</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents </a></p>
<p><strong> <a name="4.0 GENERAL RULES">4.0 GENERAL RULES</a></strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p>4.1 Each major work area and/or department having responsibility       to install, service and/or maintain mechanical equipment and facilities shall conduct       periodic audits to identify confined spaces, and post a warning sign which states: DANGER       - PERMIT-REQUIRED CONFINED SPACE, DO NOT ENTER; at each location meeting the requirements       of the (PRCS) standard.</p>
<p>4.2 Supervisors in each major work area at BYU-Idaho       will address the       requirements of this standard according to equipment and facilities that are within their       area of responsibility.</p>
<p>4.3 When a confined space is suspected to contain toxic       materials, a flammable mixture or where there may be a deficiency of oxygen; appropriate       tests shall be made by a qualified person before entry is permitted. Entry will be       permitted only after it has been determined that toxic or explosive limits are not       exceeded, and the oxygen content is not below 19.5% nor above 23.5% of the total air       mixture.</p>
<p>4.4 Where any known or suspected hazardous material is suspected       to be found, a Material Safety Data Sheet, or other similar written information, for that       substance is required to be kept at the worksite. That written information shall be made       available to the medical facility treating the exposed entrant.</p>
<p>4.5 If the atmosphere in a confined space is found to have, or is       suspected of having an oxygen deficiency or if it exceeds toxic or flammable limits the       area shall be:</p>
<p>(a) Posted with an appropriate warning sign, i.e., KEEP OUT,         FLAMMABLE, TOXIC, or OXYGEN DEFICIENT ATMOSPHERE.<br /> <br /> (b) Purged and ventilated</p>
<p>(c) Re-checked and found to be clear and safe prior to re-entry</p>
<p>4.6 Cylinders of compressed gas of any type shall not be taken       into confined spaces. (SCBA respirators are the only exception).</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="5.0 TRAINING">5.0 TRAINING</a></strong></p>
<p>5.1 The University Safety Department will train department       supervisors in the "Confined Space Entry" program. The department supervisor       will be responsible for the training of all affected personnel. All affected personnel       will be trained initially and be retrained annually or as the situation warrants. New       university personnel affected by "Confined Space Entry" program will be       trained as part of their initial orientation.</p>
<p>5.2 Entry supervisor, attendant, and authorized entrants will be       trained in:</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Confined Space Hazards, including:</span><br /> hazardous atmosphere <br /> engulfment <br /> electrical <br /> moving machinery <br /> burns <br /> trips/slips/falls <br /> entrapment</p>
<p>5.3 Training should also include Confined Space Safeguards,       Engineering, Work Practice Controls (confined space preparation and isolation, Lock       Out/Tag Out, methods of eliminating or controlling atmospheric hazards, procedures to       protect entrants from external hazards, procedures to verify that conditions in the       confined space are acceptable throughout entry)</p>
<p>5.4 BYU-Idaho Confined Space Entry Program</p>
<p>5.5 Gas Testing Procedures</p>
<p>5.6 Isolation and Control of Hazardous Energy (Lock Out/Tag Out)</p>
<p>5.7 Entry Supervisor, Authorized Entrant, and Attendant duties</p>
<p>5.8 Selection and use of proper personal protective equipment       (PPE)</p>
<p>5.9 Communication Procedures for Summoning Rescue and Emergency       Services</p>
<p>5.10 Emergency Response, and Rescue.</p>
<p>5.11 Training Records. A training outline and training record       will be maintained in departments, with copies forwarded to the University       Safety Office.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="6.0 CONFINED SPACE ENTRY PERMIT">6.0 CONFINED SPACE       ENTRY PERMIT</a> </strong></p>
<p>6.1 A confined space shall not be entered until it has been       determined by a qualified person that it is safe to enter; and a confined space entry       permit has been issued to the immediate supervisor and the person or persons who comprise       the entry crew. Permits and monitoring equipment shall be issued by the       BYU-Idaho Campus Police Division.</p>
<p>6.2 Only qualified personnel who have been trained in the use of       atmospheric monitoring and safety equipment and know the requirements of       BYU-Idaho Confined Space policy shall administer the confined space entry permit procedure.</p>
<p>6.3 The "Confined Space Entry Permit" will be       conspicuously posted at the entrance of the confined space.</p>
<p>6.4 Each person shall be instructed concerning the written       instructions on the "Confined Space Entry Permit" and shall be required to       observe those regulations for his/her own safety and the well-being of fellow personnel.</p>
<p>6.5 The immediate supervisor of the crew involved in the confined       space entry shall remove the permit only after all work is done and all entry personnel       have vacated the space.</p>
<p>6.6 The immediate supervisor involved shall forward the canceled       permit to the University Safety Department immediately after the job is completed,       where it will be kept on file.</p>
<p>6.7 Completing the Entry Permit</p>
<p>6.7.1 The entry permit must be completed and signed by the entry         supervisor. The permit must clearly identify:</p>
<p>(1) Location of the confined space;</p>
<p>(2) Purpose of entry and scope of work;</p>
<p>(3) Authorized date and duration of entry;</p>
<p>(4) Measures to isolate the space and eliminate or control           hazards;</p>
<p>(5) Initial and periodic gas results;</p>
<p>(6) List of entry requirements and safe work practices;</p>
<p>(7) Communication procedures and rescue;</p>
<p>(8) Other required permits;</p>
<p>(9) Entrant log;</p>
<p>(10) Attendant signature.</p>
<p>6.8 Closing Out the Permit</p>
<p>6.8.1 When entry work is complete, or the space must be left         unattended, the permit must be voided (canceled), entry into the space closed, or         barricaded, and signed "DO NOT ENTER".</p>
<p>6.8.2 Permits must be returned to University Safety Office         after being closed out (canceled), where they will be kept on file for one year.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<p><strong><a name="7.0 ISOLATING AND CONTROLLING HAZARDOUS ENERGY">7.0       ISOLATING AND CONTROLLING HAZARDOUS ENERGY</a> </strong></p>
<p>7.1 All energized systems that are being serviced, including:       electrical, steam, hydraulic, chemical, compressed air, gas, or other systems that might       unexpectedly, improperly or accidentally be energized; should be "Locked out"       according to BYU-Idaho Lockout/Tagout policy.</p>
<p>7.2 All lines entering and leaving a vessel must be isolated to       prevent re-entry of flammable or toxic liquids or gases. Pipes or equipment to be       disassembled or opened as part of vessel entry or hot work shall be first brought to       "safe energy state".</p>
<p>7.3 Contents of the vessel must be identified and safeguards       including the use of proper PPE shall be done prior to breaking lines or opening the       equipment.</p>
<p>7.4 Lighting/Electrical</p>
<p>7.4.1 All 110 volt cord connected lighting must be grounded and         service outlets must be of the three contact type. In addition ground fault circuit         interrupters (GFCI) must be used where wet conditions exist.</p>
<p>7.4.2 All lighting/tools/ventilating equipment used in confined         spaces containing or potentially containing flammable vapors or combustible dusts shall be         approved respectively for Class I, Division I or Class II, Division I hazardous locations         (explosion proof). This includes low voltage lighting such as drop lights, flashlights,         etc.</p>
<p>7.4.3 Electrical powered tools used in confined spaces shall be         protected through a GFCI or the tool shall be double insulated.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="8.0 CLEANING AND PURGING EQUIPMENT">8.0 CLEANING AND       PURGING EQUIPMENT</a> </strong></p>
<p>8.1 The equipment to be entered must be emptied and made as clean       and free of residue as possible by hot or cold water flush, steaming, chemical       neutralization, or air purge with harmful vapors vented safely away from the work area.       Sludge should be removed to the greatest possible degree from the confined space.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="9.0 VENTILATING THE CONFINED SPACE">9.0 VENTILATING THE       CONFINED SPACE</a></strong></p>
<p>9.1 Cleaning a vessel often results in the release and       accumulation of flammable and harmful vapors. A vessel shall be continuously ventilated if       the work in progress creates fumes (i.e. cutting, welding, coating, steaming, removal of       sludge). Air movers shall be explosion proof and bonded to the vessel. Oxygen or inert       gasses shall not be used to ventilate a confined space which personnel may enter.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="10.0 GAS TESTING THE CONFINED SPACE ATMOSPHERE">10.0 GAS       TESTING THE CONFINED SPACE ATMOSPHERE</a></strong></p>
<p>10.1 A trained, authorized person shall test the atmosphere to       determine the presence of oxygen deficiency, combustible gases and any other hazardous       condition which might be suspected (i.e. H2S, CO, SO2, total hydrocarbons).</p>
<p>10.2 Ensure that the atmosphere sampling instrument is       functioning properly. Check the battery. Check the sampling for leaks. Calibrate and zero       the instrument. Sample the confined space beginning at the top. Sample the entry, then the       work area.</p>
<p>10.3 Sample equipment for hot work beginning at the area adjacent       to the equipment. Sample the equipment outside, and where possible, inside.</p>
<p>10.4 It should always be remembered that atmosphere conditions       can change and that periodic or continuous gas testing may be needed.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="11.0 IDENTIFYING PHYSICAL HAZARDS">11.0 IDENTIFYING       PHYSICAL HAZARDS</a> </strong></p>
<p>11.1 A comprehensive hazard assessment must be conducted and work       practices and other safeguards to minimize or control hazards must be completed before       entry.</p>
<p>11.2 Physical hazards, such as agitators, steam fittings, drive       shafts, gears and other moving parts can pose a danger in confined spaces. Moving       equipment must be blocked, locked out and tagged.</p>
<p>11.3 Uneven or wet surfaces and corroded roof tops may pose slip,       trip, and fall hazards. Surfaces should be allowed to dry. Fall protection must be used on       surfaces which pose a fall hazard.</p>
<p>11.4 Engulfment hazards exist in areas where loose materials are       stored. These materials can collapse under the weight of an employee.</p>
<p>11.5 Contact with corrosive chemicals such as acids, solvents,       and cleaning solutions can cause serious irritation or burns. Personal protective       equipment (PPE) to protect against skin contact and inhalation of these materials must be       worn.</p>
<p>11.6 Safety lighting should be used when visibility is poor.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="12.0 DUTIES OF SUPERVISOR, ATTENDANT AND ENTRANT">12.0       DUTIES OF SUPERVISOR, ATTENDANT AND ENTRANT</a></strong></p>
<p>12.1 Duties of entry supervisors. Every "Entry Supervisor       shall:</p>
<p>12.1.1 Know the hazards that may be faced during entry, including         information on the mode, signs or symptoms, and consequences of the exposure;</p>
<p>12.1.2 Verify, by checking that the appropriate entries have been         made on the permit, that all tests specified by the permit have been conducted and that         all procedures and equipment specified by the permit are in place before endorsing the         permit and allowing entry to begin;</p>
<p>12.1.3 Terminate the entry and cancels the permit as required.</p>
<p>12.1.4 Verify that rescue services are available and that the         means for summoning them are operable;</p>
<p>12.1.5 Remove unauthorized individuals who enter or who attempt         to enter the permit space during entry operations; and</p>
<p>12.1.6 Determine, whenever responsibility for a permit space         entry operation is transferred and at intervals dictated by the hazards and operations         performed within the space, that entry operations remain consistent with terms of the         entry permit and that acceptable entry conditions are maintained.</p>
<p>12.2 Duties of Authorized entrants</p>
<p>12.2.1 Know the hazards that may be faced during entry, including         information on the mode, signs or symptoms, and consequences of the exposure;</p>
<p>12.2.2 Know the proper use, when necessary, of all of the         following types of equipment:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) Testing and monitoring equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) Ventilating equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) Communications equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) Personal protective equipment (PPE)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(5) Lighting equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(6) Barriers and shields</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(7) Equipment used for safe ingress and egress by entrants</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(8) Rescue and emergency equipment</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(9) Any other equipment necessary for safe entry and/or rescue</p>
<p>12.2.3 Communicate with the attendant as necessary to enable the         attendant to monitor entrant status and to enable the attendant to alert entrants of the         need to evacuate the space as required.</p>
<p>12.2.4 Alert the attendant whenever:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) The entrant recognizes any warning sign or symptom of           exposure to a dangerous situation, or</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) The entrant detects a prohibited condition; and</p>
<p>12.2.5 Exit from the permit space as quickly as possible         whenever:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) An order to evacuate is given by the attendant or the entry           supervisor,</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) The entrant recognizes any warning sign or symptom of           exposure to a dangerous situation,</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) The entrant detects a prohibited condition, or</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) An evacuation alarm is activated.</p>
<p>12.3 Duties of attendants. Every attendant shall:</p>
<p>12.3.1 Know the hazards that may be faced during entry, including         information on the mode, signs or symptoms, and consequences of the exposure;</p>
<p>12.3.2 Be aware of possible behavioral effects of hazard exposure         in authorized entrants;</p>
<p>12.3.3 Continuously maintain an accurate count of authorized         entrants in the permit space and ensure that the means used to identify authorized         entrants accurately identifies who is in the permit space;</p>
<p>12.3.4 Remain outside the permit space during entry operations         until relieved by another attendant;</p>
<p>NOTE: When the attendant has been trained and equipped for rescue         operations, attendants may enter a permit space to attempt a rescue if they have been         relieved by another authorized attendant.</p>
<p>12.3.5 Communicate with authorized entrants as necessary to         monitor entrant status and to alert entrants of the need to evacuate the space under.</p>
<p>12.3.6 Monitor activities inside and outside the space to         determine if it is safe for entrants to remain in the space and orders the authorized         entrants to evacuate the permit space immediately under any of the following conditions;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) If the attendant detects a prohibited condition;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) If the attendant detects the behavioral effects of hazard           exposure in an authorized entrant;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) If the attendant detects a situation outside the space that           could endanger the authorized entrants; or</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) If the attendant cannot effectively and safely perform all of           his required duties.</p>
<p>12.3.7 Summon rescue and other emergency services as soon as the         attendant determines that authorized entrants may need assistance to escape from permit         space hazards;</p>
<p>12.3.8 Take the following actions when unauthorized persons         approach or enter a permit space while entry is underway:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) Warn the unauthorized persons that they must stay away from           the permit space;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) Advise the unauthorized persons that they must exit           immediately if they have entered the permit space; and</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) Inform the authorized entrants and the entry supervisor if           unauthorized persons have entered the permit space;</p>
<p>12.3.9 Perform non-entry rescues.</p>
<p>12.3.10 Perform no duties that might interfere with the         attendant's primary duty to monitor and protect the authorized entrants.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="13.0 RESCUE/RETRIEVAL AND EMERGENCY SERVICES">13.0       RESCUE/RETRIEVAL AND EMERGENCY SERVICES</a></strong></p>
<p>13.1 Entry</p>
<p>13.1.1 To facilitate non-entry rescue, retrieval systems or         methods should be used whenever an authorized entrant enters a PRCS, unless the retrieval         equipment would increase the overall risk of entry or would not contribute to the rescue         of the entrant. Retrieval systems shall meet the following requirements:</p>
<p>13.1.2 Each authorized entrant shall use a body harness, with a         retrieval line attached at the center of the entrant's back near shoulder level, or above         the entrants head. Wristlets may be used in lieu of the chest or full body harness if it         can be demonstrated that the use of a chest or full body harness is infeasible or creates         a greater hazard.</p>
<p>13.1.3 The other end of the retrieval line shall be attached to a         mechanical device or fixed point outside the PRCS in such a manner that rescue is         necessary. A mechanical device shall be available to retrieve personnel from vertical type         PRCS more than 5 feet (1.52m) deep.</p>
<p>13.2 Rescue</p>
<p>13.2.1 "Non-entry" or "external" rescue will         be used where feasible. This includes the use of a retrieval of life line attached to a         full body harness worn by the entrant or a mechanical retrieval system such as a tripod         and winch.</p>
<p>13.2.2 Since most confined space fatalities involve improperly         equipped and trained rescuers, attendants will only perform external rescue and assist         rescuers from outside the confined space.</p>
<p>13.2.3 The facility rescue team must train and perform a         simulated confined space rescue at least once a year. Training shall include:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) confined space hazard recognition;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) atmosphere testing and evaluation;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) use and evaluation of material safety data sheets (MSDS);</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) use and limitations of personal protective equipment (PPE);</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(5) incident command system and confined space communication;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(6) rescue techniques;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(7) self rescue;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(8) patient assessment and care.</p>
<p>NOTE: At no time should any rescuer place himself in a dangerous           situation to perform a rescue.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of           Contents</a></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="14.0 RESPIRATORY PROTECTION">14.0 RESPIRATORY PROTECTION</a> </strong></p>
<p>14.1 Where it is not known if a toxic or oxygen deficient       atmosphere exists or if sampling/monitoring indicates that there is a known oxygen       deficiency or that toxic limits are exceeded--APPROPRIATE RESPIRATORY PROTECTION MUST BE       WORN.</p>
<p>14.2 In areas where there is less than 19.5% oxygen by volume       only SCBA's or airline respirators will be used.</p>
<p>14.3 Where toxic limits are exceeded, respiratory protection will       be approved by the University Safety Department.</p>
<p>14.4 No one will enter a confined space, at any time, where       flammable limits are more than 10% of the LEL (Lower Explosive Limit).</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong>
<p><a name="15.0 OUTSIDE SERVICING OR CONTRACTOR PERSONNEL">15.0       OUTSIDE SERVICING OR CONTRACTOR PERSONNEL</a></p>
</strong>
<p><strong>(Multi-employer Worksites)</strong></p>
<p>15.1 Whenever outside servicing or contractor personnel are to be       engaged in activities covered by the "Scope" of this program,       university       personnel and the outside employer shall inform each other of their respective       "Confined Space Entry" procedures.</p>
<p>15.2 Authorized university personnel will issue all confined       space entry permits. All co contractors whose work will involve entry into confined spaces       must train their personnel in BYU-Idaho PRCS program requirements. By signing the       Confined Space Entry Permits the contractor acknowledges that they have read, understood,       and will follow all permit requirements.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="16.0 ANNUAL AUDITS">16.0 ANNUAL AUDITS</a> </strong></p>
<p>16.1 The University Safety Department will perform annual       audits of the "Confined Space Entry" program. Results of this audit will be       forwarded to unit supervisors and department directors.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<strong> </strong>
<p><strong><a name="17.0 DEFINITIONS">17.0 DEFINITIONS</a></strong></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Acceptable entry conditions</span>: The conditions that must exist       in a permitted space to allow entry and to ensure that employees involved with a PRCSE       safely enter into, and work within the space in compliance with all work rules.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Attendant</span>: An individual stationed outside one or more       permit spaces who monitors the authorized entrants, and who performs all attendant's       duties assigned in the employers permit space program.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Authorized entrant</span>: An employee who is authorized to enter       a Permit Required Confined Space.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Blanking or Blinding</span>: The absolute closure of a pipe, line       or duct by the fastening of a solid plate (such as a spectacle blind or a skillet blind)       that completely covers the bore and that is capable of withstanding the maximum pressure       of the pipe, line, or duct with no leakage beyond the plate.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Confined Space</span>: A space which:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) is large enough and so configured that an employee can bodily         enter and perform assigned work; and</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) has limited or restricted means for entry or exit (for         example, tanks, vessels, silos, storage bins, hoppers, vaults, and pits are spaces that         may have limited means of entry), and</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) is not designed for continuous employee occupancy.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">It may be an open topped space more than 4 feet (1.2m) deep. A         confined space may have an oxygen deficient (less than 19.5% oxygen) or oxygen enriched         (greater than 23%) atmosphere, an accumulation of flammable vapors (in excess of 10% of         the LFL), toxic gasses, or other safety and/or health hazards. Examples of confined spaces         include, but are not limited to: storage tanks, process vessels, storage bins, boilers and         flues, ventilation and exhaust ducts, utility vaults, elevator pits, manholes, tunnels and         trenches.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Double Block and Bleed</span>: The closure of a line, duct, or       pipe by closing and locking or tagging two in line valves and by opening and locking or       tagging a drain or vent valve in the line between the two closed valves.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Emergency</span>: Any occurrence (including any failure of hazard       control or monitoring equipment) or event internal or external to the permit space that       could endanger entrants.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Engulfment</span>: The surrounding and effective capture of a       person by a liquid or finely divided (flowable) solid substance that can be aspirated to       cause death by filling or plugging the respiratory system or that can exert enough force       on the body to cause death by strangulation, constriction, or crushing.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Entry</span>: The action by which a person passes through an       opening into a PRCSE. Entry includes ensuing work activities in that space and is       considered to have occurred as soon as any part of the entrant's body breaks the plane of       an opening into the space [This is OSHAs' definition quoted verbatim from 29 CFR       1910.146(b)].</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Entry Permit</span>: The written or printed document that is       provided by the employer to allow and control entry into a permit space and that contains:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) The permit space to be entered</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) The purpose of entry</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) The date and the authorized duration of the entry permit</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) The authorized entrants within the permit space, by name or         by such other means as will enable the attendant to determine quickly and accurately, for         the duration of the permit, which authorized entrants are inside the permit space.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(5) The personnel, by name, currently serving as attendants.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(6) The individual, by name, currently serving as entry         supervisor, with a space for the signature or initials of the entry supervisor who         originally authorized entry.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(7) The hazards of the permit space to be entered.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(8) The measures used to isolate the permit space and to         eliminate or control permit space hazards before entry. These measures include but are not         limited to: Lock Out/Tag Out, purging, inerting, ventilating, and flushing permit spaces.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(9) The acceptable entry conditions.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(10) The results of initial and periodic tests performed,         accompanied by the names or initials of the testers and by an indication of when the tests         were performed.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(11) The rescue and emergency services that can be summoned and         the means (such as the equipment to use and the numbers to call) for summoning those         services.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(12) The communication procedures used by authorized entrants and         attendants to maintain contact during the entry.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(13) Equipment, such as personal protective equipment, testing         equipment, communications equipment, alarm systems, and rescue equipment, to be provided         for compliance.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(14) Any other information whose inclusion is necessary, given         the circumstances of the particular confined space, in order to ensure employee safety.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(15) Any additional permits, such as for hot work, that have been         issued to authorize work in the permit space.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Entry Supervisor</span>: The person (such as the employer,       foreman, or crew chief) responsible for determining if acceptable entry conditions are       present at a permit space where entry is planned, for authorizing entry and overseeing       entry operations, and for terminating entry as required by this section.</p>
<p>NOTE: An entry supervisor also may serve as an attendant or as an         authorized entrant, as long as that person is trained and equipped as required by this         section for each role he or she fills. Also, the duties of entry supervisor may be passed         from one individual to another during the course of an entry operation.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Hazardous atmosphere</span>: An atmosphere that may expose       employees to the risk of death, incapacitation, impairment of ability to self-rescue (that       is, escape unaided from a permit space), injury, or acute illness from one or more of the       following causes:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) Flammable gas, vapor, or mist in excess of 10 percent of its         lower flammable limit (LFL);</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) Airborne combustible dust at a concentration that meets or         exceeds its LFL; NOTE: This concentration may be approximated as a condition in which the         dust obscures vision at a distance of 5 feet (1.52 m) or less.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) Atmospheric oxygen concentration below 19.5 percent or above         23.5 percent;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) Atmospheric concentration of any substance for which a dose         or a permissible exposure limit is published in Subpart G, Occupational Health and         Environmental Control, or in Subpart Z, Toxic and Hazardous Substances, of this Part and         which could result in employee exposure in excess of its dose or permissible exposure         limit;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NOTE: An atmospheric concentration of any substance that is not         capable of causing death, incapacitation, impairment of ability to self-rescue, injury, or         acute illness due to its health effects is not covered by this provision.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(5) Any other atmospheric condition that is immediately dangerous         to life or health.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NOTE: For air contaminants for which OSHA has not determined a         dose or permissible exposure limit, other sources of information, such as Material Safety         Data Sheets that comply with the Hazard Communication Standard, section 1910.1200 of this         Part, published information, and internal documents can provide guidance in establishing         acceptable atmospheric conditions.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Hot work permit</span>: The employer's written authorization to       perform operations (for example; riveting, welding, cutting, burning, and heating) capable       of providing a source of ignition.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Immediately dangerous to life or health (IDLH)</span>: Any       condition that poses an immediate or delayed threat to life or that would cause       irreversible adverse health effects or that would interfere with an individual's ability       to escape unaided from a permit space.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NOTE: Some materials -- hydrogen fluoride gas and cadmium vapor,         for example -- may produce immediate transient effects that, even if severe, may pass         without medical attention, but are followed by sudden, possibly fatal collapse 12-72 hours         after exposure. The victim "feels normal" from recovery from transient effects         until collapse. Such materials in hazardous quantities are considered to be         "immediately" dangerous to life or health.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Inerting</span>: The displacement of the atmosphere in a permit       space by a noncombustible gas (such as nitrogen) to such an extent that the resulting       atmosphere is noncombustible.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NOTE: This procedure produces an IDLH oxygen-deficient         atmosphere.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Isolation</span>: The process by which a permit space is removed       from service and completely protected against the release of energy and material into the       space by such means as:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) blanking or blinding;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) misaligning or removing sections of lines, pipes, or ducts;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) a double block and bleed system;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) lockout or tagout of all sources of energy; or</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(5) blocking or disconnecting all mechanical linkages.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Line breaking</span>: The intentional opening of a pipe, line, or       duct that is or has been carrying flammable, corrosive, or toxic material, an inert gas,       or any fluid at a volume, pressure, or temperature capable of causing injury.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Non-permit confined space</span>: A confined space that does not       contain or, with respect to atmospheric hazards, have the potential to contain any hazard       capable of causing death or serious physical harm.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Oxygen deficient atmosphere</span>: An atmosphere containing less       than 19.5 percent oxygen by volume.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Oxygen enriched atmosphere</span>: An atmosphere containing more       than 23.5 percent oxygen by volume.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Permit-required confined space (permit space)</span>: A confined       space that has one or more of the following characteristics:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(1) Contains or has a potential to contain a hazardous         atmosphere;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(2) Contains a material that has the potential for engulfing an         entrant;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(3) Has an internal configuration such that an entrant could be         trapped or asphyxiated by inwardly converging walls or by a floor which slopes downward         and tapers to a smaller cross-section; or</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">(4) Contains any other recognized serious safety or health         hazard.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Permit-required confined space program (permit space program)</span>:       The employer's overall program for controlling, and, where appropriate, for protecting       employees from, permit space hazards and for regulating employee entry into permit spaces.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Permit system</span>: The employer's written procedure for       preparing and issuing permits for entry and for returning the permit space to service       following termination of entry.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Prohibited condition</span>: Any condition in a permit space that       is not allowed by the permit during the period when entry is authorized.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Rescue service</span>: The personnel designated to rescue       employees from permit spaces. (Rexburg/Madison Fire Department-Telephone: 359-3010 or 911)</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Retrieval system</span>: The equipment (including a retrieval       line, chest or full-body harness, wristlets, if appropriate, and a lifting device or       anchor) used for non-entry rescue of persons from permit spaces.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Testing</span>: The process by which the hazards that may       confront entrants of a permit space are identified and evaluated. Testing includes       specifying the tests that are to be performed in the permit space.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NOTE: Testing enables employers both to devise and implement         adequate control measures for the protection of authorized entrants and to determine if         acceptable entry conditions are present immediately prior to, and during, entry.</p>
<p><a href="#Table of Contents">Table of Contents</a></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
