<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.5.118 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x67641" Name="Ergonomics Safety Plan" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ergonomics Safety Plan</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Ergonomics Safety Plan</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p><a href="x46878.xml">Computer Workstation Check Sheet</a></p>
<strong> </strong> 
<hr />
<p><strong>Basis/Justification</strong></p>
<p>The administration of BYU-Idaho recognizes that office       "ergonomics" are essential to the overall health and well-being of employees.       Poor body position, work station arrangements, and work habits can lead to physical injury       and/or loss of mobility. Because of a commitment to provide a safe and healthful work       place, and to comply with OSHA safety standards, the<strong> Office Ergonomics Safety Policy</strong>,       described hereafter, is implemented as institutional policy.</p>
<p><strong> 1.0 Body Position.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Neutral Body Position.</strong>&nbsp; A       neutral body position minimizes the risk of computer related injuries. Start by adjusting       your chair so that you feel comfortable and supported. Position your forearms on the       keyboard parallel to the floor with your wrists flat. Depending on your workstation       set-up, either adjust the chair so that arms are in a neutral position or, if using an       articulating keyboard tray, move the tray so that forearms and wrists stay flat.</p>
<p><strong>Chair Position.</strong>&nbsp; Usually, you will       need to adjust the chair up and use a footstool, if working with the keyboard on the top       of the work surface,</p>
<p><strong>Monitor Level.</strong>&nbsp; Make sure that you       are not looking up at the monitor. The top 1/3 - 2 of the screen should be at eye level.       You may need to remove the monitor from the CPU and use monitor risers to get the correct       height.</p>
<p><strong><br /> 2.0 Workstation Arrangements.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Workstation Design.</strong>&nbsp; Corner,       "L-shaped", or "U-shaped" workstations usually work better than       rectangular work surfaces because they provide additional depth and place your accessories       within easy reach.</p>
<p><strong>Keyboards</strong>.&nbsp; Keyboard trays are one       option to increase desk space; but these devices can sometimes force you too far away from       your work surface and force you to reach for your mouse or put your mouse at a higher       level then the keyboard. Excessive reaching may cause pain or discomfort to arms and       shoulders.</p>
<p><strong>Document Holder.</strong>&nbsp; If you change       tasks, remember to move both materials and input devices within easy reach. If you use a       document holder, position it at the same height and distance as your monitor. Slant boards       can be used to hold oversize documents.</p>
<p><strong>Hand Position/Wrist Pad.</strong>&nbsp; It's       best for the hands to "float" over the keyboard rather than rest on the work       surface, but if you find yourself resting your wrists on the desktop, you may want to use       a padded wrist rest. This also helps maintain circulation by keeping your arms and/or       wrists off the hard edges of your work surface.</p>
<p><strong>Telephone Usage.</strong>&nbsp; Talking on the       phone with the receiver cradled between your ear and your shoulder can cause neck,       shoulder, and back pain. A headset will allow your body to stay in a neutral position and       leave your hands free for writing or using your computer.</p>
<p><strong><br /> 3.0 Work Habits.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Periodic Breaks.</strong>&nbsp; Periodic breaks       help to alleviate fatigue and strain to your eyes and upper body. You can vary the type of       work you are doing B making phone calls, making copies, reading, etc.</p>
<p><strong>Persistent Discomfort.&nbsp; </strong>If you       experience persistent discomfort related to your computer use at work, report your injury.       Diagnosis and proper treatment at the early stages of a cumulative injury can prevent       permanent problems.</p>
<p><strong><br /> 4.0 Proper Setup of Equipment.</strong></p>
<p>With the appropriate furniture adjustments and ergonomic       equipment, your workstation should accommodate the proper body postures as outlined below:</p>
<p><strong>Seating.&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong><br /> Adjust the height of your seat to allow for:</p>
<p>A.&nbsp; Feet to plant comfortably on the floor or footrest<br /> B.&nbsp; Knees to bend at 90 degrees or slightly greater, and <br /> C.&nbsp; Thighs to rest parallel to the floor.</p>
<p>Adjust seatback position to allow for:</p>
<p>A.&nbsp; Hips to bend at 90 degrees or slightly greater, and <br /> B.&nbsp; Adequate low back support.</p>
<p>Adjust seat pan depth to allow for a 2-4" gap between the       front edge of the seat and back of knees.</p>
<p><strong><br />Mouse and keyboard height.</strong></p>
<p>Adjust your mouse and keyboard to allow for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hands at elbow height or slightly lower</li>
<li>Forearms and hands to form straight lines</li>
<li>Shoulders to be relaxed, with elbows hanging close to your sides</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><br />Monitor placement.</strong></p>
<p>Adjust your monitor position to allow for:</p>
<ul>
<li>The top of the screen to align at or slightly below the         eye level</li>
<li>Straight-forward monitor viewing</li>
<li>A comfortable distance of between 16 - 28"</li>
<li>An upright head posture with chin tucked in</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><br /> 5.0 Healthy Work Habits and Practices.</strong></p>
<p>Ensure proper use and adjustment of office furniture and       equipment by performing ergonomic self evaluations.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do Not Exert Force.</strong>&nbsp; While       performing daily tasks, do not exert more force than is really necessary.</li>
<li><strong>Practice Developing Proper Postures.</strong> &nbsp; Practice developing proper postures for sitting, keyboarding, phone use, etc.       Maintain a constant awareness of preferred neutral body postures not only at work, but in       all modes of your life.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Extended Periods of       Continuous Computer       Use.</strong>&nbsp; Avoid extended periods of continuous computer use by taking short       breaks or performing other tasks intermittently between periods spent on the computer       (maximum of 30 minutes continuous computer use at any time).</li>
<li><strong>Take Stretch/Exercise Breaks.</strong> Take       stretch/exercise breaks during your workday and integrate them into your daily life as       well.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Bright Light.</strong>&nbsp; Avoid direct       or overly-bright lighting, but make sure you have enough light to comfortably and safely       perform you job duties.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><br /> 6.0 Office Stretches.</strong></p>
<p>To help relive office stress from your body, try incorporating       several of these stretching exercises into your morning warm-up and daytime work schedule.       If you have an injury or any type of reoccurring discomforts, you should immediately       report your injury/symptoms and obtain a medical evaluation. These stretching exercises       are not provided to cure any existing problems but may help in preventing any future ones.       Individuals with previous injury should consult with a personal physician before       performing these exercises on a routine basis. <br /> <br /> While performing these stretches</p>
<strong>
<p>Do Not:</p>
</strong> <strong> </strong> 
<ul>
<li>Bounce or use jerky motions</li>
<li>Stretch until it hurts</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Do: </strong></p>
<strong> </strong> <strong> </strong> 
<ul>
<li>Breathe deeply and relax</li>
<li>Extend until you feel a comfortable stretch</li>
<li>Move smoothly and slowly</li>
</ul>
<div style="margin-left: 30px;"><strong>Eyes</strong>
<p>Close eyes tightly for a second, then open them widely (repeat         several times)<br /> Refocus eyes momentarily on an object at least 20 feet away.</p>
<strong>
<p>Hands</p>
</strong> <strong> </strong>
<p>Spread fingers wide apart and hold for 10 seconds, form fists         for 10 seconds (repeat several times).<br /> Place hands together with fingers spread apart and fingertips at chin level. Slowly lower         hands, peel them apart, and reverse the process. Repeat several times.</p>
<strong>
<p>Neck</p>
</strong> <strong> </strong>
<p>Slowly turn head to side and hold for 10 seconds. Alternate         sides and repeat several times.<br /> Slowly tilt head to side and hold for 5-10 seconds.<br /> Alternate sides and repeat several times.</p>
<strong>
<p>Shoulders</p>
</strong> <strong> </strong>
<p>Slowly shrug shoulders in a forward circular motion.<br /> Alternate to reverse circular motion.</p>
<strong>
<p>Low Back</p>
</strong>
<p>With hands on hips and feet about shoulder width apart, slowly lean hips forward and         shoulders slightly back. Hold the stretch for 5-10 seconds.</p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x35774" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x17998" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
