<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.70 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<DetailPage ID="x67791" Name="General Services" Layout="default.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">General Services</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The BYU-Idaho Wellness Center provides health consultations and tests, such as: blood pressure, anthropometric measurements, body composition, cardiovascular VO2 max, flexibility, muscular strength, muscular endurance, nutrition analysis, bioimpedance, and blood lipid profile.</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="RelatedLinks" label="Related Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="RelatedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<strong>Take advantage of the opportunity to come into the Wellness Center for these FREE services:</strong><br /> 
<ul>
<li>Blood Pressure*</li>
<li>Anthropometric Measurements*</li>
<li>Body Composition*</li>
<li>Cardiovascular VO2 Max*</li>
<li>Flexibility*</li>
<li>Muscular Strength*</li>
<li>Muscular Endurance*</li>
<li>Nutrition Analysis</li>
<li>Bioimpedance ($1)</li>
<li>Blood Lipid Profile ($20)</li>
</ul>
<address>*Included in Full Assessment<br /> <br />--------------------------------------------------------------------------------</address>
<p><strong>Why it is Important to be Tested?</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Blood Pressure:</strong> High blood pressure usually has no symptoms. In fact, many people have this disease for years without knowing it. Having high blood pressure (hypertension) doesn't mean you're tense, nervous or hyperactive; you can be a calm, relaxed person and still have hypertension. A single high reading doesn't mean you have high blood pressure, but it's a sign that you need to watch it carefully.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Anthropometric Measurements (wt, ht, waist/hip ratio):</strong></p>
<p>The anthropometric measurements are commonly used as evaluation by comparing individual measurements to reference standards, represented by percentiles. It is most helpful to evaluate a pattern of measurements obtained on a regular basis over time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Body Composition</strong>:   Describes the different components that make up a person's body weight broken down into fat and lean weight (body fat percenatge). Levels of body fat seem to be related to performance. To increase or decrease your percent of body fat, you need to create the right balance between the calories you consume and the calories you burn. The most effective way to do this is increase your activity level. Aerobic exercise is a very effective way to decrease body fat, however you must combine strength training in order to maintain or gain muscle mass and tone.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Cardiovascular (VO2 Max):</strong> VO2 Max is used to classify cardio-respiratory fitness and is used to prescribe exercise programs.  It is a very simple way to figure out personal fitness status and allows you to evaluate your fitness changes over time. Using your VO2 Max to prescribe a fitness program will help you know how you can improve your cardiovascular fitness, or your ability to perform exercise that involves large muscle groups at moderate-to-high intensity for prolonged periods.  This is one of the most important components of physical fitness and should be checked every 3-4 months.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Flexibility:</strong> When done properly, stretching can do more than just increase flexibility. Benefits of stretching include: enhanced physical fitness, ability to learn and perform skilled movements, increased mental and physical relaxation, and reduced risk of injury to joints, muscles, and tendons. To measure your flexibility in these areas, a test called the Sit and Reach will be used.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Muscular Strength:</strong> The maximal amount of force that a muscle group can exert at one time. You'll see increases in your muscular strength as you are able to do 1 repetition of an exercise with a greater amount of resistance (or weight). Benefits of muscular fitness: ability to do more strenuous work, to do more work over a longer period of time, less susceptible to muscular fatigue, less injury prone, improved appearance and improve athletic performance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Muscular Endurance:</strong> Ability of a group of muscles to exert a sub-maximal force numerous times. Two tests commonly used to measure muscular endurance are push-ups and curl-ups. Push-ups measure upper body endurance and curl-ups measure mid torso endurance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Nutrition Analysis</strong>:   Learn proper portion sizes and balance in diet to include all nutrients for a healthy body. The Wellness Staff will meet with you weekly to set goals and plan strategies to get to them!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>BioImpedence:</strong> An undetectably low voltage electric current is sent up one leg and arm. Since fat is a very poor conductor of electricity, a lot of fat will impede the current more than a lot of lean tissue. By measuring the resistance to the current, the machine estimates the percent body fat. Testing itself takes less than a minute. There is a small fee but very reasonable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Cholesterol (Blood Lipid Level):</strong> As the heart beats, arteries expand as they are filled with blood. Once the heart relaxes, it produces enough force to push the blood through. When you have high cholesterol, you are put at much higher risk for coronary heart disease. This disease fills the arteries with fatty deposits that act as obstacles; in other words, the artery becomes clogged and the required blood cannot pass to adequately reach your heart. The good news is that we are able to find the level of your cholesterol. Make an appointment to get your blood lipid levels checked. There is a fee for this particular test, but we charge less than most doctors' offices and hospitals do for the same test.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>What is done with the information gathered?<br /></strong>A report of your fitness assessment will be discussed with you. To objectively identify areas that may require emphasis in your exercise prescription, consideration will be given to the established norms for various levels of physical fitness. The purpose of this assessment is not to place you in a fitness category. Rather, we feel it is more helpful to measure your current physical capacities and compare these with regularly scheduled fitness assessments overtime.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ImageComponent" Name="LeftColumnImageComponentList" label="Left Column Image Component List" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Component="" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x27624" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></DetailPage>
