<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EmptyShell ID="x67837" Name="pres clark.htm" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">pres clark.htm</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">pres clark.htm</Abstract><ESContent type="string" label="Content" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">&lt;html&gt;

&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=windows-1252"&gt;
&lt;title&gt;ANSWERING THE CALL&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
&lt;!--
 p.MsoNormal
	{mso-style-parent:"";
	margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	font-size:12.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:0in}
--&gt;
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" bgcolor="#000080" width="800" height="5929"&gt;
	&lt;!-- MSTableType="layout" --&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="middle" colspan="2"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentHead" --&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;
		&lt;font color="#FFFFFF" face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;ANSWERING THE CALL&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;
		&lt;font color="#FFFFFF" face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Kim B. Clark appointed 
		new president of&amp;nbsp; BYU–Idaho&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;
		&lt;font color="#FFFFFF" face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="center"&gt;
		&lt;font color="#FFFFFF" face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;By Marc Stevens&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="235"&gt;
		&lt;p align="center"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/Inauguration_3124mjl.jpg" width="360" height="235"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="417"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="NavBody" --&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/clark%20slice.jpg" width="150" height="415"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" rowspan="16" colspan="2"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentBody" --&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;“He is a man of tremendous 
		integrity who is deeply respected and admired. His colleagues describe 
		him as humble, thoughtful, measured, spontaneous, and true to his 
		convictions.” &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; With those words 
		President Gordon B. Hinckley introduced the students and faculty of 
		Brigham Young University–Idaho to their newly appointed president, Dr. 
		Kim B. Clark, then-dean of the Harvard Business School. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “I am deeply 
		honored to have been chosen for this important role,” President Clark 
		said during the June 6 announcement, broadcast by satellite from Boston 
		and Salt Lake City to Rexburg. “I am tremendously excited to be joining 
		BYU–Idaho, and I look forward to working with everyone in the community 
		in facing the opportunities that lie ahead.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Those 
		opportunities had presented themselves just two weeks before when 
		President Hinckley asked Clark if he would be interested in presiding 
		over BYU–Idaho. The position had become vacant several months before 
		when President David A. Bednar was called to serve as a member of the 
		Quorum of the Twelve Apostles. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; While at Harvard, 
		President Clark had kept a close eye on BYU–Idaho’s transition from 
		Ricks College, and he found himself intrigued by the groundbreaking work 
		being done at the university. That interest, combined with the 
		crossroads his career at Harvard had reached, made the decision easy. “I 
		thought both professionally and spiritually, and for our family, this 
		would be a wonderful opportunity,” President Clark said. “And so I said 
		I would be interested. And I meant it.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; From there, say 
		President Clark and his wife Sue, the blessings began to flow. His years 
		of academic and spiritual training began bearing new fruit in 
		preparation for the assignment of a lifetime. “I think there’s some kind 
		of orientation program for new presidents run by heaven,” President 
		Clark said. “There has to be. There’s a group up there probably 
		associated with the university in various ways who are responsible for 
		orienting a new president.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President Clark’s 
		preparation began very early on. He is the oldest of three children born 
		to Merlin and Helen Mar Clark. He spent his early childhood in Salt Lake 
		City, and when he was 11 the family moved to Spokane, Washington. The 
		teenaged Kim Clark stayed busy in high school, playing varsity baseball 
		and basketball. He also developed musical talents, playing bass guitar 
		and organ in a band. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But he found his 
		greatest satisfaction in the classroom. “From the time I was a little 
		boy growing up in Salt Lake City, to this very day, I have loved 
		school,” President Clark said at the BYU–Idaho Devotional the day after 
		his presidency was announced. “I love to learn, to discover new things, 
		and I love to teach. Schools and education have a special place in my 
		heart and, I believe, a special place in the Restoration and in the 
		Kingdom of God.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; That love of 
		learning led President Clark to Harvard University, where he was 
		accepted as a pre-med major in 1967. He struggled during his freshman 
		year, and as he left on a mission to Germany, he vowed he would not 
		return to Harvard. After finishing his mission, President Clark enrolled 
		at Brigham Young University for his sophomore year, where he flourished. 
		“I loved my year at BYU so much,” he recalled. “I had such great 
		teachers and, of course, I met Sue.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sue Hunt was a 
		young lady from the tiny town of Waterflow, New Mexico, and one of the 
		“sisters” in President Clark’s family home evening group at BYU. They 
		made Sunday dinner together one evening and have been together ever 
		since. President Clark married Sue—whom he describes as “the love of my 
		life” — in 1971, eventually bringing seven children into the world.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; With married life 
		just getting under way, President Clark decided to give Harvard another 
		chance. He returned to Boston, changed his major to economics, and 
		earned a bachelor’s degree in 1974. A master’s degree followed in 1977 
		and a doctorate in 1978. With a lifelong passion for education that 
		never waned, President Clark joined the faculty of Harvard Business 
		School that year.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And so began a 
		remarkable teaching and administrative career that would span nearly 
		three decades. President Clark taught at HBS for 27 years including 10 
		years as dean. He pushed initiatives to strengthen the school’s research 
		and educational programs and to improve its campus. Faculty grew by 20 
		percent under President Clark’s leadership, and he succeeded in raising 
		the HBS endowment from $550 million to nearly &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;$2 billion. He authored 
		several books and papers on topics such as technology, productivity, and 
		product development.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But perhaps the 
		most high-profile achievement of his administration came just last year, 
		when he took a firm stance against the scandals at major corporations 
		like Enron and WorldCom by introducing mandatory ethics classes for HBS 
		students. “We learned that it is not enough to have high standards; it’s 
		not enough even to teach about the importance of and create awareness in 
		the students about the issues,” President Clark said. “You have to equip 
		students with frameworks, concepts and tools that allow them to take 
		fairly complicated situations, break them down, and understand what is 
		at stake.” He believes ethical behavior is simply a matter of living 
		correct principles and says the idea holds true everywhere, from the 
		boardrooms of corporate America, to the Harvard Business School, to BYU–Idaho. 
		“Apply your values and principles in an effective way to come to a good 
		resolution of the issue,” he said.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President Clark’s 
		push for ethical training at HBS would become something of a punctuation 
		mark on his tenure there because several months later the call to leave 
		Harvard and assume the presidency of BYU–Idaho came. He admits it was a 
		bittersweet decision. “I think I was part of one of the very finest 
		institutions in the world,” he said. “Harvard Business School is a 
		remarkable institution, extraordinarily well run by great people.” But 
		President Clark also knew the time had come to move on. “It’s not easy 
		to leave, but ten years is about the right time for deans to serve,” he 
		said on the day of his announcement as president. “So when this 
		opportunity to become president of BYU–Idaho came, I felt that the time 
		was right.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But word of 
		President Clark’s decision to leave Harvard sent a shock wave through 
		many parts of the academic and business communities. Leaders of 
		universities and corporations alike were left scratching their heads. 
		How could anyone walk away from such a prestigious post—without 
		hesitation—to lead a new and relatively unknown university in rural 
		Idaho? It defied conventional wisdom. But President Clark was unfazed by 
		the dropping jaws and puzzled looks.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “I expected some 
		people to be completely baffled and shocked that I would go to BYU–Idaho,” 
		he said. “It’s the reaction I would have had five years ago. It doesn’t 
		make any sense because the world is organized around a set of ideas 
		about progression, careers, and what people do.” &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But like all 
		Church universities, BYU–Idaho does not follow the world’s pattern. Its 
		course is charted by a higher authority, and President Clark knows 
		exactly where the call to trade Boston for Rexburg came from. “He didn’t 
		gloss over any of the reasons why he came to BYU–Idaho,” Sister Clark 
		said, referring to his final State of the School address at Harvard. “He 
		told about getting the call from President Hinckley and that in our 
		church we hold him to be the prophet of God—and when the prophet calls, 
		you go.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “I wanted people 
		to really know what we are doing and what this place is really about,” 
		President Clark said, “and I don’t think we have to apologize to 
		anybody.” His eagerness to answer the call to lead BYU–Idaho has even 
		developed into something of a missionary tool. “Many people have told me 
		others are now talking to them about the Church, about why this 
		happened,” President Clark said. “It’s been a really positive thing.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President and 
		Sister Clark also have no reservations about leaving Boston, their home 
		of 34 years, to come to Rexburg. “We did find many wonderful people 
		there, in and out of the Church,” President Clark said of Boston. “We 
		liked living there and partook of different aspects of it.” But after so 
		many years of big city life, Rexburg appears to be a good fit for the 
		Clarks. “It’s just been terrific to be here,” President Clark said, 
		crediting his and Sister Clark’s Western roots for the easy transition. 
		“I was born out here, so it doesn’t feel foreign to us at all. It feels 
		very comfortable and very familiar. The people are so wonderful.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President Clark 
		comes to Rexburg with a clear and simple vision for BYU–Idaho; a vision 
		shaped by the direction given to him by Church leaders. “Our job is to 
		make this a great university,” he said, “in the image that the Lord 
		wants it to be.” And not surprisingly, President Clark’s own personal 
		desires for the university he is now responsible for closely mirror the 
		charge from the Brethren. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “It might sound a 
		little bit like platitude, but it’s true; my fondest, deepest hope for 
		this place is that it will become everything the Lord wants it to be,” 
		President Clark said. “It’s an interesting thing to try to understand 
		what the Lord wants done. Whose will is it? Where do we need to take the 
		university in the grand scheme of things? We’ll try to do His work, and 
		if we do that, this place will be a phenomenon. It’ll be great.” &lt;/font&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The university 
		President Clark inherits is just five years into a sweeping 
		transformation. BYU–Idaho has turned heads over the past few years by 
		quickly and efficiently adding nearly 50 new bachelor’s degree programs 
		and implementing an innovative academic calendar. Several new buildings 
		have been added, and others are being renovated. It’s an enormous task 
		to take on, but President Clark feels comfortable with the pace and 
		progress of the transition from Ricks College and believes BYU–Idaho’s 
		best days are still ahead. “I think the university is really in great 
		shape,” he said. “I think the work that has been done has been excellent 
		and the foundation is strong. I think people can come here in confidence 
		that they will find a place that is on the right track. That’s my 
		assessment of the university.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; For President 
		Clark being on the right track includes implementing an educational 
		principle he feels very strongly about: understanding how students learn 
		and helping them do it better. “I believe education is a developmental 
		process. It’s not just about imparting knowledge to people; it’s about 
		developing,” President Clark said. “We need to understand how people 
		change and grow so we can do more, be more effective, and create higher 
		quality experiences for the students.” And he believes that involves 
		much more than just what happens inside the classroom. “In this 
		university, it’s about developing the whole person. Developing 
		spiritually, personally, emotionally, socially, intellectually—all 
		aspects of their character,” he said. “That they truly become the kind 
		of disciple the Lord wants them to be.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Helping everyone 
		associated with BYU–Idaho become a disciple of Jesus Christ is one of 
		the university’s core missions. And as he begins his administration, 
		President Clark pledges to the alumni of Ricks College and BYU–Idaho 
		that the disciple creation process will start at the top. “I want the 
		alumni to know that I will live my life close to the Spirit and have the 
		constant companionship of the Holy Ghost,” he said. “I will always be in 
		perfect alignment with President Hinckley and the Brethren, and I will 
		do everything I can to help this university realize its glorious 
		destiny.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; A destiny 
		President Clark hopes all Ricks College and BYU–Idaho alumni will be 
		part of and share with others: “When someone asks where they went to 
		school and they say BYU–Idaho, I want people to say ‘that’s great.’ BYU–Idaho 
		will always be a place they will be proud of.”” Those opportunities had 
		presented themselves just two weeks before when President Hinckley asked 
		Clark if he would be interested in presiding over BYU–Idaho. The 
		position had become vacant several months before when President David A. 
		Bednar was called to serve as a member of the Quorum of the Twelve 
		Apostles. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; While at Harvard, 
		President Clark had kept a close eye on BYU–Idaho’s transition from 
		Ricks College, and he found himself intrigued by the groundbreaking work 
		being done at the university. That interest, combined with the 
		crossroads his career at Harvard had reached, made the decision easy. “I 
		thought both professionally and spiritually, and for our family, this 
		would be a wonderful opportunity,” President Clark said. “And so I said 
		I would be interested. And I meant it.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; From there, say 
		President Clark and his wife Sue, the blessings began to flow. His years 
		of academic and spiritual training began bearing new fruit in 
		preparation for the assignment of a lifetime. “I think there’s some kind 
		of orientation program for new presidents run by heaven,” President 
		Clark said. “There has to be. There’s a group up there probably 
		associated with the university in various ways who are responsible for 
		orienting a new president.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President Clark’s 
		preparation began very early on. He is the oldest of three children born 
		to Merlin and Helen Mar Clark. He spent his early childhood in Salt Lake 
		City, and when he was 11 the family moved to Spokane, Washington. The 
		teenaged Kim Clark stayed busy in high school, playing varsity baseball 
		and basketball. He also developed musical talents, playing bass guitar 
		and organ in a band. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But he found his 
		greatest satisfaction in the classroom. “From the time I was a little 
		boy growing up in Salt Lake City, to this very day, I have loved 
		school,” President Clark said at the BYU–Idaho Devotional the day after 
		his presidency was announced. “I love to learn, to discover new things, 
		and I love to teach. Schools and education have a special place in my 
		heart and, I believe, a special place in the Restoration and in the 
		Kingdom of God.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; That love of 
		learning led President Clark to Harvard University, where he was 
		accepted as a pre-med major in 1967. He struggled during his freshman 
		year, and as he left on a mission to Germany, he vowed he would not 
		return to Harvard. After finishing his mission, President Clark enrolled 
		at Brigham Young University for his sophomore year, where he flourished. 
		“I loved my year at BYU so much,” he recalled. “I had such great 
		teachers and, of course, I met Sue.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sue Hunt was a 
		young lady from the tiny town of Waterflow, New Mexico, and one of the 
		“sisters” in President Clark’s family home evening group at BYU. They 
		made Sunday dinner together one evening and have been together ever 
		since. President Clark married Sue—whom he describes as “the love of my 
		life” — in 1971, eventually bringing seven children into the world.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; With married life 
		just getting under way, President Clark decided to give Harvard another 
		chance. He returned to Boston, changed his major to economics, and 
		earned a bachelor’s degree in 1974. A master’s degree followed in 1977 
		and a doctorate in 1978. With a lifelong passion for education that 
		never waned, President Clark joined the faculty of Harvard Business 
		School that year.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And so began a 
		remarkable teaching and administrative career that would span nearly 
		three decades. President Clark taught at HBS for 27 years including 10 
		years as dean. He pushed initiatives to strengthen the school’s research 
		and educational programs and to improve its campus. Faculty grew by 20 
		percent under President Clark’s leadership, and he succeeded in raising 
		the HBS endowment from $550 million to nearly &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;$2 billion. He authored 
		several books and papers on topics such as technology, productivity, and 
		product development.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But perhaps the 
		most high-profile achievement of his administration came just last year, 
		when he took a firm stance against the scandals at major corporations 
		like Enron and WorldCom by introducing mandatory ethics classes for HBS 
		students. “We learned that it is not enough to have high standards; it’s 
		not enough even to teach about the importance of and create awareness in 
		the students about the issues,” President Clark said. “You have to equip 
		students with frameworks, concepts and tools that allow them to take 
		fairly complicated situations, break them down, and understand what is 
		at stake.” He believes ethical behavior is simply a matter of living 
		correct principles and says the idea holds true everywhere, from the 
		boardrooms of corporate America, to the Harvard Business School, to BYU–Idaho. 
		“Apply your values and principles in an effective way to come to a good 
		resolution of the issue,” he said.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President Clark’s 
		push for ethical training at HBS would become something of a punctuation 
		mark on his tenure there because several months later the call to leave 
		Harvard and assume the presidency of BYU–Idaho came. He admits it was a 
		bittersweet decision. “I think I was part of one of the very finest 
		institutions in the world,” he said. “Harvard Business School is a 
		remarkable institution, extraordinarily well run by great people.” But 
		President Clark also knew the time had come to move on. “It’s not easy 
		to leave, but ten years is about the right time for deans to serve,” he 
		said on the day of his announcement as president. “So when this 
		opportunity to become president of BYU–Idaho came, I felt that the time 
		was right.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But word of 
		President Clark’s decision to leave Harvard sent a shock wave through 
		many parts of the academic and business communities. Leaders of 
		universities and corporations alike were left scratching their heads. 
		How could anyone walk away from such a prestigious post—without 
		hesitation—to lead a new and relatively unknown university in rural 
		Idaho? It defied conventional wisdom. But President Clark was unfazed by 
		the dropping jaws and puzzled looks.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “I expected some 
		people to be completely baffled and shocked that I would go to BYU–Idaho,” 
		he said. “It’s the reaction I would have had five years ago. It doesn’t 
		make any sense because the world is organized around a set of ideas 
		about progression, careers, and what people do.” &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But like all 
		Church universities, BYU–Idaho does not follow the world’s pattern. Its 
		course is charted by a higher authority, and President Clark knows 
		exactly where the call to trade Boston for Rexburg came from. “He didn’t 
		gloss over any of the reasons why he came to BYU–Idaho,” Sister Clark 
		said, referring to his final State of the School address at Harvard. “He 
		told about getting the call from President Hinckley and that in our 
		church we hold him to be the prophet of God—and when the prophet calls, 
		you go.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “I wanted people 
		to really know what we are doing and what this place is really about,” 
		President Clark said, “and I don’t think we have to apologize to 
		anybody.” His eagerness to answer the call to lead BYU–Idaho has even 
		developed into something of a missionary tool. “Many people have told me 
		others are now talking to them about the Church, about why this 
		happened,” President Clark said. “It’s been a really positive thing.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President and 
		Sister Clark also have no reservations about leaving Boston, their home 
		of 34 years, to come to Rexburg. “We did find many wonderful people 
		there, in and out of the Church,” President Clark said of Boston. “We 
		liked living there and partook of different aspects of it.” But after so 
		many years of big city life, Rexburg appears to be a good fit for the 
		Clarks. “It’s just been terrific to be here,” President Clark said, 
		crediting his and Sister Clark’s Western roots for the easy transition. 
		“I was born out here, so it doesn’t feel foreign to us at all. It feels 
		very comfortable and very familiar. The people are so wonderful.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President Clark 
		comes to Rexburg with a clear and simple vision for BYU–Idaho; a vision 
		shaped by the direction given to him by Church leaders. “Our job is to 
		make this a great university,” he said, “in the image that the Lord 
		wants it to be.” And not surprisingly, President Clark’s own personal 
		desires for the university he is now responsible for closely mirror the 
		charge from the Brethren. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “It might sound a 
		little bit like platitude, but it’s true; my fondest, deepest hope for 
		this place is that it will become everything the Lord wants it to be,” 
		President Clark said. “It’s an interesting thing to try to understand 
		what the Lord wants done. Whose will is it? Where do we need to take the 
		university in the grand scheme of things? We’ll try to do His work, and 
		if we do that, this place will be a phenomenon. It’ll be great.” &lt;/font&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The university 
		President Clark inherits is just five years into a sweeping 
		transformation. BYU–Idaho has turned heads over the past few years by 
		quickly and efficiently adding nearly 50 new bachelor’s degree programs 
		and implementing an innovative academic calendar. Several new buildings 
		have been added, and others are being renovated. It’s an enormous task 
		to take on, but President Clark feels comfortable with the pace and 
		progress of the transition from Ricks College and believes BYU–Idaho’s 
		best days are still ahead. “I think the university is really in great 
		shape,” he said. “I think the work that has been done has been excellent 
		and the foundation is strong. I think people can come here in confidence 
		that they will find a place that is on the right track. That’s my 
		assessment of the university.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; For President 
		Clark being on the right track includes implementing an educational 
		principle he feels very strongly about: understanding how students learn 
		and helping them do it better. “I believe education is a developmental 
		process. It’s not just about imparting knowledge to people; it’s about 
		developing,” President Clark said. “We need to understand how people 
		change and grow so we can do more, be more effective, and create higher 
		quality experiences for the students.” And he believes that involves 
		much more than just what happens inside the classroom. “In this 
		university, it’s about developing the whole person. Developing 
		spiritually, personally, emotionally, socially, intellectually—all 
		aspects of their character,” he said. “That they truly become the kind 
		of disciple the Lord wants them to be.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Helping everyone 
		associated with BYU–Idaho become a disciple of Jesus Christ is one of 
		the university’s core missions. And as he begins his administration, 
		President Clark pledges to the alumni of Ricks College and BYU–Idaho 
		that the disciple creation process will start at the top. “I want the 
		alumni to know that I will live my life close to the Spirit and have the 
		constant companionship of the Holy Ghost,” he said. “I will always be in 
		perfect alignment with President Hinckley and the Brethren, and I will 
		do everything I can to help this university realize its glorious 
		destiny.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; A destiny 
		President Clark hopes all Ricks College and BYU–Idaho alumni will be 
		part of and share with others: “When someone asks where they went to 
		school and they say BYU–Idaho, I want people to say ‘that’s great.’ BYU–Idaho 
		will always be a place they will be proud of.” &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;In the News…&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;“The fact that such an 
		accomplished soul would—in the words of church President Gordon B. 
		Hinckley—‘trade the halls of Harvard for a view of the Grand Teton 
		Mountains’—should be an obvious sign to BYU–Idaho students and faculty 
		of the man’s humility and his personal priorities. He is, to the core, a 
		man of integrity and faith. Ironically, his brain-trust Harvard 
		colleagues were much more befuddled by his decision than BYU–Idaho 
		freshmen.”- &lt;i&gt;Deseret Morning News&lt;/i&gt; editorial&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;“Since he came to Harvard as 
		a freshman in 1967, Harvard Business School Dean Kim Clark has left the 
		university only once—to serve as a Mormon missionary in Germany. Now, at 
		56, Clark is once again answering the call of his church. On June 6 he 
		announced he’s leaving Harvard to become president of Mormon-affiliated 
		Brigham Young University–Idaho in Rexburg.”- &lt;i&gt;BusinessWeek&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;“The changes [President 
		Clark] foresees for the university … will be the steady and upward 
		course the university has been heading since the transition to a 
		four-year institution. That steady course is the hallmark and theme of [BYU–Idaho] 
		and what the school will be known for.”- &lt;i&gt;Rexburg Standard Journal&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;“Clark described the job as a 
		challenge—particularly in holding onto the legacy of Ricks College and 
		BYU–Idaho while propelling it into the future.”- Idaho Falls &lt;i&gt;Post 
		Register&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;Inauguration…&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;Pledging to pursue the 
		mission of Brigham Young University–Idaho with “every bit of energy and 
		ability,” Kim B. Clark was formally installed as president at inaugural 
		ceremonies in the Hart Auditorium on October 11. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “I know that with 
		all of us working as one, with the inspired guidance of the Board, this 
		university will move forward on the steady, upward course the Lord has 
		set,” President Clark said in his response to President Gordon B. 
		Hinckley’s installation and charge. “It will be a university true to its 
		heritage, true to its mission, everything the Lord wants it to be.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; President 
		Hinckley presided at the inauguration, joined by his counselors in the 
		First Presidency, President Thomas S. Monson and President James E. 
		Faust. “We are so richly blessed to have you presiding over this 
		institution,” President Hinckley said. “You are recognized for your 
		abilities across the world. Now you have been kind enough to come here, 
		to build this university.” Several members of the Board of Trustees and 
		the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles were also present, including Elder 
		David A. Bednar, former BYU–Idaho president.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Other dignitaries 
		taking part in the inauguration included Dirk Kempthorne, Governor of 
		Idaho, who described BYU–Idaho as “one of the gems of the Gem State,” 
		and Lawrence H. Summers, president of Harvard University and President 
		Clark’s colleague of some 30 years. After praising President Clark’s 
		leadership at Harvard, President Summers lightheartedly lamented his 
		departure from the school, calling it “bittersweet news for Harvard—but 
		wonderful news for your university, and for all who care about American 
		higher education and the character of those who lead its institutions.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="508"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="122"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/clark%20family%20small.jpg" width="150" height="120"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="485"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="466"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/clark%20slice3.jpg" width="150" height="466"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="465"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="98"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/presandsisclark%20small.jpg" width="150" height="98"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="450"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="390"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/clark%20slice2.jpg" width="150" height="390"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="485"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="101"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/standing-group.jpg" width="150" height="99"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="521"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="340"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/clarkhinckley%20slice.jpg" width="150" height="340"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="494"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="239"&gt;
		&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/clarkscriptures-small.jpg" width="150" height="239"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td height="58"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" colspan="3" height="51"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentFoot" --&gt;
		&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;
		&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="4" color="#FFFFFF"&gt;
&lt;a href="x51289.xml"&gt;&lt;font color="#FFFFFF"&gt;[Table of 
		Contents]&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td width="150"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td width="210"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td height="2" width="432"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;

&lt;/html&gt;</ESContent></EmptyShell>
