<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EmptyShell ID="x67835" Name="rethinkingeducation.htm" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">rethinkingeducation.htm</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">rethinkingeducation.htm</Abstract><ESContent type="string" label="Content" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">&lt;html&gt;

&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=windows-1252"&gt;
&lt;title&gt;Cover to Cover&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
&lt;!--
 p.MsoNormal
	{mso-style-parent:"";
	margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	font-size:12.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:0in}
--&gt;
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="800" height="3684" bgcolor="#EAEAEA"&gt;
	&lt;!-- MSTableType="layout" --&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top" rowspan="4" width="39" height="3684"&gt;
	&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="1" --&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#000080" colspan="2" height="1"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td valign="top" width="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
			&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#000080" height="100%" width="1"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
	&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" rowspan="4" width="9"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="middle" bgcolor="#FFFFFF"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="DecArea" --&gt;
		&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/harvesting-dreams-small.jpg" width="90" height="90"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" bgcolor="#FFFFFF"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentHead" --&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rethinking Education:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Harvesting Dreams&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;ByLaNae Hammon Poulter ’71&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" rowspan="4" width="9"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top" rowspan="4" width="40" height="3684"&gt;
	&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="2" --&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#000080" colspan="2" height="1"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#000080" width="1"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td valign="top" height="100%" width="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
			&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
	&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td height="105"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" colspan="2"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentBody" --&gt;
		&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;How do you harvest a dream? Envision vistas of beautiful 
plants, animals in all their varieties, and personal health to enjoy and 
appreciate the surroundings. Before the harvest are seasons of planting and 
nurturing&lt;sub&gt;.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;The College of Agriculture and Life Sciences at Brigham 
Young University–Idaho is developing students who make dreams come true for 
themselves and others. The college consists of six departments dedicated to the 
study of agriculture, animal science, biology, health sciences, horticulture, 
and nursing. A closer look reveals a nurturing environment and a promising 
future. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Department of Health Science Expands Experiences&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Starting a new program is never a simple task. The 
Department of Health Science got a jump start with a new medical assisting 
program by bringing in Edith Hamlin, an expert with 15 years of experience as 
director of a similar program at LDS Business College in Salt Lake City. Her new 
assignment at BYU–Idaho is to develop a top-notch program that will lead to its 
national accreditation through the Commission of Accreditation of Allied Health 
Education Programs. CAAHEP standards and guidelines are used as the framework 
for the rigorous review process. The new program’s courses are scheduled to 
begin Winter Semester 2006. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Health Science students find increased value in 
their study through internship experience. Placements in public health, health 
promotion, and other similar professions are being explored near and far. 
Location is a major consideration since internship travel and lodging are 
typically funded by the students. Multiple sites have been identified in 
Arizona, Montana, Washington, and Nevada along with some in South America. 
Faculty members recently traveled to Honduras to interact with health and 
medical personnel and to determine the potential for internships and 
humanitarian projects. Through these and other contacts about potential 
internships, the faculty gain relevant awareness of what the field is looking 
for and how to better prepare their students. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On-campus programs incorporate necessary skills 
into hands-on experiences for students through organizations such as the 
Wellness Center, located in the John W. Hart Building. The center offers 
one-on-one consultation for better personal health. The trainers are students 
such as Dora Alarcon from Xalapa, Veracruz, Mexico, who recently interned in 
Peru. The senior health science major has returned to campus and now shares her 
insights with others. “I have been able to reinforce what I am learning in my 
classes,” she observes. “I am applying it on a daily basis as I am able to help 
people and give them advice and some guidance.”&amp;nbsp; Alarcon also realizes personal 
benefits of her education and experience. “If I have good health and am eating a 
balanced diet, I am more likely to be able to do the things I enjoy,” she says.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Department of Agronomy and Agriculture Business 
&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Explores Options&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;The Department of Agronomy and Agriculture Business 
prepares students for exciting and challenging employment specialties. Graduates 
will manage diverse agricultural resources, research crop production, develop 
new biotechnology, handle agribusiness finance, or teach in community and 
secondary education settings.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Training for the students comes from case 
studies&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;and practical, “hands on” experience provided by their work 
on the university farm, practicums, and internships. Some students accept 
internships in locations such as Africa and Mexico where they are exposed to the 
diversity of the agriculture industry worldwide. In addition, an annual academic 
excursion to California gives students the opportunity to visit various stages 
in the production of commodities such as rice, prunes, figs, kiwis, lettuce, 
walnuts, cauliflower, and other specialty crops. Through the experience “their 
minds are expanded to various alternative methods and cultural practices,” says 
Stephen McGary ’73, dean of the College of Agriculture and Life Science.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The department has modified curriculum and 
resources to prepare students for the twenty-first century and beyond. The 
department’s technology coursework puts greater emphasis in electronic 
computerized systems and hydraulics, utilizing global positioning and geographic 
information systems (GPS/GIS). The plant science curriculum has grown and is now 
embracing hydroponics technologies with enhanced emphasis in the sciences. 
Agribusiness curriculum has expanded to include greater resource management 
concepts, including enhanced finance and economic rigor. In fall of 2006 the 
department will be renamed to reflect the change in emphasis as the Department 
of Agribusiness, Science, and Technology.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Department of Animal Science Advances Opportunities&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;BYU–Idaho is the only Church-operated institution of higher 
learning in the United States that has an animal science program. The Department 
of Animal Science is housed primarily at the Livestock Center five miles west of 
Rexburg. While it remains one of the smaller departments on campus, the number 
of students majoring in animal science has more than doubled in the last four 
years. In addition to courses primarily taken by agriculture students—such as 
animal nutrition, health, meats, reproduction, and genetics—enrichment classes 
offered through the program are enjoyed by hundreds of other students. Beginning 
riding classes, trail riding, and horseback field biology classes all use Animal 
Science horses. These horses also provide trail and carriage rides for the 
Activities Program.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The center currently encompasses 130 acres with 
crops to feed cattle, horses, and sheep; an indoor arena; animal laboratory; 
feedlot pens; and a meat processing laboratory where students evaluate and 
prepare animal products according to industry practices. Last year students 
worked to feed, evaluate, and sell steers donated to the university as market 
beef with proceeds going to scholarships and academic improvements. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Scientific advances are blended into the 
curriculum as they develop. For example the cow herd is partially composed of 
genetically-superior beef and dairy cattle. The calves from these top-grade 
animals are marketed as breeding stock by the students. The offspring of the 
superior herd are multiplied by having other cattle serve as surrogate mothers 
who receive embryos from the higher-value donor cows. These surrogates then give 
birth to the valuable, but unrelated, calves. Another scientific advancement is 
the recently employed ultrasound technology enabling the faculty and students to 
assess the meat characteristics and genetics of live animals. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Animal science majors fill internships 
throughout the United States and overseas in beef, dairy, horse, and swine 
operations; veterinary clinics; Disney World; hippotherapy centers; dude 
ranches; government rangeland positions; and agriculture-serving businesses. 
&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Department of Biology Finds Success&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;The Biology Department is enjoying new classrooms and 
state-of-the-art teaching laboratories created in the recent Ezra Taft Benson 
Building addition. With the acquisition of new laboratory equipment, students 
are learning the latest techniques in molecular biology and genetics. Integrated 
degrees allow students to design programs that best fit their career goals. 
Students choose fields of study ranging from botany and ecology to human biology 
and neuroscience to biology education.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Biology majors are encouraged to find 
internships with opportunities for research experience. In summer of 2005 alone, 
87 biology students interned in a variety of settings. Upon completion of their 
experience, many students receive invitations to give departmental seminars and 
report their findings. This return-and-report process strengthens their learning 
experience and serves as active research into the market for future career 
choices.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Mike Groesbeck, chair of Department of Biology, 
feels the students are receiving a useful education in biology. He says, 
“Although we are very new as a university, our students are finding success in 
getting into professional schools and graduate schools. Our acceptance rate to 
medical and dental school is well above the national average, and most students 
applying to graduate schools are being accepted.” He is quick to point out much 
of the success is due to the quality of students. “Combine these fine students 
with a dedicated, caring faculty, and great things are happening at BYU–Idaho,” 
says Groesbeck.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Department of Horticulture Nurtures Growth&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;President Gordon B. Hinckley specifically challenged 
individuals to nurture the skills of gardening, become self sufficient, beautify 
surroundings, and help those in need within the community and around the world. 
BYU–Idaho horticulture faculty and students take the challenge to heart.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Department of Horticulture traditionally 
brings horticulture industries and technology into the classroom—but the 
classroom extends far beyond the brick walls of the Benson Building. Department 
Chair Ben Romney explains, “We are blessed with state-of-the-art greenhouses and 
acres of gardens where our students are able to experience and practice the 
principles taught in their coursework.” Students also have opportunities to 
travel to parts of the world where horticulture can be observed and studied. 
&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Romney identifies the central aim of the 
Horticulture Department as a combination of secular and spiritual education. In 
a nurturing environment students gain an understanding of the spiritual and 
scientific aspects of creation by working with plants. They develop habits of 
hard work and appreciation for the world around them. “Students connect with 
many of life’s lessons, particularly the law of sowing seed and of the harvest,” 
Romney says. “Our focus is on teaching students to make their living by helping 
others surround themselves with places of peace and beauty and to produce the 
essential horticultural products they need to live.” &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Department of Nursing Rethinks Programs&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;For the past five years, the Department of Nursing has 
conscientiously fulfilled the assignment to rethink education. The bachelor’s of 
science degree in nursing (BSN) was one of the first bachelor’s degrees offered 
at BYU–Idaho. Programs were developed so students with their associate degree in 
nursing could take three more semesters’ worth of classes and earn their 
bachelor’s degree. Department Chair Kathy Oldham Barnhill ’81 says student needs 
require diverse methods for making content accessible. New options were recently 
adopted. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “Because many associate graduates will leave 
the BYU–Idaho campus and travel throughout the world to work, we felt it was 
important to make our program available online as well as on campus,” Barnhill 
says. “Students may take courses on campus or online through the Division of 
Continuing Education. By allowing this type of flexibility, students are able to 
work full time all over the United States and still continue their education.” 
All of the BSN nursing courses are offered online along with all but two of the 
general education courses required for that degree.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The new option worked for Paula Thomas Spencer 
’04 as she re-entered the nursing program after graduating with an associate 
degree from Ricks College 27 years prior. She had already accumulated a diverse 
background of experience in community and hospital settings and was now able to 
complete her bachelor’s degree in nursing from her home in Victorville, Calif. 
“It was a difficult program, but it was well worth it. The instructors were 
there to encourage and to fine tune any weaknesses,” Spencer says. “Because it 
is BYU–Idaho, you get a glimmer of the ‘Spirit of Ricks.’&amp;nbsp; Through the 
opportunity to work with the professors and with the other students, you feel 
the influence of the Spirit.”&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The Department of Nursing also answers the need 
to accommodate local students. A program taught primarily evenings and on 
weekends meets needs of the non-traditional students. For the past two years, 20 
students have been admitted into the program per year. Offered through the 
Division of Continuing Education, the non-traditional program has been 
beneficial to local hospital facilities; it allows people from the area who will 
stay and work for an extended period of time to get training in a much-needed 
profession.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;Looking Beyond the Harvest&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;As the students in the College of Agriculture and Life 
Sciences realize their dream of graduation, they are prepared to make a 
difference. Employment opportunities abound for those who prepare well. Some 
will teach in the public school system while others will work in the business 
arena. Their leadership and example will promote wise and responsible 
stewardship of divinely endowed natural resources and biological (ecological) 
systems. Through their employment, they will contribute to a safe, abundant food 
and fiber supply and promote the well-being and health of individuals, families, 
and communities. Their efforts will enhance sustainability of agricultural and 
economic systems. Ultimately as they return to their homes worldwide, they will 
influence others to harvest their own dreams of beauty, health, enjoyment, and 
education. SM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td height="3525"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" colspan="2"&gt;
		&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="4"&gt;&lt;u&gt;
		&lt;a href="x51289.xml"&gt;[Table of 
		Contents]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td height="53"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td width="141"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td width="560"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td height="1" width="2"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;

&lt;/html&gt;</ESContent></EmptyShell>
