<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.89 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<EmptyShell ID="x67841" Name="merely.hm" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">merely.hm</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">merely.hm</Abstract><ESContent type="string" label="Content" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">&lt;html&gt;

&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=windows-1252"&gt;
&lt;title&gt;Merely A Teacher&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
&lt;!--
 p.MsoNormal
	{mso-style-parent:"";
	margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	font-size:12.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:0in}
--&gt;
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="798" height="1992" bgcolor="#DBCC5A"&gt;
	&lt;!-- MSTableType="layout" --&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top" align="center" colspan="2"&gt;
	&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="8" --&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" colspan="2" height="2"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="2" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" width="2"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="2" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td valign="top" align="center" height="100%" width="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
			&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/merely-title.jpg" width="259" height="125"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
	&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
	&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="7" --&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" height="2"&gt;
			&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="2" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td valign="top" height="100%" width="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
			&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/childrens%20hands.jpg" width="97" height="125" align="right"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
	&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td valign="top" colspan="2" height="127"&gt;
	&lt;img border="0" src="images/BYUI Upward/fall2005/ettering.jpg" width="434" height="127"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="NavBody" --&gt;
		&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="2" --&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" width="2"&gt;
				&lt;img alt="" width="2" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td valign="top" height="100%" width="100%"&gt;
				&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/table&gt;
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" colspan="3" height="1817"&gt;
		&lt;!-- MSCellType="ContentBody" --&gt;
		&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="3" --&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td valign="top" height="100%" width="100%"&gt;
				&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="3"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="3"&gt;Joyce 
Anderson - Department of Teacher Education&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal" align="left"&gt;
				&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;Deep down I think I always wanted to be a teacher. Not that I 
				didn’t have other dreams—working in the sands of Egypt digging 
				for as-yet-unimagined treasures that would change man’s 
				knowledge of history, or maybe spending years at my Smith Corona 
				portable electric typewriter, capturing in words the essence of 
				life in such simplicity that it would become the next great 
				American novel. Oh, I had big dreams. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				At the same time my real-life experiences were building within 
				me an awareness of what I truly admired. Influential mentors 
				showed me the learning process has meaningful and lasting 
				results. My vision of teacher was beginning to be defined.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				Years later, I was ready. Armed with two degrees certifying that 
				I knew content and pedagogy, two student teaching experiences 
				that attested to competence, on-the-job decision making practice 
				that comes from being the mother of six young children, and a 
				conviction that I could make a difference in the world, one 
				child at a time, I anticipated that first day of school even 
				more than the children who were assigned to my charge. I was 
				ready for anything and everything...or so I thought. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				But my vision of public education and the reality of public 
				education rarely proved a match. Commitment, hard work, 
				perseverance, and dedication were all traits that I worked to 
				embed into my persona of teacher. But they were not enough! Over 
				the next thirteen years, I continued to pursue the scholarly 
				approach to learning and teaching. Yet something was missing 
				from my intellectual education. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				• I had been taught classroom management skills...but wasn’t 
				sure what to do when a second-grader was inextricably wrapped 
				around the legs of a classroom table, holding his teachers and 
				classmates at bay with his profanity, and daring me (now an 
				administrator) to do something about it. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				• I had been taught the importance of accessing prior knowledge 
				and setting the stage for learning...but didn’t know how to 
				relate the student’s tale of a drug raid and the cops and the 
				whizzing bullets and hiding under the mattress for hours until 
				it was safe to come out to our study of the weather. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				• I had learned about diversity and cultural identity...but 
				realized how little I truly understood as a student I loved sat 
				next to me in my office, waiting for the police to arrive and 
				explaining that I didn’t understand—he had to beat another 
				student with the metal pipe because if he hadn’t, he could never 
				return to the projects where he lived. (The other student had 
				made a negative comment about this boy’s mother.) &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				• I had been trained to work with parents for the benefit of 
				children...but no one had mentioned how to respond when, during 
				a conference, a parent stated in front of her child, “I don’t 
				want him.... I never wanted him,” and I was looking into the 
				eyes of that child.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				So now I am at BYU–Idaho, working with other faculty to send new 
				teachers on a journey that will bring them some of their 
				greatest moments of satisfaction and accomplishment blended with 
				their greatest moments of frustration and sadness. To prepare 
				them for this journey, we teach our students content... we teach 
				pedagogy...we teach language and management and motivation. Yet 
				because we are at BYU–Idaho, we have the right and the 
				responsibility to teach and model those things that transcend 
				secular knowledge and embody the gospel of Jesus Christ. &lt;/font&gt;
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				One of our missions at BYU–Idaho is to “build testimonies of the 
				restored gospel of Jesus Christ and encourage living its 
				principles.” Having worked “in the world,” I do not take for 
				granted the privilege of praying in class, the freedom to 
				discuss gospel doctrine within the context of my discipline, the 
				blessing of inspired leadership, faithful colleagues, and 
				honorable students. Believing that each of us has been prepared 
				to be at this university at this time for purposes beyond our 
				own, I want my students to learn from my experiences. What do I 
				want them to really know? &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&lt;i&gt;By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye 
				have love one to another (John 13:35). &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				How easy it is to love those who share our beliefs, our values, 
				and our desires—and how critical it is that we learn to love 
				unconditionally each of our Heavenly Father’s children. As 
				simple as it may sound, it truly does not matter how much we 
				know until others know how much we care. I want to always 
				remember the feelings I experienced when meeting with the family 
				of a bright, handsome young boy who had been a near-drowning&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				victim and was now severely disabled. During the meeting this 
				boy’s father, an executive officer of a major corporation in our 
				community, looked at me with tears in his eyes and said, “Thank 
				you for loving my child”—not “Thank you for teaching my child.”
				&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&lt;i&gt;Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your 
				good works, and glorify your Father which is in Heaven (Matthew 
				5:16). &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				There exists an indefinable attraction toward individuals whose 
				lives reflect the example of the Savior. I have seen it occur 
				over and over again—teachers reporting that they quickly 
				identify which of their students’ families are Latter-day Saints 
				simply by watching them, teachers asking other teachers, “What 
				is it about your life that I want to have in my life?” And they 
				are equally apt to report that a Latter-day Saint acquaintance 
				was observed doing something inconsistent with the principles of 
				the gospel. I must teach my students that what we do has much 
				more of an impact than what we say—and that a powerful influence 
				for good is generated when these are consistent. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&lt;i&gt;And now, my brethren, seeing that ye know the light by which 
				ye may judge, which light is the light of Christ, see that ye do 
				not judge wrongfully; for with that same judgment which ye judge 
				ye shall also be judged (Moroni 7:18).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				I was raised in a community not known for its morals, modesty, 
				or tastefulness. I attended thirteen years of public school with 
				classmates of differing races, religions, and cultures. I have 
				worked with families and colleagues representing diverse 
				socio-economic statuses, philosophies, backgrounds, beliefs, and 
				lifestyles. I have learned that people are innately good, that 
				they try to do the best they can with what they have been given, 
				and that no one makes the right decision all of the time. I 
				realize that I have become who I am in part because of my 
				interactions with other members of mankind. Is it then 
				conceivable that others become who they are in part because of 
				their interactions with me? &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&lt;i&gt;Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto 
				thine own understanding. In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he 
				shall direct thy paths (Proverbs 3:5,6).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				In spite of my best efforts, I will not be able to adequately 
				prepare my students for every challenge that they will encounter 
				as they enter this chosen profession. I can provide role-play 
				and simulation activities, practicum and student teaching 
				experiences, but I cannot provide every real-life parent and 
				every real-life student and every real-life life situation that 
				could possibly occur in an educational environment. I can 
				provide strategies and techniques for good instruction and 
				classroom management, but I cannot anticipate the myriad 
				variables that together create each unique learning environment.
				&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				However, I can help instill within my students a testimony that 
				their Heavenly Father knows them by name, that He knows their 
				hopes and their fears and the righteous desires of their hearts. 
				Armed with this knowledge, our students can seek understanding 
				because they will know that He will direct their paths. After 
				eight semesters (hopefully), our students leave the safety and 
				security of this formative and nurturing environment to assume 
				their rightly earned roles within the vast realm of education. 
				If we have done our job of adequately preparing them for what 
				lies ahead and they have done their job of availing themselves 
				of the learning opportunities provided, what can they—and 
				we—expect? As Elder Henry&amp;nbsp;B. Eyring prophesied: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				&amp;quot;The day will come that that capacity to influence people around 
				you for good will have you singled out as one of the great 
				leaders in whatever place you’re in. They will not quite know 
				why, but you will know that the reason you are being singled &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
				out is not because of your innate gifts as a leader but because 
				you have done what the Savior would do—learned how to, and did&amp;quot; 
				(“A Steady, Upward Course,” &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; BYU–Idaho Devotional, September 
				18, 2001). SM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="2"&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;
				Excerpts taken from an article that first appeared in 
				Perspective: Expressing Mind &amp;amp; Spirit (Volume 4, Number 1, 
				Spring 2004.)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/table&gt;
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" height="1817"&gt;
		&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="10" --&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td valign="top" width="100%"&gt;
				&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
				&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" height="100%" width="2"&gt;
				&lt;img alt="" width="2" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/table&gt;
		&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td valign="top" colspan="5" height="47"&gt;
		&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;
			&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingTableID="4" --&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" width="2"&gt;
				&lt;img alt="" width="2" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td valign="top" width="100%"&gt;
				&lt;!-- MSCellFormattingType="content" --&gt;
				&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;font face="Franklin Gothic Book" size="4"&gt;
				&lt;a href="x51289.xml"&gt;[Table of Contents]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" height="100%" width="2"&gt;
				&lt;img alt="" width="2" height="1" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td bgcolor="#932944" colspan="3" height="2"&gt;
				&lt;img alt="" width="1" height="2" src="MsSpacer.gif"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/table&gt;
		&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td width="30"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td width="231"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td width="103"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td width="404"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td height="1" width="30"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;

&lt;/html&gt;</ESContent></EmptyShell>
