<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TrainingDetails ID="x68460" Name="Academic Home" Layout="default-training.xsl"><IfComponent type="boolean" label="Check if this is a component tutorial" ID="1">false</IfComponent><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" ID="2">Academic Home</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" ID="3">Page type used for college and department home pages only. This page will be the parent to all other pages that are created for the academic office.</Abstract><TrainingImage type="imagefile" label="Page Type Image" hidden="false" readonly="false" required="false" ID="4" Width="1" Height="1" Expanded="true" AlternateText="" Border="" HSpace="" VSpace="" Alignment="">Internal_Use/Ingeniux_Training/Template Thumbnails/ColDept.jpg</TrainingImage><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" ID="5"><![CDATA[<p>The department home page may be used by any department. It has been designed as an introductory page leading the user into the more detailed pages. If your deparment home page has not already been set up for you, you will have to create this page.</p>
<p>There is content on this page that cannot be edited. This content consist of the <a href="#">Devotional component</a> and the <a href="#">News/Events component</a>. These components are updated dynamically eslewhere on the site and are maintained by their respective owners.</p>
<p>To use this page type for your site, select the department page from the page type dropdown list. *see (<a href="#">Creating a new page for your site</a>). After creating and naming your page you need to input the required fields.</p>
<p>The first two fields you will see are "Title" and "Abstract". These fields are required and you will not be able to save your page until these field requirements have been met. You may name the Title field any descriptive name. The title will be displayed at the top of your department page.</p>
<p><img alt="Title and Abstract" src="Images/Ingeniux_Training/titleAbstract.jpg" /></p>
<p>The SEO Group is used for search optimization. The first field "Browser Bar Title" will display the name you entered at the top of the browser. The meta description field is intented to be a brief and concise summary of your page's content. Think of the GOOGLE directory. You see your site title followed by a brief description of your site or business. The meta description field is designed to provide a brief description of your site which can be used by search engines or directories.</p>
<p>When you fill in the meta description field, you should limit it to 170 characters or 200 characters at most. With each of your pages you create, write a unique meta description for each.</p>
<p>The "No Follow" if checked, will tell search engine bots to ignore your page. By ignoring your page, your site is less visible to search engines.</p>
<p>The "No Index" if checked, will not list your page in the sitewide index. By checking this, you will limit your pages ease of being found by students or the public.</p>
<p><img alt="SEO Group" src="Images/Ingeniux_Training/SEOGroup.jpg" /></p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="References" References="" Name="PageUsage" label="Page or Component Reference" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true" QueryLocationRoots="" IncludeCrossReferences="false" Depth="0" QuerySchemas="TrainingDetails" ID="6" Expanded="false"><Exports></Exports></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5758" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Children" Query="" Name="FAQs" label="FAQs Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" ID="7"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x10283" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Children" Query="" Name="Icons" label="Element Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false" ID="8"/></TrainingDetails>
