<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.101 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x68925" Name="Agreement" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Teacher Agreement - Education Week 2014</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Teacher Agreement</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">true</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<div class="style-container">[x50728][x51144]</div>
<style><!--
.type h2 {
	background-color: #fff;
	margin-top: 30px;
	margin-bottom: 20px;
	font-size: 1.3em;
	letter-spacing: 1pt;
	padding: 0;
	color: #0f6cb6;
	display: block;
}
.type h3 {
	margin-bottom: 15px;
	font-size: 1.3em;
}
.type h4 {
	margin-bottom: 6px;
	text-indent: 0;
	font-size: 1.1em;
}
.type h3,
.type h2
{
	font-family: "Century Gothic", "Helvetica Neue", Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
}
--></style>
<div class="main-title-container">
<h1>Teacher Acceptance Agreement</h1>
</div>
<div class="text-box">
<p>All presentations given at Education Week should conform to the following guidelines. Your acceptance of the invitation to teach indicates your commitment to abide by these guidelines.</p>
</div>
<div id="text-container"><!-- PAGE INDEX -->
<ul>
<li><a href="#terms">Terms of Agreement</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#subject">Subject Matter</a></li>
<li><a href="#counseling">Individual Counseling</a></li>
<li><a href="#commercialism">Commercialism</a></li>
<li><a href="#recording">No Recording of Lectures</a></li>
<li><a href="#guests">Invited Guests</a></li>
<li><a href="#outline">Outline</a></li>
<li><a href="#selection">Selection Process</a></li>
<li><a href="#media">Media</a></li>
<li><a href="#video">Video Public Performance Use</a></li>
<li><a href="#benefits">Benefits</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#samples">Submission Material Samples</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#pre">Sample Outline of Pre-Conference Materials</a></li>
<li><a href="#class">Sample of Class Outline</a></li>
<li><a href="#post">Sample of Outline for Post-Conference Materials</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#suggestions">Helpful Suggestions and Information for Teaching at Education Week</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#campus">Campus Overview</a></li>
<li><a href="#classroom">Classroom Overview</a></li>
<li><a href="#dress">Dress and Grooming&mdash;Event Attire</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!-- END OF PAGE INDEX --><hr />
<h2 id="terms">Terms of Agreement</h2>
<h3 id="subject">Subject Matter</h3>
<p>All presentations should be consistent with the principles of the restored gospel, be free of <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=define+sectarianism" target="_blank">sectarianism</a>, build faith, and be filled with the spirit of deepest reverence. Areas of speculation, fanaticism, or the discussion of mysteries and doctrines upon which there is not a widely recognized, accepted view should be avoided. The purpose is to present truth in a plain, understandable, and applicable way.</p>
<h3 id="counseling">Individual Counseling</h3>
<p>Students may approach faculty before, during, or after a class to pose personal questions and share personal problems in hope of obtaining counsel and advice. Please do not counsel program participants but refer them to their local ecclesiastical leader.</p>
<h3 id="commercialism">Commercialism</h3>
<p>Please avoid referencing your own commercially available materials in any handouts, titles, or during your lecture. Also, please do not mention that your materials are available at the BYU-Idaho Bookstore. Gathering names of participants or handing out business cards is not appropriate.</p>
<h3 id="recording">No Recording of Lectures</h3>
<p>No unauthorized audio or video recording of presentations is allowed. This policy applies to participants and instructors.</p>
<h3 id="guests">Invited Guests</h3>
<p>All those who teach and present in the classroom must be cleared through BYU-Idaho's President's Council. Please do not invite others to speak, share testimony, sing, play an instrument, etc. in the classroom.</p>
<h3 id="outline">Outline</h3>
<p>All material distributed during Education Week must first be approved through BYU-Idaho. All teachers are to submit pre-conference and post-conference materials as well as a synopsis and an outline of their class. Please submit materials, along with your outline, to the BYU-Idaho University Relations department.</p>
<h3 id="selection">Selection Process</h3>
<p>Each year, Education Week will offer opportunities for a mix of past and new teachers. Some teachers will not be asked to return each year to allow others to have a chance to teach. However, let us know which years you would like to teach, and we will try to work you in.</p>
<h3 id="media">Media</h3>
<p>Use of any part of professionally prepared media is subject to copyright law, whether or not the media is copyright marked. Only the "Public Performance Use" category qualifies for use at Education Week.</p>
<h3 id="video">Video Public Performance Use</h3>
<p>Videos cleared under the "Public Performance Use" category can be used at Education Week. Usually there is a higher fee to buy or rent such videos. Many videos from public libraries have this authorization as well as many of the videos available from BYU-Idaho Media Services.</p>
<p>If a video has not been cleared for Public Performance Use, written permission must be obtained from the producer to use the video (or any portion thereof) at Education Week.</p>
<h3 id="benefits">Benefits</h3>
<p>Instructing at BYU-Idaho Education Week is a volunteer experience; no monetary compensation is offered to instructors. However, teachers and their immediate family will receive complimentary full-event passes that will allow them to attend any Education Week class or event, provided seating is available.</p>
<hr />
<h2 id="samples">Submission Material Samples</h2>
<h3 id="pre">Sample Outline of Pre-Conference Materials</h3>
<h4>Pre-Conference Materials</h4>
<p><strong>Teacher:</strong> Robert Johnson</p>
<p><strong>Class Title 1:</strong> The Prophet Joseph Smith: Missionary</p>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> Members of the Church will be given more and more opportunities in coming years to serve missions and otherwise testify of the prophet Joseph Smith. In this class, we will discuss the prophet Joseph Smith's style and approach as a missionary and show that it is a pattern for us.</p>
<ol>
<li>Hymn No. 27, <em>Praise to the Man</em></li>
<li>Joseph Smith&mdash;The Prophet of the Restoration (Tad R. Callister, October 2009 General Conference Address).</li>
<li>Doctrine and Covenants 135</li>
<li>2 Nephi 3:15&ndash;21</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="class">Sample of Class Outline</h3>
<h4>Class Outline</h4>
<p><strong>Teacher:</strong> Robert Johnson</p>
<p><strong>Class Title 1:</strong> The Prophet Joseph Smith: Missionary</p>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> Members of the church will be given more and more opportunities in coming years to serve missions and otherwise testify of the prophet Joseph Smith. In this class, we will discuss the prophet Joseph Smith's style and approach as a missionary and show that it is a pattern for us.</p>
<p><strong>Learning Objectives:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>He was bold in presenting what he knew (History of Joseph Smith by Lucy Mack Smith, pp. 155-156; 254-256; Autobiography of Parley P. Pratt, pp. 210-211).</li>
<li>He was ready, often at the first instance, to speak of baptism (D&amp;C 19:31; 33:11, "Notes of a Conversation With Clinton Harris, in Feb. 1857, recorded by George A. Smith," LDS Church Archives; "Jo. Of Joseph Heywood," Church Archives).</li>
<li>He spoke of the First Vision and of the coming of Moroni and did so by way of testimony (JS-H 1:9-20, 27-54; Wentworth Letter, Hist. Of the Church 4:535-541; "The Prophet Joseph Smith: The Testimony of Sister M. Isabella Horne," Relief Society magazine, March, 1951, Vol. 38, No.3, p. 159-160; Hist Of Church 6:600, 610).</li>
<li>He constantly bore testimony of Christ, also publishing that testimony for the world to see (Book of Mormon Title page; D&amp;C 20:17-28; 76:22-24; 110:1-10: Dean Jessee, Papers of Joseph Smith, 1:xxii-xxiii, Hist. Of Church 2:312).</li>
<li>He was ever ready to testify that the Church was restored, that it was the Kingdom of God, and "the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth" (D&amp;C 1:30).</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Media needs:</strong> I will need a projector and computer to display a PowerPoint&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 1.4em;">presentation.</span></p>
<h3 id="post">Sample of Outline for Post-Conference Materials</h3>
<h4>Post-Conference Materials</h4>
<p><strong> Teacher:</strong> Robert Johnson</p>
<p><strong>Class Title 1:</strong> The Prophet Joseph Smith: Missionary</p>
<p><strong>Discussion Questions:</strong></p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>Why is a testimony of the prophet Joseph Smith vital for Latter-day Saints?</li>
<li>How can we gain a testimony that Joseph Smith is the prophet of the restoration?</li>
<li>How can gaining a testimony of the Book of Mormon help us gain a testimony of Joseph Smith?</li>
<li>What experiences have you had learning about Joseph Smith?</li>
<li>What are some ways we can share our testimony of Joseph Smith with others?
<ul></ul>
</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p><strong>Activity Ideas:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Reenact scenes from the history of the church in which Joseph Smith bore testimony</li>
<li>Role-play missionaries visiting with someone about the prophet Joseph Smith. Have them:
<ul>
<li>Teach the story of the First Vision</li>
<li>Explain the Book of Mormon and how we got it</li>
<li>Testify why we need prophets in our day</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h2 id="suggestions">Helpful Suggestions and Information<br />for Teaching at Education Week</h2>
<h3 id="campus">Campus Overview</h3>
<p>BYU-Idaho seeks to develop students who are spiritually focused and ready for leadership in their families, the workplace, and the community.</p>
<ul>
<li>Be familiar with the location of BYU-Idaho campus and its buildings.</li>
<li>Arrive early for the conference to tour the campus and to visit your assigned teaching rooms.</li>
<li>Review your presentation materials. Event Services will bring any media support items right before your class. Be ready for technology to fail or be delayed but hope for the best.</li>
<li>Parking will not be ticketed during Education Week; however, you must not park in Service or other Specialty marked parking spaces.</li>
<li>You can pick up your complimentary passes and conference materials at the Education Week Headquarters. Please check in early, so we know you are here, and we can give you any updates you might need.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="classroom">Classroom Overview</h3>
<p>Education Week hosting staff will be present in each classroom. They will open the class with prayer, introduce you, and take a count of the participants attending.</p>
<p>Education Week participants may come with questions and insights to share. For ideas on preparing for classroom discussions, visit the <a href="http://www.byui.edu/about/defining-aspects/learning-model" target="_blank">Learning Model website</a>.</p>
<p>We have four different types of class periods to help participants make the most of their Education Week experience.</p>
<ul>
<li>A <strong>Standard Class</strong> teacher will teach at least one topic on one of the days of conference. (Some teachers may be asked to teach other classes as needed.)</li>
<li>A <strong>Multi Class</strong> teacher will have the same room but will be encouraged to teach different topics. (2 p.m.-Friday and Saturday)</li>
<li>A <strong>Repeat or Series Class</strong> teacher will teach the same topic or a series of related class topics in the same classroom each day of conference. This allows participants to attend a different class during that hour that they might have missed on other days. (3 p.m. on Thursday, Friday, and Saturday)</li>
<li>A <strong>Correlated Class</strong> teacher will teach a topic that also will be taught in the adult classes and youth programs at the same time, so participants will be able to gather afterwards and share insights on the correlated topic. (4 p.m. on Thursday and Friday)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="dress">Dress and Grooming&mdash;Event Attire</h3>
<p>The minimum standard for men is a shirt and tie. Jeans are not appropriate. The minimum standard for women is a dress (or a skirt and blouse or sweater). Casual dress or clothing will not be permitted.</p>
</div>
<hr class="separator" />
<div>[x91900]</div>
<script type="text/javascript">
// Thanks to Chris Coyier, css-tricks.com
$(document).ready(function() {
  function filterPath(string) {
  return string
    .replace(/^\//,'')
    .replace(/(index|default).[a-zA-Z]{3,4}$/,'')
    .replace(/\/$/,'');
  }
  var locationPath = filterPath(location.pathname);
  var scrollElem = scrollableElement('html', 'body');
 
$('a[href*=#]:not([href=#])').click(function() {
    if (location.pathname.replace(/^\//,'') == this.pathname.replace(/^\//,'') 
        || location.hostname == this.hostname) {

        var target = $(this.hash);
        target = target.length ? target : $('[name=' + this.hash.slice(1) +']');
           if (target.length) {
             $('html,body').animate({
                 scrollTop: target.offset().top
            }, 450);
            return false;
        }
    }
});
 
  // use the first element that is "scrollable"
  function scrollableElement(els) {
    for (var i = 0, argLength = arguments.length; i < argLength; i++) {
      var el = arguments[i],
          $scrollElement = $(el);
      if ($scrollElement.scrollTop()> 0) {
        return el;
      } else {
        $scrollElement.scrollTop(1);
        var isScrollable = $scrollElement.scrollTop()> 0;
        $scrollElement.scrollTop(0);
        if (isScrollable) {
          return el;
        }
      }
    }
    return [];
  }
});
</script>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x28840" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="true" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="x50728" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x51144" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x91900" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x47794" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
