<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 8.0.101 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content ID="x69149" Name="continuing" Layout="byuidefault.xsl" IsComponent="false"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">continuing</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">continuing</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" label="No Follow" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" label="No Index" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" label="No ODP" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="true" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageOptions" label="Page Options" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><HideTitle type="boolean" label="Hide Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</HideTitle><Hideleftnavigation type="boolean" label="Hide left navigation" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</Hideleftnavigation></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Height=""><![CDATA[<p>
<title>I Never Knew</title>
</p>
<style type="text/css"><!--
A:link {color:00008B;font-size:11pt}
A:visited {color:00008B}
A:hover {color:B22222}

TD {text-align:left;font-size:12pt}
span.bodytxtitalic
	{mso-style-parent:"";
	font-family:"Minion Pro";
	font-style:italic
	}
 span.MsoFootnoteReference
	{font-family:"Times New Roman PS MT";
	color:black;
	vertical-align:super}
 span.cttsubheads
	{mso-style-parent:"";
	font-family:"News Gothic BT";
	color:#8B411B}
 
--></style>
<p>
<script src="../../webstyle/BYU-IdahoRicksCollegeAlumniAssociationSectionStyle/SSH.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
</p>
<!--ENDSMALLSECTIONHEADER-->
<table border="0" cellpadding="4" cellspacing="4" style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 1966px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td height="45" width="1012">
<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 167px;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td height="152" width="1%">
<p align="center"><img border="0" height="131" src="Images/BYUI upward/fall2004/ctt1.jpg" width="131" /></p>
</td>
<td height="152" width="164%"><span style="line-height: 120%; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"> <span style="font-size: 300%;"><br /> WHY DO PEOPLE CARE ABOUT<br /> <br /> <br /> &nbsp;STUDENTS AT BYU-IDAHO?</span></span>
<p align="right" class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: 'Franklin Gothic Book';"> <span style="mso-bidi-font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: Requiem; letter-spacing: 1.05pt;"><em style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"> <span style="color: #ff0000; font-size: xx-large;">&nbsp;</span></em></span></span><strong><span style="font-family: 'Franklin Gothic Book';">By Brett Sampson '88</span></strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" height="14" width="165%"><hr /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td bgcolor="#FFFFFF" height="1897" valign="top" width="1119">
<p class="bodytxt"></p>
<p class="Noparagraphstyle" style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"> <img align="right" border="0" height="171" hspace="10" src="Images/BYUI upward/fall2004/CTT3.jpg" vspace="10" width="171" />It is amazing&mdash;though not surprising&mdash;how many people really care about what is happening to and for students at BYU&ndash;Idaho. Often, that interest leads to financial contributions of anywhere from a few dollars to many thousands of dollars every year. But why? What is it that motivates so much generosity? What is it, this year, that is prompting so many to give the specific amount of $177?</span></p>
<p class="ctttxt" style="line-height: normal;"><span class="cttsubheads"> <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"> Providing the &ldquo;<span style="letter-spacing: .4pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho Experience&rdquo;</span></span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; letter-spacing: .1pt;"><br /> In talking with alumni in particular, I learned that many desire to help today&rsquo;s students get the same life-changing experiences they had. They support the institution that provides the environment for specific experiences like personal association with teachers, social growth, and some other aspects unique to the campus in Rexburg, Idaho.</span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I had a wonderful discussion with <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">Pearl Anderegg Anderson &rsquo;54</span></span> of Texas who is 91 years old this year. As we talked, she said, &ldquo;I first attended in the late 1930s, back when some of the kids put a cow in the library&rdquo; (though she said she had nothing to do with it). &ldquo;We enjoyed ourselves and, besides that prank, had a lot of very good experiences. I gave because I believe those good things are still happening there.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Those good things&rdquo; are now happening for an incrementally increasing number of young men and women from every one of the United States and 40 countries<br /> around the world. <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While here, students serve, lead, and associate with other committed young adults; they sometimes meet and marry their eternal companions. They gain valuable experiential learning, and they leave with degrees to serve and lead throughout the world.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">Blake Chamberlin &rsquo;82</span></span> of Texas said, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sure the school is continuing the tradition of what was there when I went. It was small enough and the teachers weren&rsquo;t completely involved in research, so we had PhDs teaching instead of graduate students. I got a good education; I respect that and want to continue that possibility for others.&rdquo; <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Donations from people like Blake simply enhance the overall experience students have at <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho.</span></p>
<p class="ctttxt" style="line-height: normal;"><span class="cttsubheads"> <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">Giving Back</span></span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"><br /> When it comes down to figuring the actual cost of providing a quality college education, those who attend <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho benefit from a tuition that is greatly supplemented. Some alumni tell me they feel a need to &ldquo;give something back&rdquo; to the institution that provided so much toward their development. <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;I know that those of us who went there received far more than we ever had to pay for,&rdquo; says <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">Shane Nelson &rsquo;77</span></span> of Florida, &ldquo;so even though I&rsquo;m not necessarily affluent, when I do get a call or a letter, it makes me feel good to give a little back.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whether it carried the name Bannock Stake Academy, Ricks Normal College, Ricks College, or Brigham Young University&ndash;Idaho when we attended, it will forever be <span style="letter-spacing: -.05pt;">part of us&mdash;who we are and whom we become.<br /> </span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alumna <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">Tamara Bagley Henry &rsquo;91</span></span> of Nebraska says, &ldquo;I gave because I had such a good experience there. I got a good education <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">and</span></span> I gained a religious background that has strengthened my testimony.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="ctttxt" style="line-height: normal;"><span class="cttsubheads"> <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">A General Feeling of Philanthropy</span></span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"><br /> &ldquo;When you help others help themselves, you&rsquo;re <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">truly</span></span> helping them, versus just giving handouts to them,&rdquo; says Tamara Henry. &ldquo;Giving to <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho is going to help them get an education so they can help themselves through life.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tamara captured the core of why we do what we do. It is that &ldquo;teach someone to fish&rdquo; idea. It is acting on our love for others. I have come to learn that &ldquo;philanthropy&rdquo; is the term that describes it.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some years ago I attended a luncheon at which the keynote speaker was Jon M. Huntsman, a well-known philanthropist and <span style="letter-spacing: .3pt;">CEO</span> of Huntsman Chemical, the largest privately-owned chemical company in the world. He presented a wonderful message that day; however, the thing I remember most was something his wife Karen shared prior to his speech.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In her introduction, she said that soon after they were married and pinching pennies like any newlyweds, she discovered that her husband had been giving $50 a month to help another member of their ward. <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That day Sister Huntsman taught me that one does not become a &ldquo;philanthropist&rdquo; only when one is wealthy. Philanthropy can develop at any time in our lives because it is essentially giving out of a love for one&rsquo;s fellowman. In a broader perspective, as we assist in the education of young people, we are also fulfilling something important personally in regard to building the kingdom.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While there are often additional reasons for giving to <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho students, philanthropy, especially within a Latter-day Saint society, is usually the ultimate catalyst for a gift that improves a mind and a saves a life. </span></p>
<p class="ctttxt" style="line-height: normal;"><span class="cttsubheads"> <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">Jacob Spori and $177</span></span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"><br /> Lives <span class="bodytxtitalic"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">are</span></span> made better anytime alumni and others give, in any amount. This year however, something interesting is happening. Hundreds of contributions of exactly $177 are being sent to <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In March 2004, a letter from President David A. Bednar was mailed to many alumni and friends of the university. In it he recounted a unique sacrifice made by Jacob Spori, the first principal of this institution.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To sum up Spori&rsquo;s experience, after just two years of existence, the fledgling school was $177 in debt. Principal Spori felt personally responsible and not only applied his salary to cover the deficit, but worked on the railroad for a time and used those earnings to help pay the salaries of the other teachers.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Bednar&rsquo;s letter included an invitation to honor Jacob&rsquo;s sacrifice by giving $177 to <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho this year. The response has been remarkable.</span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black;"><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, many valued gifts were given in various amounts, but the $177 challenge brought about some interesting results. Of the $177 donations, 84 percent represented the largest gift ever given to the institution by those individuals. It had been over two years since 22 percent of them had given anything to <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;"> BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho, and 66 percent of those who gave $177 this year had given less than $50 previously.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Recently President Bednar said, &ldquo;It is gratifying to see the list of those who have responded to our specific request in behalf of the students presently attending Brigham Young University&ndash;Idaho. Many gifts of exactly $177 have come in already this year. These gifts are but a sampling of the regular, ongoing contributions of time, talents, and treasure through the years. Certainly we can only begin to imagine the good that thousands of alumni-leaders will continue to accomplish throughout the world after having benefited from the generosity and sacrifice of so many.&rdquo;</span><span class="cttsubheads"><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;">&nbsp;</span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify; text-autospace: none; vertical-align: middle;"><span class="cttsubheads"><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"> Continuing the Tradition</span></span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black;"><br /> By and large, many of those who gave $177 this year did so because they were touched by what Jacob Spori did so long ago. They liked the historical significance of the target amount. While they acknowledged that a gift of $177 in today&rsquo;s dollars will not go as far as Spori&rsquo;s did, they wanted to do their part.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Shane Nelson gave $177 this year. He said, &ldquo;I was touched by Jacob Spori&rsquo;s story and thought, &lsquo;Well if I give $177, I know it&rsquo;s not the same as it was back in 1890. But it&rsquo;s a target amount that has some meaning, and it&rsquo;s something I can contribute.&rsquo; It might have been a little bit of a stretch for us, but it was reachable.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of his $177 gift, Blake Chamberlin said, &ldquo;It seemed like it was reasonable to meet the challenge the same way Jacob Spori did in the past. I liked the historical context of giving what one of the founders of the school gave, so I gave out of a respect for the history.&rdquo; <br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since the time of Principal Spori and the initial financial struggles, <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">all contributions to the school </span> reflect a tradition of sacrifice over the years. More than once, it was the rallying together of community members and campus personnel that kept the school afloat during these times of economic crisis.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Many times over, alumni and even students have pooled their resources to begin or maintain programs to help the student body.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Much of what is deemed the &ldquo;Spirit of Ricks&rdquo; comes from a perpetual feeling of hunkering down, lending a hand, taking some extra time, giving a little more, and sheltering one another from rough winds (pun intended) on campus. Throughout the lifetime of <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;"> BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho, these expressions have come in the form of, or along with, financial contributions. These gifts are trustfully presented to those who lead the school.</span><span class="cttsubheads"><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"><br /> &nbsp;</span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify; text-autospace: none; vertical-align: middle;"><span class="cttsubheads"><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"> Faith in the President and Board of Trustees</span></span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black;"><br /> &ldquo;I have a lot of faith in the leaders,&rdquo; said Shane Nelson, &ldquo;and feel that whatever it is we give&mdash;whether it be tithes or any other contributions like those given to <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho&mdash;that it will be treated as sacred and that they&rsquo;ll use it appropriately in whatever fashion is most beneficial, whether it&rsquo;s used to help those who can&rsquo;t afford schooling or whatever will help the most.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some people give simply because they are invited to do so and trust that their gifts will be used appropriately. More often than not, instead of directing their gifts to specific university philanthropic priorities (areas through which support can be given) they allow the president and Board of Trustees to use their donations for priorities that need it most.</span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black; letter-spacing: -.05pt;"><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Regarding those philanthropic priorities for </span> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black; letter-spacing: .25pt;"> BYU</span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black;">&ndash;<span style="letter-spacing: -.05pt;">Idaho, a new set for 2005-2009 has recently been approved by the Board of Trustees. While a few priorities have been added to the existing list, no major changes in direction have occurred. The focus on students remains constant amidst change&mdash;a recurring theme among the administration. </span> </span><span class="cttsubheads"> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"><br /> &nbsp;</span></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify; text-autospace: none; vertical-align: middle;"><span class="cttsubheads"><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book;"> In the End, It&rsquo;s About the Students</span></span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black;"><br /> At a gathering of <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho employees on August 27, 2002, President Bednar said, &ldquo;The hallmark of this institution is readily apparent when visitors come to our campus and say, &lsquo;I can&rsquo;t believe how student-focused the faculty are, the staff are, all of the employees are.&rsquo; Think of that scenario, given what we have heard about the climate of critique in the secular world wherein students frequently are considered a &lsquo;bother.&rsquo; Here at <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho, the students are and always will be the focus of everything we do.&rdquo;<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every employee hired on campus is interviewed and observed regarding their individual attention toward the ultimate good of the students. Likewise, the <span style="letter-spacing: .2pt;">BYU</span>&ndash;Idaho Board of Trustees chaired by the First Presidency, the vice presidents, and others who oversee <span style="letter-spacing: -.05pt;">the philanthropic contributions ensure that any gift given to the university benefits students. <br /> </span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are many reasons people care about the students of this university and act on those motivators. This year students have been collectively and personally supported by more gifts than ever before, a good number of them in the amount of $177.<br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ultimately it&rsquo;s about the students&mdash;their experiential learning, their quality of academic training, and their opportunity to even attend.</span><span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: black; letter-spacing: -.1pt;"><br /> </span> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; letter-spacing: -.1pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As always, the students thank you. And we thank you. </span> <span style="font-family: Franklin Gothic Book; color: #817b6a;">SM</span></p>
<p class="bodytxt" style="text-align: center;"><span style="vertical-align: middle;"><a href="x69148.xml"> <span style="color: #000000; font-family: 'Franklin Gothic Book'; font-size: medium;">[TABLE OF CONTENTS]</span></a><span style="font-family: 'Franklin Gothic Book'; font-size: medium;"><span style="mso-bidi-font-size: 10.0pt;"> </span></span> </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td bgcolor="#FFFFFF" height="1897" valign="top" width="1119">&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="PageComponents" label="Page Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded=""><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_Optional" Name="OptionalColumnComponent" label="Optional Column Components" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="Optional" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="FacebookComponent;Image;ColumnTextComponent;Media;Quote"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn1" label="QuickLinks Column 1" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn2" label="QuickLinks Column 2" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="QuickLinksColumn3" label="QuickLinks Column 3" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="QuickLinksComponent"/></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="List" List="xpowercomponent_ContentSnippet" Name="ContentSnippet" label="Content Snippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" Component="" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ContentSnippet" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false" CompTypes="ContentSnippet"/></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content>
