<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x9081" Name="Course Descriptions" Layout="byuidefault.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Course Descriptions</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Course Descriptions</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" hidden="true" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent" Expanded="false"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<div><a href="#chem101"></a><a name="top"></a></div>
<table align="center" border="0" id="top">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_101">Chem 101</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_101L">Chem 101L</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_105">Chem 105</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_106">Chem 106</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_150">Chem 150</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_153">Chem 153</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_220">Chem 220</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_351">Chem 351</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_352">Chem 352</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_391">Chem 391</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_405">Chem 405</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_461">Chem 461</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_462">Chem 462</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_464">Chem 464</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_468">Chem 468</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_470">Chem 470</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_471">Chem 471</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_481">Chem 481</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_482">Chem 482</a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_490">Chem 490</a><a href="#chem_490"> </a></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="#chem_498">Chem 498</a><a href="#chem_498"> </a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<div></div>
<div><a name="chem_101"></a></div>
<div><strong><span id="chem_101" style="text-decoration: underline;">Syllabus Info for (CHEM 101) Introductory General Chemistry</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Course Description</strong></div>
<div><br />This is an introductory course covering basic concepts in general chemistry. The course is designed for students in home economics, nursing, agriculture, biology, and other areas that require a broad introduction to general and inorganic chemistry. It serves as a preparation for Chem. 150. This course does not include a laboratory experience.</div>
<div><br /><strong>Content and Topics</strong></div>
<div><br />Matter, energy, measurement, conversions of units, atoms, the periodic table, ionic and molecular compounds, shapes of molecules, chemical reactions, stoichiometry, gas laws, solutions, reaction rates, equilibrium, acids and bases, and basic chemistry laboratory techniques.</div>
<div><br /><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></div>
<div><br />1. Explore the role of measurements in understanding and quantifying principles of chemistry.<br />2. Understand the structure of matter on atomic and molecular levels and its correlation to chemical and physical properties.<br />3. Comprehend quantitative relationships in chemical equations.<br />4. Identify types of chemical reactions.<br />5. Understand the energetics and kinetics of chemical reactions.<br />6. Characterize the differences in the states of matter and the unique properties associated with each.</div>
<div><br /><strong>Course Requirements</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Varies by instructor, generally there are quizzes and exams.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Prerequisites </strong>Completion of or concurrent enrollment in Math 108 or higher.<br /><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</div>
<div><br /><strong>Online course available</strong><br /><strong>Separate online lab is offered </strong><br />
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_101L"></a>S</span><span style="text-decoration: underline;">yllabus Info for (CHEM 101L online only)</span></strong><br /><strong>Introductory General Chemistry Laboratory</strong></p>
<p><br /><strong>Course Description</strong></p>
<p>Chemistry 101L is an online introduction to chemistry lab that illustrates principles of chemistry and laboratory techniques. Participation in the course requires reading pre-lab materials, completion of a pre-lab quiz, watching videos demonstrating laboratory procedures, recording data and observations in electronic format, and completing a post-lab quiz.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Scientific Measurements, Density, Physical Properties, Heat and Temperature, Light and Matter, Moles and Stoichiometry, Chemical Reactions, Gas laws, Rates of Reaction, and Titration.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>1. Observe laboratory techniques and understand their usefulness in providing data for problem solving.<br />2. Record measurements from scientific instruments with correct precision.<br />3. Preform calculations and solve problems using data collected from laboratory measurements.<br />4. Use computer software to present experimental data in graphs for the interpretation of experimentally acquired data.<br />Course Requirements<br />1. Computer with high speed internet access.<br />2. Spreadsheet software (Microsoft Excel or equivalent).<br />3. Completion or concurrent enrollment in Chemistry 101. It is strongly recommended that this course is taken concurrently with Chemistry 101.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Semesters</strong> Taught Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites </strong>Completion of or concurrent enrollment in Chem 101.<br /><strong>Separate classroom lecture is offered </strong></p>
<p></p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><strong><br /></strong><br /></strong></p>
<strong><span id="chem_105" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_105"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 105) General Chemistry I</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">&nbsp;<strong></strong></span>
<p><strong>Course Description</strong></p>
<p>The first semester of a two-semester course designed to meet the general chemistry requirements in engineering, science, and pre-professional majors. This course includes a lecture and laboratory experience.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Physical and chemical changes, scientific method, uncertainty in measurements, energy transformations, stoichiometry, types of chemical reactions, naming compounds, thermochemistry, electrolytes and solution properties, atomic structure, bonding, molecular geometry, states of matter, gas laws, and intermolecular forces. The laboratory component of the course teaches standard laboratory techniques and emphasizes the role quantitative measurements play in extracting chemically useful information.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Recognize and distinguish between physical and chemical change.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understand the scientific method.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Demonstrate appropriate use of numbers related to uncertainty in measurements.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Apply stoichiometry in determining quantity relationships for compounds and chemical reactions.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Write chemical equations and classify chemical reactions.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Name ionic and covalent compounds.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Know the properties of acids and bases.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Identify aspects of atomic structure.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Describe bonding theories and recognize molecular geometry.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Describe states of matter, including changes of state.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perform calculations with gas laws.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Recognize different types of intermolecular forces.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements </strong></p>
<p>Varies with instructor. Typically there are 5 exams, 10 quizzes, and 10 lab experiments. Some sections may require writing or Internet assignments.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisites </strong></strong>Completion of or concurrent enrollment in Math 109, 110, 112, 113, or 119 with a C- or higher.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<br />
<p><strong><span id="chem_106" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_106"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 106) General Chemistry II</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">&nbsp;<strong> </strong></span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>The second semester of a two-semester course designed to meet the general chemistry requirements in engineering, science, and pre-professional majors. This course includes a lecture and laboratory experience.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Colligative properties, chemical thermodynamics, chemical kinetics, general chemical equilibria, properties of acids and bases, acid and base equilibria, pH, buffers, ionic compound solubility and nomenclature nuclear chemistry. The laboratory component of the course teaches standard laboratory techniques and emphasizes the role quantitative measurements play in extracting chemically useful information. The laboratory component also reinforces the equilibria concepts through the application of these principles in the qualitative analysis of cations and anions.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understand the colligative properties. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understand the laws of thermodynamics and calculate the change in values of state functions for various physical and chemical processes.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Identify and calculate mathematical descriptions of the kinetics of chemical processes.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Demonstrate an understanding of chemical equilibrium and calculate solutions for equilibrium expressions.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Demonstrate an understanding of acid-base equilibrium by calculating resulting values in pH and reactant/product concentrations for acid-base processes such as buffer solutions and titrations.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Using concepts from solubility equilibria, calculate solutions from solubility-product expressions and compound solubility.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Identify the basic concepts of electrochemistry and calculate voltages and the concentrations of species in electrochemical cells.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Write mathematical representations for nuclear processes and predict products as nuclear processes take place.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perform calculations with colligative properties equations.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements </strong></p>
<p>Varies with instructor. Typically there are 5 exams, 10 quizzes, and 10 lab experiments. Some sections may require writing or Internet assignments.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisites </strong></strong>Chem 105 and Math 109, 110, 112, 113, or 119 with a C- or better.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span id="chem_150" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_150"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 150) Intro Organic and Biochemistry</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>This class is a one-semester introduction to organic and biochemistry that is a continuation of Chemistry 101 and is designed for students pursuing degrees or advanced training in nursing, dental hygiene, exercise and sports science, or health science. Students who also need an organic and biochemistry laboratory should concurrently register for Chemistry 153. This course is not preparatory for advanced organic and biochemistry courses.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Topics include the structure and reactions of major organic functional groups with significant emphasis on the biochemical context of the chemical properties of organic molecules. The structure and function of carbohydrates, lipids, amino acids, proteins, nucleotides, and nucleic acids is also covered.&nbsp; Significant emphasis is given to the major catabolic and anabolic pathways of carbohydrate, lipid, and amino acid metabolism.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Identify the physical and chemical properties of common functional groups in Organic Chemistry.</p>
<p>Understand the structure and function of carbohydrates, lipids, amino acids, proteins, nucleotides, and nucleic acids.</p>
<p>Know the reactions of the major catabolic and anabolic pathways of carbohydrate, lipid, and amino acid metabolism.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements </strong></p>
<p>Completion of Chemistry 101 or Chemistry 105 with a grade of C- or higher.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisites&nbsp;</strong></strong>Chem 101 or Chem 105 with a C- or higher.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter, Spring</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_153"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 153) Intro Organic &amp; Biochemistry Lab</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>This course is a laboratory experience that provides an introduction to basic techniques in organic chemistry and introduces the physical and chemical properties of some organic molecules.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>The following techniques are part of the laboratory experience: recrystallization, steam distillation, thin layer chromatography, solvent extraction, and elementary organic synthesis. Additional principles covered relate to the physical and chemical properties of carbohydrates, amino acids, and nucleic acids.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Demonstrate proficiency in the following laboratory techniques: recrystallization, steam distillation, thin layer chromatography, solvent extraction, and elementary organic synthesis.</p>
<p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Discover principles relating to the physical and chemical properties of organic molecules.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements </strong></p>
<p>This lab must be taken concurrently with Chemistry 150.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter, Spring</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a></p>
<br />
<p><strong><span id="chem_220" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_220"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 220) Quantitative Analysis</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>A one-semester course that introduces quantitative analytical techniques, instrumental analysis, and associated chemical principles. This course includes a lecture and laboratory experience.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Lecture topics include error analysis and statistical treatment of experimental data; sampling and analysis techniques; chemical equilibrium topics applied to chemical analysis; and selected topics in instrumental analysis, including electrochemistry, spectrophotometry, and chromatography. The laboratory&nbsp;emphasizes accuracy and precision in measurement;&nbsp;wet chemistry techniques such as titration and gravimetric analysis; and&nbsp;selected instrumental methods of analysis.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p><strong>1.</strong><strong> </strong><strong>Learn </strong></p>
<p>a.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Statistical interpretation of data</p>
<p>b.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Various analytical chemistry principles, concepts, and techniques (e.g., complex equilibria, activities, and instrumentation)</p>
<p>c.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calculations for volumetic, gravimetric, electroanalytical, chromatographic, and spectroscopic analyses</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong><strong> </strong><strong>Develop </strong></p>
<p>a.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Meticulous laboratory skills</p>
<p>b.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Detailed note-taking practices</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements </strong></p>
<p>Varies with instructor.&nbsp;Four semester exams, one final comprehensive ACS exam, homework assignments, eight laboratories, and&nbsp;a notebook grade. Three lecture hours and six laboratory hours per week. Approximately&nbsp;one third&nbsp;of grade based on laboratory performance.&nbsp; Chem. 106 is a prerequisite for this course.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisites&nbsp;</strong></strong>Chem 106 and Chem 391 (when possible) with a grade of C- or better.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span id="chem_351" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_351"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 351) Organic Chemistry I</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>The first semester of a year-long course that studies the principles and theories of organic chemistry including the properties, preparation, and reactions of organic compounds. The course is designed for students in Chemistry, Chemical Engineering, Pre-medicine, Pre-dentistry, Pre-pharmacy, Pre-veterinary and Biology. This course includes a lecture and laboratory experience.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Chemical Bonding; Alkanes; Conformations of Alkanes and Cycloalkanes; Alcohols and Alkyl Halides; Structure and Preparation of Alkenes: Elimination Reactions; Reactions of Alkenes: Addition Reactions; Stereochemistry; Nucleophilic Substitution; Alkynes; Conjugation in Alkadienes and Allylic Systems; Spectroscopy.<br /> The class also includes laboratory experience. Laboratory experiments are Intermolecular Forces; Distillation; Chemical Kinetics; Extraction; Recrystallization; GC Chromatography; Thin Layer Chromatography; Column Chromatography; IR Spectroscopy; and NMR Spectroscopy.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prepare for professional exams.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have the opportunity to learn and understand the theories, properties, and reactions of organic compounds.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have the opportunity to develop scientific reasoning and perform lab techniques.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements </strong></p>
<p>Varies with instructor. Generally the grades are based on about 10 quizzes, 10 labs, and 5-6 exams that are administered throughout the semester. Some classes may require writing assignments or possibly internet assignments. There will also be an American Chemical Society final.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisites </strong></strong>Chem 106 with a C- or better.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span id="chem_352" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_352"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 352) Organic Chemistry II</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>The second semester of a year-long course presenting the principles and theories of organic chemistry including the properties, preparation and reactions of organic compounds. The course is designed for students in Chemistry, Chemical Engineering, Pre-medicine, Pre-dentistry, Pre-veterinary and Biology. This course includes a lecture and laboratory experience.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Organometallic Compounds; Alcohols, Diols and Thiols; Ethers, Epoxides and Sulfides; Aldehydes and Ketones; Enols and Enolates; Carboxylic Acids; Carboxylic Acid Derivatives; Ester Enolates; Amines; Arenes and Aromaticity; Reactions of Arenes&nbsp; The class includes a laboratory experience. Laboratory experiments are Friedel-Crafts Acylation, Grignard Reaction, Esterification and Sequential Synthesis.&nbsp; The sequential synthesis varies from semester to semester.</p>
<br />
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prepare for professional exams.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have the opportunity to learn and understand the theories, properties, and reactions of organic compounds.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have the opportunity to develop scientific reasoning and perform lab techniques.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Varies with instructor. Generally the grades are based on about 10 quizzes, 5-6 exams, 10 labs, and laboratory essays that are administered throughout the semester. Some classes may require writing assignments or possibly internet assignments. There will also be an American Chemical Society final.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisites </strong></strong>Chem 351 with a C- or better.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong><span id="chem_391" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_391"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 391) Tech Writing in Chemical Lit</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>This course provides instruction and experience in advanced writing techniques for students planning careers in chemistry or related scientific disciplines. The course will help students:&nbsp;</p>
<p>1) Prepare for further chemistry courses that require scientific writing as a part of their curriculum.&nbsp;</p>
<p>2) Search the chemical literature using relevant database tools.&nbsp;</p>
<p>3) Develop practical experience in writing for a professional, technical audience.</p>
<p>4) Become more effective written communicators in their future scientific careers.</p>
<p>This course is a prerequisite for CHEM 220, CHEM 464, and CHEM 471.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Searching chemical literature, writing a journal article in the proper style, scientific oral/poster presentations, business communication (resumes cover letters).</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Become familiar with, and learn to effectively use common electronic resources for searching the scientific literature.</p>
<p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Learn to communicate scientific findings in a manner consistent with chemical literature practices.&nbsp; Specifically,</p>
<p>a.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Become familiar with the common structure of a typical research article in the literature (Abstract, Introduction, Experimental/Methods, Results, Discussion, Summary)</p>
<p>b.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Learn writing styles appropriate for the literature.</p>
<p>c.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Learn to properly incorporate tables and figures into a research article.</p>
<p>d.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Properly cite references in a research article using accepted literature formats.</p>
<p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Learn how the process of peer-review is used in the chemical literature, and practice &nbsp;&nbsp;effective reviewing techniques when reading others' work.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Each student will write a research article in the style of the chemical literature, using data gathered by the student in a previous research project, data provided by the instructor, or data acquired from an independent project in your kitchen.&nbsp; The article will consist of approximately 10-15 pages of polished prose, not including tables, figures, or references.&nbsp; Assignments for the course will be built around meeting this major outcome.</p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Chem 106, FDENG 201.&nbsp; Chem 351 recommended.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Once a year, alternating Winter and Spring semesters</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><span id="chem_405" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_405"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 405) Chemistry Teaching Methods</span></strong></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>This course will focus heavily on preparing students to be competent in laboratory procedures, including lab safety issues. Students will learn how to set up labs, order supplies, prepare and design laboratory experiments in the sciences. In addition students will become familiar with how demonstrations can be effectively used in the classroom. Ample opportunity will be given to each student to practice the skills needed to effectively teach chemistry in the secondary schools. Students will become familiar with and learn to apply the national and state science and chemistry standards for teaching chemistry at the secondary level.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Laboratory safety, National Science Standards, effective demonstrations, chemical literature for high school chemistry, history of science, use of simulations and games, use of computers in laboratories, microscale chemistry, concept mapping, using everyday materials to teach chemical principles.</p>
<br />
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Design a safe, cost effective laboratory/demonstration program that helps to make more tangible the abstract concepts in chemistry.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Demonstrate the ability to perform correct laboratory procedure such as bending glass and reading a vernier. Things that are not routinely taught in other chemistry courses.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Incorporate instrumentation, spreadsheets, computer simulations, games and technology into classroom presentations.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Appreciate the scientific method, the limitation of science, and the evolutionary nature of chemistry concepts.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Demonstrate the ability to effectively perform demonstrations.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Analyze and structure chemical concepts so that the sequential presentation of ideas is done in an order that will facilitate meaningful learning.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Explore chemical literature appropriate to the high school setting.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Know and demonstrate proper use and disposal of chemicals and improve safety.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; learn practical laboratory tips that reduce waste, save time, and improve safety.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Review the topics that are to be covered in a high school program and verify mastery of those concepts at least at the level they will be taught.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong> Attendance 10%, class assignments 30%, Portfolio 40%, exams 20%.</p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites </strong>Completion of Chem 352 or Chem 461 and Ed 361 with a grade of C- or better.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong><span id="chem_461" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_461"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 461) Physical Chemistry</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>First semester of a course covering the fundamental concepts of physical chemistry. This course provides a theoretical and mathematical description of the physical behavior of chemical systems. The first semester covers quantum mechanics and spectroscopy.</p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Principles of quantum mechanics, with application to atomic and molecular structure and spectroscopy.</p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Understanding of the following: Failings of classical physics at the molecular level; wave mechanics and its applications in classical and quantum physics; basic quantum mechanical models (particle in a box, harmonic oscillator, rigid rotor): the hydrogen atom model and applications, atomic structure and spectroscopy, molecular structure and spectroscopy.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Three unit exams, a final exam, and homework assignments.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisite </strong></strong>Completion of&nbsp; Chem 351, Phys 220, Math 215 with a C- or higher.&nbsp;&nbsp; Math 316 is Strongly recommended.&nbsp; <br /><br /> <strong><strong> </strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<br />
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_462"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 462) Physical Chemistry II</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>Second semester of a course covering the fundamental concepts of physical chemistry. This course provides a theoretical and mathematical description of the physical behavior of chemical systems. The second semester covers statistical mechanics, thermodynamics, and kinetics.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Statistical mechanics, thermodynamics, and kinetic theory.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Know the following: properties of gases, partition functions and the Boltzmann distribution, the laws of thermodynamics and their chemical applications, phase equilibrium and reaction equilibrium, kinetic rate laws and mechanisms. The kinetic theory of gases is covered as time permits.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Three unit exams, a final exam, and homework assignments.</p>
<p><strong><strong><strong>Prerequisite </strong></strong></strong>Chem 461 with a grade of C- or better.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong><span id="chem_464" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_464"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 464) Physical/Instrumental Chem. Lab</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><strong>Course Description</strong></p>
<p>Laboratory experience with modern instrumentation in performing physical and analytical chemistry experiments, practice scientific writing.</p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Physical chemistry experiments covering principles in thermodynamics, kinetics, statistical mechanics and quantum mechanics. Application of a variety of instrumental techniques.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Plan, conduct, and summarize results of laboratory-based scientific inquiries.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Use of instrumentation and computers in data collection and processing.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Practice scientific/technical writing.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Six laboratory reports in ACS journal format, one poster for a poster session at the end of the semester.</p>
<p><strong><strong><strong>Prerequisite </strong></strong></strong>Chem 220, chem 461 and PH 250 with a grade of C- or higher.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a name="chem_468"></a>S</strong></span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ylla</span>bus Info for (CHEM 468) Physical Biochemistry</strong></span></p>
<p><strong>Course Description</strong><br />This course will provide an introduction to physical biochemistry: the application of physical laws to the chemistry to biological systems. This subject is at the intersection of physics, chemistry, and biology and serves as a capstone to the undergraduate biochemistry education.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Content and Topics</strong><br />Thermodynamics, equilibrium, kinetics, quantum theory, macromolecular structure and biophysical experimental techniques are among the topics that will be covered.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong><br />1. Understand and describe the relationship between chemistry, physics, and biology.<br />2. Be able to search, read, and understand the applicable primary literature.<br />3. Analyze data and organize information.<br />4. Discuss physical biochemistry research, experiments, and techniques and explain the factors that affect the experimental outcome.</p>
<p><br /><strong><strong>Prerequisite</strong></strong> &nbsp;Completion of Chem. 481and PH 220 with a grade of C- or better.<br /><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong><br /><br /></p>
<p><strong><span id="chem_470" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_470"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 470) Inorganic Chemistry</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Course Description</strong></p>
<p>This course involves a study of structure, physical and chemical behavior, and bond theory as applied to inorganic chemistry.&nbsp; Using concepts, models, and experimental data, a variety of inorganic systems will be analyzed in a systematic and detailed fashion.&nbsp; Underlying trends in both the elements&nbsp;and also their compounds will be explored and identified.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Atomic theory and chemical bonding models</li>
<li>Molecular symmetry involving group theory</li>
<li>Acid-base concepts</li>
<li>Solid-state structures and concepts</li>
<li>Structure, bonding, and reactivity of coordination complexes including organometallic and bioinorganic complexes</li>
<li>Topics of current interest in inorganic chemistry</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Describe the structures, the physical/chemical properties, the bonding behaviors, and the reactivities of inorganic complexes utilizing atomic and bonding theories/models as well as experimental data.</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Describe the physical and electronic properties of atoms and simple molecules using atomic and bonding theories/models.</li>
<li>Identify symmetries and point groups of inorganic complexes.</li>
<li>Construct molecular orbitals (MO's) for simple molecules and inorganic complexes using the molecular orbital theory.</li>
<li>Describe acid-base chemistry in terms of modern models and concepts.</li>
<li>Name, draw, and identify isomers of inorganic complexes</li>
<li>Preform spectral analysis on inorganic complexes using common instrumental techniques.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Participation in classroom sessions (3 hours per week)</li>
<li>Completion of 4 exams which includes one final exam</li>
<li>Completion of homework as assigned</li>
<li>Preparation and presentation of a group technical report on an instrumental technique</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><strong><strong>Prerequisite&nbsp; </strong></strong></strong>Chem 461 with a grade of C- or higher.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_471"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 471) Advanced Laboratory</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>This laboratory course includes laboratory exercises in the preparation and purification of inorganic compounds utilizing modern synthetic techniques and equipment.&nbsp; Characterization of inorganic compounds will be performed by modern spectroscopic techniques such as nuclear magnetic resonance, UV-vis, infrared, and magnetic susceptibility. <br /> <strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Synthesis and characterization of inorganic compounds including organometallic, solid-state, and bioinorganic complexes.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Prepare, purify, and characterize inorganic compounds using modern techniques.&nbsp; Types of compounds will include:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Coordination compounds including organometallic complexes;</li>
<li>Solid-state compounds; and</li>
<li>Bioinorganic compounds</li>
</ul>
<p>Operate modern inorganic instrumentation to characterize synthesized inorganic compounds that include the following:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Infrared spectroscopy;</li>
<li>UV-vis spectroscopy;</li>
<li>NMR spectroscopy; and</li>
<li>Magnetic susceptibility</li>
</ul>
<p>Record results of discussion of syntheses in a laboratory notebook using proper record-keeping procedures.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Synthesize and characterize inorganic compounds in laboratory (6 hours per week).</li>
<li>Preparation of a laboratory notebook according to specified format.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><strong><strong>Prerequisite</strong></strong> &nbsp;</strong>Concurrent enrollment in Chem. 470.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong><span id="chem_481" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_481"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 481) Biochemistry I</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"></span></div>
<div></div>
<p><strong>Course Description</strong></p>
<p>The first semester course emphasizing the structure, function, and metabolism of proteins, carbohydrates, lipids, and nucleis acids. The course is designed for students in Chemistry, Biology, and those preparing to attend graduate or professional schools.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Structure and function of proteins, carbohydrates, lipids, and nucleic acids. Introduction to enzyme kinetics and cell singaling mechanisms.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>1. Understand the structure and function of four major classes of biomolecules: proteins, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, and lipids.<br />2. Apply kinetic and thermodynamic laws to enzyme catalyzed systems.</p>
<p><br /><strong>Course Requirements</strong> Completion of Chem. 351 with a grade of C- or better.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Prerequisite</strong></strong> Chem 351 with a grade of C- or higher.<br /><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<div>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a name="chem_482"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 482) Biochemistry II</strong></span></div>
<div><br /><strong>Course Description</strong></div>
<div><br />This course will provide an introduction to biochemistry; focused on metabolism. Thermodynamics, equilibrium, and cellular metabolism will be covered during the second semester of biochemistry.</div>
<div><br /><strong>Content and Topics</strong></div>
<div><br /><strong>Bioenergetics:</strong><br />Thermodynamics and equilibrium of metabolic reactions<br /><strong>Central metabolic pathways:</strong><br />Carbohydrate metabolism<br />Lipid metabolism<br />Nitrogen containing molecule metabolism<br /><strong>Electron transport in respiration and photosynthesis:</strong><br />Oxidative phosphorylation<br />Photophosphorylation<br />Carbon assimilation<br /><strong>Integration and regulation:</strong><br />Metabolism in cells and multicellular organisms</div>
<div><br /><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></div>
<div><br />1. Understand and describe the relationship between chemistry and biology in metabolic pathways.<br />2. Be able to search, read, and understand the applicable primary literature.<br />3. Analyze data and organize information.<br />4. Design and propose experimental approaches to solve biochemical questions.<br />5. Discuss biochemistry research, experiments, and techniques and in relationship to metabolic reactions.</div>
<div><br /><strong>Course Requirements</strong> Completion of Chem. 481 with a grade of C- or better.<br /><strong></strong></div>
<div><strong><strong><strong>Prerequisite</strong>&nbsp; </strong></strong>Chem 481 with a grade of C-or higher.</div>
<div><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong><br /><br /> <br />
<p><strong><span id="chem_490" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_490"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 490) Special Topics in Chemistry</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></p>
<p><strong> Course Description</strong></p>
<p>A one-semester course emphasizing current topics in chemistry. Each class participant will select a faculty supervisor who will oversee the design and implementation of a curriculum within a specific field of chemistry.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Will vary according to student and instructor design.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Will vary according to student and instructor design.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong> Instructor approval.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<strong><span id="chem_498" style="text-decoration: underline;"><a name="chem_498"></a>Syllabus Info for (CHEM 498) Chemistry Internship</span></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> </span></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Course Description</strong>
<p>All chemistry majors must find and experience a work internship. This would generally occur the semester after their junior year or during their senior year. The experience could involve working for a government agency, industry, an academic institution, or any organization that employs laboratory chemists on their staff. The credit for the internship would count as the capstone experience required for graduation. The student will have a contract agreement with the employer and be responsible to a faculty supervisor. Upon completion of the internship, a written report and a technical presentation will be made to the BYU-Idaho chemistry department as part of the requirement.</p>
<p><strong>Content and Topics</strong></p>
<p>Scientific experience in a chemistry laboratory in a professional, industrial or academic setting.&nbsp; Scientific chemistry content varies according to laboratory specifics and student interest.</p>
<p><strong>Goals and Objectives</strong></p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Participate in a "real world" laboratory intensive chemistry experience.</p>
<p>&middot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Effectively communicate the results of this experience in oral and written form.</p>
<p><strong>Course Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Completion of Chem. 220 Chem. 352, Chem. 462, Chem. 464, or instructor approval.</p>
<p>It is the student's responsibility to find an internship. The internship must then be approved through the internship coordinator in the chemistry department. The student must then complete the internship, prepare a written report and a presentation that will be given to the BYU-I chemistry department.</p>
<p><strong>Semesters Taught</strong> Winter Spring Fall</p>
<p><a href="#top">back to top</a><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
</div>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="x1892" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
