<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x9272" Name="Becoming BYU-Idaho" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">Becoming BYU-Idaho</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">A miraculous transformation was set in motion as the campus community worked to fulfill the prophetic vision for the new university</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<style><!--
.content a{
color: #1c74b5!important;
text-decoration:underline!important;
}
.content a:hover{
color:#666666!important;
}
--></style>
<p><img alt="Historical Spori Building" height="319" src="Images/Internal_Use/About BYU-Idaho/Spori(old).jpg" title="Historical Spori Building" width="650" /></p>
<p>At Brigham Young University-Idaho, you will find a legacy of   dedicated service and faithful perseverance that began more than 100   years ago on the newly settled plains of the Upper Snake River Valley.   In keeping with the belief in education held by the area's Latter-day   Saint pioneers, the Bannock Stake Academy opened in a meager log church   building in 1888.</p>
<p>After several name changes and the construction of a new building,   the academy became known as Ricks College in 1923, honoring founder   Thomas E. Ricks. New buildings and facilities were added and the   curriculum expanded. By the latter part of the 20th Century, Ricks   College had blossomed into the nation's largest private junior college   with a student body of nearly 9,000.</p>
<p>Then in 2000 leaders of <a href="http://www.lds.org/">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints</a> made a historic <a href="http://www.byui.edu/AboutBYUIdaho/transitionannouncement.htm">announcement</a>: Ricks College would become a four-year university and take the name Brigham Young University-Idaho.</p>
<p>A miraculous transformation was set in motion as the campus community   worked to fulfill the prophetic vision for the new university. Several   innovative ideas were introduced that reflected a complete rethinking  of  traditional education, including a year-round calendaring system, a   program for increased student participation outside the classroom, a  new  approach to internships, and innovative degree options.</p>
<p>In 2004, BYU-Idaho received accreditation at the baccalaureate level by the Northwest Association on Colleges and Universities.</p>
<p>Progress continued. From a standardized learning model to a complete   redesign of traditional general education, and from new technologies to   online courses that resemble campus classrooms, BYU-Idaho sought ways  to  create even more quality learning opportunities for students.</p>
<p>In describing this spirit of progress at BYU-Idaho, Elder Henry B.   Eyring said, &ldquo;Change will not end. The phrase &lsquo;rethinking education&rsquo; is   not to be only a slogan for the transformation from a two-year to a   four-year status. The school is to be a place of educational innovation permanently.</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho continues to innovate and improve. Because of the faith and   devotion that has characterized the institution from the very   beginning, the university will remain true to its legacy and faithful to   its mission while moving forward on a steady upward course.</p>
<p>Click <a href="http://streaming.byui.edu/presentations/wagonbox.wmv" target="_parent">here</a> to watch a video presentation prepared for BYU-Idaho students that    describes the university's place in the history of the Upper Snake River Valley.</p>
<p>To read the original announcement of the transition from Ricks College to BYU-Idaho, click <a href="http://www.byui.edu/AboutBYUIdaho/transitionannouncement.htm" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>For a more detailed look at BYU-Idaho's past, click <a href="http://www.byui.edu/PR/General/BYUIHistory.htm" target="_parent">here</a> for a general history or <a href="http://www.byui.edu/pr/thespiritofricks/" target="_parent">here</a> for <em>The Spirit of Ricks: A History of Ricks College</em> by David L. Crowder.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x86" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
