<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--*** Ingeniux CMS 7.0.33 - http://www.ingeniux.com ***-->
<Content_wSideColumn ID="x9329" Name="The Announcement" Layout="general_content.xsl"><Title type="string" label="Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Announcement</Title><Abstract type="string" label="Abstract" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="true">The Announcement</Abstract><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SideColumn" label="L/R Column" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><MoveLeft type="boolean" label="Toggle column right or left (right is default)" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">false</MoveLeft><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="ImageComponent" label="Image Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="LeftColumnImageComponent"/><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="TextComponent" label="Text Component" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="ColumnTextComponent"/></xPower><BodyCopy type="dhtml" label="Body Copy" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"><![CDATA[<p>June 21, 2000</p>
<h3>Ricks College to become Brigham Young University-Idaho</h3>
<h3>&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>
<p>REXBURG, Idaho - The First Presidency of The Church of Jesus Christ of  Latter-day Saints and the Board of Trustees of Ricks College announce  that Ricks College will change from its present two-year junior college  status to a four-year institution. The new four-year school will be  known as Brigham Young University-Idaho, with the name change designed  to give the school immediate national and international recognition. The  memory of Thomas E. Ricks will continue to be appropriately honored and  perpetuated.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This change of status is consistent with the ongoing tradition of  evaluation and progress that has brought Ricks College from infant  beginnings to its present position as the largest privately owned  two-year institution of higher education in America. With some additions  and modifications, the physical facilities now in place in Rexburg are  adequate to handle the new program. Undoubtedly, some changes to the  campus will be necessary. However, they will be modest in nature and  scope.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho's move to four-year status will be phased in over a period of  time and accomplished in such a way as to preserve the school's autonomy  and identity. Adjustments to its mission will be minimal. The school  will have a unique role in and be distinctive from the other  institutions of higher education within the Church Educational System.  For the immediate future, the president of BYU-Idaho will report  directly to the Commissioner of the Church Educational System.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho will continue to be teaching oriented. Effective teaching and  advising will be the primary responsibilities of its faculty, who are  committed to academic excellence. The institution will emphasize  undergraduate education and will award baccalaureate degrees; graduate  degree programs will not be offered. Faculty rank will not be a part of  the academic structure of the new four-year institution.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>BYU-Idaho will operate on an expanded year-round basis, incorporating  innovative calendaring and scheduling while also taking advantage of  advancements in technology which will enable the four-year institution  to serve more students. In addition, BYU-Idaho will phase out its  involvement in intercollegiate athletics and shift its emphasis to a  year-round activity program designed to involve and meet the needs of a  diverse student body.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Of necessity, the new four-year institution will be assessing and  restructuring its academic offerings. Predictably, the school will need  to change and even eliminate some long-standing and beneficial programs  as the school focuses upon key academic disciplines and activities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Specific programmatic details about and time lines for the change are  presently being worked out. These details, which will be discussed with  and approved by the Board of Trustees, will be announced at appropriate  times in the future.</p>]]></BodyCopy><xPower Type="Component" Component="" Name="HighlightedLinks" label="Highlighted Links" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="HighlightedLinksComponent" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="Navigation" StartPage="x5" MaxDepth="" MaxNodes="" GenerationOrder="down" Navigation="Ancestors" Query="" Name="AncestorNavigation" label="Ancestor Navigation" readonly="true" hidden="true" required="false" Expanded="false"/><xPower Type="GroupStart" GroupStart="" Name="SEOGroup" label="SEO Group" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false" Expanded="false"><BrowserBarTitle type="string" label="Browser Bar Title" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></BrowserBarTitle><MetaDescription type="string" label="Meta Description" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false"></MetaDescription><NoFollow type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Follow" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoFollow><NoIndex type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No Index" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoIndex><NoODP type="boolean" hidden="true" label="No ODP" readonly="false" required="false">false</NoODP><Priority type="enumeration" values="0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0" label="Priority" readonly="false" hidden="false" required="false">0.5</Priority></xPower><xPower Type="Component" Component="x86" Name="SiteControl" label="Site Control" readonly="true" hidden="false" required="false" CompTypes="SiteControl" Expanded="false"/></Content_wSideColumn>
